<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23uncategorized&amp;_t=rss&amp;offset=90" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Three Types of Troll</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/three-types-of-troll</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/three-types-of-troll</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 22:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A huge issue with a lot of discussions of how to handle trolling on the internet is that it is often not recognized that trolling refers to three distinct types of behavior. For one of these the usual no troll feeding logic applies, but for the others that is a much more dubious rule to follow. Here is my taxonomy of trolling</p>
<ul><li>The classic troll: This is the core thing that people think of when they think of trolling. This type of troll posts things on message boards to with the intent of getting the most lulzy response from that community. This is the type of troll that rants about how bad Micro$haft winblows is. But other than being mildly annoying and disruptive, the attention getting behavior of this troll type is pretty harmless. This is also the type of troll that the no feeding rule works the best for.  The other type of trolls are more toxic extensions of this variant. 
</li><li>The "flacker" – this type of troll is an ideologue that exhibits a lot of the same effect as the classic troll, but this effect and behavior is the result of extremism, not lulz seeking. Limited feeding/interaction with trolls of this kind is not useless, but you are usually dealing with a personality that is immune to logic.
</li><li>The grifer. This is the type of troll that does extremely destructive behavior like harassment, doxing, SWATing, script kiddy hacking, defacement of websites, mailbombing, and the like. This type of troll deserves a decisive response, and should not just be ignored.  This is the type that inhabits such places as 8chan /Baphomet/.</li></ul><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aftermath of swarm from beehive</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/aftermath-of-swarm-from-beehive</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/aftermath-of-swarm-from-beehive</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 08:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>My beehive had a swarm. These are photos of what happened.<br /><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157653794667561">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157653794667561</a></p>

<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YM1-DVsDIE0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More photos</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-photos</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-photos</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 20:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Here are some more of the photos that I've taken recently. These ones are mostly of plants.See the following flickr album <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157653388769888">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157653388769888</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Photos</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-photos</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-photos</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 04:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I recently got a new camera (a Nikon Coolpix L330). Here are some of the photos I took with it.<br />You can view them on flickr here <a href="https://flic.kr/s/aHskcoM6hB"></a><a href="https://flic.kr/s/aHskcoM6hB">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>s/<wbr></wbr>aHskcoM6hB</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looks like the Lizard Squad Script Kiddies are going to jail</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/looks-like-the-lizard-squad-script-kiddies-are-going-to</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/looks-like-the-lizard-squad-script-kiddies-are-going-to</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 09:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.inquisitr.com/1760468/lizard-squad-caught-ddos-attacks-and-possible-swatting-lead-to-second-arrest/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.inquisitr.com/<wbr></wbr>1760468/<wbr></wbr>lizard-squad-caught-ddos-attacks-and-possible-swatting-lead-to-second-arrest/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>U.K. Police have arrested a teenager claiming responsibility for similar DDoS attacks, as well as other possible shenanigans. In cooperation with the U.S. FBI, the Finnish 18-year-old was taken into custody and had his/her computer and electronic equipment seized under suspicion of hacking, as well as threats to kill and “swat” various targets. The first arrest was made on New Years Eve 2014, when 22-year-old Vinnie Omari was said to be connected to the Lizard Squad attacks.<br />Read more at <a href="http://www.inquisitr.com/1760468/lizard-squad-caught-ddos-attacks-and-possible-swatting-lead-to-second-arrest/#AAFeSMFvdBCbZDRf.99">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.inquisitr.com/<wbr></wbr>1760468/<wbr></wbr>lizard-squad-caught-ddos-attacks-and-possible-swatting-lead-to-second-arrest/<wbr></wbr>#AAFeSMFvdBCbZDRf.99</a></p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fbi" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fbi</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lizardsquad" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lizardsquad</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyearseve" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyearseve</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#AAFeSMFvdBCbZDRf</category>
      <category>#fbi</category>
      <category>#lizardsquad</category>
      <category>#newyearseve</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is science denialism just a right wing problem?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/is-science-denialism-just-a-right-wing-problem</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/is-science-denialism-just-a-right-wing-problem</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 08:51:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The idea that antiscience tendencies are just a right-wing thing is often presented. In this post I will argue that science denialism is as big a problem for the left as for the right. The right wing examples of this are clear and blatant; creationism, climate change skepticism, issues excepting basic public health knowledge, and so on. However, the left has its own skeletons in the closet. Antiscience is something that comes out of ideology. Strict ideology and partisanship is the mind killer. In some ideological fact become such a part of someone's worldview that is beyond reproach them, denial of facts is a simple consequence. Many people want a world where the facts neatly aligned with their political beliefs, as these beliefs that come stronger, more partisan, more ideological the contradictions between the belief and the real world will become more acute. A vast portion of the antiscience tendencies and current politics come from this tendency. It is easy to try to adjust the facts to your belief, instead of the other way around. The only way to prevent people from denying basic facts of science is to train people to be rational and to put behind partisanship and ideology when the facts clearly contradict deeply held beliefs. It's not primarily a problem of lack of education, <a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/2015/01/education-plus-ideology-exaggerates-rejection-of-reality/">studies have looked at this and found that generally education is little to do with science denying tendencies and can in fact make them worse in some cases</a>, it's a problem of politics and people. The fact that people often deny reality conflicts with their subjective viewpoint creates something I've heard called "crank magnetism". Crackpot ideas are rarely alone, and someone who believes one crank theory likely believes another. Really, I think politics has a lot to with this. A lot of people don't want to accept facts that are inconvenient to their political ideology. And some people are more likely to reject facts to preserve their ideology than others. Just in my contacts, I've noticed a lot of overlap between global warming denialism ,creationism, and general conspiracy theories (new world order, Illuminati , birtherism, Agenda 21, moon landing hoax, etc...) . These people tend to be politically right wing. I've also noticed a left-wing crank cluster. Anti-GMO crap, alternative medicine, homeopathy, vitalism, problems accepting some basic principles of economics (this last one could probably be put as both an issue of the left-wing and right-wing, but it's probably more problematic in the left, I'll discuss more about how people's understandings of economics can elucidate a lot about how people come to deny facts in a later post) and a general persistence of Freudian type psychoanalytic ideas in much of left-wing  (particularly feminist academic theory). Additionally<a href="http://old.richarddawkins.net/articles/824-postmodernism-disrobed">, persistence of so-called "postmodernist" ideas in left-wing theory also tell us a lot about antiscience in the left</a>. Anti-vaccine nonsense seems to be the one overlap between the two. I will go into a bit more about that left-wing crackpot cluster.</p>
<ol><li>As I have discussed earlier in this blog, opposition to genetically modified foods from the left is absurd and reflective of many the antiscience trends in the left. Pretty much every major public health organization in the world is concluded there is little risk to the health of the public from GM foods. In fact, there is quite a bit of potential from this technology. And use of genetic modification by many accounts has increased agricultural yields. While there are some legitimate issues of the current deployment of technologies, there are few issues that are unique to this industry (anti-GMO activists will often point out the patent trolling by many companies in this industry, but patent trolling is becoming pretty common across the tech world). And there is pretty much no scientific basis to GMO bans or GMO labeling mandates, in fact many GMO labeling proposals produce substantial constitutional issues.
</li><li>Certain types of hipster left-wingers seem strongly attracted to alternative medicine. But there is a reason why most alternative medicine is "alternative". It doesn't work. Medicine that works is just called "medicine". Homeopathy is a particular type of alternative medicine that has a very large following. The scientific evidence on the subject unequivocally indicates that homeopathy treatments simply put, do not work at all, in fact the core theories of homeopathy violate fundamental principles of physics, chemistry, and biology. Homeopathy treatments are usually diluted to such an extent and there is little to no active ingredient actually present in the tincture. The problem with alternative medicine is that it's use tends to displace real medicine. People waste money on quacks instead of seeing real doctors for their issues. Money and lives are put at risk. And due to opposition from the left that attempts to regulate alternative medicine, little is done to stop this damage.
</li><li>Embedded in both the opposition to GMOs and the belief in alternative medicine is a pseudo-vitalism. A lot of people believe in some kind of inherent life force found in living things that is not found elsewhere. There is, of course, absolutely no scientific evidence for such a thing.
</li><li>I'll discuss some of the issues of economics in a later post.
</li><li>The pseudoscientific tendencies much of critical theory and the like is clear. A lot of this very embeds a pseudoscientific quasi-Freudian understanding of human psychology, particularly the idea of the deep subconscious which is reflected by people's thoughts and the media in the art that results from these thoughts. Since this is a detailed enough subject to be worth quite a bit more time than I could give it in this single post, I will probably write an additional post on the subject.
</li></ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is a good smartwatch design possible?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/is-a-good-smartwatch-design-possible</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/is-a-good-smartwatch-design-possible</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 06:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I've been pretty skeptical about the future of smart watches. Sure, they are getting a whole lot of attention, but are they really good for? As far as I can tell not very much. There's some benefit to having the ability to push out arbitrary data to the user handheld scale device. But really that benefit is dwarfed by the fact that smart watches are vastly inferior at being, well watches. Battery life can see the real killer of smart watch designs. Pretty much every smart watch on the market that I've seen is the battery life that's in days. A traditional watch can go years, or at least months without a recharge. There are other clear advantages of traditional watches over smart watches, for example, a smart watch pretty much is it going to be waterproof. Traditional watches are waterproof, this allows them to be used in situations like swimming pools and such. Really, about the only reasonable use of smart watches I've seen are fitness tracking related apps. But, this is a pretty niche use. Most the population isn't going to want a hundred and fifty dollars device that exists simply do slightly increase the ease of tracking their running performance. I'm critical of smart watches a pretty earlier adopter of PDAs and other proto-smartphones. Years before the iPhone came out, I had multiple Palm OS PDAs. But it was pretty clear at that point there was a clear use for a computer that can fit in your pocket. The screens of PDAs and smart phones are more than large enough to convey useful data to the user and to allow nontrivial input from the user. Palm OS PDAs, even though they were early and immature, still had a pretty great use in my workflow. They were decent for notetaking and basic calendar use, the ability load simple applications on to them allowed them to do other stuff like simple gaming. The main problem with Palm OS was some of their clunky interface issues, and their missing of a few critical details. Palm OS PDAs, even though they were general-purpose computers trying to still keep some interaction like that of a simple peripheral. In Palm OS PDAs could only sync through a relatively clunky Palm desktop application. With the iPhone, Steve Jobs had an pretty critical insight, design a smart phone like a general-purpose computer that could function completely autonomously of other devices. The thing was smart phone were good enough to be a second computer for the user. However I am not seeing such a niche for the smart watch. First of all pretty much all smart watches in existence are nearly fully dependent on the smart phone. Which means outside of a few niche uses for them, like the uses for the early PDAs, there's not much reason why a typical user would want one when they could just use their smart phone for most of the features. And even worse for the future of the smart watch, due to their input and output limitations I don't see much improvement on this front as a possibility. What really would a smart watch is an independent device be good for? I don't see much. The few best designs I've seen the smart watch, have come close to tantalizing but still have critical limitations. Microsoft Band is a good example of this. This smart watch is a nice interface and a fairly clean touch based input. With the band Microsoft seems to be targeting the fitness market, and the few people who want instant notifications of incoming text and email. The first thing to note about this smart watch is that it's battery life straight up crippling. With the band you can only expect about a day or so of battery life. That's not good. But $200 costs of the band also is not good. These limitations will make it unable to exceed the cost of value ratio of the normal watch for the vast majority of users. Another interesting smart watch design the targets the battery life issue is that by the manufacturer Martian. This smart watch divides the watch part in the smart part in to two halves. The upper part of this watch is a simple analog clock. Below this clock is a ticker that shows the output. This solves the battery life issues to some degree. The smart part is a battery life of a few days, but the actual watch part runs on a separate battery and can run for years. However the reducing of the input-output makes the other issues of the smart watch even more acute. Watch live a ticker like that can do even less than other smart watches. That data can be displayed and the range of user interface interactions are severely reduced. Added at the fact that the price tag is over $200, and you don't get a good cost of value ratio. The problems of our so inherent in the form factor but I doubt any designer will be able to bypass them. There is one type of smart device that I think has a lot of future. Smart pens. I have a Livescribe pen, and live this device I see a lot of the same issues I saw early Palm OS devices. The pen can only sync through this "Livescribe desktop" application, an application is quite crippling the functionality of the whole device. However despite this smart pen has really integrated itself into my overall personal workflow. The simple way around the current limitations of these pens would be to simply make Smart pens independent device, just like was done with smart phones. I will probably elaborate on this later in a future post.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/microsoftband" class="p-category" rel="tag">#microsoftband</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/stevejobs" class="p-category" rel="tag">#stevejobs</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#microsoftband</category>
      <category>#stevejobs</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why 100+ Mile Range TV Antennas Do Not Exist</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-100-mile-range-tv-antennas-do-not-exist</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-100-mile-range-tv-antennas-do-not-exist</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 11:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I'm in the market for an over-the-air TV antenna to go with a TV tuner, and while searching I've noticed more than a few sellers advertising antennas that can get ranges as high as 150 miles.   [caption id="attachment_1440" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/1802424443_21761d4caa_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/1802424443_21761d4caa_o-300x213.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user  anomalous4 &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3KgTZv</a>" width="300" height="213" class="size-medium wp-image-1440" /&gt; Image via Flickr user  anomalous4<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/3KgTZv%5B/caption%5DSuch">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3KgTZv[/<wbr></wbr>caption]Such</a> a thing would be neat as it would allow me reach signals from other cities. But it is too good to be true. Such a device would violate the laws of physics considering the methods used to broadcast TV signals. You will be unlikely to find an antenna that gets more than 60 miles of range, and getting more than 50 miles will come at a high price premium. However, there are lots of people who seem to have fallen for this scam and brought these devices. There are two clear issues that prevent the creation of such a device, at least at a reasonable price. The first is the inverse-square law  of light. Even assuming a flat Earth, a radio signal declines in proportion to square of the distance. Because TV broadcasts are information rich, the antenna needs to catch a lot of information from the broadcast. But the strength of the signal rapidly declines as the broadcast gets farther away. And as there are three dimensions of space that the signal is spreading out in, this change isn't merely linear -- its quadratic.  When the distance doubles the signal (and the cost of picking it up) quadruples. When the distance doubles, the signal reduces nine-fold, when the distance quadruples the signal reduces 16 fold.   There is a second, even more restrictive limit on the creation of a long range antenna -- the fact that the earth is curved. This curvature enforces a line of sight on radio transmissions and therefore sets a maximum range for radio transmissions. Were the broadcasting station merely suspended in space the signal would go out evenly in all directions. However, in the real world, the Earth provides an obstruction. Therefore, the signal is directional, and as the recipient of the signal moves farther away the curvature of the Earth means that he is facing in a direction that is blocked by the Earth. Therefore the recipient is unable to receive the signal past the line of sight.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scienceandtech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scienceandtech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#scienceandtech</category>
      <category>#tv</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Irrational Ebola Panic: 30 Year Old Ohio Small Business Shuts Down Because an Ebola Victim Shopped There</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-irrational-ebola-panic-30-year-old-ohio-small-business</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-irrational-ebola-panic-30-year-old-ohio-small-business</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 07:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/09/us/ebola-store-ohio-bridal-shop-where-ebola-patient-shopped-will-close.html?_r=0">According to the New York Times, a small business bridal store in Ohio has closed its doors</a>due to public concern due to Ebola. A victim of the virus shopped there while infected but asymptomatic (and therefore non-contagious). [caption id="attachment_1443" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/2537685236_0eb9a6c92f_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/2537685236_0eb9a6c92f_o-300x138.jpg" alt="Image via CDC." width="300" height="138" class="size-medium wp-image-1443"></a> Image via CDC.[/caption]The store replaced its inventory and conducted an intensive cleaning and when it reopened after the cleaning it had the support of a number of local officials. However, the fact that there was no reasonable threat to the public didn't stop people from avoiding the store because of its Ebola "connection". The sales of the store halved after the re-opening. This store is a victim of a public that does not understand basic science. It is the victim  of irrational paranoia over an extremely rare virus. A basic understand of the facts of medicine would give a typical individual little to fear in such a situation. Only two people have caught the virus in the United States and the clear facts of the biology of the virus show that the infected individual was not contagious. The fact that irrational parinoa destroyed that small business is outrageous.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/cdc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#cdc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialismantiscience" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialismantiscience</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/economybusiness" class="p-category" rel="tag">#economybusiness</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyorktimes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyorktimes</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scienceandtech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scienceandtech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#cdc</category>
      <category>#denialismantiscience</category>
      <category>#economybusiness</category>
      <category>#newyorktimes</category>
      <category>#scienceandtech</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Post Will Prove that You've Been Writing Articles the Wrong Way Your Whole Life: Is Clickbaiting Just Professional Trolling?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-post-will-prove-that-youve-been-writing-articles-the</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-post-will-prove-that-youve-been-writing-articles-the</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 02:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The New Yorker <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/01/05/virologist?mbid=rss">recently profiled Emerson Spartz</a>, the founder of a number of "viral content" websites, including Doze and Brainwreck. The thing I noticed in this article is how close the motivation of viral content designers become to those of internet trolls. The classic [caption id="attachment_1418" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/5297464066_736311e515_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/5297464066_736311e515_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user Si1very &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>957Tvm</a>" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1418" /&gt; Image via Flickr user Si1very <a href="https://flic.kr/p/957Tvm%5B/caption%5Dbehavior">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>957Tvm[/<wbr></wbr>caption]behavior</a> of trolls is posting material designed more to inflame readers than to get a true viewpoint through. This can be seen in the attention getting nature of clickbait, as clickbaiters put attention getting before actual value. Says Spartz “The way we view the world, the ultimate barometer of quality is: if it gets shared, it’s quality. If someone wants to toil in obscurity, if that makes them happy, that’s fine. Not everybody has to change the world.” To the authors of clickbait, quality is no goal, attention is the only goal. During <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AHqGV5WjS4w">a talk at the Defcon security and hacking conference, Matt Joyce</a> defined trolling as a fuzzing attack on users. In a fuzzing attack the hacker feeds a wide variety of unexpected input into a computer program until anomalous behavior appears in the program. Likewise, a troll feeds unexpected input into internet users until a good response is obtained. Clickbaiters work in a similar way. Spartz quite literally has bots generate candidate article content by crawling forums and social media. Humans then approve and collate the most promising content suggestions and the bots then proceed to test them on users and the articles that gain the biggest response are then pushed out. This is quite close to fuzzing. Their bots quite literally generate the input fed into users.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/emersonspartz" class="p-category" rel="tag">#emersonspartz</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mattjoyce" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mattjoyce</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#emersonspartz</category>
      <category>#mattjoyce</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
