<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23supremecourt</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23supremecourt&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Indiana is considering a RFRA clone</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 06:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Indiana legislature is considering a law that is very similar to the federal Religious Freedom Restoration Act.  The bill provides that religious belief exempts one from regulations, even neutral ones, unless the government produces a compelling need. Neither the Indiana bill nor its federal twin are particular to any type of regulation and include everything from anti-discrimination laws to drug possession laws (the original inspiration for the federal RFRA). I don't think either law is a good idea. The idea of religious exemptions from neutral laws is almost always a bad idea. This is a good issue to actually read the bill on, and to read (or at least Wikipedia) some of the relevant court opinions. <a href="https://iga.in.gov/static-documents/9/2/b/a/92bab197/SB0101.05.ENRS.pdf">The bill is only four generously spaced pages long</a>.  The media coverage on this subject is pretty error ridden and contains a lot of misconceptions about what the bill actually says. The religious should not be exempted from neutral laws on the basis of religious belief and I oppose it. But, a lot of people fundamentally misunderstand what the bill actually says. A number of media outlets have claimed that it's an anti-gay bill (even though it does not directly touch on that subject, <a href="http://www.indystar.com/story/opinion/readers/2015/03/07/indiana-needs-religious-freedom-legislation/24477303/">and it likely will not affect anti-discrimination law in any meaningful way</a>). The point of this post will be to clarify a bit of the legal background, and to summarize the bill.  The Supreme Court has made it pretty clear that that the First Amendment does not allow people to ignore neutral laws on the basis of religious belief (with a handful of exceptions. See, for example, <em>Employment Division v. Smith</em>. The goal of RFRAs is to override that ruling (the federal RFRA was actually spawned by that ruling) and make actions conducted as a product of religious belief protected. Now, I strongly believe that SCOTUS got it right in Smith, and that RFRAs are fundamentally a bad idea, but the final decision belongs with the legislative branch.  Lets look at what the 11-section Indiana bill (which is likely to pass) actually says as I go through a brief summary</p>
<ul><li>Section 1: Says that the bill applies to all government laws and regulations, even ones made prior to the enactment of it. 
</li><li>Section 2: Only regulations particularly exempted by law are exempt.
</li><li>Section 3: Definitions. Says that regulators are not allowed to use unconstutional provisions to work around the bill with particular mention of the establishment clause of the first amendment. 
</li><li>Section 4: More definitions. Pretty obvious and straightforward stuff. 
</li><li>Section 5. Defines "exercise of religion" as "any exercise of religion, whether or not compelled by, or central to, a system of religious belief". 
</li><li>Section 6: Defines "government entity". 
</li><li>Section 7: Defines "Person", includes corporations, but so does the federal RFRA.
</li><li>Section 8: States that a governmental entity may not substantially burden a person's exercise of religion unless it meets strict scrutiny
</li><li>Section 9: People can sue over violations of the law. 
</li><li>Section 10: Government agencies can be ordered to pay damages to those affected. 
</li><li>Section 11: The bill does not limit the actions of private actors, only government actions, laws and regulations.
</li></ul>
<p>Section 8 is the core of the bill and most of the definition sections are mostly boilerplate. This legislation is likely not just a useless repetition of current law. It goes far beyond what the Constitution mandates and even with the federal RFRA, a state RFRA has some effect. In <em>City of Boerne v. Flores</em> the Supreme Court struck down the part of the federal RFRA that applies to the states. But panicking over a state RFRA is a bit too much because we have a decade's worth of litigation over its federal version and good caselaw on what it means.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/firstamendment" class="p-category" rel="tag">#firstamendment</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rfra" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rfra</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scotus" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scotus</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/supremecourt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#supremecourt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#firstamendment</category>
      <category>#rfra</category>
      <category>#scotus</category>
      <category>#supremecourt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Hobby Lobby Case</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-hobby-lobby-case</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-hobby-lobby-case</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 18:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Yesterday the U.S Supreme Court announced its decision in <em>Burwell v. Hobby Lobby</em>. The Court ruled that the Religious Freedom Restoration Act (RFRA) mandates that Hobby Lobby and other companies with owners that have religious objections to the federal contraceptive mandate be given an exemption to the mandate. The RFRA is a statute passed in 1993 that requires religious exemptions to a wide range of laws and was passed due to Congressional frustration at the courts' unwillingness to mandate exemptions to neutral laws under the First Amendment. The range of the protections for religious objection provided by RFRA are much broader than what the Constitution requires. The RFRA can be repealed or amended like any other law, and due to the Court's ruling in <em>City of Boerne v. Flores</em> (1997) it only applies to federal regulations, not state laws. A Democratic controlled Congress, and Bill Clinton passed the RFRA despite court rulings that stated that applying such a standard would open a floodgate of litigation and requests for exemptions. In <em>Employment Division v. Smith</em> (1990) the Court rejected the standard eventually imposed by the RFRA saying it would effect laws that include "payment of taxes to health and safety regulation such as manslaughter and child neglect laws, compulsory vaccination laws, drug laws, and traffic laws; to social welfare legislation such as minimum wage laws, child labor laws, animal cruelty laws, environmental protection laws, and laws providing for equality of opportunity for the races" . For reasons I will discuss later I think that the majority opinion is the correct interpretation of the RFRA and of current law. The problems with this ruling are mostly the fault of Congress.  However, I also think that the RFRA should be repealed and I am largely opposed to grants of religious exemptions to neutral laws. I will discuss that problem in a future blog post.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Historically, the Supreme Court has long ruled that while religious exemptions can be added to laws, there is no obligation under the First Amendment to grant such exemptions. The First Amendment requires that members of different religions be allowed to communicate their beliefs, requires that the government refrains from favoring certain religious beliefs, and protects the freedom of believers to associate with others who share their beliefs. However, the religious still have to abide by the same laws as everyone else. The first case where the court found this is in <em>Reynolds v. United States</em> (1878) which upheld a law banning polygamy against a religious freedom based challenge.  It is worth noting that <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/12/15/us/a-utah-law-prohibiting-polygamy-is-weakened.html">a 2013 case before the United States District Court in Utah struck down</a> the same polygamy ban statute on privacy grounds. <em>Reynolds</em> created a solid boundary between belief and action. While it is acceptable for one to have and express a religion, it is not as acceptable to put this belief into action, when that action conflicts with the law. That principle was the law until the Supreme Court broadened its interpretation of the Free Exercise clause to allow for more religious exemption to laws. In <em>Sherbert v. Verner</em> (1963) the court found that it violated the First Amendment when the plaintiff in the case was deprived of unemployment benefits as a result of refusing to accept a job that required work on the Sabbath. In <em>Wisconsin v. Yoder</em> (1972) the Court ruled that Amish parents and children must be exempted from truancy laws when those laws mandate attendance to a school that conflicts with Amish belief. In these cases the court ruled that when someone has <span style="color: #252525;">a sincere religious belief that conflicts with a law and when complying with the law would put a substantial burden on the objector's ability to act on that belief, the government has a strong obligation to grant exemptions to the law. The only times when a exemption does not have to be granted occur when the government has a compelling interest that cannot be fulfilled by lesser means. </span> These rulings soon provoked further litigation that eventually drove the Supreme Court to reconsider its stance on this subject matter. In Employment Division v. Smith (1990) the court finally reversed itself and returned to the policy that religious exemptions are not required. In the majority opinion justice Scalia wrote</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The "compelling government interest" requirement seems benign, because it is familiar from other fields. But using it as the standard that must be met before the government may accord different treatment on the basis of race, see, e.g., Palmore v. Sidoti, or before the government may regulate the content of speech, see, e.g., Sable Communications of California v. FCC, is not remotely comparable to using it for the purpose asserted here. What it produces in those other fields -- equality of treatment, and an unrestricted flow of contending speech -- are constitutional norms; what it would produce here -- a private right to ignore generally applicable laws -- is a constitutional anomaly.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Later in the opinion he said</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The rule respondents favor would open the prospect of constitutionally required religious exemptions from civic obligations of almost every conceivable kind -- ranging from compulsory military service to the payment of taxes to health and safety regulation such as manslaughter and child neglect laws, compulsory vaccination laws, drug laws, and traffic laws; to social welfare legislation such as minimum wage laws, child labor laws, animal cruelty laws, environmental protection laws, and laws providing for equality of opportunity for the races</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, Congress didn't see the problem and passed the RFRA three years later, finding that "<span style="color: #000000;">laws 'neutral' toward religion may burden religious exercise as surely as laws intended to interfere with religious exercise"</span>. The full text of the RFRA can be found at <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130611205052/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>religiousfreedom.lib.virginia.edu/<wbr></wbr>sacred/<wbr></wbr>RFRA1993.html</a>"&gt;<a href="http://religiousfreedom.lib.virginia.edu/sacred/RFRA1993.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>religiousfreedom.lib.virginia.edu/<wbr></wbr>sacred/<wbr></wbr>RFRA1993.html</a> The core of the law states that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>(a) In General: Government shall not substantially burden a person's exercise of religion even if the burden results from a rule of general applicability, except as provided in subsection (b). (b) Exception: Government may substantially burden a person's exercise of religion only if it demonstrates that application of the burden to the person-- (1) is in furtherance of a compelling governmental interest; and (2) is the least restrictive means of furthering that compelling governmental interest..</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even the application of the word "person" to a corporation such as Hobby Lobby isn't something the Court just came up with. If you object to that <span style="color: #262626;">blame Congress for it.  Even the application of it to corporations is due to the wonderful work of Congress. The Dictionary Act statute at 1 U.S. Code § 1 defines what "person" refers to in legislation in the absence of clarification otherwise, and  the RFRA just said "person" without any clarification otherwise. </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p>the words “person” and “whoever” include corporations, companies, associations, firms, partnerships, societies, and joint stock companies, as well as individuals;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Furthermore, it is worth noting that ultimately the application of religious freedom legislation to a company protects the owners of it. The rights of a company come out of their rights. And the Hobby Lobby company is owned by just a few individuals, all of whom are of uniform opinion on this matter..<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2014/06/30/hobby-lobby-and-the-legal-rights-of-people-organized-as-corporations/"> An editorial in the Washington Post discusses this, and quotes the following passage</a> from Justice Alito's opinion in the Hobby Lobby case.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Congress provided protection for people like the [owners of Hobby Lobby and Conestoga Wood] by employing a familiar legal fiction: It included corporations within RFRA’s definition of “persons.” But it is important to keep in mind that the purpose of this fiction is to provide protection for human beings. A corporation is simply a form of organization used by human beings to achieve desired ends. An established body of law specifies the rights and obligations of the people(including shareholders, officers, and employees) who are associated with a corporation in one way or another. When rights, whether constitutional or statutory, are extended to corporations, the purpose is to protect the rights of these people. For example, extending Fourth Amendment protection to corporations protects the privacy interests of employees and others associated with the company. Protecting corporations from government seizure of their property without just compensation protects all those who have a stake in the corporations’ financial well-being. And protecting the free-exercise rights of corporations like Hobby Lobby, Conestoga, and Mardel protects the religious liberty of the humans who own and control those companies….</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now that it has been established that a firm like Hobby Lobby can claim religious freedom rights under the RFRA, now lets see why the RFRA mandates religious exemptions to the mandate. To win the case Hobby Lobby at the least has to prove two things.</p>
<ol><li>That its owners have a sincere religious belief that conflicts with the mandate. A<span style="color: #262626;">ll that has to be proven is that Hobby Lobby's owners' belief is sincerely held. They don't have to prove that their belief is actually correct.</span></li>
    <li>They have to prove that their ability to exercise  their beliefs are substantially burdened by their beliefs</li>
</ol>
<p>In regards to the first question, the owners of Hobby Lobby claim to believe that using certain forms of contraceptives, or even being complicit in their distribution is immoral. The trial court found no reason to doubt their sincerity in this belief. Much press coverage has though it is absurd that such a indirect connection to the allegedly immoral activity as buying an insurance plan that could be used to acquire contraception, can be the foundation of a RFRA claim. <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2014/06/30/the-religious-freedom-restoration-act-and-complicity-in-sin/">However, the RFRA clearly allows such a claim.</a> As per the terms of that legislation, all that matters is that the owners of Hobby Lobby believe that the law compels them to do an immoral action. If they believe that contributing to someone else's activity is itself immoral, than that is still sufficient.  The conditions for a substantial burden to occur and similarly broad. All that needs to be met is that the owners of the company think that the law compels them to do something that is intolerably sinful.</p>

<p>At this point the government could still salvage its case if it could prove the following two things</p>
<ol><li>There is a compelling government interest involved</li>
    <li>The regulation is the least intrusive legislation possible to meet the interest.</li>
</ol>
<p>The court found that there is a compelling government interest involved. However, there are regulations possible that put less of a burden on the beliefs of the Hobby Lobby owners. The government could for example pay for the contraceptives out of pocket.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/employmentdivision" class="p-category" rel="tag">#employmentdivision</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hobbylobby" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hobbylobby</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rfra" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rfra</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/supremecourt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#supremecourt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#252525</category>
      <category>#000000</category>
      <category>#262626</category>
      <category>#262626</category>
      <category>#employmentdivision</category>
      <category>#hobbylobby</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#rfra</category>
      <category>#supremecourt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt Ceiling Shakedown 2013</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/debt-ceiling-shakedown-2013</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/debt-ceiling-shakedown-2013</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 17:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p> </p>

<p>Politicians, driven by faulty economic theories and their own political ambitions, are again thinking about taking the nation's reputation hostage and gambling with America's future. Yes, the Republicans seem to be planning another debt ceiling crisis. <a title="According to the Los Angeles Times" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130614000138/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.latimes.com/<wbr></wbr>business/<wbr></wbr>la-fi-debt-limit-20130510,0,7705505.story</a>" target="_blank"&gt;According to the Los Angeles Times, the party's legislators want "tangible progress on overhauling the tax code" in return for a debt ceiling increase.</p>

<p>The debt ceiling limits the the number of government bonds that can be issued. Although a debt ceiling increase does not authorize additional spending, under current government practice, debt issue is needed to meet commitments already made by Congress. If the debt ceiling is not raised, the United States government will default on obligations committed to by existing law. The U.S Treasury would not be able to make payments on all government liabilities and programs, or would have to resort to unconventional means to fund the government deficit. Many major government programs would necessarily face rapid cuts. The economic consequences of such a default could be disastrous. Let's first look at what would have happened if the debt limit was not increased during the 2011 crisis. <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2011/02/17/news/economy/debt_limit_spending_cuts/index.htm?iid=EL" target="_blank">According to CNN</a>, the cuts required would have been equivalent to the any of the following: the amount spent on “all discretionary spending, including defense,” plus 50 billion dollars; 70 percent of the funds spent on Social Security or Medicare; or two-thirds of total government tax revenue.Additional cuts would have been needed to cover the government through 2012, or to account for the effect that depressed private spending would have had on the economy. Clearly, suddenly disbanding the military or ending Social Security would not be good policy. But unrealistic budget slashing of that magnitude is proposed when the Tea Party demands that their ideology rule the day, regardless of whether it's supported by sound economic theory or the majority of the nation's voters.<br />If the debt ceiling is not raised this year, the program cuts made necessary by this inaction will be very harsh. Budget reductions amounting to between four to five percent of GDP, or about one-half of those that would have been required during the 2011 crisis, will be necessary. Obviously, this would be very harmful. The decreases in government spending that would be required would also immediately reduce economic output. This is because decreases in government spending will directly reduce demand for products. The possible supply of goods and services in the current depressed economy is substantially greater than the demand for these goods. Therefore, an increase in demand will increase economic production in the current situation because businesses will have the capacity to absorb it. But if the debt ceiling isn't raised, just the opposite will happen. Demand and output will be reduced by a decrease in government spending because less money will be around to purchase American products. Government contracts with businesses may be canceled or the amount spent decreased. Benefit reductions will also lessen demand for goods and services. If food stamp benefits are reduced, grocery purchases will decrease. Social Security and unemployment benefit recipients are all buyers of goods and services. With less money, they too will buy less.<br />In fact, the cuts can be expected to reduce demand more than just their raw value. And they would disproportionately harm the poor and middle class, who spend most of their income and have low rates of savings. One person's spending is another's income. Government programs like food stamps and unemployment benefits are extremely good at stimulating demand. <a href="http://www.economist.com/node/18958475" target="_blank">According to an article published in The Economist</a>, “When Moody’s Analytics assessed different forms of stimulus, it found that food stamps were the most effective, increasing economic activity by $1.73 for every dollar spent. Unemployment insurance came in second, at $1.62, whereas most tax cuts yielded a dollar or less.”<br />Failing to raise the debt ceiling would hurt the U.S. government and the economy in one other way that is even more detrimental than the effects of budget reductions. A default on government obligations would cause serious harm. A default would occur if the government failed to pay past commitments made by Congress. If the debt ceiling is not raised, the president and the treasury will be obligated to violate at least one law, either a law allocating funds to a government program, or the debt ceiling law itself. As the Supreme Court ruled in Train v. City of New York (1975), the treasury is obligated to disburse all funds allocated by Congress. The cuts made in this fashion will be made without public debate and will not be made through the regular political process. They will be made by orders made by executive branch officials. The ability for the public to debate and contest such cuts is limited and great legislative power–the ability to dissolve or dramatically reduce programs enacted by Congress– would be transferred to the executive.<br />The procedure to avoid default is simple. All Congress has to do is pass a debt ceiling extension. Debt ceiling raises have not been such intense issues in the past. <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2011/01/03/news/economy/debt_ceiling_faqs/index.htm" target="_blank">The debt ceiling has been raised 74 times since March 1962, before it became a major political issue</a>.All that is needed to avoid an economic crisis is a return to this previous pattern where debt ceiling votes are not held up as political tools.<br />This latest game from the Republican Party is just a simple shakedown that lacks even a superficial connection to fixing the debt. Instead of budget cuts, or a budget program, what is being demanded are changes to the fundamental structure of tax policy. The tax reform proposals supported by the Republicans will not reduce the debt, just change the distributional effects of the tax code in a way that benefits the wealthy. In fact, a majority of Republicans have signed a no-tax-increase pledge. Those truly concerned about the deficit would not be proposing tax cuts that would reduce government revenue.<br />Why not eliminate the deficit? A deficit is necessary at many times for two reasons. The first is that when the economy is below full-employment, government deficit spending is often the only way to restore the economy. The second is that <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/johntharvey/2012/07/18/why-you-should-love-government-deficits/" target="_blank">a government surplus necessarily means a private sector that is as a whole running a deficit</a>. By accounting identity, net (domestic) private savings equals the sum of the government deficit and the trade balance (positive if a trade surplus, negative if a trade deficit).The only way that the U.S government can be in surplus when there is a trade deficit is if, on average, households and domestic businesses are in deficit. Large private debts are inherently more harmful than government debts because households and businesses have finances that are much more constrained than the finances of the government.<br />Republicans have learned that shakedowns like this work because Obama has folded before. The majority of the Republican party has also been cowed by the risk of a primary challenge from the <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/127181/tea-partiers-fairly-mainstream-demographics.aspx" target="_blank">28 percent of the population that supports the extremists of the Tea Party</a>. It is high time that we stop this small minority from setting the nation's agenda. The fact that the Tea Party, and its supporters, want to risk irreparable, long-term damage to the nation to achieve short-term political goals makes such an extreme political movement unfit to govern.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/republicanparty" class="p-category" rel="tag">#republicanparty</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/socialsecurity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#socialsecurity</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/supremecourt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#supremecourt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/teaparty" class="p-category" rel="tag">#teaparty</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#republicanparty</category>
      <category>#socialsecurity</category>
      <category>#supremecourt</category>
      <category>#teaparty</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
