<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23denialismantiscience</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23denialismantiscience&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Mentioning the Possibility of Geoengineering Efforts Might Induce More Acceptance of Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/mentioning-the-possibility-of-geoengineering-efforts-might-induce-more-acceptance</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/mentioning-the-possibility-of-geoengineering-efforts-might-induce-more-acceptance</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 04:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.culturalcognition.net/browse-papers/geoengineering-and-the-science-communication-environment-a-c.html">A new study published in <em>Annals of the AAPS</em> suggests</a>that providing information about the possibility of geoengineering might cause individuals to accept climate change. The authors speculate that it has to do with ideology -- conservatives (or hierarchical-individualists as the paper calls them) tend to put a lot of faith in business and industry, and a conventional presentation of the climate change issue tends to be at least somewhat in opposition to business. Geoengennering uses the tools of industry and thus it might be more palatable to conservatives. That line of reasoning makes me wonder if it was a mistake for activists to emphasize renewable energy as the main alternative to fossil fuels. Nuclear might be more favorable for conservatives. The abstract of the paper reads</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We conducted a two-nation study (United States, n = 1500; England, n = 1500) to test a novel theory of science communication. The cultural cognition thesis posits that individuals make extensive reliance on cultural meanings in forming perceptions of risk. The logic of the cultural cognition thesis suggests the potential value of a distinctive two-channel science communication strategy that combines information content (“Channel 1”) with cultural meanings (“Channel 2”) selected to promote open-minded assessment of information across diverse communities. In the study, scientific information content on climate change was held constant while the cultural meaning of that information was experimentally manipulated. Consistent with the study hypotheses, we found that making citizens aware of the potential contribution of geoengineering as a supplement to restriction of CO2 emissions helps to offset cultural polarization over the validity of climate-change science. We also tested the hypothesis, derived from competing models of science communication, that exposure to information on geoengineering would provoke discounting of climate-change risks generally. Contrary to this hypothesis, we found that subjects exposed to information about geoengineering were slightly more concerned about climate change risks than those assigned to a control condition.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://www.skepticalscience.com/kahan-geoeng-polar.html">SKS' Andy Skuce notes</a> that their framing of geoengineering is pretty slanted. The article presented to participants is the following.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/kahangeo1.jpg"><img class=" size-full wp-image-2120 alignnone" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/kahangeo1.jpg" alt="kahangeo1" width="545" height="702"></a></p>

<p>The techniques vary a lot, but I generally consider geoengineering better than just bearing the costs of severe climate change and adapting, but worse than actually preventing emissions. The other thing is that the most practical/cheapest geoengineering schemes tend to be the ones with the most adverse impacts. I also think that a geoengineering project will be deployed at some point, as I don't see a full mitigation of CO2 emissions happening anything soon with enough strength to avoid dangerous levels of climate change. The scale of the shift in energy infrastructure is on the scale of the investment that happened to fight world war II, and I see no indication that policy makers are willing to commit to that type of investment quickly enough to change things (even though they should).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aaps" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aaps</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialismantiscience" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialismantiscience</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scienceandtech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scienceandtech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aaps</category>
      <category>#denialismantiscience</category>
      <category>#scienceandtech</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare events get more attention than frequent ones, or why people care more about terrorists in France than Nigeria</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/rare-events-get-more-attention-than-frequent-ones-or-why</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/rare-events-get-more-attention-than-frequent-ones-or-why</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 05:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>On Facebook and twitter I've seen a number of people posting about how the recent terrorist attacks in Nigeria by Boko Haram among other groups have not received as much coverage as the French terrorist attack. These posters point out that the Nigerian attacks claimed many more lives than the French terrorists. However that is the same reason that the Nigerian attacks are not getting covered. Media prefers to give coverage to rare that destructive events, and does not like to give coverage to more common events even if the more common events in combined are much more destructive. This is a persistent media bias that occurs across multiple different fields.<img align="left" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/011515_0603_Rareeventsg1.jpg" alt=""><span style="color:#44546a; font-size:9pt"><em>British anti-terrorism poster via <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5hm7vX"></a><a href="https://flic.kr/p/5hm7vX">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5hm7vX</a><br /></em></span></p>

<p> It seen in discussions of energy policy, gun policy, climate change, transportation policy, tech policy and many other different fields. It's the reason why you're much more likely to have heard the likes of Fukushima or Chernobyl then the many smaller accidents and disasters of occurred with conventional energy sources. It's why in discussions of gun policy relatively rare mass shootings have received much more attention in a much more frequent regular shootings and gang violence. It's why something like the disappearing Malaysian planes ever see much more coverage than the frequent car wrecks the claim tens of thousands of lives. Many commentators have tried to frame the lack of coverage in Nigeria is a side effect of racism. However treating it as a symptom of media bias towards large and rare events is much more likely. The Nigerian conflict claimed almost 4000 lives in just 2014 alone. And this conflict occurred in one of the most war prone areas in the world, a part of the world where some of the most destructive conflicts ever have occurred. Unfortunately, what happened in Nigeria is a very common event. For after a kidnapping in the Nigerian school girls this conflict received a lot of coverage, the media simply got tired of the subject because the destruction is so ubiquitous, the press moved on to a juicier subject.  The possibility of racism is a main driver of the lack of coverage given to Nigeria can be eliminated simply due to the fact that ignoring large events is so common among the press. This can also be eliminated to the wide range of politicians and officials who expressed concern about the conflict in Nigeria. Here are just a few examples of the press giving more time to a major but rare event into much more common related event.</p>
<ul><li>An obvious example of this is the recent Malaysian plane crash. Plane crashes are exceedingly rare, much rarer than car crashes. However, the Malaysian plane crashes received 24-7 coverage from number of media outlets. The reason for this is pretty much that plane crashes are something that people perceive as high risk but which are in reality a very infrequent low risk thing. Air travel is on the safest forms of mass transportation and transportation in general. When you divide the number of fatalities by the number of passenger miles traveled you obtain a result of dispels the commonly held perception that flying is dangerous. <a href="http://www.pbs.org/wgbh/nova/space/how-risky-is-flying.html">One report determined</a> that the risk of being killed in a plane crash for the typical American is about one and 11 million per year, however the equivalent risk of dying in a car accident is about one in 5000. When varying number of passenger miles traveled is taken into account, comes out to be that air travel is about as safe as driving a car or riding a train. The number of deaths per mile traveled turns out to be about the same for each mode of transit. Car crashes and railway accidents account for about 1.3 deaths per hundred million vehicle miles. Motorcycles count for about 31.3 deaths per hundred vehicle miles traveled, making it one most dangerous forms of transit widely used. And when plane crashes do happen they are single events that cause a lot of damage at once. A rare event that causes a lot of damage? That something journalists will want to cover.
</li><li>Another good example of this can be found in the energy industry. Nuclear energy is one of the safest forms of energy <a href="http://nextbigfuture.com/2011/03/deaths-per-twh-by-energy-source.html">and when you divide the amount of fatalities caused by nuclear accidents by the amount of energy produced in reactors</a>, the number is very low compared to many other major sources of energy. Fossil fuels and biomass energy are among the top most lethal energy sources and nabbed in Trieste relaxants there much more frequent than nuclear energy's accidents, and which are in aggregate much more destructive. You could probably name and number of well-known nuclear accidents. Chernobyl. Fukushima. Three Mile Island. These types of rare but high destruction at once events get a lot of media coverage. The public's view of the frequency of these accidents is highly distorted. Nuclear is perceived as one of the more dangerous energy sources around, when in fact it is one of the safer ones. Coal is by far the most dangerous energy source, air pollution produced and industrial accidents caused are factored into the death toll. Depending on the type of coal and how it is used, coal causes between 60 and 170 deaths per terawatt hour. Oil is second on the death count, coming in at about 32 deaths per terawatt hour equivalent. Biofuels are the next on the list causing about 12 deaths per terawatt hour equivalent generated (this does not include the fairly high death count caused by competition with the food supply for fuel feedstock, the excess deaths due to this are counted biofuels have a death toll that exceeds coal). Nuclear's fatalities are very low at about 0.04 deaths per terawatt hour.
</li><li>You can think of many other examples of this phenomenon happening in the media. I could for example mention the excess attention in the media given to mass shootings over regular crime. Or for that manner the excess attention given to terrorism in general compared to the many other threats facing the world. Or the wide distortion of perceptions of disease threats. People were treating the Ebola crisis as if it were a science fiction disaster movie coming to life. I can mention the relatively low priority given to the many mundane diseases around. Humans are terrible at perceiving risk, media coverage is no exception.</li></ul><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialismantiscience" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialismantiscience</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/france" class="p-category" rel="tag">#france</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/nigeria" class="p-category" rel="tag">#nigeria</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/threemileisland" class="p-category" rel="tag">#threemileisland</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#44546a</category>
      <category>#denialismantiscience</category>
      <category>#france</category>
      <category>#nigeria</category>
      <category>#threemileisland</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Irrational Ebola Panic: 30 Year Old Ohio Small Business Shuts Down Because an Ebola Victim Shopped There</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-irrational-ebola-panic-30-year-old-ohio-small-business</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-irrational-ebola-panic-30-year-old-ohio-small-business</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 07:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/01/09/us/ebola-store-ohio-bridal-shop-where-ebola-patient-shopped-will-close.html?_r=0">According to the New York Times, a small business bridal store in Ohio has closed its doors</a>due to public concern due to Ebola. A victim of the virus shopped there while infected but asymptomatic (and therefore non-contagious). [caption id="attachment_1443" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/2537685236_0eb9a6c92f_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/2537685236_0eb9a6c92f_o-300x138.jpg" alt="Image via CDC." width="300" height="138" class="size-medium wp-image-1443"></a> Image via CDC.[/caption]The store replaced its inventory and conducted an intensive cleaning and when it reopened after the cleaning it had the support of a number of local officials. However, the fact that there was no reasonable threat to the public didn't stop people from avoiding the store because of its Ebola "connection". The sales of the store halved after the re-opening. This store is a victim of a public that does not understand basic science. It is the victim  of irrational paranoia over an extremely rare virus. A basic understand of the facts of medicine would give a typical individual little to fear in such a situation. Only two people have caught the virus in the United States and the clear facts of the biology of the virus show that the infected individual was not contagious. The fact that irrational parinoa destroyed that small business is outrageous.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/cdc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#cdc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialismantiscience" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialismantiscience</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/economybusiness" class="p-category" rel="tag">#economybusiness</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyorktimes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyorktimes</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scienceandtech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scienceandtech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#cdc</category>
      <category>#denialismantiscience</category>
      <category>#economybusiness</category>
      <category>#newyorktimes</category>
      <category>#scienceandtech</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
