<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23yomkippurwar</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23yomkippurwar&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Global Warming Is Lethal</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2012/global-warming-is-lethal</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2012/global-warming-is-lethal</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 14:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>300,000, 13,000, and 893. These three numbers will help you understand why global warming and our nation's fossil fuel dependency are grave issues that merit immediate attention.</p>

<p>300,000 represents the number of people who die each year due to the effects of global warming,<a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2009/WORLD/europe/05/29/annan.climate.change.human/"> according to a study by the Global Humanitarian Forum</a>, a think tank headed by former United Nations Secretary General Kofi Annan. Of those 300,000 deaths, 90 percent were due to malnutrition and disease caused by environmental degradation in developing nations. Additional deaths were caused by weather-related disasters.</p>

<p>300,000 is the number of Americans who die each year due to particle pollution from power plants, according to <a href="http://www.lung.org/about-us/our-impact/top-stories/toxic-air-coal-fired-power-plants.html"> a study by the American Lung Association.</a> That same study also found that "Coal-fired power plants that sell electricity to the grid produce more hazardous air pollution in the U.S. than any other industrial pollution sources".</p>

<p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20120718072711/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>mediakit.motherjones.com:80/<wbr></wbr>blue-marble/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>carbon-dioxide-emissions-cost-economy-underestimated</a>"&gt;$893 is the economic damage that each ton of emitted carbon dioxide causes.The total cost of the damage done by all CO2 pollution that the average American produces in a year is almost $15,000 (the per capita CO2 emissions of the United States is 17.5 tons).</p>

<p>Polluting industries, such coal, oil and gas, make their profits by not cleaning up the messes they make. They are profitable only because they are not paying the full costs of doing business and instead are placing those costs on the public.Natural resources are never free and they are not limitless. By destroying them now we are depriving future generations of their use and placing the costs of their depletion elsewhere.</p>

<p>Global warming is real and the damage it causes is already devastating to people throughout the world and to the world economy. We have an ethical obligation to rapidly reduce CO2 emissions now and move our economy towards sustainability and alternative energy sources.A full presentation of the scientific evidence for global warming is out of the scope of this blog post, but if you're interested, see this article for a basic overview <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150325153156/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>physics.ucsd.edu/<wbr></wbr>do-the-math/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>recipe-for-climate-change/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;<a href="http://physics.ucsd.edu/do-the-math/2011/08/recipe-for-climate-change/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>physics.ucsd.edu/<wbr></wbr>do-the-math/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>recipe-for-climate-change/<wbr></wbr></a> and this website for rebuttals for common denialist arguments <a href="&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a>"&gt;<a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a> Even if you are a global warming denialist, the fact is we are starting to run out of oil and high-grade deposits of coal and natural gas.<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150630144808/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>physics.ucsd.edu/<wbr></wbr>do-the-math/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>10/<wbr></wbr>the-energy-trap/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;If we wait until there are dire shortages of energy resources, it will be more difficult to make the switch to alternative energy sources.</p>

<p>Unaddressed global warming will amount to to the mass violation of the human rights of tens of millions of people.Through no fault of their own whole populations will be exposed to health risks, food shortages, increased poverty and damage to their property. Coastal communities will be threatened with destruction as water levels rise. As Penn State professor Donald A. Brown stated "inadequate climate change policies must be understood to trigger human rights violations because climate change will not only make human dignity impossible for tens of millions of people around the world, including countless members of future generations, but directly threaten life itself and resources necessary to sustain life. That is, inadequate climate change policies qualify as human rights violations because of the enormity of harm to life, health, food, property, and inviolability of the right to enjoy the places where people live."(<a href="http://rockblogs.psu.edu/climate/2010/09/ethical-problems-with-cost-arguments-against-climate-change-policies-increased-costs-may-not-justify.html"></a><a href="http://rockblogs.psu.edu/climate/2010/09/ethical-problems-with-cost-arguments-against-climate-change-policies-increased-costs-may-not-justify.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>rockblogs.psu.edu/<wbr></wbr>climate/<wbr></wbr>2010/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>ethical-problems-with-cost-arguments-against-climate-change-policies-increased-costs-may-not-justify.html</a>) If the United States government did not take appropriate and rapid actions to reduce greenhouse gas pollution it would be a default on the principles set out under treaties including the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p>

<p>High CO2 fuels also come with high costs to national security. According to <a href="http://www.iags.org/costofoil.html"> a report published by the Institute for the Analysis of Global Security “the economic penalties of America's oil dependence total $297.2 to $304.9 billion annually”</a><a>. Most of those costs of importing oil come from the military and political instability the oil trade creates and exposes the United States to. Our oil dependence also exposes the United States to price manipulation by the few major oil producers. An example of this risk came in</a><a href="http://www.setamericafree.org/index.php?option=com_content&task=view&id=20&Itemid=2#1"> "1973 when, in response to the Yom Kippur War, OPEC slashed production by 4.3 million barrels a day and caused a four-fold increase in oil prices"</a><a>.</a><a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/global-warming-is-leathal" rel="attachment wp-att-30"> That oil price shock was a primary trigger of the stagflation of the 1970s.</a></p>

<p>Phasing out fossil fuels will have minimal costs. A <a href="http://www.google.org/energyinnovation/growth.html"> study funded by Google found </a> that in their model investment in low CO2 energy sources "added $155 billion per year in GDP, creating 1.1 million net jobs, while reducing household energy costs by $942 per year". That study also found that "a mere five year delay in starting aggressive cost curves could cost the economy an aggregate $2.3-3.2 trillion in unrealized GDP gains, 1.2-1.4 million net jobs, and 8-28 gigatons in avoided greenhouse gas emissions by 2050".</p>

<p>Global warming will become a severe economic and human rights issue if rapid attempts to reduce fossil fuel use are not made. We have a ethical obligation to reduce CO2.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/globalhumanitarianforum" class="p-category" rel="tag">#globalhumanitarianforum</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/yomkippurwar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#yomkippurwar</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#1</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#globalhumanitarianforum</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#yomkippurwar</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
