<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23centrism</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23centrism&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With The Growing Toxicity Of American Politics Does Not Mean Centrism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/dealing-with-the-growing-toxicity-of-american-politics-does-not</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/dealing-with-the-growing-toxicity-of-american-politics-does-not</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';">There are two ideas about what is wrong in American politics that, are often confused with each other</div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><strong> </strong></div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><strong>The toxicity problem</strong>— The idea that politics has become very divisive, partisan, and that this toxicity is beginning to undermine shared goals and values. This issues is roughly symmetrical on both sides of American politics. Furthermore, this is worse than in the recent past. There are a few sub-issues with in this that I identify</div><ul style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><li>Partisanship </li>
<li>Irreason (science denials, the inability for people to challenge wrong/disingenuous arguments from their own side) </li>
<li>The inability to admit uncertainty in one’s beliefs </li>
<li>The growth of political media outlets — (Fox News, social media, talk radio etc.) </li>
<li>Attacks on important shared values like civil liberties, due process, and freedom of speech.</li>
<li>The end of bipartisan cooperation to meet shared goals</li>
<li>The increasing inability to separate personal, non-political life from politics </li>
<li>Overconfidence — over estimating the probability that one’s ideas are correct</li>
</ul><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><strong>The centrism solution </strong>— The idea that the ideas promoted by both sides of American politics are extreme, and the optimal set of policies is roughly in-between the two extremes. </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"> </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';">I believe that the increasing toxicity of American politics is a major problem for the country. However, centrism is not the solution to it. The ultimate issue with the current American political situation is the <em>way</em> that political issues are being resolved. It is the political culture where the other side is viewed as the enemy. A threat to be countered before it destroys the real americans. It is the political culture that considers a “safe place” as one in which the other side is not present. It is the red tribe versus blue tribe politics. However, this is not nessarily an issue with the particular policies being promoted. It does not mean that the correct policy is halfway in-between those favored by the typical democrat and those favored by the typical republican. In many cases one side is wrong, and one side is right. Either action needs to be taken on climate change or it does not. The half-way centrist solution may very well be the worse of all options — one that neither side desires, and one that does just enough to incur a lot of costs but not enough to actually fix the climate change issue (think of the introduction of biofuels as a real world example of this). Either gay marriage should be legal or it shouldn’t, and any attempts at half way policies (such as civil unions) are unsatisfactory at best. Either the minimum wage produces dangerous disemployment effects or it doesn’t. And so on. </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"> </div><p> </p><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';">Now, the centrism-as-the-solution idea seems intuitive for a simple reason — in an highly toxic political climate , people will reject the good with the bad from the other side. The mere fact that an idea comes from the other side of the political spectrum (or even attains an association with it) becomes sufficient reason to reject it. The behavior and ideas of one side are given favoritism compared to the ideas from the other side. This may give one the idea that the middle is where the solution can be found. But even though some good conservative ideas may be rejected by liberals and some good liberal ideas may be rejected by conservatives , this does not mean that the correct choice for each issue is the middle. It means that liberals and conservatives should pay attention to each others’ ideas. </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"> </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/centrism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#centrism</a><strong> </strong></div></div>]]></description>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#centrism</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
