<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23arabspring</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23arabspring&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Libertarianism and Humanitarian Intervention: the Libertarian Rorschach Test</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/libertarianism-and-humanitarian-intervention-the-libertarian-rorschach-test</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/libertarianism-and-humanitarian-intervention-the-libertarian-rorschach-test</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 19:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>[caption id="attachment_335" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Noentanglements.jpg"></a> NO FOREIGN ENTANGLEMENTS anti-war protest sign prior to U.S. entry into WWII.[/caption]</p>

<p>The libertarian opposition to intervention in Syria and humanitarian interventions in other places brings up a fundamental contraction in libertarian political theory. Libertarians are unable to come up with a plausible theory of when it is acceptable for a state to intervene to prevent human rights violations in the territory of another.Almost all libertarians fall into either the <a href="http://thespeechatimeforchoosing.wordpress.com/2012/01/01/ron-paul-i-wouldnt-have-sent-troops-to-fight-nazis-and-save-jews-israel-shouldnt-exist/">pacifism of </a><a href="http://thespeechatimeforchoosing.wordpress.com/2012/01/01/ron-paul-i-wouldnt-have-sent-troops-to-fight-nazis-and-save-jews-israel-shouldnt-exist/">the Austrian School/Ron Paul variant</a> of libertarianism or the <a href="http://www.aynrand.org/site/News2?page=NewsArticle&id=15537&news_iv_ctrl=1223">ultra-militarism of the Ayn Rand variant</a>.This contradiction is one that runs very deep and highlights even greater issues with libertarianism. As I will show, libertarian political philosophy is a incoherent Rorschach test that can justify a vast range of policy choices and libertarianism has in general failed to come up with a justification for its core proposals.</p>

<p>As far as I can tell almost all non-anarchist libertarians accept these two principles</p>
<ol><li>The government policies that maximize liberty are the optimal ones. Illegitimate initiation of force against another is usually a violation of liberty.</li>
    <li>It is acceptable for governments to take measures intended prevent violations of liberties by third parties, including appropriate retaliatory force. This justifies the government to maintain armies, police forces and the like.</li>
</ol>
<p>When it comes to intervention to stop clear human rights violations, these two core principles of libertarian ideology are in conflict. Ayn Rand libertarianism argues that dictatorships are "initiating force" and are therefore legitimate subjects of "retaliatory force". Other variants of libertarianism  contend that the intervention itself will be the "initiation of force". Even before the Arab Spring the view of the<a href="http://www.aynrand.org/site/News2?page=NewsArticle&id=13659&news_iv_ctrl=1221"> Ayn Rand institute was that</a> "Iran and Syria are our enemies...The United States should be bombing, not 'engaging,' these terrorist "regimes."  On the other extreme <a href="http://www.ynetnews.com/articles/0,7340,L-4167841,00.html">Ron Paul's opinion on war is almost complete pacifism</a>. Ron Paul “wouldn’t have risked American lives to end the Holocaust." and  "I wouldn't send US troops to fight Nazis”. A former top aide for Ron Paul said of these comments, "I don't think that's because he's an anti-Semite. It's because he’s an extreme isolationist and he’s trying to be 100% principled–he doesn't think there’s any reason to intervene for human rights or any other reason anywhere on the planet."  What both Ron Paul's and Ayn Rand's followers have in common is their libertarianism is unable to produce a viewpoint on foreign policy that is workable when applied to the real world.</p>

<p>This highlights an even greater contradiction in libertarian ideology. The theoretical justifications of libertarianism fail on their own terms, are incoherent and may not even justify a libertarian state even when they are assumed to hold true. <a href="http://ppe.sagepub.com/content/8/1/43.abstract">Karl Widerquist in a 2009 paper points out</a> that the basic principles of libertaianism, the same ones that are claimed to justify "no more than a minimal state with sharply limited powers", can actually be interpreted to justify "the acceptance of whatever state powers and property rights have been in place for a sufficient amount of time".</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/arabspring" class="p-category" rel="tag">#arabspring</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aynrand" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aynrand</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/karlwiderquist" class="p-category" rel="tag">#karlwiderquist</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/syria" class="p-category" rel="tag">#syria</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#arabspring</category>
      <category>#aynrand</category>
      <category>#karlwiderquist</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#syria</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
