<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?offset=70</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?_t=rss&amp;offset=70" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Gamergate is trashing the reputation of the tech community</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-is-trashing-the-reputation-of-the-tech-community</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-is-trashing-the-reputation-of-the-tech-community</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7439512656_04f88d7461_z.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7439512656_04f88d7461_z.jpg" alt="7439512656_04f88d7461_z" width="640" height="426" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2454"></a>There is another reason to dislike the toxic cloud of sexism that is <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a>. It's totally trashing the reputation of every community it touches. The gaters have reinforced pretty much every negative stereotype about gamers. They have made every gamer look like a doxing and SWATTing idiot. They have created a massive harassment campaign in the name of "protecting" gaming. And all they have done is to damage the reputation of the tech community. Look at anything in the popular press on this issue. Look at this article, for instance <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/culture/2015/06/05/3661042/women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/"></a><a href="http://thinkprogress.org/culture/2015/06/05/3661042/women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>thinkprogress.org/<wbr></wbr>culture/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>3661042/<wbr></wbr>women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/<wbr></wbr></a>   What is its first example of sexism in tech? <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> . Incidents like <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> have made it look like everyone in tech is like the gaters.  It makes us all look like a pack of Neanderthals that was dredged up from the Pleistocene.  The gaters may screech and holler about the so-called "gamers are dead" articles what were published earily in this controversy. But all they have done is prove that gaming will be dead in its current form if it doesn't clean up its toxic community. And gaters and their ilk are at the forefront of the toxic elements of the gamer community. And that's the saddest thing about GG, they have failed by even their own objectives. They have made every issue they claim to care about worse. They have proven to the world that, even their fiercest critics, and the fiercest critics of the gaming community have a point. Its time fight back against GG and its toxic sexism, lest the gaters burn the community to the ground.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: Flickr user JD Hancock <a href="https://flic.kr/p/ckprVA">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>ckprVA</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I've seen a lot of el cheapo Ethernet...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-seen-a-lot-of-el-cheapo-ethernet</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-seen-a-lot-of-el-cheapo-ethernet</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I've seen a lot of el cheapo Ethernet cabling on Amazon and other places that uses  "copper clad aluminum" wiring instead of copper. This is a bad idea for quality, breaks Ethernet standards, and if you run POE through it, it can start a fire. This article does a good job of explaining the issue.<br /><a href="http://www.cetecglobal.com/technologies/cabling/cca.htm">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cetecglobal.com/<wbr></wbr>technologies/<wbr></wbr>cabling/<wbr></wbr>cca.htm</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/etherent" class="p-category" rel="tag">#etherent</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/poe" class="p-category" rel="tag">#poe</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#etherent</category>
      <category>#poe</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest from the gaters http www vocativ...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-latest-from-the-gaters-http-www-vocativ</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-latest-from-the-gaters-http-www-vocativ</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The latest from the gaters<br /><a href="http://www.vocativ.com/tech/internet/gamergate-newest-nemesis-phd-student-natalie-zed/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.vocativ.com/<wbr></wbr>tech/<wbr></wbr>internet/<wbr></wbr>gamergate-newest-nemesis-phd-student-natalie-zed/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Gamergate’s zombie horde of trolls have struck again. This time, the target was Canadian journalist, author and PhD candidate Natalie Zed, slammed for trying to discuss gamergate for an entire conference without publicly saying the word: gamergate.</p>

<p>Last week, Zed attended the Canadian Game Studies Association’s 2015 conference as a panelist. In the opening comments, the organizers asked attendees to refrain from using the Gamergate hashtag, even though many of the panels were focused on the Gamergate phenomenon (depending on your perspective, either a debate about ethics in gaming, mostly focused on the sexism in games and gaming culture, or a vitriolic campaign of hatred directed at women who dare venture into the gaming industry).</p>

<p>The imposed twitter silence was an effort both to protect attendees from Gamergate troll hostility and to prevent Gamergaters from hijacking the online conversation about the conference, rendering Twitter useless for attendees.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti Vaxxer recants after child gets diphtheria http...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/anti-vaxxer-recants-after-child-gets-diphtheria-http</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/anti-vaxxer-recants-after-child-gets-diphtheria-http</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Anti-Vaxxer recants after child gets diphtheria.<br /><a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2015/06/09/1391864/-Parents-of-6-year-old-with-diphtheria-feel-tricked-by-anti-vaxxers?detail=facebook_sf">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.dailykos.com/<wbr></wbr>story/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>1391864/<wbr></wbr>-Parents-of-6-year-old-with-diphtheria-feel-tricked-by-anti-vaxxers?detail=facebook_sf</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Last week it came to the public's attention that a six-year-old child had contracted diphtheria in Spain, a disease not seen in Spain since 1987. Spain's El Pais is reporting now that the parents of the child, who had forgone vaccinating their child against diseases like diphtheria are more than contrite.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/antivaxxer" class="p-category" rel="tag">#antivaxxer</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#antivaxxer</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Game of Thrones Rape Scene Issue</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3245498261_093141423b_b.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3245498261_093141423b_b.jpg" alt="3245498261_093141423b_b" width="1024" height="683" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2458"></a> </p>

<p>I've been seeing this issue invade Twitter and Facebook. I don't really have enough knowledge to evaluate the substance of the claim that the rape in the GOT episode was too much (I'm not a GOT watcher). But I'll chime in on the issue with a few points</p>

<p><strong>Note: When I talk of things like "free speech", "censorship" and "rights" in this post I mean ethics, not law. A number of the ethical rules I suggest regarding free speech would be difficult to encode into law.<br /></strong></p>

<p>1) Everyone has the right to criticize the media they watch. Others retain the right to dismiss the criticism as wrong headed. Criticism is not censorship.</p>

<p>2) Consumers of media have to right to not watch a TV show if they don't like it, or think that part of it is beyond the pale, or if they think it downplays rape. Even if wrong headed and irrational, the exercise of this preference is not censorship.</p>

<p>3) Censorship happens when this criticism turns into outside pressure, with two types of pressure counting. Direct coercion -- ie. by law and indirect coercion by deprivation of a generally shared resource.</p>

<p>4) I don't consider a publisher that exercises direct editorial control (such as a TV station) to be a generally shared resource. I'm fine if consumers try to lobby TV stations and other such publishers to make media that they like.</p>

<p>5) Things like YouTube, Twitter, and such are generally shared resources. I would consider an attempt to pressure YouTube into dropping clips of the rape scene to be an attempt at censorship, and unethical.</p>

<p>6) It seems to me like a lot of activists are under the impression that the best way to "avoid downplaying" rape is to purge the media and the arts of all references to it. Its a very ostrich head in sand way of looking at the issue and one that probably serves to actually downplay the issue. Rape happens, and art should reflect that.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>:Flickr user Sarah Reid <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5WN2yz">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5WN2yz</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#tv</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Basic Assumptions of Mine about Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o.jpg" alt="486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o" width="769" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2463"></a>I am almost a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Positivism">positivist</a>/empiricist in my philosophical beliefs, I believe that about the only reliable source of knowledge is observation, the scientific method, and the repeated refinement of theories through science. This applies even for human society. My one difference from this view is the belief that just raw observation isn't sufficient. There is the need for bridge assumptions in order to translate mere observations into explanatory theories and moral judgements. Additionally, some basic metaphysical assumptions are needed. The list of such assumptions should be as short as possible, and as much of the heavy lifting should be loaded on to observation. But these bridge assumptions are needed as just pure observation is not enough. A pile of data is not a theory and is not an explanation of the world. Mere observation is not sufficient to produce knowledge. Results need to be merged into something greater than their parts. Correlations between different results need to be drawn together into a greater theory. All this requires interpretation, and there needs to be rules that to interpretation. Likewise there have to be a few basic assumptions about how the world works in order to make science workable. Ethics is another thing where mere data isn't enough. The is-ought gap needs to be bridged. Therefore a basic assumption about how to turn facts about how the world is to ethical judgments is needed. As follows in the rest of this blog post is a rough overview of what my basic assumptions about the world is like. Additionally, a positivist/empiricist worldview without bridge assumptions will be unavoidably self-contradictory. There is no way that empiricism itself can be confirmed through mere observation.</p>
<ol><li>Physicalism --- all objects that exist follow laws of physics that exist independently of the subjective views of observers. My preferred variant of this is the mathematical universe hypothesis, the idea that the universe is a mathematical structure.</li>
    <li>The basic rules of logic.</li>
    <li>The scientific method. For this I prefer something along the lines of Popperlian falseificationsim. This is the idea that science is the repeated refinement of falsifiable theories through observation.</li>
    <li>A rule regarding ethics. I prefer preference utilitarianism – the idea that the moral set of actions is the one that results in the longest long-run preference satisfaction when aggregated over all individuals.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: Flickr user Seth de l'Isle  <a href="https://flic.kr/p/JX2US">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>JX2US</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#philosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#philosophy</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#Gamergate link roundup http www motherjones com mojo...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-link-roundup-http-www-motherjones-com-mojo</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-link-roundup-http-www-motherjones-com-mojo</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 06:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a>link roundup<br /><a href="http://www.motherjones.com/mojo/2015/06/anti-gamergate-bill">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.motherjones.com/<wbr></wbr>mojo/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>anti-gamergate-bill</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Could This Bill Prevent Another "Gamergate"?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://southborough.wickedlocal.com/article/20150604/NEWS/150608123">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>southborough.wickedlocal.com/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>20150604/<wbr></wbr>NEWS/<wbr></wbr>150608123</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>U.S. Rep. Katherine Clark unveiled legislation Wednesday that would require the Department of Justice to put more resources into prosecuting individuals who go online to stalk, harass or threaten others – particularly women.<br />Her bill would provide $4 million annually to hire and train more FBI agents to investigate and prosecute such cybercrimes. It would also require the Attorney General, FBI and U.S. Attorneys to make cybercrimes a priority.<br /> “Imagine while you are in our office people threaten to sexually assault you,” said Clark, D-Melrose. “We would never tolerate this in our offices, but this is a daily reality for women online.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Cracked series on GG<br /><a href="http://www.cracked.com/blog/7-ways-gamergate-debate-has-made-world-worse/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cracked.com/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>7-ways-gamergate-debate-has-made-world-worse/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>7 Reasons "Gamergate" Proves Humanity is Doomed</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.cracked.com/quick-fixes/a-90-second-guide-to-determine-if-your-internet-cause-bs/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cracked.com/<wbr></wbr>quick-fixes/<wbr></wbr>a-90-second-guide-to-determine-if-your-internet-cause-bs/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A 90-Second Guide to Determine if Your Internet Cause Is BS</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.cracked.com/blog/4-ways-gamers-still-suck-at-dealing-with-women/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cracked.com/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>4-ways-gamers-still-suck-at-dealing-with-women/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>4 Ways Gamers Still Suck at Dealing With Women</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://storify.com/a_man_in_black/how-chan-style-anonymous-culture-shapes-gamergate">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>storify.com/<wbr></wbr>a_man_in_black/<wbr></wbr>how-chan-style-anonymous-culture-shapes-gamergate</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>How Chan-Style Anonymous Culture Shapes <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a></p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Via https storify com a man in black...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/via-https-storify-com-a-man-in-black</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/via-https-storify-com-a-man-in-black</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 06:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Via <a href="https://storify.com/a_man_in_black/patreon-and-common-carrier-sociopathy">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>storify.com/<wbr></wbr>a_man_in_black/<wbr></wbr>patreon-and-common-carrier-sociopathy</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/resize.png"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/resize.png" alt="resize" width="429" height="401" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2326"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seen on a tabloid in the grocery store...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/seen-on-a-tabloid-in-the-grocery-store</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/seen-on-a-tabloid-in-the-grocery-store</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 06:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Seen on a tabloid in the grocery store. Looks like the good ol GOP noise machine is getting fired up. <br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Office-Lens_20150602_175624_processed1.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Office-Lens_20150602_175624_processed1-300x218.jpg" alt="Office Lens_20150602_175624_processed(1)" width="300" height="218" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2324"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gop" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gop</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gop</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New photos more at https www flickr com...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-more-at-https-www-flickr-com</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-more-at-https-www-flickr-com</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 04:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>New photos (more at <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/721576540417405750">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>721576540417405750</a> )<br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0549.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0549.jpg" alt="DSCN0549" width="1500" height="1125" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2321"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0557.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0557.jpg" alt="DSCN0557" width="1500" height="1125" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2322"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
