<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23dustinmoore</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23dustinmoore&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Marginal Cost?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/zero-marginal-cost</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/zero-marginal-cost</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Jeremy Rifkin's book <i>The Zero Marginal Cost Society: The Internet of Things, the Collaborative Commons, and the Eclipse of Capitalism</i> has received quite a bit of attention. He has also written some editorials on the Huffington Post, and has been interviews by multiple media sources. However, his core argument borders on the absurd. And perhaps the incredulity that the press has taken showcases a wider problem. Rifkin argues that the transition to products and</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1320" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1320" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC</a> " width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/42PQoC%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>services that are dominated by fixed costs will provide a fundamental economic problem. However, the economics behind this view is deeply problematic. The idea that a high dependence on fixed costs provides an insurmountable economic issue is based on the idea that the prices in a competitive market tend towards the marginal cost (the non-fixed cost). This is the result of some simple economic models, but the real pricing behavior of businesses is way different. The problem of how businesses can effectively account for high fixed costs in their pricing is effectively solved. The second major part of Rifkin's argument is that the problems he expects to occur with the wider economy have already happened in the knowledge industries (music, videos, news, ect.). However, he omits a a key difference. Knowledge industries don't just have high fixed costs, they also have a second issue; non-excludeability. Information wants to be free and the copying of media cannot be effectively controlled without producing severe problems. The development of information technology exacerbates this problem because with the internet anyone can become a publisher. However, the physical industries that are tending towards low marginal costs do not have anything like this problem. Therefore, the situation of the knowledge industries cannot be extrapolated further.</p>

<p>It is clear that technology is expanding the role of fixed costs in the economy. Sustainable energy (both nuclear and renewable) tends to be dominated by fixed costs. The cost to run a nuclear power plant at all is about the same as the cost to run it at full capacity. Automation is replacing labor in many industries, and the cost involved with the robots is largely fixed. The services provided by internet service providers are also dominated by fixed costs. Many other examples could be named. Rifkin is perhaps correct to see a trend towards However, the economic problem of how to deal with them in the pricing of products is also not new. While some simple economic models tend to indicate that a competitive market tends towards the marginal cost (which would be insufficient to cover the rising fixed costs), the real world is different. Real businesses price their products based on cost-plus pricing. They take both the fixed and marginal costs, plus the desired profit into account when setting their prices. Real world businesses are capital constrained and will not invest in a sector of the economy if they do not see a net profit. This profit must be on top of both the fixed and marginal costs. Now, how can a business price a product based around a high fixed cost? Simple. There are two options, both of which are in wide use in current markets</p>
<ol><li>The businesses could simply charge a fixed cost to each user, and allow the users to use as much of their share as they want. This is roughly how internet usage is billed. Users pay a monthly fee, and get to use the internet with that access. This method of paying for the fixed costs effectively divides up the fixed cost among each of the users.</li>
    <li>Businesses could charge the average unit cost of the good. Think of a toll road. The costs involved in running a road are effectively fixed up the the point where the road becomes congested. Most toll roads charge a fee for each use of the road. This fee is set on the basis of the average cost per trip (both fixed and marginal cost combined).</li>
</ol>
<p>The problem of pricing low marginal cost goods is effectively dealt with every day by businesses around the world. The rise of fixed costs will not bring down the world. What about Rifkin's comparison to the changes in knowledge industries? Excludeability is the problem there, not high fixed costs. With the internet, it is impossible to prevent someone from copying a work and distributing it. People throughout the world can simultaneously posses a piece of information, and with the internet copying this information is trivial. Copyright, the only widely used way to exclude access to this knowledge is falling apart under this pressure. However, it is perfectly easy to exclude someone from using the power grid, or from using most of the physical services that having growing fixed costs. What happened in the knowledge industries is irrelevant to the wider economy.</p>

<p>it is to a degree amazing that the press did not bring up these issues when covering the book. But the press coverage of technical issues is abismial. The coverage on this subject is no exception.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/collaborativecommons" class="p-category" rel="tag">#collaborativecommons</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/dustinmoore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#dustinmoore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/huffingtonpost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#huffingtonpost</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#collaborativecommons</category>
      <category>#dustinmoore</category>
      <category>#huffingtonpost</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Inflation Overestimated?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-inflation-overestimated</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-inflation-overestimated</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 04:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It is a common argument among libertarians and other conservatives that the official statistics are dramatically understating the level of inflation in the economy. However, I will argue that the opposite is most likely the truth. The government is probably <i>overestimating</i> the level of inflation. This is because most measures of inflation look at a fixed basket of products and monitor how the price of the basket changes over time. However, in the world of real</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1320" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1320" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC</a> " width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/42PQoC%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>consumers,  price isn't the only thing that is changing, the basket itself is. As technology improves, consumers begin to buy other products that were not even on the market at the time. There is a substantial economic value to this ability to use this technology and most economic measures of real GDP don't take this value into account. Therefore, they over estimate the level of inflation in the economy.</p>

<p>The yearly change in real GDP can be described as follows:</p>

<p>RealChange = NominalChange - InflationRate</p>

<p>Inflation is calculated in terms of the real GDP. One inflation measure, the GDP deflator works as follows. Economists calculate what it would cost to buy the goods and services produced in the economy last year in both the dollars of this year and last year. The change can be taken as the imputed level of inflation. We have already seen the problem with this type of method. The products bought by consumers are not constant. The other major measure of inflation is not much better. The CPI is created by forming a basket of goods that represents typical consumer spending, and tracking how this basket of goods changes over time. Nether measure takes changes in technology into account.</p>

<p>There are two reasons why this is inaccurate.</p>
<ol><li>Technology change has great economic value. If the consumers of this year were allowed to pay a fee to access the technology of next year, this would likely be a substantial amount (although a difficult to calculate one at that).</li>
    <li>The items subject to the lowest level of technological change tend to be ones with the lowest reduction in price.</li>
</ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/dustinmoore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#dustinmoore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#dustinmoore</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
