<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?offset=140</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?_t=rss&amp;offset=140" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>How Should the Energy Grid Be Ran?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-should-the-energy-grid-be-ran</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-should-the-energy-grid-be-ran</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 23:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The way in which the U.S energy grid is ran is severely flawed. Energy pricing is unrelated to consumer demand. This creates many problems. It encourages consumers (and even more importantly industry) to use energy without concern for the impacts on the grid.<br />The way in which the U.S energy grid is ran is severely flawed. Energy pricing is unrelated to consumer demand. This creates many problems. With a power grid</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1322" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1322" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o-300x178.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H</a>" width="300" height="178" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/e8B95H%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>the only thing that matters isn't raw energy production, it is the time frame during which the energy is produced, not all energy production is equally valuable. It encourages consumers (and even more importantly industry) to use energy without concern for the impacts on the grid. It encourages the formation of energy producers with a parasitic business model that is based around dumping as much energy on the grid as possible, regardless of whether this is actually useful production. By extension it wastes the money of consumers and results in higher prices for them. This setup also distorts the energy sources used by producers. The current energy system also merges two unrelated things, producing the energy and distributing it. This creates a wide range of inefficiencies. I will propose four simple changes</p>
<ol><li>Prevent energy producing companies from also owning the distribution systems for energy</li>
    <li>Set up a two stage system for energy purchase by consumers. Along with dealing with the energy distributor, consumers will also select an energy producer to buy from. (energy producers could still buy from a wholesale market). Consumers with their own energy production (such as a home solar setup) would sell this energy to a producer</li>
    <li>Allow energy producers to experiment with a wide range of energy pricing methods</li>
    <li>The energy distribution companies should charge a flat fee for the use of the grid.</li>
</ol>
<p>Why should you care about this? Simple. The structure of the energy grid has a wide range of impacts. How it conducts its pricing affects the mix of energy sources used. If this is set wrong, both consumers and the public may suffer. If energy companies use their power over distribution to affect production, consumers will lose. Inefficient management of the energy grid may slow deployment of sustainable energy, and energy storage tech. The concentration of energy production into a single hand will also remove choice from consumers, and reduce the level of competition in the energy markets.</p>

<p>Slate did an article about something called "Demand Destruction". They make it sound like something that is the result of people just switching over to home-produced electricity, thereby becoming independent of the grid and leaving the power company in the dust. In reality, truly off-grid systems are extremely rare -- and expensive at almost $3.20 a kilowatt hour (mostly batteries and energy storage, commercial energy storage is much cheaper than home energy storage, but energy storage in general is quite expensive). The source of the problem is malformed renewable energy incentive laws that force power companies to pay all energy production an equal rate -- even if the energy is produced at an off-peak time that has little use. This enables a business model that I will call "Grid Leeching". This business model takes advantage of a simple fact. Electricity companies are required to pay and receive payment based on energy produced. But consumers don't want raw energy; they want power -- a constant flow of energy. energy is much cheaper to produce than power. Individuals and businesses buy cheap solar production systems that are designed to barf large amounts of off-peak energy on to the grid. The electricity company is required to pay full price for this energy. The grid leechers then get to use the power grid for their actual power needs practically free of charge. These cheap solar systems can sell for as little as $2 a watt average production or about the equivalent to 15 cents a kilowatt hour. Around this has developed a little market of companies that specialize in attaching leeches to the grid. One of these profiled is SolarCity, which rents out these cheap solar systems. This is very destructive to the grid. The only way that a electricity company can make up for this type of thing is to run load-following power plants -- usually natural gas -- in an inefficient, and rapidily fluctuating way. This happens while the leechers are drawing power while not paying anything on the net. The leechers only give back low quality, off-peak energy.</p>

<p>What can be done about this. It is simple: fluctuate energy charges, and energy production payouts based on the current demand. When there is little energy demand, pay the producers of energy less (and charge the consumers less). When energy demand is high, pay producers more and charge consumers more. Charge a flat monthly fee for a connection to the grid (based on the maximum current the user is allowed to draw). This will put the grid leechers out of business, because their core business model of dumping energy on the grid at low-demand times will no longer work. This will encourage companies to produce constant power (or even better, demand following energy), and will encourage consumers to modulate their energy usage during peak demand times. This may reduce the incentives for renewable energy deployment. However, the current model encourages the formation of grid leechers, instead of actually productive renewable energy firms. Furthermore, it puts nuclear energy (one of the best sources of baseload power) at a disadvantage. Sustainable energy should be directly subsidized at very large levels.</p>

<p>I will contend that energy utilities really do two distinct things that can and should be separate. The first is producing energy. The second is distributing that electricity. Separating these two roles will vastly improve the competitiveness of the electricity markets and will have benefits in regard to climate change and pollution. It would improve consumer choice , and allow consumers greater choice in what energy is consumed and how it is produced. However in reality, most utilities are also the main producers of the electricity that they distribute. As I will discuss towards the end of the post, this change would be<br />Electricity production is a natural monopoly — that is the lowest cost market outcome is one electricity utility serving an entire community. This of course has problems, a monopoly can of course over charge consumers. Monopolies charge based on what the consumer is willing to pay while a firm in a competitive market charges based on the actual cost. Additionally, a monopoly can abuse their power to gain market share of other related markets. This is in effect what most utilities have done with energy production. Because they are the sole distributor of electricity it is easy for them to make themselves the main producer of it. This not only increases costs to consumers, but also reduces their choice. If a consumer wants an energy plan heavy on a given energy source, or billed in a certain way, it may be very difficult to arrange that in the current system. In a more competitive energy market, there would be many energy producers each vying for the dollars of consumers. They would not have to wait for the sluggishness of one utility company for a new method to arrive. There would be an explosion of energy plans and energy sources, and types of billing. Want a energy plan centered on nuclear power, but no fossil fuels? Tough to find under current conditions, but perhaps not so tough under a more competitive arrangement. Want a energy plan billed on a fixed monthly rate — like how internet is billed? Very few utilities offer such a thing, but it might be more easy to find that type of thing in a more competitive market. More examples of how this would work could be envisioned.<br />Such a change would also have positive implications for the environment. Remember the issue about net metering of solar production at home? There is a great public benefit to allowing consumers to sell back energy they produce. But the types of net metering that regulators commonly implement have a severe flaw. They enable people to produce energy at low-value, off peak times and use the grid as a free battery. Separating energy production from distribution would solve this dilemma. People with home solar systems would sell their energy production to a energy production company, and a reasonable agreed upon value that takes into account the level of demand for the energy. But the distribution utility would charge a fee for the connection to the grid. This would prevent people from producing low value energy in-order to use the grid as a free battery. But it would reward people who use clean energy production at home to produce valuable energy. There are other clean energy production benefits of such a change. There would be a great opportunity for energy producers to experiment with clean energy sources, and sell this production to consumers who are willing to be early adopters. This is in contrast to utilities which can take many years to adapt to a change.</p>

<p>This change would be easy to implement. Instead of dealing with one power company, consumers would pay two companies. Consumers would pay a utility to hook their house to the grid. This would likely be billed as a flat monthly fee. They would then find a energy production company that has a plan that they like. The billing for this would vary from plan to plan. Despite the increased complexity of this setup, consumers would greatly benefit.</p>

<p>In this blog post I have proposed a way to reform the energy grid. This proposal will benefit consumers. It will result in increased consumer choice. And it will result in lower prices and a more efficient market.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind Mapping Tool That I Use on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mind-mapping-tool-that-i-use-on-arch-linux</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mind-mapping-tool-that-i-use-on-arch-linux</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 08:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I use the free mind mind mapping program on Arch. It can be installed with the freemind package. The other major linux mind mapping program is xmind, but there are problems getting it to work on Arch.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC:"UK embassy apologises for 'burning White House' tweet"</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/bbcuk-embassy-apologises-for-burning-white-house-tweet</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/bbcuk-embassy-apologises-for-burning-white-house-tweet</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>Commemorating the 200th anniversary of burning the White House. Only sparklers this time! <a href="http://t.co/QIDBQTBmmL">pic.twitter.com/QIDBQTBmmL</a></p>
<p>— British Embassy (@UKinUSA) <a href="https://twitter.com/UKinUSA/statuses/503668849750056960">August 24, 2014</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-28929626"></a><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-28929626">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.bbc.com/<wbr></wbr>news/<wbr></wbr>world-us-canada-28929626</a></p><blockquote><p>The British embassy in Washington has apologised after tweeting a picture of a White House cake surrounded by sparklers, "commemorating" the burning of the building 200 years ago.The US presidential residence was set on fire by British forces in 1814 during the "War of 1812" with the United States.
  ....
  The embassy later said: "Apologies for earlier Tweet."</p></blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/whitehouse" class="p-category" rel="tag">#whitehouse</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#whitehouse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Brokers and Epsilon</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/data-brokers-and-epsilon</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/data-brokers-and-epsilon</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Today the CBS 60 Minutes program aired a segment on "data brokers" like Epsilon. The CEO of that company was interviewed on that show and highlighted the firm's openness and noted that consumers can request a "summary" of the data that they have on consumers. What was not noted in that segment is that this request can only be made by snail-mail (odd for a tech company, the form can be found here <a href="http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-info/marketing-data-summary-request"></a><a href="http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-info/marketing-data-summary-request">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.epsilon.com/<wbr></wbr>consumer-info/<wbr></wbr>marketing-data-summary-request</a>). Also, they need a voided check.It seems they are trying to</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1325" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/9663345203_959c0b91c6_o-1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1325" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/9663345203_959c0b91c6_o-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via flickr (user Intel Free Press) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>fHVaS4</a>" width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via flickr (user Intel Free Press) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/fHVaS4%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>fHVaS4[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>make this process as difficult as possible. I am going to mail this request tomorrow to see what I get back.</p>

<p>Here is their excuse for it</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The mail process is designed to ensure security and to verify identity. Since we are matching your name and address to our database, we can be confident that we are mailing your information to you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A justification for an obtuse process based on privacy rings a bit hollow for this company. I mean, they are selling my information.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In addition, by conducting this process through the mail, we believe that more consumers will have an opportunity to make a/this Marketing Data Summary request. Some consumers may not feel comfortable using other methods to verify their identity on the internet. We believe that conducting this process through the mail allows the greatest number of consumers access to their reports.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This does not explain why snail-mail is the <em>only</em> method.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/cbs" class="p-category" rel="tag">#cbs</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/intelfreepress" class="p-category" rel="tag">#intelfreepress</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/marketingdatasummary" class="p-category" rel="tag">#marketingdatasummary</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#cbs</category>
      <category>#intelfreepress</category>
      <category>#marketingdatasummary</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GMO Labeling and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gmo-labeling-and-the-first-amendment</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gmo-labeling-and-the-first-amendment</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 21:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Vermont passed a law requiring the labeling of GMO products a few months ago. The law won't take effect until 2016, but there is already litigation about the constitutionality of the legislation. In this post I will argue that the labeling law most likely violates the protections of the First Amendment. Due to the <a href="http://hstlj.org/articles/a-brief-history-of-the-commercial-speech-doctrine-with-some-implications-for-tobacco-regulation/">commercial speech doctrine</a> courts have ruled that advertising (including product labeling) is protected by the Constitution, although to a lesser extent than other forms of speech. The courts have not precisely delineated a boundary for when law makers can regulate commercial speech, but have generally found that</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1327" align="alignnone" width="646"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2835892559_d94c45ff7e_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1327 size-large" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2835892559_d94c45ff7e_o-1024x768.jpg" alt="Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances." width="646" height="485"></a> Image Via Flickr (user david__jones) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5jAG4i%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5jAG4i[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>there must be a provable harm (or at least possible harm) to the consumer. Courts have given little weight to subjective consumer preferences, leaving the fulfillment of those to the market. There are some trends in the major Supreme Court cases on the subject such as <em>Virginia State Board of Pharmacy v. Virginia Citizens Consumer Council</em>, and <em>Central Hudson Gas v. Public Service Commission of New York</em></p>
<ol><li>The general standard for commercial speech cases is intermediate scrutiny. This also is the standard that applies to time place and manner speech restrictions (like city noise laws), sex/gender discrimination( among other protected classes).To pass this standard a law must further important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest</li>
    <li>Lawmakers have broad power to ban false advertising and advertising for illegal products.</li>
    <li>Advertising over electronic media receives lower protection than adverting in traditional publications.</li>
    <li>Prior restraint is permissible in the realm of commercial speech</li>
    <li>There is a wide scope for disclosure regulations, but there still needs to be a substantial government interest involved. Justifications based on consumer choice in the absence of tangible harm are usually not sufficient.</li>
</ol>
<p>The most similar case to the GMO one is <em>International Dairy Foods Association v. Amestoy</em> which came before the Second Circuit. This case involved a Vermont labeling law mandating that dairy products produced by cows treated with the rBST hormone be labeled. The government made no claims of a safety risk before the court, and the plaintiffs in that case entered evidence indicating that there was no safety risk. The trial court opinion noted that the government “does not claim that health or safety concerns prompted the passage of the Vermont Labeling Law,” and that there defense is based around "strong consumer interest and the public's ‘right to know’". The Second Circuit found that this interest in consumer choice is not a substantial interest. There may have been animal welfare justifications for the law made in the public discourse, but neither side made such arguments before the court, so that issue was never considered. However, a consumer survey was entered as evidence that indicated that such issues were a reason why consumers may have wanted to avoid rBST products, but none of these responces ammounted to a full argument on this basis (other than noting that the cows were “Producing enough milk already.”) The court found that the most common consumer reasons included</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>(1) They consider the use of a genetically-engineered hormone in the production unnatural;  (2) they believe that use of the hormone will result in increased milk production and lower milk prices, thereby hurting small dairy farmers;  (3) they believe that the use of rBST is harmful to cows and potentially harmful to humans;  and, (4) they feel that there is a lack of knowledge regarding the long-term effects of rBST.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The situation with GMO labeling is even less favorable. There are no reasonable safety arguments that could be used against GMO products. As the GMO products targeted are plants there are not any animal welfare arguments either. This leaves the consumer choice argument, which courts have already rejected as problematic. Allowing abstract preferences that have no basis in fact into the law produces severely paradoxical results when used to justify limits on fundamental rights. Imagine if such preferences were allowed into the other areas of law where the intermediate scrutiny standard was used. The results would be clearly unacceptable. Satisfying subjective consumer preferences in an efficient way are what markets are good at. If there is a consumer demand for notice about GMO products, then a voluntary (and perhaps privately owned) certification system should serve the purpose (with the producers paying the full cost of maintaining the system through fees).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyork" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyork</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/secondcircuit" class="p-category" rel="tag">#secondcircuit</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vermontlabelinglaw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vermontlabelinglaw</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#newyork</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#secondcircuit</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vermontlabelinglaw</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Interesting Article On Racism in Israel</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><a href="http://www.haaretz.com/mobile/.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2"></a><a href="http://www.haaretz.com/mobile/.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.haaretz.com/<wbr></wbr>mobile/<wbr></wbr>.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2</a></p><p>The linked article features a discussion of the growth of racism in the Isreali school system. A choice quote is as follows.  </p><blockquote><p>“For me, personally, Arabs are something I can’t look at and can’t stand,” a 10th-grade girl from a high school in the central part of the country says in abominable Hebrew. “<strong>I am tremendously racist. I come from a racist home. If I get the chance in the army to shoot one of them, I won’t think twice.</strong> I’m ready to kill someone with my hands, and it’s an Arab. In my education I learned that ... their education is to be terrorists, and there is no belief in them. I live in an area of Arabs, and every day I see these Ishmaelites, who pass by the [bus] station and whistle. I wish them death.”</p></blockquote><p>Emphasis added. </p><p>What type of person thinks being "tremendously racist" is something to brag to journalists about? And what does it say about the nation that churns out students who think like this? Now, viewpoints this extreme seem to still be in the miniority, but they seem way to common. This point of view is also deeply influential on politics, with strong hostility to the "leftists" that oppose the policies of the Isreali government</p><blockquote><p>A year later, however, the incident itself was still remembered in the school. The same student who told Yaron that she won’t think twice if she gets the opportunity “to shoot one of them” when she serves in the army, also said, “As soon as I heard about the quarrel with that leftist girl [Michal], I was ready to throw a brick at her head and kill her. In my opinion, all the leftists are Israel-haters. I personally find it very painful. Those people have no place in our country – both the Arabs and the leftists.”</p></blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gawker and Trolls</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gawker-and-trolls</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gawker-and-trolls</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>You may have seen the hubhub about Gawker media and its troll problem. In short the trolls are flooding its sites with porn images. This is part of a campaign by 4chan. Writers of the sites are outraged and demanding a</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1330" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6288497038_5d4e68c0b5_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1330" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6288497038_5d4e68c0b5_o-300x201.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Tama Leaver) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>azGc5J</a>" width="300" height="201" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Tama Leaver) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/azGc5J%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>azGc5J[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>soloution to the issue. In short they want to make sure that they do not have to moderate the trollage. This however may be an impractical goal. It is very difficult for a</p>

<p>website to deal with a troll issue short of human moderation. A suggested alternative method is IP banning, but this cannot deal with a persistent and skilled troll (and 4chan counts). Also, IP banning rules out users that use systems like Tor. This means that such a system will hurt real users.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ip" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ip</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tamaleaver" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tamaleaver</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#ip</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#tamaleaver</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Inflation Overestimated?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-inflation-overestimated</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-inflation-overestimated</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 04:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It is a common argument among libertarians and other conservatives that the official statistics are dramatically understating the level of inflation in the economy. However, I will argue that the opposite is most likely the truth. The government is probably <i>overestimating</i> the level of inflation. This is because most measures of inflation look at a fixed basket of products and monitor how the price of the basket changes over time. However, in the world of real</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1320" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1320" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC</a> " width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/42PQoC%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>consumers,  price isn't the only thing that is changing, the basket itself is. As technology improves, consumers begin to buy other products that were not even on the market at the time. There is a substantial economic value to this ability to use this technology and most economic measures of real GDP don't take this value into account. Therefore, they over estimate the level of inflation in the economy.</p>

<p>The yearly change in real GDP can be described as follows:</p>

<p>RealChange = NominalChange - InflationRate</p>

<p>Inflation is calculated in terms of the real GDP. One inflation measure, the GDP deflator works as follows. Economists calculate what it would cost to buy the goods and services produced in the economy last year in both the dollars of this year and last year. The change can be taken as the imputed level of inflation. We have already seen the problem with this type of method. The products bought by consumers are not constant. The other major measure of inflation is not much better. The CPI is created by forming a basket of goods that represents typical consumer spending, and tracking how this basket of goods changes over time. Nether measure takes changes in technology into account.</p>

<p>There are two reasons why this is inaccurate.</p>
<ol><li>Technology change has great economic value. If the consumers of this year were allowed to pay a fee to access the technology of next year, this would likely be a substantial amount (although a difficult to calculate one at that).</li>
    <li>The items subject to the lowest level of technological change tend to be ones with the lowest reduction in price.</li>
</ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/dustinmoore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#dustinmoore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#dustinmoore</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Political Questions</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/debt-and-political-questions</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/debt-and-political-questions</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 19:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In this post I will argue that lawsuits in U.S courts by vulture funds against governmental defaults, <a href="http://en.mercopress.com/2014/08/16/global-trade-union-summit-condemns-actions-of-vulture-funds-against-argentina">like the litigation that recently forced Argentina into default</a>, should be dismissed due to separation of powers under the political question doctrine. The political question doctrine declares that some questions before the courts cannot be heard because hearing them would step on a fundamental role of the political branches. In <i>Baker v. Carr</i> the U.S supreme</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1336" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/4123495075_dd9a64af31_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1336" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/4123495075_dd9a64af31_o-300x200.jpg" alt="Image via flickr (user Orin Zebest) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7hnZqF</a>" width="300" height="200" /&gt; Image via flickr (user Orin Zebest) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/7hnZqF%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7hnZqF[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>court found that the doctrine prevents the courts from hearing a case when any of the following conditions are met</p>
<ol><li>"Textually demonstrable constitutional commitment of the issue to a coordinate political department;"</li>
    <li>"A lack of judicially discoverable and manageable standards for resolving it;"</li>
    <li>"The impossibility of deciding without an initial policy determination of a kind clearly for nonjudicial discretion;"</li>
    <li>"The impossibility of a court's undertaking independent resolution without expressing lack of the respect due coordinate branches of government;"</li>
    <li>"An unusual need for unquestioning adherence to a political decision already made;"</li>
    <li>"The potentiality of embarrassment from multifarious pronouncements by various departments on one question."</li>
</ol>
<p>In the area of foreign policy, this doctrine has been used by the courts to dismiss legal claims that involve the legal status of Taiwan, and the legality of military actions.</p>

<p>The litigant suing Argentina is a vulture fund. Vulture funds buy distressed debt that is near or in default. They then collect on this debt at a large profit. They are debt collectors for governments. <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jun/27/us-vulture-funds-argentina-bankruptcy">All creditors other than the group of vulture funds suing Argentina</a> settled the debt at a loss .</p>

<p>In the case of lawsuit at question in the Argentina debt case, the judiciary is taking up questions of international relations and public finance that fundamentally belong in the political branches. A lawsuit that forces a country into the risk of default has clear foreign policy consequences, and is almost entirely a foreign policy question. The case requires the courts to make a determination of the relative importance of debt payment over other obligations of the government of Argentina. This is also an inherently political decision. The court's actions in this case is already causing the U.S government international embarrassment. Such a decision should of never of been made.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/argentina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#argentina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/orinzebest" class="p-category" rel="tag">#orinzebest</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#argentina</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#orinzebest</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problems With Using Cost-Benefit Analysis In Climate Change Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><i><a href="https://theojones.name/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">This is part of a blog post series on climate change.</a></i>In this post I will discuss how a cost/benefit type analysis of climate change can fail to truly appreciate the harms that it produces. In fact, a climate change policy based on a cost benefit <a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2324660064_1e9550c25b_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2324660064_1e9550c25b_o-300x200.jpg" alt="2324660064_1e9550c25b_o" width="300" height="200" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1450"></a>analysis will contradict fundamental rights, and will clearly violate the concept of equality before the law. Furthermore this type of policy will cause a climate change policy that is much less aggressive than it should be. In this post I will elaborate on these claims. I will give a definition of what I mean by a cost-benefit analysis, I will argue that people actually value other goals more highly than the monetary costs measured by a cost-benefit analysis, I will argue that it makes ethical assumptions that are dubious, and I will show that when applied to the world of climate change it produces severely inegalitarian results. These inegalitarian results create problems involving human rights, and equality before the law. </p>

<p>Now, what do I mean by cost-benefit analysis? I simply mean an analysis of the impacts of climate change based solely on the economic damage it causes. This economic impact is measured in terms of money. This type of analysis is able to measure damage to things other than the markets however. Damage to things that are not traded on the market measured in are terms of how much money people would be willing to give up for them. I.e if the members of a community would be willing to pay $100,000 to preserve a historic building, than the economic value of that building is \$100,000. If the building is then destroyed by an impact of climate change, then $100,000 is added to the impacts of climate change from a cost benefit perspective. Probabilistic impacts are measured using the concept of expected value. The expected value of an event is the product of its cost and the probability that it will occur. If the building has a 25 percent (0.25 probability) of being damaged then the expected value of the damage is $25,000. This type of cost benefit analysis is widely used. Pretty much all estimates of the form "the social cost of CO2 pollution is \$50 per ton of CO2" were created in this way. However, this method has severe flaws. Many proposals suggest building the response to climate change around this analysis, and conducting a "market-based" response by setting the carbon price at a level consistent with the cost of the pollution determined by the cost-benefit analysis.  </p>

<p>However, this method has clear flaws. The first is that it gives higher priority to the interests of the wealthy. Since this analysis is fundamentally based on <em>economic</em> damage and the amount of money that people would give up to advert the damage it weights the interests of the wealthy very highly. It also downgrades the interest of the poor. Because climate change is a global phenomenon and because global economic inequality is very lopsided, this effect is stark. The interests of someone earning the median American wage (about $50,000) is weighted over 130 times more than the interests on someone earning a dollar a day ($365 per year). The impacts of climate change (along with some strategies for mitigating it) fall disproportionately on the poor. Because of this the poor will get a raw deal with any climate change policy built around a cost-benefit analysis. Furthermore, this huge discrepancy conflicts with the notion of equality before the law. A just system should treat the interests of all equally and in a neutral fashion. The cost-benefit analysis method does not come close to doing this.  </p>

<p>Furthermore, the ethical assumptions behind the cost-benefit analysis method are dubious. There are three major assumptions behind the use of cost-benefit analysis</p>
<ol><li>The type of material wealth usually measured with money is a good proxy for the types of harms created by climate change  </li>
<li>All preferences of equal strength are equally worthy of concern by the political system  </li>
<li>Maximizing total well being (as measured by monetary value) is a good value to peruse </li>
</ol>
<p>All three of these points are dubious. I believe that political policies should be judged based on what a neutral observer would judge of the situation. Of course, with something global like climate change there are no truly neutral observers. However, we can appeal to a thought experiment like Rawls' original position where people are asked to judge policy options based on the assumption that they lack knowledge of their position in society, and therefore could be anyone in society. Under conditions like this people would probably not choose a social structure that maximizes well being (contradicting point 3). The idea of utility maximization embedded in the cost-benefit analysis method makes the errornous assumption that utilities and preferences of people are things that can be easily quantified and added up. Such an assumption is dubious. Even if it were not, I would contend that most people would want to avoid situations of being severely disadvantaged. I contend that people in such a thought experiment should instead  choose a situation where the policies enacted are the most widely acceptable even if this results in lower over all well being or a lower expected value of wealth. I would also contend that net wealth or material well being is not what people desire, wealth is a means not a end so taking it as a goal is superficial. I would prefer freedom (in a broad based sense) to wealth; "Give me liberty, or give me death!". Of course, defining liberty is a task of its own. I reject libertarian notions of freedom that define freedom purely in terms of some type of non-interference without any effective abilities preserved. I would contend that people are free to the extent that they have the widest range of abilities and capabilities to act that are not subject to and are protected from the risk of uncontrolled interference by others. Among these abilities priority should be given to fundamental rights. The capibilities of concern should be those that would be highlighted by a neutral party.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
