<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23emt</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23emt&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Ferguson Incident</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-ferguson-incident</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-ferguson-incident</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 00:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>That the shot person was a suspect in a robbery is interesting. I've always thought that neither story in the case adds up and that there is some missing detail. However, it is clear that the cops clearly used vastly excessive force. </p><p>1) The cops' story that Brown attacked Wilson to take his gun seems extremely unlikely to begin with, and contradicts witness testimony. <br />
2) However, I find it implausible that the cops would shoot someone for no apparent reason. That would very unusual, even for cops.</p><p>If Brown was a suspect in a robbery it would explain what happened (even if he had noting to do with it). Note that I am not justifying the clearly excessive force used in that case and in its aftermath.</p><p>I would also say that the focus on the past actions of the actors in this type of case is irrelevant. This goes on both sides to a degree. If the possible involvement in the robbery is not directly related, then it is not really that worthy of discussion. I will note however that  its as related as the claims by activists that Brown was a gentle giant who wouldn't hurt a fly. I.e not very related (my suggested policy towards robbers is NOT shoot on sight). But if activists get to bring up Brown's character I have no huge problem with the cops publishing a police report that puts Brown's character into question (the evidence of his involvement does seem pretty compelling, see <a href="http://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2014/08/15/Mike-Brown-called-robbery-suspect-in-police-report/9901408112725/ph2/"></a><a href="http://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2014/08/15/Mike-Brown-called-robbery-suspect-in-police-report/9901408112725/ph2/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.upi.com/<wbr></wbr>Top_News/<wbr></wbr>US/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>15/<wbr></wbr>Mike-Brown-called-robbery-suspect-in-police-report/<wbr></wbr>9901408112725/<wbr></wbr>ph2/<wbr></wbr></a>) <br />
The police report (released today) about the robbery that Brown allegedly was involved in should have been public record put on internet anyways.</p><p>Also, what this type of case makes me think is that cops have too much experience. And that dealing with the worst the world has to offer creates a cop culture that is toxic to the public interest. To see this go to any forum that is targeted to the police community. The discussion at the following link is a good case study in this <a href="http://theerant.yuku.com/topic/68862/FDNY-EMTs-official-complaint-against-NYPD-of-EDP-Handling#.U-8E-3XoJhE"></a><a href="http://theerant.yuku.com/topic/68862/FDNY-EMTs-official-complaint-against-NYPD-of-EDP-Handling#.U-8E-3XoJhE">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theerant.yuku.com/<wbr></wbr>topic/<wbr></wbr>68862/<wbr></wbr>FDNY-EMTs-official-complaint-against-NYPD-of-EDP-Handling#.U-8E-3XoJhE</a> Because one EMT ratted them out, about half the cops on that forum want to "hammer" all emergency medical workers. The only reservation of many of the people there who don't is that screwing with EMTs would look bad to the public and bring a lot of crap down on them. There are a few people that talk of "rotten apples", but it seems that by "rotten apple" they mean "snitch". The comments on the following article are also "good" <a href="http://www.policeone.com/use-of-force/articles/7385823-Video-NY-man-dies-in-struggle-during-arrest/"></a><a href="http://www.policeone.com/use-of-force/articles/7385823-Video-NY-man-dies-in-struggle-during-arrest/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.policeone.com/<wbr></wbr>use-of-force/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>7385823-Video-NY-man-dies-in-struggle-during-arrest/<wbr></wbr></a></p><p>The police become something separate and above the regular population. Just trying to regulate the system won't work because the culture will fight all attempts at limiting abuse. I think that the best way to deal with this type of thing would be to in a way de-professionalize the police system. Make it so that most cops aren't career cops. I envision a system where people become cops for a few years and then go back to a different job. It could be one option in a universal national service system. The police roles that need professionals could be part time to the extent possible. This would limit the emergence of a cop culture that is separate from the general culture, and would therefore make it easier to regulate the few remaining bad apples out of existence.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/emt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#emt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#emt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
