<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23bzzztlooks</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23bzzztlooks&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>A Response to an Article from the Cato Institute on Global Warming</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-response-to-an-article-from-the-cato-institute-on</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-response-to-an-article-from-the-cato-institute-on</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Cato institute recently published an article titled <em><a href="http://www.cato.org/publications/commentary/carbon-tax-would-make-no-sense">A Carbon Tax Would Make No Sense</a></em> that represents many of the most common arguments made by climate change denialists. In this post I will do a analysis of why these arguments are wrong.</p>
<!--more--><blockquote>
<p>Do you know how much carbon dioxide is in the atmosphere? It is a little less than 400 parts per million. Do you know what the optimum level of carbon dioxide is? No one does, even though some have the extreme conceit to think they do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is the optimal level of CO2. Any level between 250-350 parts per million.Climate change is harmful because of the rapid rate of temperature change it has caused, not the absolute level of temperature created. Ecosystems and human civilization have developed around a relitively stable climate since the last ice age. The current rate of change to this climate is almost unprecedented in the Earth's geologic history and every time a similarly rapid change has happened, the result has been a mass extinction and a widespread disruption of ecosystems. <a href="http://www.ecologyandsociety.org/vol14/iss2/art32/main.html">A CO2 concentration at this level would stabilize</a> the climate at a level that is consistent with what ecosystems have evolved to handle and what human infrastructure is adapted to handle. The human economy is extremely dependent on this stable ecosystem. In fact it could be said that the economy is a wholly-owned subsidiary of the global ecosystem.These impacts will be disastrous for human health, agriculture and the economy. The 2007 IPCC assessment contains a excellent diagram that summarizes these impacts. <br /><a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg2/en/figure-spm-2.html"></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earth’s atmosphere is 78 percent nitrogen, about 21 percent oxygen, less than 1 percent argon, and only 0.038 percent carbon dioxide — plus a variable amount of water vapor. The gas is necessary for life. Plants cannot grow without it. .... There is evidence that as carbon-dioxide levels have risen, plants are growing faster, which means cheaper food.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A small amount of CO2 can do a lot as this video via <a href="http://climateplace.org">climateplace.org</a> shows</p>

<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/81FHVrXgzuA" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>

<p>First of all the claim <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-plant-food-advanced.htm">that increased CO2 in the atmosphere will increase agricultural productivity is false</a>. Second, plants are also sensitive to temperature which means more expenive food. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>When fossil fuels are burned, they produce small amounts of carbon dioxide but large amounts of water vapor. Increases in water vapor show up as more cloud cover. Clouds both trap heat (which increases warming) and reflect sunlight (which reduces warming), but there is no consensus about which effect is greater.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Want to hear something that will rock your world? Climatologists know clouds exist and have taken them into account in their models.In fact, the IPCC report devotes <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg1/en/ch1s1-5-2.html">a whole section</a> to the effect of clouds on the climate system. Oh wait not just one section <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg1/en/ch8s8-6-3-2.html">but two sections</a>. The result of this research into the clould feedback is that clouds can have a significant effect of the climate system but don't even come close to being able to neutralize the effect of a CO2 increase.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is known with a high degree of certainty is that at times in the past, the Earth has been both warmer and cooler at current levels of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-higher-in-past-intermediate.htm">Compare CO2 levels for the past 500 million years to temperature. <br /></a> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is also known is the current climate models have a dreadful record of prediction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Climate models have actually been very accurate. <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Hansen-1988-prediction-advanced.htm">Compare Hansen's 1988 predictions</a></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_575" align="alignnone" width="433"]<a href="https://theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Hansen88Temps.jpg"></a> Note scenario B.[/caption]</p>

<p><a title="What is the Evidence of Global Warming? Part one: How we know that the temperature is increasing." href="https://theojones.name/index.php/what-is-the-evidence-of-global-warming-part-one-how-we-know-that-the-temperature-is-increasing/">to what actually happened. <br /></a></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_159" align="alignnone" width="410"] Image Description from NASA:Graph of global annual surface temperatures relative to 1951-1980 mean temperature. Air and ocean data from weather stations, ships and satellites. The 2007 point is the 11-month anomaly.[/caption]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Twenty years ago, we were told that the Earth’s temperatures would steadily rise from then on, yet there has been no average warming for the past 16 years — oops.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=47">Bzzzt</a>! Looks like you still haven't had any luck at understanding climate science.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_569" align="alignright" width="1024"] One of the most common misunderstandings amongst climate change "skeptics" is the difference between short-term noise and long-term signal. This animation shows how the same temperature data (green) that is used to determine the long-term global surface air warming trend of 0.16°C per decade (red) can be used inappropriately to "cherrypick" short time periods that show a cooling trend simply because the endpoints are carefully chosen and the trend is dominated by short-term noise in the data (blue steps). Isn't it strange how five periods of cooling can add up to a clear warming trend over the last 4 decades? Several factors can have a large impact on short-term temperatures, such as oceanic cycles like the El Niño Southern Oscillation (ENSO) or the 11-year solar cycle. These short-term cycles don't have long-term effects on the Earth's temperature, unlike the continuing upward trend caused by global warming from human greenhouse gas emissions. Image and caption via Skeptical Science Graphics by Skeptical Science is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.[/caption]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A carbon tax has real costs to the American economy. Energy prices and food prices would be higher, and virtually everything else that people consume would cost more. The results of higher prices are a lower standard of living, less economic opportunity, lower real wages and fewer jobs. All for what?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is of course why the Cato Institute thinks <a href="http://www.cato.org/blog/unfair-criticism-fair-tax">replacing the current tax system with a sales tax is a "pro-growth"</a> option.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an economist, I make no pretense to knowing what the optimum temperature of the earth ought to be and what the optimal level of carbon dioxide should be.....</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then why tell policymakers to ignore the advice of an overwhelming majority of researchers in the natural sciences on the subject?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an economist, though, I am prepared to make judgments as to whether a proposed tax is likely to have more benefits than costs.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You seem to be doing this by assuming away the costs of climate change. <a href="http://economics.about.com/od/termsbeginningwith1/g/assume_a_can_opener.htm">Ever hear of the joke about when an economist, a chemist and a physicist got struck on an island</a>?" <em>A physicist, a chemist and an economist are stranded on an island, with nothing to eat. A can of soup washes ashore. The physicist says, "Let's smash the can open with a rock." The chemist says, "Let's build a fire and heat the can first." The economist says, "Let's assume that we have a can-opener..."</em> "</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bzzztlooks" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bzzztlooks</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/creativecommonsattribution" class="p-category" rel="tag">#creativecommonsattribution</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/elni" class="p-category" rel="tag">#elni</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bzzztlooks</category>
      <category>#creativecommonsattribution</category>
      <category>#elni</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
