<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23uncategorized&amp;offset=80&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>As an anti poverty measure the minimum wage...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/as-an-anti-poverty-measure-the-minimum-wage</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/as-an-anti-poverty-measure-the-minimum-wage</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 14:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>As an anti-poverty measure the minimum wage is a pretty inefficient instrument. It has a lot of economic side effects, and at high rates serves to reduce bargaining power on non-wage elements of employment due. That last fact might explain why unions are U-turning on the issue --- at least as regards to their workers.<br /><a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2015/05/27/los_angeles_15_minimum_wage_labor_unions_want_to_be_exempt_from_it.html?utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+Trending+Content&utm_content=5566813204d3014d00000001&utm_medium=trueAnthem&utm_source=twitter">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.slate.com/<wbr></wbr>blogs/<wbr></wbr>moneybox/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>27/<wbr></wbr>los_angeles_15_minimum_wage_labor_unions_want_to_be_exempt_from_it.html?utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+Trending+Content&utm_content=5566813204d3014d00000001&utm_medium=trueAnthem&utm_source=twitter</a><br />And Warren Buffet was right to suggest an increase in the earned income tax credit as an alternative  --- although I would favor a straight basic income (the ENTC is effectively a partial basic income with a work requirement)<br /><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/better-than-raising-the-minimum-wage-1432249927?mod=trending_now_1">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.wsj.com/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>better-than-raising-the-minimum-wage-1432249927?mod=trending_now_1</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/poverty" class="p-category" rel="tag">#poverty</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#poverty</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The #Gamergate mascot comes from the 4chan ...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gamergate-mascot-comes-from-the-4chan-</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gamergate-mascot-comes-from-the-4chan-</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 06:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> mascot comes from the 4chan "picclo dick" rape joke.<br /><a href="https://www.fastcodesign.com/3037941/the-secret-meaning-behind-gamergates-branding#3">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.fastcodesign.com/<wbr></wbr>3037941/<wbr></wbr>the-secret-meaning-behind-gamergates-branding#3</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The meme is based around an animated GIF called “Piccolo Dick,” which shows the Dragon Ball anime character Piccolo sodomizing Vegeta, another character from the series. Banned by many internet forums, posters began to abstract the image to the point that the colors alone were easily associated with the meme.....The image first appeared on 4chan in the 2000s and was frequently reposted by forum trolls, who spoke of giving a "daily dose" of the graphic to forum members, who’d then reply with the catchphrase "Thanks, doc," according to the meme encyclopedia Know Your Meme. Soon, the image was banned, and users began to post other purple-and-green images understood to be a reference to the forbidden GIF...... in the initial forum discussion that led to the Vivian James design, a draft of the Vivian character with her distinctive color palette got plenty of "thanks, doc" replies, as did an anonymous illustrator who a few days later posted a first draft of the now standard GamerGate logo, showing a stylized video game controller with purple and green G’s.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#3</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A beef of mine in the world of...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/a-beef-of-mine-in-the-world-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/a-beef-of-mine-in-the-world-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 01:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A beef of mine in the world of politics is the rise of ideologies that are just apriori hairballs. They try to get high level claims from logical deduction with little input from outside facts or data. Examples would be the "praxology" or Austrian school libertarians (and other related ideologies like that of Ayn Rand), many religions, and the type of third wave feminism seen on Tumblr.  But this type of deductive analysis never works for something as complex as human society. You get conflicts with the factual world quite a bit, and many conflicts with science (see libertarian climate change deniers, or "postmodernism/poststructuralism" in the feminist world). Ideally, a political philosophy should instead bridge the is-ought gap with the fewest assumptions possible and from then on rely to the fullest extent possible on scientifically knowable results about the economy and society.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/femminism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#femminism</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/libertarians" class="p-category" rel="tag">#libertarians</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politicalphilosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politicalphilosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/religion" class="p-category" rel="tag">#religion</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#femminism</category>
      <category>#libertarians</category>
      <category>#politicalphilosophy</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#religion</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's a heads up. Sourceforge is now loading the opensource projects they host with malware</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/heres-a-heads-up-sourceforge-is-now-loading-the-opensource</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/heres-a-heads-up-sourceforge-is-now-loading-the-opensource</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 22:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Here's a heads up. Sourceforge is now loading the opensource projects they host with malware. DON'T download from there. They weren't hacked. They have been crapware pushing for a long time. Previously, they waited for developer permission, but now they are being more aggressive and hitting projects without permission. They claim that the projects affected, such as GIMP, were "abandoned" <a href="http://sourceforge.net/blog/gimp-win-project-wasnt-hijacked-just-abandoned/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>sourceforge.net/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>gimp-win-project-wasnt-hijacked-just-abandoned/<wbr></wbr></a>  ; an excuse that is dubious at best.  Even if it were "abandoned" that's not an excuse to junk up  their binaries. And look at the junk they are bundling. Malware companies don't even try to come up with names that look legit. "Funnel Delivery", really? Sounds like something involved in Foie Gras production. A lot of older projects still use them, even though there are now better options around legacy projects started off using them as their main form of hosting. Its hard to switch something that big. (although Sourceforge has become scummy enough to make it worth it)<br /><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/05/sourceforge-grabs-gimp-for-windows-account-wraps-installer-in-bundle-pushing-adware/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>information-technology/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>sourceforge-grabs-gimp-for-windows-account-wraps-installer-in-bundle-pushing-adware/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/informationtechnology" class="p-category" rel="tag">#informationtechnology</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/malware" class="p-category" rel="tag">#malware</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sourceforge" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sourceforge</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/windows" class="p-category" rel="tag">#windows</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#informationtechnology</category>
      <category>#malware</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#sourceforge</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#windows</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video of Milton Friedman discussing the possibility of a basic income/negative income tax in 1968</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/video-of-milton-friedman-discussing-the-possibility-of-a-basic</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/video-of-milton-friedman-discussing-the-possibility-of-a-basic</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 21:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Milton Friedman discussing the possibility of a basic income/negative income tax in 1968. Don't you wish conservatives were still like this instead of like Rush Limbaugh? Probably, part of the reason why Friedman supported this is because, adopting a basic income will allow government policy that is in most other aspects much more libertarian.<br /><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xtpgkX588nM">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.youtube.com/<wbr></wbr>watch?v=xtpgkX588nM</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/basicincom" class="p-category" rel="tag">#basicincom</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/conservatives" class="p-category" rel="tag">#conservatives</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/libertarians" class="p-category" rel="tag">#libertarians</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#basicincom</category>
      <category>#conservatives</category>
      <category>#libertarians</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I've hinted this before in previous postings of...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-hinted-this-before-in-previous-postings-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-hinted-this-before-in-previous-postings-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 21:07:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I've hinted this before in previous postings of mine about health care, but the way to resolve a lot of the tension between fee for service health care pricing, and fixed rate pricing is to reimburse doctors like in fixed rate pricing to avoid toxic incentives on the provider end. But use (government) administered prices to manage demand on the consumer side and to prevent wasteful usage of health services. Straight up fee for service won't work because that would give providers intensive to over-treat due to imperfect information. But you still want to put some price signals on consumers. Its like the "market socialism" proposals to introduce pseudo-prices into planned economies to avoid shortage.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/healthcare" class="p-category" rel="tag">#healthcare</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/marketsocialism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#marketsocialism</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#healthcare</category>
      <category>#marketsocialism</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Land Use is a Major Underappreciated Element of Environmental Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/land-use-is-a-major-underappreciated-element-of-environmental-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/land-use-is-a-major-underappreciated-element-of-environmental-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 03:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"> The extent to which land use is an important factor in environmental policy is heavily unappreciated. It is as likely to be a major future environmental issue and is likely to be as destructive as other major issues, like climate change. Major developed countries of the world are on a massively unsustainable track of their land use regards to agriculture and other major sources of land use. Major adjustments in these economies will have to be made sooner or later. There is simply not enough land available on earth to sustain the current consumption patterns of the typical American, or the typical Western European. What cannot continue will not continue. Things will have to change one way or another. The question in regards to land use is, the choice over if consumption will be changed in response to a very rapid crisis, or it will be changed gradually time to adjust to new conditions. And in the meantime, the large-scale overconsumption of land based resources results in major economic distortions, and causes critical resources like food to be overpriced for the rest of the world. Overconsumption of land produced resources also causes severe environmental damage such as species loss, deforestation, loss of culturally valuable natural sites, and feedbacks that result in increased climate change and other forms of pollution. But things like forests and fisheries, and other naturally bioproductive areas can be depleted in a way that damages their future production. We do not want to be in the situation where we have depleted a resource that will take generations to rebuild. And with things like species loss, once the environmental damage has been done it is impossible to repair. This is why action must be taken before there is a crisis. We must conserve our land resources. Energy is also another issue where land use plays a particularly unappreciated role. Most people take "sustainable energy" as meaning something largely synonymous with "does not emit CO2 pollution". However, this is necessary but not sufficient part of sustainable energy. There are plenty of energy sources that serve to seriously worsen the land use issue, even though they are nominally carbon neutral. <a href="https://www.theojones.name/why-biofuels-will-never-amount-to-a-substantial-proportion-of-future-world-energy-use/">As I discussed in yesterday's post on this blog</a>, biofuels are a particularly severe case of this. The land use issue is a major factor in why I am under the belief that the most sustainable energy source that can be deployed with current technology is nuclear energy, as it uses very little land.<br /></span> </p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westerneuropean" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westerneuropean</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westerneuropean</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Biofuels Will Never Amount to a Substantial Proportion of Future World Energy Production</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-biofuels-will-never-amount-to-a-substantial-proportion-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-biofuels-will-never-amount-to-a-substantial-proportion-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 04:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><span style="font-size: 14pt;">I am strongly against the wider deployment of biofuels. There are the obvious interactions between biofuel production and food prices, and biofuel production is largely responsible for the 2007 price crisis. Other than the large-scale humanitarian reasons to oppose biofuel production as a serious alternative energy, there is also the fact that even considering very generous projections, the fuel source is unlikely to ever produce a large amount of the world's energy supply. Compared to the land they take up, plants are just extremely efficient energy producers. This blog post will show how is simply not possible with anything like current technology to meet even a substantial amount of the world's energy needs with biofuels. I will start with a generous estimate of the maximum possible biomass energy production come out of agricultural land. First are some quick assumptions. The first is that world's future energy supply will need to provide a developed nation level of energy use to a population of about 9 billion people. Furthermore, this will at the very least require power production amounting to about 5000 W per person on average. The current US power consumption amounts to about 10,000 W on average. Now let's calculate based on highly favorable assumptions how much of the world's energy supply biomass energy could reasonably provide.<br /></span><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Let's first start the total surface area of the Earth, <a href="http://www.webcitation.org/query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fhypertextbook.com%2Ffacts%2F2001%2FDanielChen.shtml&date=2015-05-24">which is about 361,800,000 square kilometers</a>. How much of this is reasonably available to agriculture? Only 150,000,000 square kilometers is land and only some of this land is actually useful for agriculture. So when you adjust you get a total useful percentage of the Earth's land surface area of <a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v461/n7263/full/461472a.html">about 15%</a>. Now, that estimate, would result in estimate of global available crop land of substantially less than half a hectare, or about 1 acre of cropland per person. However, that estimate is based on many environmental constraints. Let's ignore them. The purpose of this article let's pretend we want to maximize biofuel production regardless of any environmental constraints, even if it means destroying almost every natural ecosystem around. Let's pave over every roughly arable plot of land. When you subtract out on the uninhabitable land or land is otherwise useless to large-scale agriculture and divide by the future expected population of 9 billion, <a href="http://www.webcitation.org/query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.zo.utexas.edu%2Fcourses%2FTHOC%2Fland.html&date=2015-05-25">you get an area of about one hectare (~2 acres) of land per person</a>. If all this land were converted to biofuel production, how much energy could it produce? Of course, this will be a highly generous estimate. One hectare is 10,000 square meters. How much energy do biofuel crops produced per square meter? Depends on the crop. <a href="http://www.webcitation.org/query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.withouthotair.com%2FcD%2Fpage_284.shtml&date=2015-05-25">Corn grown in the United States converted to ethanol produces about 0.02 watts of energy per square meter</a>. When scaled up across the per-person hectare, this amounts to about 200W per person. This is a straight up puny amount of energy production compared to the total world needs. What about improved technology? The previous link suggests that theoretical cellulosic ethanol system could deliver about 0.2 watts per square meter. This gives a somewhat reasonable contribution to overall energy production. However, such a large number as a product of a very generous estimate, and predicts some technology that only exists on paper. And remember, that per person amount is based on an assumption where all reasonably useful land is being devoted voted to the purpose. Already, most reasonably usable agricultural land is already being used for food production. From page 21 of<br /></span></p>

<p><a href="http://www.stockholmresilience.org/download/18.1fe8f33123572b59ab800012568/pb_longversion_170909.pdf"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><a href="http://www.stockholmresilience.org/download/18.1fe8f33123572b59ab800012568/pb_longversion_170909.pdf">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.stockholmresilience.org/<wbr></wbr>download/<wbr></wbr>18.1fe8f33123572b59ab800012568/<wbr></wbr>pb_longversion_170909.pdf</a></span></a><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><br /></span></p>

<p><a href="http://www.webcitation.org/query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.stockholmresilience.org%2Fdownload%2F18.1fe8f33123572b59ab800012568%2Fpb_longversion_170909.pdf&date=2015-05-25"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><a href="http://www.webcitation.org/query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.stockholmresilience.org%2Fdownload%2F18.1fe8f33123572b59ab800012568%2Fpb_longversion_170909.pdf&date=2015-05-25">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.webcitation.org/<wbr></wbr>query?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.stockholmresilience.org%2Fdownload%2F18.1fe8f33123572b59ab800012568%2Fpb_longversion_170909.pdf&date=2015-05-25</a></span></a><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><br /></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><span style="font-size: 12pt;"><strong><em>About 12 % of the global land surface is currently under crop cultivation (Foley et al., 2005; Ramankutty et al. 2008). The allowed 3 % expansion (approximately 400 Mha) to the level we propose as a land system boundary will most likely be reached over the coming decades,and includes suitable land that is not either currently cultivated or is under forest cover – e.g., abandoned cropland in Europe, North America and the former Soviet Union and some areas of Africa's savannas and South America's cerrado
</em></strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;">Overall, is clear that, at least with current technology biofuels will be extremely unlikely to provide a substantial contribution to the overall substantial energy production. The current programs of subsidies for biofuel production should be immediately phased out. It will be extremely unlikely to contribute to a substantial energy future. In the meantime, biofuel production will compete with food production while producing very little economic value. Because of this competition with food production and because of the tendencies for this competition increase prices and inflation, I furthermore think that even privately funded biofuel production should be outlawed on any commercial, near commercial, or industrial scale. The small scale production that does continue should be heavily regulated, should be forced to use feed stocks that have no risk of competition with food supplies, and should be heavily taxed (due to the imperfections of regulation in catching all unwanted use of the tech). </span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/africa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#africa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/southamerica" class="p-category" rel="tag">#southamerica</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/us" class="p-category" rel="tag">#us</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#africa</category>
      <category>#southamerica</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#us</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An interesting interview with one of the main targets of #Gamergate connected harassment</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-interesting-interview-with-one-of-the-main-targets-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-interesting-interview-with-one-of-the-main-targets-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 05:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>An interesting interview with one of the main targets of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> connected harassment</p>

<p><a title="" href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/03/that-life-is-over-zoe-quinn-looks-beyond-gamergate/"></a><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/03/that-life-is-over-zoe-quinn-looks-beyond-gamergate/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>gaming/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>03/<wbr></wbr>that-life-is-over-zoe-quinn-looks-beyond-gamergate/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indiana is considering a RFRA clone</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 06:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Indiana legislature is considering a law that is very similar to the federal Religious Freedom Restoration Act.  The bill provides that religious belief exempts one from regulations, even neutral ones, unless the government produces a compelling need. Neither the Indiana bill nor its federal twin are particular to any type of regulation and include everything from anti-discrimination laws to drug possession laws (the original inspiration for the federal RFRA). I don't think either law is a good idea. The idea of religious exemptions from neutral laws is almost always a bad idea. This is a good issue to actually read the bill on, and to read (or at least Wikipedia) some of the relevant court opinions. <a href="https://iga.in.gov/static-documents/9/2/b/a/92bab197/SB0101.05.ENRS.pdf">The bill is only four generously spaced pages long</a>.  The media coverage on this subject is pretty error ridden and contains a lot of misconceptions about what the bill actually says. The religious should not be exempted from neutral laws on the basis of religious belief and I oppose it. But, a lot of people fundamentally misunderstand what the bill actually says. A number of media outlets have claimed that it's an anti-gay bill (even though it does not directly touch on that subject, <a href="http://www.indystar.com/story/opinion/readers/2015/03/07/indiana-needs-religious-freedom-legislation/24477303/">and it likely will not affect anti-discrimination law in any meaningful way</a>). The point of this post will be to clarify a bit of the legal background, and to summarize the bill.  The Supreme Court has made it pretty clear that that the First Amendment does not allow people to ignore neutral laws on the basis of religious belief (with a handful of exceptions. See, for example, <em>Employment Division v. Smith</em>. The goal of RFRAs is to override that ruling (the federal RFRA was actually spawned by that ruling) and make actions conducted as a product of religious belief protected. Now, I strongly believe that SCOTUS got it right in Smith, and that RFRAs are fundamentally a bad idea, but the final decision belongs with the legislative branch.  Lets look at what the 11-section Indiana bill (which is likely to pass) actually says as I go through a brief summary</p>
<ul><li>Section 1: Says that the bill applies to all government laws and regulations, even ones made prior to the enactment of it. 
</li><li>Section 2: Only regulations particularly exempted by law are exempt.
</li><li>Section 3: Definitions. Says that regulators are not allowed to use unconstutional provisions to work around the bill with particular mention of the establishment clause of the first amendment. 
</li><li>Section 4: More definitions. Pretty obvious and straightforward stuff. 
</li><li>Section 5. Defines "exercise of religion" as "any exercise of religion, whether or not compelled by, or central to, a system of religious belief". 
</li><li>Section 6: Defines "government entity". 
</li><li>Section 7: Defines "Person", includes corporations, but so does the federal RFRA.
</li><li>Section 8: States that a governmental entity may not substantially burden a person's exercise of religion unless it meets strict scrutiny
</li><li>Section 9: People can sue over violations of the law. 
</li><li>Section 10: Government agencies can be ordered to pay damages to those affected. 
</li><li>Section 11: The bill does not limit the actions of private actors, only government actions, laws and regulations.
</li></ul>
<p>Section 8 is the core of the bill and most of the definition sections are mostly boilerplate. This legislation is likely not just a useless repetition of current law. It goes far beyond what the Constitution mandates and even with the federal RFRA, a state RFRA has some effect. In <em>City of Boerne v. Flores</em> the Supreme Court struck down the part of the federal RFRA that applies to the states. But panicking over a state RFRA is a bit too much because we have a decade's worth of litigation over its federal version and good caselaw on what it means.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/firstamendment" class="p-category" rel="tag">#firstamendment</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rfra" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rfra</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scotus" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scotus</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/supremecourt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#supremecourt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#firstamendment</category>
      <category>#rfra</category>
      <category>#scotus</category>
      <category>#supremecourt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
