<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23uncategorized&amp;_t=rss&amp;offset=200" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Immigration Helps the Economy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A great body of research done by economists and other researchers shows that immigration has a potentially great potential to benefit the economy. The cost of immigration restrictions <a href="http://www.cgdev.org/publication/economics-and-emigration-trillion-dollar-bills-sidewalk-working-paper-264">is a large fraction of global GDP (around 25 percent)</a> and one of the most costly. This global cost of the current restrictions on immigrants from poor nations migrating to richer nations is trillions of dollars per year. Immigration restrictions can increase global economic inequality, particularly between nations, but also within nations.<br /><!--more--></p>

<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither. . .“</p>

<p>This immigration has been clearly beneficial to the nation. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.tcd.ie%2FEconomics%2FTEP%2F2003_papers%2FTEPNo15KOR23.pdf&ei=hZA-UvjGIYyayQH45ID4AQ&usg=AFQjCNH6zbsRZWrNg1bhyvSEUUZwrpIkxA&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc">Economist Kevin O'Rourke found that</a> immigration from Europe to the United States and Canada in the 19th and early 20th centuries narrowed the wage gaps between developed nations and then developing European nations, such as Ireland, Norway, and Italy.In the mid to late 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had an almost free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, as well as immigrants from Asia. This migration was at its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. In 1911, almost 15 percent of the United States population was foreign born. This immigration had substantial benefits for both nations. It fueled much of United States industrial development in the period before World War I and immigration from 1840 to 1920 was a primary contributor to American urbanization. <a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w12900">The migrants tended to be unskilled labor of the type best suited to employment in industry</a>, compared to the highly skilled craftsmen who made up the bulk of native workers. This is because labor is a limiting factor to economic output in nations with high development of capital and technology. The result of migration, therefore, is an increase in industrial capacity triggered by the easing of that limiting factor.Additionally, the nations where the migrants emigrated from received great benefits from their migration flows. Nations with limited capital and technology development compared to the available labor are the most likely to produce emigrants. This migration drives local wages up. While emigration between 1870 and 1910 lowered the Irish labor force by 45 percent, the Italian by 39 percent, and the Norwegian by 24 percent, wages increased dramatically in those nations. Irish wages rose by almost 25%.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/canada" class="p-category" rel="tag">#canada</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/irishpotatofamine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#irishpotatofamine</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#canada</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#irishpotatofamine</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Papers Show How Global Warming Harms Agriculture</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 23:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Three recent papers looked into the effect that global warming has on our agricultural system, and found many possibly harmful impacts. Food price instability can be expected to increase and households and farmers in developing nations will feel the pain of a changing climate. Hundreds of thousands will face risk of starvation. Farmers in developed nations will face reduced agricultural output and possibly increased exposure to plant diseases. The papers I will discuss provide case studies into this issue through looking at the impacts that can be expected in Yemen, Australia and the Netherlands.<br /><!--more--><br />[caption id="attachment_624" align="alignright" width="365"] Graph from Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change[/caption]</p>

<p>The paper<a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0306919213001139"> <em>Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change</em></a> published in the journal Food Policy discusses the effect that global warming will have on the people of the Middle Eastern nation Yemen. The paper found substantial harms. Agricultural productivity will be reduced in Yemen and the cost of imported food will increase. 32% percent of Yemen's population is unable to afford enough food to meet their calorie requirements. Unfortunately, global warming can be expected to increase this problem.  An additional 224,000 people can be expected to face hunger in Yemen in an average year between 2010 and 2050 because of climate change. Rural populations will be the most strongly affected. This study uses the climate change models by the Model for Interdisciplinary Research on Climate and the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation which are based on the IPCC's A1B projection<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ipcc.ch%2Fpdf%2Fassessment-report%2Far4%2Fwg1%2Far4-wg1-spm.pdf&ei=ODY9UqWtOYSwyQHpx4GQBQ&usg=AFQjCNH3kgAs4cAqOcmHrYLSRHIUIbkouw&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc"> which predicts 2.8 degrees Celsius warming by the end of the century</a>.The A1B scenario assumes that substantial attempts will be made to convert from fossil fuels to clean energy but that a complete conversion will not be attempted. The harsher A1FI projection assumes that no substantial changes to energy policy will be made and predicts 4.0C warming by the turn of the century.</p>

<p>The paper <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1467-8489.12021/abstract;jsessionid=986D3D8963DAA5D9F2A14937CB6BB8BE.d02t02?systemMessage=Wiley+Online+Library+will+be+unavailable+for+approximately+4+hours+between+09%3A00+EDT+and+14%3A00+EDT+on+Saturday%2C+28+September+2013+as+we+make+upgrades+to+improve+our+services+to+you.+There+will+also+be+some+delays+to+online+publishing+between+25+to+28+September+2013.+We+apologize+for+the+inconvenience+and+appreciate+your+patience.+Thank+you+for+using+Wiley+Online+Library%21&userIsAuthenticated=false&deniedAccessCustomisedMessage="><em>Economic impacts of climate change on the Australian dairy sector</em></a> published in the Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics looks at how global warming will affect dairy production in Australia. This study finds that production of dairy products will be substantially reduced by climate change. Additionally, production will be pushed to the areas of the country that are least affected by global warming. This effect will be so strong that some of these mildly affected areas will actually increase production because they will gain a competitive advantage over the areas with the most damaged productivity.<a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0073602#s4"><em>Impact of Climate Change Effects on Contamination of Cereal Grains with Deoxynivalenol</em></a> looks at how global warming (with intensity based on the A1B) will affect the spread of fungus infestations responsible for wheat and corn deoxynivalenol contamination in the Netherlands. The paper found no nationwide change in fungus growth but some regions may experience changes and increases after 2040.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/australia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#australia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/middleeastern" class="p-category" rel="tag">#middleeastern</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/yemenchallenges" class="p-category" rel="tag">#yemenchallenges</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#s4</category>
      <category>#australia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#middleeastern</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#yemenchallenges</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am not trading in my iPad for a MS Surface</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-not-trading-in-my-ipad-for-a</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-not-trading-in-my-ipad-for-a</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 22:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Microsoft has announced that they will give a <a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2013/microsoft-offering-350-gift-cards-nonmicrosoft-device/">350 dollar gift certificate</a> to anyone who trades in an Ipad. This effectively means a free Surface RT [1. See this refurb tablet on sale from Microsoft <a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Surface-RT-Refurbished/productID.275706600"></a><a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Surface-RT-Refurbished/productID.275706600">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.microsoftstore.com/<wbr></wbr>store/<wbr></wbr>msusa/<wbr></wbr>en_US/<wbr></wbr>pdp/<wbr></wbr>Surface-RT-Refurbished/<wbr></wbr>productID.275706600</a> ]. Needless to say, I will not be taking Microsoft up on this offer. The tablet that I currently use is an iPad. If I had to reccomend a new tablet it would probably be one running the Android OS. To convince me to switch, Microsoft does not just have to persuade me that they have a product that is as good as the competition. They must show me a reason why it is worth my effort to give up the apps I currently use and other investments in Apple's platform. They are nowhere near being able to do this.</p><!--more--><p>Microsoft has two distinct products under the surface banner. Their cheapest tablet, the Surface RT in in the same league as a iPad. The surface pro is pretty much a laptop. Neither products give much reason to recommend them. Microsoft's surface RT has failed to provide a reasonable alternative to their major competitors in the tablet market, namely Apple and Android. It it more expensive and has a weaker selection of software than Android tablets. Despite the RT's cost, Microsoft has not been able to create the community or support that make Apple products successful. The Surface Pro is underpowered and overpriced compared to other laptops in the market and Microsoft's Windows 8 operating system is a flop.</p><p>The surface RT <a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Surface-RT/productID.275275300">sells for </a>about 350 dollars (reduced from over $500), <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2013/09/nvidia-unveils-the-tegra-note-brought-to-you-by-evga/">compared to 200</a> for a similar Android. It looks like an RT user gets almost nothing for this extra 150 dollars. The RT's hardware is lackluster and similar to lower priced Android tablets. <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us/storage">It has just 36 GB of storage</a>, over half of which is hogged by the operating system.Its battery life is also comprible to other tablets. The selection of applications available for the RT is much more limited than other tablets. <a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/tablets/microsoft-surface-rt/4505-3126_7-35332494.html">The Windows 8 app store is sparse </a>and because the RT is based on an ARM chipset normal Windows 8 software will not run on the RT. Microsoft seems to be trying to avoid discussion of this situation as the word "apps" appears exactly twice in the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us">company's promotional website</a>.Apple's success in the tablet market to due to the company's ability to provide great customer support and present their products as the cool alternative. Microsoft can do nether.  </p><p>Microsoft's Surface Pro sells for $700. What does your money get you? 64 GB of hard drive space, 4 GB Ram and a 3rd generation Intel Core i5. There are much better laptops avaiable at that price range.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gb" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gb</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/intelcore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#intelcore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/microsoftsurfacepro" class="p-category" rel="tag">#microsoftsurfacepro</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gb</category>
      <category>#intelcore</category>
      <category>#microsoftsurfacepro</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#rt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Energy Is the Safest Energy Source</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/nuclear-energy-is-the-safest-energy-source</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/nuclear-energy-is-the-safest-energy-source</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 22:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Nuclear energy Is the safest energy source in existence.<a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/FAQ_on_radioactivity_and_nuclear_technology"> It produces a lower number of deaths per trillion kilowatt hours produced than any other power source in use</a>, even beating out renewable energy sources.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Energy source                              Deaths/Trillion KWH<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:HEUraniumC.jpg"></a> <br />Coal (world, all uses)                         100,000 <br />Coal (world, electricity only)                60,000 <br />Coal (China, all uses)                        170,000 <br />Coal (USA, all uses)                          15,000 <br />Oil                                                    36,000 <br />Natural gas                                       4,000 <br />Biomass                                          12,000 <br />Peat                                                12,000 <br />Solar PV (rooftop)                             440 <br />Wind                                               150 <br />Hydro (world)                                    1,400 <br />Hydro (Europe)                                 100 <br />Nuclear                                            40</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/coalchina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#coalchina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hydroeurope" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hydroeurope</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#coalchina</category>
      <category>#hydroeurope</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Eliminate Poverty in the United States</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-best-way-to-eliminate-poverty-in-the-united-states</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-best-way-to-eliminate-poverty-in-the-united-states</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 21:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america/" title="Poverty: A Economic and Moral Crisis in America">As I have previously discussed</a>, poverty is a great problem in America.</p>
<p dir="ltr">To replace many of the current welfare programs that we have in the United States, I would recommend a basic income program along the lines of the negative income tax proposal created by the Nobel Prize winning economist Milton Friedman.</p><p dir="ltr">Every family would receive a sum of money from the federal government to make their income above the poverty line level. All income earned separately, apart from the federal government grant would be taxed at a flat rate to help pay for the program. This proposal would simplify the current welfare programs by replacing many of them with a single program. Because everyone would get to keep the income they earned by working, without effecting the lump sum paid to them, someone is always better off working. Also an income level just barely above the poverty line isn't enough to take away someone's motivation to work, since isn't very much money and wouldn't provide for many or any extras or luxuries.</p><p dir="ltr">This sum of money would be distributed through the federal income tax system as a refundable tax credit.  If you owed no taxes, instead of a tax credit, you would receive a grant check from the federal government.</p><!--more--><p dir="ltr">A negative income tax isn't just some idea that some economist came up with, during the 1960s and 70s this idea was seriously considered by the federal government. In 1969 Richard Nixon proposed a bill that would have created a basic income through a negative income tax system. The bill failed in the Senate.  The Johnson administration studied the possibility of a negative income tax and George McGovern proposed it during his failed 1972 presidential campaign.</p>
<p>This system would give the working poor a living wage that would not take away their motivation to work. To help the unemployed, I would recommend that we create a jobs program to help them. This could provide work and help the United States by improving its infrastructure and creating alternative energy projects. This would work like the Works Progress Administration, which was created during the Great Depression to reduce unemployment.  It constructed roads streets, parks and other public buildings.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/greatdepression" class="p-category" rel="tag">#greatdepression</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/richardnixon" class="p-category" rel="tag">#richardnixon</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worksprogressadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worksprogressadministration</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#greatdepression</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#richardnixon</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#worksprogressadministration</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Response to an Article from the Cato Institute on Global Warming</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-response-to-an-article-from-the-cato-institute-on</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-response-to-an-article-from-the-cato-institute-on</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Cato institute recently published an article titled <em><a href="http://www.cato.org/publications/commentary/carbon-tax-would-make-no-sense">A Carbon Tax Would Make No Sense</a></em> that represents many of the most common arguments made by climate change denialists. In this post I will do a analysis of why these arguments are wrong.</p>
<!--more--><blockquote>
<p>Do you know how much carbon dioxide is in the atmosphere? It is a little less than 400 parts per million. Do you know what the optimum level of carbon dioxide is? No one does, even though some have the extreme conceit to think they do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is the optimal level of CO2. Any level between 250-350 parts per million.Climate change is harmful because of the rapid rate of temperature change it has caused, not the absolute level of temperature created. Ecosystems and human civilization have developed around a relitively stable climate since the last ice age. The current rate of change to this climate is almost unprecedented in the Earth's geologic history and every time a similarly rapid change has happened, the result has been a mass extinction and a widespread disruption of ecosystems. <a href="http://www.ecologyandsociety.org/vol14/iss2/art32/main.html">A CO2 concentration at this level would stabilize</a> the climate at a level that is consistent with what ecosystems have evolved to handle and what human infrastructure is adapted to handle. The human economy is extremely dependent on this stable ecosystem. In fact it could be said that the economy is a wholly-owned subsidiary of the global ecosystem.These impacts will be disastrous for human health, agriculture and the economy. The 2007 IPCC assessment contains a excellent diagram that summarizes these impacts. <br /><a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg2/en/figure-spm-2.html"></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earth’s atmosphere is 78 percent nitrogen, about 21 percent oxygen, less than 1 percent argon, and only 0.038 percent carbon dioxide — plus a variable amount of water vapor. The gas is necessary for life. Plants cannot grow without it. .... There is evidence that as carbon-dioxide levels have risen, plants are growing faster, which means cheaper food.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A small amount of CO2 can do a lot as this video via <a href="http://climateplace.org">climateplace.org</a> shows</p>

<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/81FHVrXgzuA" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>

<p>First of all the claim <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-plant-food-advanced.htm">that increased CO2 in the atmosphere will increase agricultural productivity is false</a>. Second, plants are also sensitive to temperature which means more expenive food. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>When fossil fuels are burned, they produce small amounts of carbon dioxide but large amounts of water vapor. Increases in water vapor show up as more cloud cover. Clouds both trap heat (which increases warming) and reflect sunlight (which reduces warming), but there is no consensus about which effect is greater.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Want to hear something that will rock your world? Climatologists know clouds exist and have taken them into account in their models.In fact, the IPCC report devotes <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg1/en/ch1s1-5-2.html">a whole section</a> to the effect of clouds on the climate system. Oh wait not just one section <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg1/en/ch8s8-6-3-2.html">but two sections</a>. The result of this research into the clould feedback is that clouds can have a significant effect of the climate system but don't even come close to being able to neutralize the effect of a CO2 increase.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is known with a high degree of certainty is that at times in the past, the Earth has been both warmer and cooler at current levels of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-higher-in-past-intermediate.htm">Compare CO2 levels for the past 500 million years to temperature. <br /></a> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is also known is the current climate models have a dreadful record of prediction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Climate models have actually been very accurate. <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Hansen-1988-prediction-advanced.htm">Compare Hansen's 1988 predictions</a></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_575" align="alignnone" width="433"]<a href="https://theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Hansen88Temps.jpg"></a> Note scenario B.[/caption]</p>

<p><a title="What is the Evidence of Global Warming? Part one: How we know that the temperature is increasing." href="https://theojones.name/index.php/what-is-the-evidence-of-global-warming-part-one-how-we-know-that-the-temperature-is-increasing/">to what actually happened. <br /></a></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_159" align="alignnone" width="410"] Image Description from NASA:Graph of global annual surface temperatures relative to 1951-1980 mean temperature. Air and ocean data from weather stations, ships and satellites. The 2007 point is the 11-month anomaly.[/caption]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Twenty years ago, we were told that the Earth’s temperatures would steadily rise from then on, yet there has been no average warming for the past 16 years — oops.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=47">Bzzzt</a>! Looks like you still haven't had any luck at understanding climate science.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_569" align="alignright" width="1024"] One of the most common misunderstandings amongst climate change "skeptics" is the difference between short-term noise and long-term signal. This animation shows how the same temperature data (green) that is used to determine the long-term global surface air warming trend of 0.16°C per decade (red) can be used inappropriately to "cherrypick" short time periods that show a cooling trend simply because the endpoints are carefully chosen and the trend is dominated by short-term noise in the data (blue steps). Isn't it strange how five periods of cooling can add up to a clear warming trend over the last 4 decades? Several factors can have a large impact on short-term temperatures, such as oceanic cycles like the El Niño Southern Oscillation (ENSO) or the 11-year solar cycle. These short-term cycles don't have long-term effects on the Earth's temperature, unlike the continuing upward trend caused by global warming from human greenhouse gas emissions. Image and caption via Skeptical Science Graphics by Skeptical Science is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.[/caption]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A carbon tax has real costs to the American economy. Energy prices and food prices would be higher, and virtually everything else that people consume would cost more. The results of higher prices are a lower standard of living, less economic opportunity, lower real wages and fewer jobs. All for what?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is of course why the Cato Institute thinks <a href="http://www.cato.org/blog/unfair-criticism-fair-tax">replacing the current tax system with a sales tax is a "pro-growth"</a> option.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an economist, I make no pretense to knowing what the optimum temperature of the earth ought to be and what the optimal level of carbon dioxide should be.....</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then why tell policymakers to ignore the advice of an overwhelming majority of researchers in the natural sciences on the subject?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an economist, though, I am prepared to make judgments as to whether a proposed tax is likely to have more benefits than costs.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You seem to be doing this by assuming away the costs of climate change. <a href="http://economics.about.com/od/termsbeginningwith1/g/assume_a_can_opener.htm">Ever hear of the joke about when an economist, a chemist and a physicist got struck on an island</a>?" <em>A physicist, a chemist and an economist are stranded on an island, with nothing to eat. A can of soup washes ashore. The physicist says, "Let's smash the can open with a rock." The chemist says, "Let's build a fire and heat the can first." The economist says, "Let's assume that we have a can-opener..."</em> "</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bzzztlooks" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bzzztlooks</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/creativecommonsattribution" class="p-category" rel="tag">#creativecommonsattribution</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/elni" class="p-category" rel="tag">#elni</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bzzztlooks</category>
      <category>#creativecommonsattribution</category>
      <category>#elni</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Connects Media Coverage of Global Warming to Lack of Images</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/study-connects-media-coverage-of-global-warming-to-lack-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/study-connects-media-coverage-of-global-warming-to-lack-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 22:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://pus.sagepub.com/content/early/2013/09/04/0963662513500196.abstract">A study published this month </a>in the journal Public Understanding of Science [1. León, Bienvenido, and Mª Carmen Erviti. "Science in pictures: Visual representation of climate change in Spain’s television news." Public Understanding of Science (2013): 0963662513500196.] looked at the relation of visual images to coverage of the global warming issue in Spain's television media.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_533" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/Features/WorldOfChange/decadaltemp.php"></a> This images represents the causes of climate change. Image via NASA Earth Observatory[/caption]</p>

<p>The study found that "<em>the low rate of coverage of CC[Climate Change] can be related to the scarcity of attractive images available to the channels</em>".<!--more--> The authors looked at three issues; the extent to which the lack of images to illustrate global warming, the extent to which images used showcase the impacts of climate change rather than its causes and the extent to which images used represent climate change as a remote process. The research was done through a mix of analysis of television shows aired by Spain's major networks and interviews with journalists. The authors found that climate change is generally considered a niche topic and that scarcity of images is one core reason this is true. Of particular importance is the amount of original images available to networks. Furthermore the visual representation of impacts of climate change looms large in media coverage and can produce spectacular images. Images of climate change impacts are almost always focused on international matters such as the effects of global warming on polar bears. Images of local impacts are rare. The most common way to visually represent the causes of climate change is by showing an image of a smokestack. These representations have a tendency to make the climate change issue seem distant, remote, mundane and insignificant.</p>

<p>I think that the results of this study are related to the current state of climate change denialism. Those who try to ignore the human role in global warming have switched their focus away from arguing that it isn't happening to arguing that it isn't important. Conservative groups in the United States have tried to make it seem like climate change activists are just a bunch of tree huggers trying to save the polar bears at the expense of the economy. Portrayal in the media can bolster this impression when climate change gets portrayed as unimportant.</p>

<p><strong>Published Work Cited </strong></p>

<p>León, Bienvenido, and Mª Carmen Erviti. "Science in pictures: Visual representation of climate change in Spain’s television news." Public Understanding of Science (2013): 0963662513500196</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/spain" class="p-category" rel="tag">#spain</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#spain</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top Three Reasons Why Nuclear Energy is Better than Fossil Fuels</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/top-three-reasons-why-nuclear-energy-is-better-than-fossil</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/top-three-reasons-why-nuclear-energy-is-better-than-fossil</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 18:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Nuclear energy is a fuel source that is far superior to the fossil fuels that our economy is currently based on. As I will show in this post  nuclear power produces lower greenhouse gas emissions, is safer and is cheaper than many fossil fuels.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_526" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Nuclear_Power_Plant_Cattenom_a.png"></a> Unlike fossil fuel power plants, the only substance leaving the cooling towers of nuclear power plants is water vapour and thus does not pollute the air or cause global warming. Image and caption via Wikipedia and licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license.[/caption]</p>
<ol><li><strong>Lower Greenhouse Gas Emissions:  </strong>France with 73% of its power from nuclear has per-capita CO2 emissions three times LOWER then the U.S. Power costs in France are half that of Germany.</li>
    <li><strong>Health and Safety:</strong> The pollution produced by the fossil fuel industry kills more Americans every year than nuclear energy generation has in the entire world in all of history. <!--more-->A study of more than 400 coal power plants by the American Lung Association<a href="http://www.lungusa.org/about-us/our-impact/top-stories/toxic-air-coal-fired-power-plants.html"> found that the pollution from the power plants kill approximately 13,000 people a year</a> or about 20 people a power plant. <a href="http://www.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fatomicinsights.com%2F1996%2F04%2Fchernobyl-health-effects-best-available-data.html&h=jAQH8I97P">The Chernobyl disaster killed 42 people.</a>What the nuclear industry calls their worst disaster in history the coal industry calls "clean coal". Fukushima and Chernobyl were light water reactors from the 1970s based on designs from the 50s. 95% of the radioactive material from Fukushima was contained and there were no fatalities. The failure of the Fukushima reactor was caused by a once in a lifetime magnitude 9.0 earthquake and a 45 foot high tsunami. Three similar but more modern reactors were hit by the same tsunami and earthquake and remained intact. The latest reactor designs can produce even better safety results. Generation III reactors such as Westinghouse Electric's AP1000, which are the most modern designs currently in production have a very small risk of accident.A report by British regulators found that the AP1000 has a less than 1 in ten million chance of undergoing an accident that results in reactor core damage. The risk of a similar failure from a fourth generation reactor design such as a lead-cooled fast reactor is near-negligible. <a href="http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,2050039-1,00.html">These reactors can also breeder reactors that are much smaller and compact than light water reactors and require much less fuel. In these reactors liquid lead is used to cool the reactor and transfer heat instead of water.</a> These reactors can not produce enough heat to vaporize the lead and cause an explosion. If there is a fuel leak the escaped lead solution will quickly solidify. A lead-cooled fast reactor that can produce enough power for 17,000 households and the fuel needed to run it for over a decade can be the size of a household refrigerator (the equipment to control and monitor the reactor would be the size of a small factory) and kept underground and covered by enough steel and reinforced concrete to contain any failure.</li>
    <li><strong>Cost:</strong> Nuclear power is the cheapest clean energy source and is cost competitive with fossil fuels. <a href="http://www.energy.ca.gov/2007publications/CEC-200-2007-011/CEC-200-2007-011-SD.PDF">According to the California Energy Commission</a> without subsidies nuclear power costs 7.7 cents per kilowatt hour. Coal without subsidies costs 7.4 cents per kilowatt hour. Natural gas and oil cost more than nuclear without subsidies.</li>
</ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americanlungassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americanlungassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/costnuclear" class="p-category" rel="tag">#costnuclear</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westinghouseelectric" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westinghouseelectric</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#americanlungassociation</category>
      <category>#costnuclear</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westinghouseelectric</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signatures Being Collected for an Initiative to Legalize Marijuana in Arizona</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/signatures-being-collected-for-an-initiative-to-legalize-marijuana-in</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/signatures-being-collected-for-an-initiative-to-legalize-marijuana-in</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2013 21:07:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There is a initiative petition in Arizona to legalize marijuana.Its full text can be found on the website of Safer Arizona, the group organizing the initiative. <a href="http://legalizeaz.com/"></a><a href="http://legalizeaz.com/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>legalizeaz.com/<wbr></wbr></a> has a list of locations where signatures are being collected. I have already had the opportunity to sign it</p>

<p><a href="http://www.azcentral.com/news/politics/articles/20130612personal-experience-spurs-effort-legalize-pot-recreational-use.html">From an article in the <em>Arizona Republic</em> on the the initiative.</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Dennis Bohlke, the 59-year-old computer programmer who is leading the effort, said the Safer Arizona initiative is modeled after Colorado’s newly enacted law, which taxes and regulates marijuana.</p>

<p>“The intent of the initiative is to legalize marijuana in Arizona and to treat it as we treat alcohol,” said Bohlke.</p>

<p>The effort would amend the state Constitution to allow people 18 and older “to consume or possess limited amounts” of marijuana. The initiative would allow state officials to license grow facilities, marijuana stores and other facilities.</p>

<p>The initiative needs 259,213 valid signatures by July 3, 2014, to qualify for the November 2014 ballot.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/arizonarepublic" class="p-category" rel="tag">#arizonarepublic</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/dennisbohlke" class="p-category" rel="tag">#dennisbohlke</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/saferarizona" class="p-category" rel="tag">#saferarizona</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#arizonarepublic</category>
      <category>#dennisbohlke</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#saferarizona</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-funding Energy Consumption: A Proposal to Encourage Energy Efficiency of Consumer Products</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/pre-funding-energy-consumption-a-proposal-to-encourage-energy-efficiency-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/pre-funding-energy-consumption-a-proposal-to-encourage-energy-efficiency-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 21:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It is clear that there is much that we can do to improve the energy efficiency of our economy. However, the main reason why these options are not deployed is consumers are unable to price and evaluate the future energy consumption of the products that they buy. Here I will propose a method of pre-funding energy consumption of consumer products. Under my proposal manufacturers of consumer, business and industrial electronics and appliances would be required to make an energy deposit based on the future energy consumption of their products. This deposit will be equal to the cost of the energy that the typical user of the product would pay over a typical product lifetime. The consumer could then redeem this energy deposit when they buy electricity or fuel.This proposal would provide consumers a clear signal of the value of the future energy consumption of their purchases. This is because the energy consumption would be part of the cost of purchase. The effect of this proposal on the pocketbooks of consumers would be minimal because the cost of the energy deposit would be rebated dollar for dollar to the consumer's future energy consumption.If consumers buy more efficient products as a result of this program then they will on the whole save money.Unlike alternatives, my proposal is a market-based way of encouraging energy efficiency. It works by making markets more efficient instead of telling consumers what they can buy. As far as I can tell no one has proposed this idea before. This blog post gives an overview of the justifications for this program. In later posts I will go deeper into these issues and provide more details on how pre-funding energy consumption would work.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The potential scale of energy efficiency improvements that can be made in the United States is vast. The United States is much less efficient in its energy usage than other industrialized nations. <a href="http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/EG.USE.PCAP.KG.OE">According to the World Bank,</a> the average American uses about 300.91 GJ (83586 KWH) of energy per year. For comparison, the average resident of France uses a little over half that or 169.28 GJ per year.The following map depicts the differences of energy consumption between different countries.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_490" align="alignnone" width="530"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Energy-consumption-per-capita-2003.png"></a> Map Via Wikipedia and licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license.[/caption]</p>

<p>It is possible that America could attain this type of energy efficiency in two decades.</p>

<p>Why haven't we achieved a more efficient economy already? One important reason is that consumers have imperfect information about energy usage.When buying a product consumers often have little knowledge about which is more energy efficient. Even when the energy usage of a product is labeled, it is difficult for a typical person to quantify this into a long term cost of ownership. How many consumers check how much money a 60 watt light-bulb will cost to run? How many even know how to conduct these calculations? Most likely very few. To run efficiently markets require consumers to have good information on what they are purchasing and how the product compares to alternatives. My proposal will solve this issue. The future cost of energy will be made immediately known to the consumer because it will show up on the price tag.The guesswork that consumers have to do to compare energy efficiency will be eliminated. A strong source of bias and inefficiency in the marketplace will be fixed.</p>

<p>My proposal is different than others which have been previously made as it relies on giving consumers and businesses a market signal without supporting particular options on the market. Consumers are allowed to apply other information they have and their knowledge of their exact circumstances to their product decisions. While the government should certainly use multiple methods to encourage energy efficiency my proposal may be best suited to form the core of an energy efficiency policy because of its market-based nature. Regulations that ban certain products act by taking choose away from consumers. When the government subsides a type of product it may be picking favorites, even when an even more cost effective energy efficiency option may be available.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/france" class="p-category" rel="tag">#france</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/kwh" class="p-category" rel="tag">#kwh</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mapviawikipedia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mapviawikipedia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worldbank" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worldbank</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#france</category>
      <category>#kwh</category>
      <category>#mapviawikipedia</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#worldbank</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
