<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23westerneuropean</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23westerneuropean&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Land Use is a Major Underappreciated Element of Environmental Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/land-use-is-a-major-underappreciated-element-of-environmental-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/land-use-is-a-major-underappreciated-element-of-environmental-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 03:27:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><span style="font-size: 12pt;"> The extent to which land use is an important factor in environmental policy is heavily unappreciated. It is as likely to be a major future environmental issue and is likely to be as destructive as other major issues, like climate change. Major developed countries of the world are on a massively unsustainable track of their land use regards to agriculture and other major sources of land use. Major adjustments in these economies will have to be made sooner or later. There is simply not enough land available on earth to sustain the current consumption patterns of the typical American, or the typical Western European. What cannot continue will not continue. Things will have to change one way or another. The question in regards to land use is, the choice over if consumption will be changed in response to a very rapid crisis, or it will be changed gradually time to adjust to new conditions. And in the meantime, the large-scale overconsumption of land based resources results in major economic distortions, and causes critical resources like food to be overpriced for the rest of the world. Overconsumption of land produced resources also causes severe environmental damage such as species loss, deforestation, loss of culturally valuable natural sites, and feedbacks that result in increased climate change and other forms of pollution. But things like forests and fisheries, and other naturally bioproductive areas can be depleted in a way that damages their future production. We do not want to be in the situation where we have depleted a resource that will take generations to rebuild. And with things like species loss, once the environmental damage has been done it is impossible to repair. This is why action must be taken before there is a crisis. We must conserve our land resources. Energy is also another issue where land use plays a particularly unappreciated role. Most people take "sustainable energy" as meaning something largely synonymous with "does not emit CO2 pollution". However, this is necessary but not sufficient part of sustainable energy. There are plenty of energy sources that serve to seriously worsen the land use issue, even though they are nominally carbon neutral. <a href="https://www.theojones.name/why-biofuels-will-never-amount-to-a-substantial-proportion-of-future-world-energy-use/">As I discussed in yesterday's post on this blog</a>, biofuels are a particularly severe case of this. The land use issue is a major factor in why I am under the belief that the most sustainable energy source that can be deployed with current technology is nuclear energy, as it uses very little land.<br /></span> </p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westerneuropean" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westerneuropean</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westerneuropean</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
