<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23old&amp;_t=rss&amp;offset=30" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>On the Gender Pay Gap</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/on-the-gender-pay-gap</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/on-the-gender-pay-gap</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 04:52:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I think that a fraction of the 70% pay gap is due to direct discrimination (sexist employers deciding explicitly or implicitly that women are less valuable employees). Lets say, a 5%-10% lower pay due to discrimination. M<a href="http://consad.com/content/reports/Gender%20Wage%20Gap%20Final%20Report.pdf">ost of the pay gap seems to be factors exogenous to the labor market</a>  Ie. the reason that women are generally paid less is more that they never went into highly paid fields like IT, than active discrimination. The linked paper also finds other causes, such as a preference for benefits over wages among women. And exiting and re-entering the labor market due to child care.If there is direct wage discrimination (what most legislation aimed to reduce the pay gap targets) large enough to produce a 70% gap, then why aren't there quite a few businesses that prefer the (lower-paid) female workers?</p><p>Now, some of this may be due to a less direct form of sexism. I.e a belief that IT (or [insert highly paid field here]) isn't for women. Or a belief that child care is a thing for women. But businesses have little control over that type of thing. </p><p>I've seen quite a few people though claim that the whole 70% gap is due to direct discrimination. That seems as unlikely as the "there is no wage gap, only Zuul" claim of the Tea Party types.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/it" class="p-category" rel="tag">#it</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/teaparty" class="p-category" rel="tag">#teaparty</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#it</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#teaparty</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Demand Destruction"? More like "Grid Leeching"</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/demand-destruction-more-like-grid-leeching</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/demand-destruction-more-like-grid-leeching</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Slate did an article about <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/business/the_juice/2014/07/energy_efficiency_vs_demand_destruction_the_big_problem_facing_america_s.html">something called "Demand Destruction"</a>. They make it sound like something that is the result of people just switching over to home-produced electricity, thereby becoming independent of the grid and leaving the power company in the dust. In reality, truly off-grid systems are extremely rare -- and expensive at almost <a href="http://life.gaiam.com/article/whats-it-going-cost-me-go-solar">$3.20 a kilowatt hour</a> (mostly batteries and energy storage, commercial energy storage is much cheaper than home energy storage, but energy storage in general is quite expensive). The source of the problem is malformed renewable energy incentive laws that force power companies to pay</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1322" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1322" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o-300x178.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H</a>" width="300" height="178" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/e8B95H%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>all energy production an equal rate -- even if the energy is produced at an off-peak time that has little use. This enables a business model that I will call "Grid Leeching". This business model takes advantage of a simple fact. Electricity companies are required to pay and receive payment based on energy produced. But consumers don't want raw energy; they want power -- a constant flow of energy. energy is much cheaper to produce than power. Individuals and businesses buy cheap solar production systems that are designed to barf large amounts of off-peak energy on to the grid. The electricity company is required to pay full price for this energy. The grid leechers then get to use the power grid for their actual power needs practically free of charge. These cheap solar systems can sell for as little as $2 a watt average production or about the equivalent to 15 cents a kilowatt hour. Around this has developed a little market of companies that specialize in attaching leeches to the grid. One of these profiled is SolarCity, which rents out these cheap solar systems. This is very destructive to the grid. The only way that a electricity company can make up for this type of thing is to run load-following power plants -- usually natural gas -- in an inefficient, and rapidily fluctuating way. This happens while the leechers are drawing power while not paying anything on the net. The leechers only give back low quality, off-peak energy.</p>

<p>What can be done about this. It is simple: fluctuate energy charges, and energy production payouts based on the current demand. When there is little energy demand, pay the producers of energy less (and charge the consumers less). When energy demand is high, pay producers more and charge consumers more. Charge a flat monthly fee for a connection to the grid (based on the maximum current the user is allowed to draw). This will put the grid leechers out of business, because their core business model of dumping energy on the grid at low-demand times will no longer work. This will encourage companies to produce constant power (or even better, demand following energy), and will encourage consumers to modulate their energy usage during peak demand times. This may reduce the incentives for renewable energy deployment. However, the current model encourages the formation of grid leechers, instead of actually productive renewable energy firms. Furthermore, it puts nuclear energy (one of the best sources of baseload power) at a disadvantage. Sustainable energy should be directly subsidized at very large levels.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material Efficiency versus Economic Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/material-efficiency-versus-economic-efficiency</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/material-efficiency-versus-economic-efficiency</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 08:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There is a large difference between how scientists/engineers and economists/business leaders about how efficiency in the economy is viewed. Scientists tend to look at efficiency as minimizing the materials and labor needed to reach a tangible outcome (such as an increase in life expectancy, or general well being). I will call this material efficiency  However, economists tend to look at efficiency as maximizing the goods and services produced in the economy -- even if the production is just for the churn of it and has minimal impact on outcomes.[caption id="attachment_1452" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8196207581_4c583b3543_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8196207581_4c583b3543_o-300x214.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user  Pavel P. &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>dugGXP</a>" width="300" height="214" class="size-medium wp-image-1452" /&gt; Image via Flickr user  Pavel P.<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/dugGXP%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>dugGXP[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a> Efficiency to an economist is about maximizing GDP. To a scientist GDP (the sum of all goods and services produced in the economy) is effectively the cost of producing the desired outcomes. As I will discuss  later this is very different from the perspective of some hard line environmentalists who beleive that the economy is over-grown and needs to be pruned down to shape. <a href="http://www.c2.com/cgi/wiki?EconomicEfficiencyIsNotEngineeringEfficiency">An article describes this difference as follows:</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In Engineering, a design or process is efficient if it maximizes the amount of work done, while minimizing the resources used (raw materials, time, labor, fuel, etc). An efficient design should do everything it is designed for, and if possible eliminate the need for other devices or processes, while avoiding any unnecessary steps or equipment. Cost is only an issue to the extent that money is itself a resource, and often a limiting one. An important engineering goal is to produce a solution that is lasting; if a product can be maintained indefinitely, and need not be replaced, it is especially esteemed.  <br />In Microeconomics, a company is efficient if it returns the greatest profit in the shortest amount of time, and continues to do so indefinitely. All other considerations are irrelevant; maximizing the bottom line is the only yardstick. This contradicts the Engineering definition in that a sensible manager can and should be ready to throw vast amounts of cheap resources into a project, if it means that greater revenue is made as a result.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When scientists obtain management of an industry material efficiency is generally focused on, while when economists and business types are in charge economic efficiency is emphasized. This has strong implications in many industries. From a strict GDP maximizing perspective the U.S health-care system is quite "efficient", i.e it produces over 15% of the nation's GDP. However, it does not do as well at more tangible measures -- such as improvements in health outcomes. In European health care systems, where scientists have more say in the management of the system the health care system tends to produce less of the GDP (ie. lower economic efficiency), but produces better real world outcomes for fewer resources (ie. better material efficiency). </p>

<p>In the software industry, similar issues come up. The opensource community (which is ran mostly by computer scientists, and software engineers)  tends to favor less profitable development methodologies that reduce profit. For example, the licencing found in this community has vastly more provisions for code reuse. The code is licensed to anyone under terms that allow anyone to make use of it. This ability to reuse reduces the labor required (improved material efficiency), but this also eliminates much of the profit of the companies, and makes it hard to sell the software (reduced economic efficiency).</p>

<p>This focus on material efficiency is very different from the hardline environmentalist "degrowth" perspective. In regards to a material efficiency outlook economic output is not considered a bad, just not something that should be an explicit target. Increased economic growth should be favored when it produces improved real world outcomes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Economy Separate From the Political System</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-the-economy-separate-from-the-political-system</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-the-economy-separate-from-the-political-system</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 13:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In this post I will argue that the economy is fundamentally part of the political system and not some separate thing. By extension I will argue that economics should not be considered a separate field but instead  should be considered as part of the theory of politics and political science. <a href="http://economics.about.com/od/economics-basics/a/What-Is-Economics.htm">Lets start with looking at a common definition of economics. </a>  Emphasis added. [caption id="attachment_1454" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/4744388119_4afba167a4_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/4744388119_4afba167a4_o-300x199.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user  JD Hancock &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8efeia</a>" width="300" height="199" class="size-medium wp-image-1454" /&gt; Image via Flickr user  JD Hancock<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/8efeia%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8efeia[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Simply, and perhaps surprisingly put,<strong> economics is the study of scarcity</strong>. Resources are limited, and every society wants to figure out how to allocate its resources for maximum benefit. The field of economics serves in large part to help answer this resource allocation question. Economists study topics such as:  <br />How prices and quantities of items are determined in market economies  <br />How much value markets create for society  <br />How taxes and regulation affect economic value  <br />Why some goods and services are under-supplied in a market economy  <br />How firms compete and maximize profit  <br />How households decide what to consume, how much to save, and how much to work (or, more generally, how people respond to incentives)  <br />Why some economies grow faster than others  <br />What effect monetary and fiscal policy has on economic well-being  <br />How interest rates are determined</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This definition argues that the allocation of goods under scarcity is the defining factor of economics, and by extension the difference between the general political system and the economy. However, all institutions work to allocate goods under scarcity. Without scarcity there would be no need for a government and anarchism would be a functioning system. Politics is about scarcity as much as economics. Likewise the examples used in the quoted section all assume some kind of market existing outside of the government and political system. But the market is fundamentally a creature of this system. The government decides how contracts will be made (if you think that there is some kind of natural contract law look at how much this law has varied between societies over history).The government sets the broad outlines of what is sold, it sets the question of who has the authority to make decisions within the businesses in the market. The government sets the outlines of property rights, and determines what can be owned, and how this ownership can be obtained. It creates the currency system. Markets cannot exist in a stable fashion without governments. Governments have shaped every economic intuitions. There is no economy or set of economic institutions that is separate from the political system as a whole. There is no distinction between economics and the study of the political system as a whole.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'm Going to Start the 500 Word Writing Challenge For My Blog</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/im-going-to-start-the-500-word-writing-challenge-for</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/im-going-to-start-the-500-word-writing-challenge-for</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 13:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I'm going to write at least 500 words every day for this blog as part of the 500 Word Writing Challenge. <br /><a href="http://goinswriter.com/my500words/"></a><a href="http://goinswriter.com/my500words/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>goinswriter.com/<wbr></wbr>my500words/<wbr></wbr></a></p><blockquote>
<p>The rules:  <br />Write 500 words per day, every day during the month of January.  <br />You can write more if you want, but 500 words is the minimum.  <br />Don’t edit. Just write.  <br />If you miss a day, pick up where you left off. Don’t make up for lost days.  <br />Encourage, don’t criticize (unless explicitly invited to do so).  <br />Blogging counts, but email does not.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/wordwritingchallenge" class="p-category" rel="tag">#wordwritingchallenge</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#wordwritingchallenge</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Appoints New CEO</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mozilla-appoints-new-ceo</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mozilla-appoints-new-ceo</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 13:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>This happened: <br /><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2014/07/mozilla-confirms-interim-ceo-as-new-top-hire/"></a><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2014/07/mozilla-confirms-interim-ceo-as-new-top-hire/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>business/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>mozilla-confirms-interim-ceo-as-new-top-hire/<wbr></wbr></a> <br /></p><blockquote>
<p>On Monday, the Mozilla Corporation announced that its last-minute April hire for interim CEO, Chris Beard, has been permanently appointed to the position. Mozilla Executive Chairwoman Mitchell Baker confirmed the news in a blog post, stating that "the board has reviewed many internal and external candidates—and no one we met was a better fit."</p>

<p>Beard's Mozilla tenure began in 2004 and saw him eventually rise to chief innovation and chief marketing officer. He left the company in 2013 to become an "executive in residence" at Greylock Partners, an investment firm with a heavy focus on tech companies. His return to Mozilla in April came on the heels of Brendan Eich's controversial hire to the CEO position, which ended with Eich's resignation that month.</p>
</blockquote><p>Its idiotic to make decisions about the management of a company based on the basis of political stuff that has little to do with the running of the company. Based pretty much on the opinion of people writing flamage on Tumblr, Mozilla replaced one of the founders of the company, a person with wide experience in the firm's core competency -- creating web browsers -- with a marketing type based solely on a donation to a political campaign in 2008. This is utter insanity. I believe that this decision will be a future business school case  study on why it is a good idea to keep personal politics out of the running of a company. The new CEO's current tenure has already shown that he is an inferior candidate. As interim CEO Beard has doubled down on multiple bad decisions by expanding the company's phone project and attempting to enter the computer market by creating a laptop. Beard is attempting to run the company like a regular software company. But the world of open source is different. The open source world already suffers from a high degree of market fragmentation and the actions of the new management of Mozilla will only make matters worse. Beard's decision to add Digital Rights Management systems to the Firefox browser has widely alienated the Linux community. The decision to manafucture a phone puts them in open warfare with many companies with deeper pockets -- particularly Microsoft and Google. It also takes Mozilla far from areas where it has a history of product development. Considering the fact that the Firefox Phone has no user or developer base it has no chance on the market. It is in the same price range as Microsoft's low end phones, and it is also in direct competition with the various Chinese landfill Androids that are on the market. They have simply no serious hope of winning this battle. Their decision to make a Chromebook competitor is similarly boneheaded.  They will be competing with dozens of established computer manufacturers when they have no experience in this area. </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/brendaneich" class="p-category" rel="tag">#brendaneich</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ceo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ceo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/digitalrightsmanagement" class="p-category" rel="tag">#digitalrightsmanagement</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/firefoxphone" class="p-category" rel="tag">#firefoxphone</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#brendaneich</category>
      <category>#ceo</category>
      <category>#digitalrightsmanagement</category>
      <category>#firefoxphone</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Future of the Blog Post Series on Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-future-of-the-blog-post-series-on-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-future-of-the-blog-post-series-on-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 12:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I am creating a ebook on the subject of <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/" title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics">the blog post series</a>. When it is done (should be in less than a month), I will gradually complete the rest of the blog post series based on the content in that book.  I will do a post in the series every other week once the book is done.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conservative Groups Create Facebook Clone</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/conservative-groups-create-facebook-clone</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/conservative-groups-create-facebook-clone</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 12:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>From <a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/reaganbook-facebook-for-patriots"></a><a href="http://talkingpointsmemo.com/livewire/reaganbook-facebook-for-patriots">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>talkingpointsmemo.com/<wbr></wbr>livewire/<wbr></wbr>reaganbook-facebook-for-patriots</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The president of conservative pro-family group Faith2Action last weekend announced the pre-launch of ReaganBook, a social networking site described as "the Facebook for patriots"</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I will say that Facebook is pretty loose with the banhammer and bans both conservative and liberal groups for BS reasons. Its moderation policies seem pretty inconsistent from what I've heard, and they rely on automated systems for a lot of it. For some pages, just getting a large number of people reporting a status of yours can get you banned by a computer. But, its a system-wide issue and doesn't seem to be just a thing that targets conservatives.</p>

<p>My solution to this issue would be to <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140403093812/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>30/<wbr></wbr>ideal-distributed-social-networking-application-look-like/<wbr></wbr></a>" title="What Would the Ideal Distributed Social Networking Application Look Like?"&gt;create a decentralized social network. Facebook has complete control over their system and can abuse that control. But social networking systems are generally natural monopolies and therefore different competing networks can not remain in stable competition.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bs" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bs</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bs</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don't Use Word Processors</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/i-dont-use-word-processors</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/i-dont-use-word-processors</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 20:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I don't use standard WYSIWYG type word processors when it is possible to avoid them. Instead I use typesetting systems like LATEX for long documents, and plain ANSI text for shorter documents. This has three huge benefits </p><p>1) Separation between layout and content. With a typesetting program, you just write the text and the program takes care of formatting it. <br />
2)Follows the UNIX philosophy. The LATEX + Typesetting system closely follows the core rule of the UNIX philosophy "<em>This is the Unix philosophy: Write programs that do one thing and do it well. Write programs to work together. Write programs to handle text streams, because that is a universal interface.</em>" The core of TEX is extremely small and the entire LATEX system is formed out of a set of small scripts that are built upon this. The system is extremely modular and flexible. These programs are driven by the command line. While it is impossible to use a command driven system without first learining it, it gives vast power to the user <br />
3)Flexibility. Due to the modular and flexible nature of LATEX the system can do almost anything. Want to properly format math equations? Sure.  Want to create a circut diagram? There is a package for that? Want to format a book so it is ready to go for Amazon's CreateSpace system?<a href="https://github.com/aginiewicz/createspace"> A package just for that</a> is ready to go. I could name many other examples. This is only made possible by the code driven modular nature of a typesetting type system. <br />
4) Plain text is the universal system. Almost every operating system written since the 70s can edit and view plain text files. LATEX is just a plain text file of markup code.So, anything could view a document written in LATEX. Try that with Libreoffice or MS Word. </p><p>The following article is written by someone with a similar opinion to me on this. It mostly focuses on the layout versus content issue. <br /><a href="http://ricardo.ecn.wfu.edu/~cottrell/wp.html"></a><a href="http://ricardo.ecn.wfu.edu/~cottrell/wp.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ricardo.ecn.wfu.edu/<wbr></wbr>~cottrell/<wbr></wbr>wp.html</a></p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ansi" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ansi</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/latex" class="p-category" rel="tag">#latex</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unix" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unix</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/wysiwyg" class="p-category" rel="tag">#wysiwyg</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#ansi</category>
      <category>#latex</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unix</category>
      <category>#wysiwyg</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economics and Externalities</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/economics-and-externalities</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/economics-and-externalities</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 17:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I will discuss the economics of externalities. An externality is a cost of producing something that is not materialized in the price charged (or any other cost) to a willing participant in that transaction. This is problematic because the cost of a thing is highly tied to the level of demand for it. In general, when the cost of something is lower then people buy more of it. When, in the case of an externality, a large part of the cost of something is on other people then the consumers will bear less than the full cost of that thing and will therefore want to buy more of it than is generally socially desirable. Climate change, of course produces an externality. Because a large number of the costs of fossil fuels are on third parties consumers will buy more of these fuels than is desirable, and favor these fuels over alternatives to an extent that is unmerited. Of course, in the real world things are usually not as simple as a simple case where we can place the full weight of the blame for the externality-producing condition on a single person.Even on the climate change issue we can come up with situations where people other than polluters are to blame for some impacts. Take for instance the case of someone who purchases a house in an area that is becoming increasingly flood prone due to climate change, and is flooded out due to that risk. It it clear that this person experienced an externality due to the greenhouse gas pollution, but it is also arguable that the home-buyer was responsible for part of this harm. Policy makers will have to sort out this type of issue when making climate policy. But despite this objection, the externality model is still a good way to theorize about the effects of climate change. </p><p>The government has multiple ways to adjust individual intensives to deal with externalities problem. It could pass a regulation that bans a externality-producing activity. Or it could pass a tax on the activity. The tax could raise the cost of the activity, thereby bringing its paid cost in line with its true cost. It could do a cap and trade type regulation whereby a limit is set on the amount of the activity allowed, and the permits to do the activity are auctioned off. The government could also subsidize the alternative's to the activity. </p><p>The regulation method is at the core of command and control type responses to climate change. These have the possibility of being relativity egalitarian in their distributional impacts. But they also have the possibility of being the most inefficient. These methods mandate the same abatement methods uniformly, and fail to encourage other resolutions to climate change. Local laws and urban planning changes will have a strong role in mitigating climate change. I also think that governments should pass regulations that commit to the shutdown of polluting industries. Additionally, direct regulation and civil litigation is particularly effective at targeting industries that are in countries that do not have an effective climate policy.  I will discuss the role that I think direct regulation should have in an energy policy in an later post.</p><p>The taxing method in the climate change world is known as a carbon tax. It has the benefit of allowing free consumer choice while still providing for a strong incentive to switch. A tax works by directly increasing the cost of the extenality-producing pollution. This is in order to make the effective cost that consumers face when buying products equal to the real cost of the polluting energy involved. Carbon taxes provide incentive to reduce pollution, while still allowing for individual choice. The huge counter argument to a climate policy that relies on carbon taxes is the fact that they provide no guarantee that the CO2 emissions will fall to their target level. This is problematic because the optimal level of CO2 emissions is effectively zero.</p><p>A related option to a carbon tax is a cap and trade program. In a cap and trade system a finite number of permits to pollute are distributed. This provides a stable emissions reduction at the expense of stability of the price of carbon.  Because they target the level of CO2 emissions, not the price of these emissions they have the benefit of being more responsive to economic conditions. If there is high inflation, the real/effective carbon tax will be reduced because the money used to pay the tax is worth less, but with a cap and trade the price will quickly adjust.  Distributing the permits is also a design issue for cap and trade programs. Many cap and trade programs distribute the credits to firms based on past pollution. I believe that this is generally a bad idea and instead the permits should just be auctioned off. Both cap and trade programs and carbon taxes have potential distributional issues. That is, without any attempt to mitigate their effects they have the potential to effect the poor more than the wealthy. </p><p>Subsidies work by reducing the cost of alternatives to the externalities. In regards the the climate change issue the government can fund investment in  clean energy sources, and in energy conservation methods. The reduction of cost of alternative energies will cause consumers to switch over to them. Subsidies have strong distributional benefits, while still allowing more consumer choice is designed right.However, they can also cause overconsumption of energy. Subsidizes can also include methods such as public works projects that build infrastructure. As I will discuss further in the section on French investment in nuclear energy,  subsidizes have one huge advantage. They can overcome the problems of imperfect information and short term bias in investment. Companies are often under pressure to bring forth a short term profit, and this will often mean that they will forgo long-term investments that will cost more in the short run, but bring longer run benefits. Government subsidy policy can overcome this issue and can be used to encourage the longer term investment. Companies also face a high degree of risk due to their lack of knowledge. Some investments have a high possible return, but a high risk. Because companies can not afford a large loss, they will be risk adverse and will forgo high-risk, high-return investments. Government policy can change this. Imperfect information also bites companies in a different way. The profitability of an investment -- particularly in the energy world -- can strongly depend on what the competitors of a company are doing. There are cases where companies can compete in an mutually destructive way, or an uncoordinated way. Government subsidy policy and indirect planning can provide a way to coordinate the actions of firms. This will improve the efficiency of markets. </p><p>In a more controversial economic note I will discuss my opinions on how inequality effects the efficiency of markets. Of course, there are many economists that would disagree with what I am about to say in this paragraph. Purely market based programs have one Achilles' Heel though. Their economic efficiency is dependent on the assumption that monetary value (the amount of money that someone would give up for a benefit) is equal to the associated change in well being. Economists call this a linear welfare function -- with "welfare" in this circumstance referring to well being. This is a questionable assumption. In reality, the relation between market efficiency in the since that advocates of a market-based solution to global warming discuss, and the real welfare of the populace are often in conflict. This conflict is particularly strong when there is high inequality in the economic system.This economic inequality makes prices into something that depends as much on ability to pay as actual need. I also would argue that all preferences are not equal. An wealthy person's preference to convert grains into biofuels to save money on fuel is of much lower value than the preference of a poor person to eat the grains. In regards to how resources should be distributed, my thinking is along the line of the "difference principle" that has been often discussed in the political philosophy literature -- the well worst off groups in society should be maximized, even if this means reduced over all economic production. This factor means that countries who want to conduct an effective climate change policy will also need to enact anti-poverty measures along with their climate change mitigation policy.  Additionally, because global inequality is even higher than the level of inequality that prevails within nations there will necessarily be a role for command and control regulation, and indirect economic planning through subsidizes. Without these more hands on policies the world's poor will face severe harms from the climate change mitigation policies that should help them. Additionally, the effects that inequality has on market efficiency will mean that a much more rapid climate change policy will be needed than what would be justified by a purely economic cost benefit analysis. In reality a sustainable energy plan would need to use all four of the methods of changing incentives. All of these methods have their benefits in some circumstances. </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/achillesheel" class="p-category" rel="tag">#achillesheel</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#achillesheel</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
