<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23bt</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23bt&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why give cranks the benefit of the doubt?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-give-cranks-the-benefit-of-the-doubt</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-give-cranks-the-benefit-of-the-doubt</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 06:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In issues like the "debate" over GMOs I've seen a pattern where extreme charity is given to the arguments of the antiscience side. Let's take a person who thinks GMOs cause health issues clearly, by the plain language of how he phrases things indicates that he thinks that method of genetic modification introduces the health risk. It's a blatantly absurd position. Genetic modification is a method to synthesize compounds. A chemical compound is the same thing the matter how it was synthesized. BT toxin from a GMO corn plant is unequivocally the exact same compound is BT toxin collected from <em>B. thuringiensis </em>bacteria. This is completely without doubt. For a chemical that have "memory" of how it was synthesized or its past would contradict a vast swath of physics, chemistry, and biology. However, it is quite common this type of debate for the other side to rephrase his argument away from the plain language of it but towards a more plausible but different argument. Those scientifically literate people will tend to interpret the statement not as what its plain language says of compounds having "memory" but will instead interpret it as some kind of a claim at BT toxin itself is dangerous. (Which is itself an extremely doubtful claim that contradict quite a bit of scientific research, and known mechanism of how the toxin works against insects) Of course, this cannot be what most of the GMO health risk types mean, as they have no objection to the use of <em>B. thuringiensis </em>bacteria and the toxin it produces in organic agriculture. They must mean the prime face absurd claim that chemical compounds remember their past. Why should anyone do this charitable interpretation of what they are saying? Me? I am now at the point where I assume people exposing crank viewpoints mean what they say and say what they mean. If you say something that's clearly in contradiction with a large swath of science, I'm going to assume very vastly ignorant,or  are engaging in outright science denialism. I think, reason why a lot of people reinterpret what crackpots have to say, is because the claims of antiscience types are so absurd they immediately assume no one could seriously mean them. But, there are vastly ignorant or deluded people out there. There are people who put their preconceptions before any reasonable logic. There are people who don't understand the basics of chemistry and physics. There are Luddite types that have an extreme knee-jerk opposition to technology. It's time to take them seriously.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bt</category>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
