<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23newdeal</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23newdeal&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal of America</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-ideal-of-america-1</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-ideal-of-america-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <div title="Page 1">
<p>[caption id="attachment_317" align="alignright" width="203"] Unveiling of the Statue of Liberty Enlightening the World (1886) by Edward Moran[/caption]</p>

<p>What are the values that have made America and Americans different? An American can be of any race, creed, religion, philosophy, or ethnicity. The United States has never been a country of one religious or ethnic group, and Americans have many diverse political philosophies. The ideal of America has been that of a country where immigrants from throughout the world could come and make a good life and where Americans from all socioeconomic backgrounds could move up the economic ladder, or at the least attain a good education and provide for themselves and their families if they work hard. America has always been a melting pot and a nation of diversity. America is a home for persons of all types­­ there is no one stereotypical real American.</p>

<p>Americans enjoy freedom of speech and religion and live under a legal system that protects these basic individual rights. What makes a real American is the strong belief in these values and the freedoms that come with being a citizen of the United States, as well as respect for those values and freedoms. The United States was founded to be a country where the most famous lines of the Declaration of Independence -- a document ratified 237 years ago today -- ring true, where “<em>We hold these truths to be self­ evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>America was founded to be a nation of laws, not men, where there would never be a European­style aristocracy and where all were equal in rights and opportunity. These values are inherently both communal and individual as both liberty and equality involve the relations between individuals to other individuals in society. Because of this, the power of community has been at the heart of what makes America great. While these values and hopes have never been fully implemented, and there are still great inequities in American society, these values form the heart and soul of America and its people.</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>The fact that America is a nation of diversity can be seen in where Americans have come from. There have been Americans that have come from almost all cultural groups in the world.</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. British Puritans and Pilgrims migrated to the New World for religious liberty and settled in New England and founded the colonies of Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Connecticut. Quaker immigrants settled Pennsylvania looking for religious freedom. Pennsylvania after Quaker settlement was the first colony to provide religious freedom to all and soon became home to individuals of many religions. The Dutch founded what is now New York City, but this land was eventually absorbed into the British Empire. New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Delaware attracted many Irish, German and Scandinavian immigrants. By 1790 almost one half of the American population was not of British ancestry. Restrictions on immigration and importation of goods imposed by the British were a significant cause of the American Revolution. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “<em>He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither</em>... “</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>After independence, the United States immigration laws were extremely permissive. The Naturalization Act of 1790, which was the first U. S. immigration law, placed no restrictions on immigration and allowed free whites to obtain citizenship after two years of residency in the United States. In the 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had a free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, and immigrants from Asia. This migration was its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. The inscription on the Statue of Liberty greeted the immigrants entering the country through Ellis Island with the following poem written by Emma Lazarus and titled The New Colossus. It summed up America's values toward immigrants,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Not like the brazen giant of Greek fame, With conquering limbs astride from land to land; Here at our sea­washed, sunset gates shall stand A mighty woman with a torch, whose flame Is the imprisoned lightning, and her name Mother of Exiles. From her beacon­ hand Glows world­ wide welcome; her mild eyes command The air-­bridged harbor that twin cities frame. 'Keep, ancient lands, your storied pomp!' cries she With silent lips. 'Give me your tired, your poor, Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free, The wretched refuse of your teeming shore. Send these, the homeless, tempest ­tossed to me, I lift my lamp beside the golden door!'”</p>
</blockquote><div title="Page 3">
<p>America was open to immigrants throughout the world and was a nation of opportunities. It is clear that this history has made the United States a nation of diversity created by immigrants from all over the world. This American history of immigration is what makes being American not about what religious or ethnic group you are part of, but about the American values of liberty and equality that are so eloquently summed up by The New Colossus. American values have always been to create a nation where people from throughout the world could come to experience liberty and opportunity. What makes an American is therefore belief in these values, the values that have attracted and brought so many immigrants to the United States.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The core values of America that shape and created the nation are liberty and equality. These values have drawn immigrants to the nation since the Puritans, Pilgrims and Quakers first set foot in the New World looking for religious liberty. It is these values that define what being an American is and form the basis of the American community. America was founded to be a place where no king could arbitrarily interfere with basic liberties. Freedom and equality come hand in hand and cannot exist without each other.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>Freedom in the American community means not being dominated over, and living in a community with other citizens that are equal in rights and opportunities. American poet and author Walt Whitman defined freedom as follows, “<em>Freedom --­ to walk free and own no superior.</em>“ and said this of being a citizen of America, “<em>Neither a servant nor a master am I</em>.” These values have motivated American activists throughout the nation's history to fight for what is right and to fight to bring liberty and equal opportunity to all.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The founders of the United States saw freedom and equality as inherently linked. Excessive inequality could result in aristocracy and would be corrosive to society and freedom. But freedom was inherently linked with accepting that all men are created equal. Alexis de Tocqueville, a famous French author who wrote about the early United States, said, “<em>Grant me thirty years of equal division of inheritances and a free press, and I will provide you with a republic.</em>” In the Federalist #10, James Madison stated that “<em>the most common and durable source of factions has been the various and unequal distribution of property. Those who hold and those who are without property have ever formed distinct interests in society.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 4">
<p>The struggle for freedom and equality for all has defined the United States throughout its history and defines what it means to be an American. The biggest questions in American history have been “what is liberty?” and “what is the proper relation between liberty and order?” and the biggest struggles in American history have involved expanding freedom and equality. The greatest victories in these struggles have come in four waves. The first wave of this struggle came with the Revolutionary War and the formation of the new United States government. The second wave of the American struggle for freedom for all came with the U.S Civil War and its aftermath. The third wave of this struggle came with the Great Depression, the New Deal and the Second World War and its aftermath. The fourth wave was the Civil Rights Movement. The Declaration of Independence was the statement of the core values of America and its people. However, the realization that “<em>all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights</em>” came throughout the history of the United States and is still not entirely complete. The Declaration of Independence stated that the role of government ought to be to protect these rights and that a just government is based around the consent of the governed. After independence, American society became the closest in existence to a society without an aristocracy. A government was created that was the closest thing to a republic of laws, not men, that existed in the world. About a decade after the end of the revolution, a constitution was ratified that created a new national government for the United States. In its Preamble the Constitution stated its purpose as follows, “<em>to form a more perfect Union, establish Justice, insure domestic Tranquility, provide for the common defense, promote the general Welfare, and secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity.</em>” Shortly thereafter, a second great American document was created, the Bill of Rights. This document protected many fundamental rights from government violation. Through many years of existence and legal interpretation, the Bill of Rights became a great American document that has played a large role in determining the nature of American freedom and liberty and has been at the heart of the shared American historical and cultural heritage. These documents are part of what makes America what it is and Americans who they are.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The history of the Civil War and reconstruction resulted in a great expansion of liberty, the end of slavery, and the expansion of the rights of citizenship to many Americans who did not receive those liberties before. The legal changes that happened during this period are most dramatically reflected in the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, which reads in part, “<em>No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</em>” The 14th Amendment's declaration that all are equal before the law put the Declaration of Independence's most famous value into the constitution. It stated that all Americans have rights that must be protected by law. Furthermore, the Civil War and its aftermath helped define what it means to be American by creating an American national identity. Americans were Americans first and foremost instead of residents of their states first and foremost.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The New Deal era and the aftermath of World War II brought a new era in the expansion of rights in the United States. During the New Deal, it was realized that liberty included certain economic rights and that protecting the liberty of the population included giving everyone economic opportunities. In a tradition that went back to the nation's founding, it was realized that excessive concentrations of wealth were harmful and made it difficult to maintain the conditions needed for freedom to continue. The Second World War and its aftermath saw the exportation of the American values of freedom for all to the rest of the world. During the war, President Franklin D. Roosevelt made his Four Freedoms speech in which he stated that freedom of speech, freedom of religion, freedom from fear, and freedom from want were human rights that ought to be protected for all persons everywhere in the world. This speech served to be an inspiration for the development of the United Nations after the war, and the expansion of human rights to everyone throughout the world. The civil rights movement that started in the 1950s expanded the horizons of American liberty and freedom. The formal racial segregation and discrimination of the Jim Crow era was ended and economic discrimination was reduced. Courts made important civil rights and civil liberties decisions that expanded liberty and equality for all. Economic programs such Lyndon Johnson's Great Society expanded opportunity and alleviated poverty. During the 1970s and 80s women's rights were established and expanded., in a large part due to court victories won by activists.</p>
<div title="Page 6"><div title="Page 6">America is a nation of diversity created by a history of immigration, a nation not made of any one cultural or religious group. This nation has been a place where people of all kinds came for a better life throughout its entire history. This has been true since even before U.S independence. From Quaker and Puritan immigrants looking for religious freedom, to the immigrants of Ellis Island to modern immigrants, people have come to America looking for freedom. America has been a nation of ideals and laws, not of men or aristocracy, throughout its history. These values of freedom and equality have inspired struggle for all of America's history. While these struggles have never created a perfect union, America has become more perfect and a greater home to the blessings of liberty over its history. What makes a real American is not simply who you are, but it is our shared values and the belief that you have the freedom and opportunity to become all that you want to be, as long as you don't violate the freedoms and liberties of others. It is this belief in liberty and equality for all that makes America great and makes being an American great. The constitution gives Americans certain rights and our freedom and liberty are guaranteed. But what makes an American a real American is the respect for these values and the respect for the struggle that secured these freedoms, as well as a determination to continue to protect and fight for these values.</div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/civilwar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#civilwar</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newdeal" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newdeal</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyorkcity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyorkcity</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#10</category>
      <category>#civilwar</category>
      <category>#newdeal</category>
      <category>#newyorkcity</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal of America</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-ideal-of-america</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-ideal-of-america</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 22:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <div title="Page 1">
<p>[caption id="attachment_317" align="alignright" width="203"] Unveiling of the Statue of Liberty Enlightening the World (1886) by Edward Moran[/caption]</p>

<p>What are the values that have made America and Americans different? An American can be of any race, creed, religion, philosophy, or ethnicity. The United States has never been a country of one religious or ethnic group, and Americans have many diverse political philosophies. The ideal of America has been that of a country where immigrants from throughout the world could come and make a good life and where Americans from all socioeconomic backgrounds could move up the economic ladder, or at the least attain a good education and provide for themselves and their families if they work hard. America has always been a melting pot and a nation of diversity. America is a home for persons of all types­­ there is no one stereotypical real American.</p>

<p>Americans enjoy freedom of speech and religion and live under a legal system that protects these basic individual rights. What makes a real American is the strong belief in these values and the freedoms that come with being a citizen of the United States, as well as respect for those values and freedoms. The United States was founded to be a country where the most famous lines of the Declaration of Independence -- a document ratified 237 years ago today -- ring true, where “<em>We hold these truths to be self­ evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>America was founded to be a nation of laws, not men, where there would never be a European­style aristocracy and where all were equal in rights and opportunity. These values are inherently both communal and individual as both liberty and equality involve the relations between individuals to other individuals in society. Because of this, the power of community has been at the heart of what makes America great. While these values and hopes have never been fully implemented, and there are still great inequities in American society, these values form the heart and soul of America and its people.</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>The fact that America is a nation of diversity can be seen in where Americans have come from. There have been Americans that have come from almost all cultural groups in the world.</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. British Puritans and Pilgrims migrated to the New World for religious liberty and settled in New England and founded the colonies of Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Connecticut. Quaker immigrants settled Pennsylvania looking for religious freedom. Pennsylvania after Quaker settlement was the first colony to provide religious freedom to all and soon became home to individuals of many religions. The Dutch founded what is now New York City, but this land was eventually absorbed into the British Empire. New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Delaware attracted many Irish, German and Scandinavian immigrants. By 1790 almost one half of the American population was not of British ancestry. Restrictions on immigration and importation of goods imposed by the British were a significant cause of the American Revolution. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “<em>He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither</em>... “</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>After independence, the United States immigration laws were extremely permissive. The Naturalization Act of 1790, which was the first U. S. immigration law, placed no restrictions on immigration and allowed free whites to obtain citizenship after two years of residency in the United States. In the 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had a free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, and immigrants from Asia. This migration was its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. The inscription on the Statue of Liberty greeted the immigrants entering the country through Ellis Island with the following poem written by Emma Lazarus and titled The New Colossus. It summed up America's values toward immigrants,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Not like the brazen giant of Greek fame, With conquering limbs astride from land to land; Here at our sea­washed, sunset gates shall stand A mighty woman with a torch, whose flame Is the imprisoned lightning, and her name Mother of Exiles. From her beacon­ hand Glows world­ wide welcome; her mild eyes command The air-­bridged harbor that twin cities frame. 'Keep, ancient lands, your storied pomp!' cries she With silent lips. 'Give me your tired, your poor, Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free, The wretched refuse of your teeming shore. Send these, the homeless, tempest ­tossed to me, I lift my lamp beside the golden door!'”</p>
</blockquote><div title="Page 3">
<p>America was open to immigrants throughout the world and was a nation of opportunities. It is clear that this history has made the United States a nation of diversity created by immigrants from all over the world. This American history of immigration is what makes being American not about what religious or ethnic group you are part of, but about the American values of liberty and equality that are so eloquently summed up by The New Colossus. American values have always been to create a nation where people from throughout the world could come to experience liberty and opportunity. What makes an American is therefore belief in these values, the values that have attracted and brought so many immigrants to the United States.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The core values of America that shape and created the nation are liberty and equality. These values have drawn immigrants to the nation since the Puritans, Pilgrims and Quakers first set foot in the New World looking for religious liberty. It is these values that define what being an American is and form the basis of the American community. America was founded to be a place where no king could arbitrarily interfere with basic liberties. Freedom and equality come hand in hand and cannot exist without each other.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>Freedom in the American community means not being dominated over, and living in a community with other citizens that are equal in rights and opportunities. American poet and author Walt Whitman defined freedom as follows, “<em>Freedom --­ to walk free and own no superior.</em>“ and said this of being a citizen of America, “<em>Neither a servant nor a master am I</em>.” These values have motivated American activists throughout the nation's history to fight for what is right and to fight to bring liberty and equal opportunity to all.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The founders of the United States saw freedom and equality as inherently linked. Excessive inequality could result in aristocracy and would be corrosive to society and freedom. But freedom was inherently linked with accepting that all men are created equal. Alexis de Tocqueville, a famous French author who wrote about the early United States, said, “<em>Grant me thirty years of equal division of inheritances and a free press, and I will provide you with a republic.</em>” In the Federalist #10, James Madison stated that “<em>the most common and durable source of factions has been the various and unequal distribution of property. Those who hold and those who are without property have ever formed distinct interests in society.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 4">
<p>The struggle for freedom and equality for all has defined the United States throughout its history and defines what it means to be an American. The biggest questions in American history have been “what is liberty?” and “what is the proper relation between liberty and order?” and the biggest struggles in American history have involved expanding freedom and equality. The greatest victories in these struggles have come in four waves. The first wave of this struggle came with the Revolutionary War and the formation of the new United States government. The second wave of the American struggle for freedom for all came with the U.S Civil War and its aftermath. The third wave of this struggle came with the Great Depression, the New Deal and the Second World War and its aftermath. The fourth wave was the Civil Rights Movement. The Declaration of Independence was the statement of the core values of America and its people. However, the realization that “<em>all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights</em>” came throughout the history of the United States and is still not entirely complete. The Declaration of Independence stated that the role of government ought to be to protect these rights and that a just government is based around the consent of the governed. After independence, American society became the closest in existence to a society without an aristocracy. A government was created that was the closest thing to a republic of laws, not men, that existed in the world. About a decade after the end of the revolution, a constitution was ratified that created a new national government for the United States. In its Preamble the Constitution stated its purpose as follows, “<em>to form a more perfect Union, establish Justice, insure domestic Tranquility, provide for the common defense, promote the general Welfare, and secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity.</em>” Shortly thereafter, a second great American document was created, the Bill of Rights. This document protected many fundamental rights from government violation. Through many years of existence and legal interpretation, the Bill of Rights became a great American document that has played a large role in determining the nature of American freedom and liberty and has been at the heart of the shared American historical and cultural heritage. These documents are part of what makes America what it is and Americans who they are.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The history of the Civil War and reconstruction resulted in a great expansion of liberty, the end of slavery, and the expansion of the rights of citizenship to many Americans who did not receive those liberties before. The legal changes that happened during this period are most dramatically reflected in the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, which reads in part, “<em>No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</em>” The 14th Amendment's declaration that all are equal before the law put the Declaration of Independence's most famous value into the constitution. It stated that all Americans have rights that must be protected by law. Furthermore, the Civil War and its aftermath helped define what it means to be American by creating an American national identity. Americans were Americans first and foremost instead of residents of their states first and foremost.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The New Deal era and the aftermath of World War II brought a new era in the expansion of rights in the United States. During the New Deal, it was realized that liberty included certain economic rights and that protecting the liberty of the population included giving everyone economic opportunities. In a tradition that went back to the nation's founding, it was realized that excessive concentrations of wealth were harmful and made it difficult to maintain the conditions needed for freedom to continue. The Second World War and its aftermath saw the exportation of the American values of freedom for all to the rest of the world. During the war, President Franklin D. Roosevelt made his Four Freedoms speech in which he stated that freedom of speech, freedom of religion, freedom from fear, and freedom from want were human rights that ought to be protected for all persons everywhere in the world. This speech served to be an inspiration for the development of the United Nations after the war, and the expansion of human rights to everyone throughout the world. The civil rights movement that started in the 1950s expanded the horizons of American liberty and freedom. The formal racial segregation and discrimination of the Jim Crow era was ended and economic discrimination was reduced. Courts made important civil rights and civil liberties decisions that expanded liberty and equality for all. Economic programs such Lyndon Johnson's Great Society expanded opportunity and alleviated poverty. During the 1970s and 80s women's rights were established and expanded., in a large part due to court victories won by activists.</p>
<div title="Page 6"><div title="Page 6">America is a nation of diversity created by a history of immigration, a nation not made of any one cultural or religious group. This nation has been a place where people of all kinds came for a better life throughout its entire history. This has been true since even before U.S independence. From Quaker and Puritan immigrants looking for religious freedom, to the immigrants of Ellis Island to modern immigrants, people have come to America looking for freedom. America has been a nation of ideals and laws, not of men or aristocracy, throughout its history. These values of freedom and equality have inspired struggle for all of America's history. While these struggles have never created a perfect union, America has become more perfect and a greater home to the blessings of liberty over its history. What makes a real American is not simply who you are, but it is our shared values and the belief that you have the freedom and opportunity to become all that you want to be, as long as you don't violate the freedoms and liberties of others. It is this belief in liberty and equality for all that makes America great and makes being an American great. The constitution gives Americans certain rights and our freedom and liberty are guaranteed. But what makes an American a real American is the respect for these values and the respect for the struggle that secured these freedoms, as well as a determination to continue to protect and fight for these values.</div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ellisisland" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ellisisland</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newdeal" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newdeal</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newworld" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newworld</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#10</category>
      <category>#ellisisland</category>
      <category>#newdeal</category>
      <category>#newworld</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
