<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23environment</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23environment&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>One of the better reads on environmental policy...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/one-of-the-better-reads-on-environmental-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/one-of-the-better-reads-on-environmental-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 02:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>One of the better reads on environmental policy in a while<br /><a href="http://www.ecomodernism.org/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.ecomodernism.org/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/environment" class="p-category" rel="tag">#environment</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#environment</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Evidence of Global Warming? Part one: How we know that the temperature is increasing.</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/what-is-the-evidence-of-global-warming-part-one-how</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/what-is-the-evidence-of-global-warming-part-one-how</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 13:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>How about 117 degrees Fahrenheit for hot weather? <a href="http://www.ndtv.com/article/india/heat-wave-unabated-rajasthan-s-sriganganagar-sizzles-at-48-2-degrees-370148">This was the high temperature during last month's heat wave in Sriganganagar, India</a>. While single events, including this heat wave, cannot be attributed individually to climate change, global warming will make such events much more likely. The planet is undergoing one of the most rapid periods of temperature change in the history of the Earth. This level of change is only exceeded by what occurred during the five mass extinctions, the most recent of these being the Cretaceous-Tertiary event which caused the extinction of the dinosaurs. The rate of biodiversity loss due to current human caused climate change may be <a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/Default.aspx?id=3897120&p1=0#.UZ2bu3wy0b0">sufficient to qualify as a mass extinction fully on par</a> with these events by mid-century.</p>

<p>In this article, I will show the evidence that there is an increase in global temperature of about 0.16 degrees Celsius per decade. The following chart from NASA shows the rise of global average temperature to a level that is 1.5C above pre-industrial levels and 0.6C above mid-20th century levels.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_159" align="aligncenter" width="300"] Click to enlarge image. <a href="http://www.nasa.gov/centers/goddard/news/topstory/2008/earth_temp.html">Image description from NASA</a>: "Graph of global annual surface temperatures relative to 1951-1980 mean temperature. Air and ocean data from weather stations, ships and satellites. The 2007 point is the 11-month anomaly."[/caption]</p>

<p>This graph clearly shows a dramatic and exponential rise in global surface temperatures. While often criticized, researchers have confirmed this general temperature trend many times. A <a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/2012/07/berkeley-earth-project-is-back-to-re-re-confirm-earth-is-warming/">recent confirmation of this data was done by former climate change skeptic Richard Muller</a> in his <a href="http://berkeleyearth.org">Berkeley Earth</a> project. Muller was funded by many conservative groups which believed that his work offered one of the best opportunities for a scientific falsification of global warming theory.As the following chart shows, the Berkeley Earth results are effectively the same as previous attempts to measure global temperature.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_163" align="aligncenter" width="300"] Click to enlarge image. "Land temperature with 1- and 10-year running averages. The shaded regions are the one- and two-standard deviation uncertainties calculated including both statistical and spatial sampling errors. Prior land results from the other groups are also plotted. The NASA GISS record had a land mask applied; the HadCRU curve is the simple land average, not the hemispheric-weighted one." Image and caption from Berkeley Earth <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130723044740/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>berkeleyearth.org:80/<wbr></wbr>results-summary/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;<a href="http://berkeleyearth.org/results-summary/%5B/caption">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>berkeleyearth.org/<wbr></wbr>results-summary/<wbr></wbr>[/<wbr></wbr>caption</a>]The above chart compares the temperature reconstructions made by Berkeley Earth with other temperature measurements, including the NASA results used in the first graph. All of the major data sets come to effectively the same result for recent temperatures. Despite claims from climate change skeptics that "urban heating, data selection, poor station quality, and data adjustment" has biased past attempts to measure global temperatures, Berkeley Earth has found that "these [factors] do not unduly bias the results".</p>

<p>There are many short-term effects such as the El Nino, La Nina cycle that can cause temporary reductions in global temperatures. But as the following animation shows these effects do not nullify the greater global temperature trends.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_169" align="aligncenter" width="300"] Image from skepticalscience.com licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution licence. Click to view animation.</p>

<p>[/caption]</p>

<p>The current rapid increases in global temperature can be confirmed in other ways. As this image produced by the Environmental Protection Agency shows, Arctic ice is melting at a rapid rate.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_172" align="aligncenter" width="300"] Click to enlarge.[/caption]</p>

<p>In a period of just 28 years, climate change reduced Arctic ice by over a third. Ice melts when heated. This reduction in ice coverage reflects and supports the conclusion that temperatures are soaring.Temperatures in the Arctic have increased at a rate four times the world average.</p>

<p>The case that the world is warming is very strong. As I will show in my next post, we are causing this increase. If this increase in global temperature continues, the results will be catastrophic.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/berkeleyearth" class="p-category" rel="tag">#berkeleyearth</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/environmentalprotectionagency" class="p-category" rel="tag">#environmentalprotectionagency</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lanina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lanina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/nasa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#nasa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#berkeleyearth</category>
      <category>#environmentalprotectionagency</category>
      <category>#lanina</category>
      <category>#nasa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
