<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23imageviawikipedia</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23imageviawikipedia&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>New Study: Twitter Discussions Reflect Political Polarization on Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-study-twitter-discussions-reflect-political-polarization-on-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-study-twitter-discussions-reflect-political-polarization-on-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 15:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A <a href="http://eprints.nottingham.ac.uk/2236/">study published this month</a> ,<em>Climate change on Twitter: topics, communities and conversations about the 2013 IPCC report</em>, looked into the debate about climate change on Twitter around the release of the latest Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change assessment.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_843" align="alignright" width="238"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:GRES-2.jpg"></a> Image Via Wikipedia.Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.[/caption]</p>

<p>They analysed the content of  tweets that mentioned the IPCC. Most Twitter posts on climate change  Among their findings is the discovery of a clear political polarization in online discussions of this issue. The discussions largely fit into four topics, "relation to science, political campaigns, geography, and social meanings of climate change". Of particular frequency in this discussion is the debate over the carbon tax bill in Australia. The debate over the accuracy of the science strongly follows these political lines. The following two example tweets given in the paper illustrate this.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Australian" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Australian</a> PM thinks that if he doesn't read the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/IPCC" class="p-category" rel="tag">#IPCC</a> report then <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> is still crap. That's the way this government works.</p>
</blockquote><blockquote>
<p>Global Warming Scam unravelling by the day. IPCC exposed as corrupt liars. <a href="http://t.co/rotD07eIEX"></a><a href="http://t.co/rotD07eIEX">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>t.co/<wbr></wbr>rotD07eIEX</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/auspol" class="p-category" rel="tag">#auspol</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ausvotes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ausvotes</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the United States tweets followed liberal and conservative lines with conservative tweets outnumbering liberal ones two to one. The authors state that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The dominance of conservative-leaning hashtags in the US provide support for the theory that the country’s climate debate is in danger of becoming so polarized as to be described as a “logic schism”, in a similar manner to struggles over President Obama’s healthcare program.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/globalwarmingscam" class="p-category" rel="tag">#globalwarmingscam</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviawikipedia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviawikipedia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/us" class="p-category" rel="tag">#us</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Australian</category>
      <category>#IPCC</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#auspol</category>
      <category>#ausvotes</category>
      <category>#globalwarmingscam</category>
      <category>#imageviawikipedia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#us</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Energy Efficiency is Important</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-energy-efficiency-is-important</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-energy-efficiency-is-important</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 23:08:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a title="Pre-funding Energy Consumption: A Proposal to Encourage Energy Efficiency of Consumer Products" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/pre-funding-energy-consumption-proposal-encourage-energy-efficiency-consumer-products/">A while ago I introduced a way that governments could encourage increased energy efficiency</a>. In this followup post I will discuss why energy efficiency is important. Improvements to America's energy efficiency is one of the quickest ways that pollution can be reduced. This change can also save vast amounts of money. <a href="http://www.worldwatch.org/node/6212">One report on energy efficiency</a> showed that a one time investment of 520 billion dollars in energy efficiency could reduce energy usage by about 25%</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_738" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Compact_fluorescent_straight_crop.jpg"></a> Image Via Wikipedia and Dedicated to the Public Domain[/caption]</p>

<p>and save over one trillion dollars.One trillion dollars is about $3200 per every American and is equal to about 28 percent of the annual Federal budget. This energy efficiency investment would also reduce CO2 pollution by 1.1 billion tons of carbon dioxide per year. Other sources substantiate that there is a vast potential to improve America's energy use by efficiency.<br /><!--more--><br />Industry is one major sector of the economy where vast energy efficiency improvements are possible.<a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360544201000172">A 2001 paper</a> [1. Worrell, Ernst, Lynn Price, and Nathan Martin. "Energy efficiency and carbon dioxide emissions reduction opportunities in the US iron and steel sector." Energy 26.5 (2001): 513-536.] showed that with current technology the energy efficiency of the American steel industry could be increased by 18 percent. This would result in a 19% reduction of that industry's emissions. It was estimated that these improvements would pay for themselves within three years. Similarly, <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360544200000426">a 2000 paper</a> [2. Worrell, Ernst, Nathan Martin, and Lynn Price. "Potentials for energy efficiency improvement in the US cement industry." Energy 25.12 (2000): 1189-1214.] found that an 11% reduction in the energy useage of the cement industry was possible and that this shift would reduce the emissions of American cement production by 5 percent. <a href="http://escholarship.org/uc/item/31b2f7bd#page-3">A separate 2000 study</a> [3. Martin, Nathan, et al. "Opportunities to improve energy efficiency and reduce greenhouse gas emissions in the US pulp and paper industry." (2000).] found that energy usage in the paper industry could be reduced by almost 37 percent. The paper industry accounts for 12 percent of industrial energy usage in America. This data shows that if all of the possible industrial energy efficiency improvements were made, then pollution could be greatly reduced and billions of dollars could be saved. <br />There are also massive ways that households could save energy. A 2009 study found that it is possible for American households to reduce their contributions to CO2 emissions by 20% [4. Dietz, Thomas, et al. "Household actions can provide a behavioral wedge to rapidly reduce US carbon emissions." Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 106.44 (2009): 18452-18456.].<a href="http://www.nohairshirts.com/chap17.php"> A calculation in a 2008 book</a> found that home heating, lighting and water energy usage could be reduced by 80% for newly constructed houses. Already constructed buildings can drive smaller but still substantial energy savings. The cash value of these savings is almost 3000 dollars per household per year.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviawikipedia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviawikipedia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#page</category>
      <category>#imageviawikipedia</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
