<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23canada</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23canada&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Immigration Helps the Economy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A great body of research done by economists and other researchers shows that immigration has a potentially great potential to benefit the economy. The cost of immigration restrictions <a href="http://www.cgdev.org/publication/economics-and-emigration-trillion-dollar-bills-sidewalk-working-paper-264">is a large fraction of global GDP (around 25 percent)</a> and one of the most costly. This global cost of the current restrictions on immigrants from poor nations migrating to richer nations is trillions of dollars per year. Immigration restrictions can increase global economic inequality, particularly between nations, but also within nations.<br /><!--more--></p>

<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither. . .“</p>

<p>This immigration has been clearly beneficial to the nation. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.tcd.ie%2FEconomics%2FTEP%2F2003_papers%2FTEPNo15KOR23.pdf&ei=hZA-UvjGIYyayQH45ID4AQ&usg=AFQjCNH6zbsRZWrNg1bhyvSEUUZwrpIkxA&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc">Economist Kevin O'Rourke found that</a> immigration from Europe to the United States and Canada in the 19th and early 20th centuries narrowed the wage gaps between developed nations and then developing European nations, such as Ireland, Norway, and Italy.In the mid to late 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had an almost free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, as well as immigrants from Asia. This migration was at its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. In 1911, almost 15 percent of the United States population was foreign born. This immigration had substantial benefits for both nations. It fueled much of United States industrial development in the period before World War I and immigration from 1840 to 1920 was a primary contributor to American urbanization. <a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w12900">The migrants tended to be unskilled labor of the type best suited to employment in industry</a>, compared to the highly skilled craftsmen who made up the bulk of native workers. This is because labor is a limiting factor to economic output in nations with high development of capital and technology. The result of migration, therefore, is an increase in industrial capacity triggered by the easing of that limiting factor.Additionally, the nations where the migrants emigrated from received great benefits from their migration flows. Nations with limited capital and technology development compared to the available labor are the most likely to produce emigrants. This migration drives local wages up. While emigration between 1870 and 1910 lowered the Irish labor force by 45 percent, the Italian by 39 percent, and the Norwegian by 24 percent, wages increased dramatically in those nations. Irish wages rose by almost 25%.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/canada" class="p-category" rel="tag">#canada</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/irishpotatofamine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#irishpotatofamine</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#canada</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#irishpotatofamine</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HIV/AIDS Vaccine Passes Phase I Clinical Trial</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/hivaids-vaccine-passes-phase-i-clinical-trial</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/hivaids-vaccine-passes-phase-i-clinical-trial</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 11:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>An HIV vaccine developed in Canada <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130905155703/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>communications.uwo.ca:80/<wbr></wbr>media/<wbr></wbr>releases/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>September/<wbr></wbr>no_adverse_effects_in_volunteers_following_phase_i_clinical_trial_of_sumagen_aids_vaccine.html</a>"&gt;has passed a phase 1 clinical trial according to a press release by Western University, which conducted the research in collaboration with Sumagen. This clinical trial shows that the vaccine is safe to administer to humans and according to the press release "No serious adverse event was observed in any volunteer throughout the observation periods". A phase 1 trial</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_386" align="alignright" width="420"]<a href="http://phil.cdc.gov/phil/details.asp?pid=10000"><img class=" wp-image-386 " alt="Scanning electron micrograph of HIV-1 virions budding from a cultured lymphocyte. Image via Centers for Disease Control and Prevention." src="http://web.archive.org/web/20130908154233/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>wp-content/<wbr></wbr>uploads/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>10000_lores.jpg</a>" width="420" height="279" /&gt; Scanning electron micrograph of HIV-1 virions budding from a cultured lymphocyte. Image via Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.[/caption]</p>

<p>provides little information on the effectiveness of the vaccine and is only designed to detect severe side effects or safety issues. <!--more-->The vaccine is a genetically modified killed whole virus vaccine, which means that it relies on a modified version of the HIV virus which is more capable of triggering an immune response that results in immunity than an unmodified virus. The researchers report finding increased antibody production, providing some evidence that the vaccine is indeed effective. As stated in the press release</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The antibody against p24 capsid antigen increased as much as 64-fold in some vaccinees and antibody against gp120 surface antigen increased up to eight-fold after vaccination.</p>

<p>....</p>

<p>In particular, the antibody against gp120 surface antigen is considered to be very important, since some of these antibodies may represent the broadly neutralizing antibodies, which seem to be the most important parameter of an effective HIV vaccine for prevention of HIV-infection.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The researchers plan future trials to confirm that the vaccine is effective.</p>

<p>An effective vaccine would give public health officials a way to control the spread of AIDS.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aids" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aids</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/canada" class="p-category" rel="tag">#canada</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hiv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hiv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westernuniversity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westernuniversity</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aids</category>
      <category>#canada</category>
      <category>#hiv</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westernuniversity</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
