<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/?offset=270</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?offset=270&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Poverty: A Economic and Moral Crisis in America</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2012/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2012/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 23:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Today, many people in our nation face decisions like these:"<em>Should I pay for my children to go to the doctor or should I pay the rent?</em>" "<em>Should I put food on the table or pay my mortgage?</em>" Poverty shouldn't be an issue in our country. Nobody should have to face these decisions. We are better than that. We are the richest nation in the world. There is sufficient wealth in the United States to eliminate poverty. We have taken the path of inaction when all Western European and Scandinavian nations have for decades tried to eliminate and alleviate the suffering of the poor. They have made great strides in doing so, while still keeping strong economies. But the U.S. has stood still, letting poverty deprive millions of access to basic rights such as food, shelter, health care, and a chance for a productive life. The United States must take action.In this post I will explain why we have a obligation to help the poor and why current government programs are not up to the task of alleviating poverty.When you think of someone that is in poverty you might think of someone that is lazy and never does any work . But this is not true. Millions of those in poverty are the working poor that currently have a job. Many others are unemployed while they try to find a job. According to <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/content/04_22/b3885001_mz001.htm">an article in Business Week magazine</a>, 24 percent of the workforce is in poverty.A <a href="http://www.urban.org/publications/310291.html">study by the Urban Institute</a> found that over 44 percent of homeless persons surveyed said they have worked at a job during the week that they were polled. A study by the Department of Health and Human Services <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20070510103756/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.nrchmi.samhsa.gov/<wbr></wbr>facts/<wbr></wbr>facts_question_2.asp</a>"&gt;found that 23 percent of the homeless are veterans. According to the National Coalition for the Homeless, <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20141229123239/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.nationalhomeless.org/<wbr></wbr>factsheets/<wbr></wbr>who.html</a>"&gt;39 percent of those that are currently homeless are in families with children.rnrnPoverty prevents many people from becoming the productive citizens that they would otherwise become. Someone will not pursue their higher goals, like getting an education or other job training, if their basic needs are not met.Our Declaration of Independence states that. We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.But to realize these rights we must guarantee that people have a degree of equality of opportunity and their basic needs for food and shelter are met. This is especially true for children who are just starting out and who must rely on their parents.If we want to realize the principles of the Declaration of Independence, we must try our best to give everyone the same chance at a successful life. We must try our best to eliminate the cycle of poverty. We must try our best to allow everyone to get a good education, to receive health care, to get a decent job, to enjoy the same opportunities that all others enjoy. Poverty in childhood comes close to setting how far someone will go in their life. Poverty is the ultimate source of inequality in a modern democracy like the U.S.Alleviating poverty will not hurt the economy. Instead it will improve the economy. To see this, just look at the economies of the social democracies such as Sweden, Finland, Norway and Denmark. These countries tend to have even greater economic prosperity then the United States, without much of the poverty seen all too often in the U.S.Norway , Iceland, Canada, Sweden, and France, all countries with larger welfare systems then the United States, have higher Human Development Index scores then the U.S., according to the United Nations Development Program. The Human Development Index is a measure of the well-being of the population based on per capita GDP, life expectancy and education level.We are country that prides itself on the American Dream. But, the U.S has the second lowest income mobility of any developed nation (only the income mobility of the United Kingdom is worse). In other words "<a href="http://www.freakonomics.com/2012/01/19/is-higher-income-inequality-associated-with-lower-intergenerational-mobility/">rich parents have rich kids and poor parents have poor kids</a>".rnrnAccording to an ABC News report, which cited a study released in November 2009 in the Archives of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Health/wireStory?id=8977934">almost half of the children in the United States will be on food stamps at some point during their childhood</a>. The cost of a home continues to decrease with our current economic depression. Yet many people still can't afford a home. We have almost 500,000 homeless in the U.S. at any given time and <a href="http://www.nationalhomeless.org/factsheets/How_Many.html">at some point in a typical year there will be 3.5 million people</a> that experience homelessness according to the National Coalition for the Homeless .rnrnEvery welfare program that we currently have leaves many behind. For example, look at Medicaid. It has done much to provide healthcare to the poor but does nothing for the 17% percent of the population that a Gallup survey published in 2012 found is uninsured. These people earn too little to buy insurance, but earn too much to qualify for our current welfare programs.The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, which is commonly known as the food stamp program, has a similar problem. This program helps many people, but still millions of people have to worry about putting food on the table.According to the Food Research and Action Center, 49.1 million people in the United States live in food insecure households.Public housing programs, such as the Housing Choice Voucher program, that provide aid to families to help them rent a house, haven't eliminated homelessness.Our welfare programs leave millions behind. We need new programs that will help those that fall through the current welfare safety net, particularly the working poor. We have an ethical obligation to help those who are currently in poverty. Everyone deserves a basic standard of living and everyone should have equality of opportunity. We need to make sure everyone has the human rights outlined by our Declaration of Independence. Millions of the poor have been denied equality of opportunity by being born to impoverished parents. They have been denied the basic right to food, shelter, health care and a chance for a productive life.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/housingchoicevoucher" class="p-category" rel="tag">#housingchoicevoucher</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sweden" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sweden</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/urbaninstitute" class="p-category" rel="tag">#urbaninstitute</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#housingchoicevoucher</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#sweden</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#urbaninstitute</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If you love freedom, vote to allow gay marriage</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2012/if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2012/if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Last week, in a dangerously misguided decision, North Carolina voters passed a referendum banning gay marriage. In a freedom loving country this referendum makes no sense because gay marriage is simply a matter of preserving and extending liberty and equality to all. Anti-gay marriage advocates are often (if not usually) motivated by either severely misguided and false stereotypes and/or a desire to force everyone to conform to their conservative religious code of morality. Gay marriage bans are unjust infringements on the rights and freedoms of gay Americans. These bans violate the Equal Protection Clause found in the 14<sup>th</sup> Amendment to the U.S Constitution and deprive a large group of liberties protected by the Constitution. There's no justification for current bans on gay marriage.</p>

<p><a name="__DdeLink__0_472281813"></a> Marriage licenses provide many important legal benefits. A 2004 study by the United States General Accounting Office found that 1,138 federal laws use marital status as a factor in determining or receiving benefits, rights, and privileges. According to the Ontario Consultants on Religious Tolerance (OCRT), <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/aboutus.htm">a nonsectarian group that</a> "<em>that promotes the freedom of individuals to follow the religious path of their choosing, without discrimination or oppression</em>", <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/hom_marr.htm">these include benefits</a> to individuals that affect their "<em>Social Security, Medicare, medical leave, and other benefits; property inheritance; the right to visit their spouse in hospital, and make medical decisions if they are incapacitated; security of the couple and of their children</em>". This means gay couples lack the financial security of married couples and the right to have their partner involved in critical decisions if they become incapacitated.</p>

<p>The liberty and well-being of gays is also threatened by the hostility they face. A <a href="http://www.apa.org/pi/lgbt/resources/policy/ohio-marriage.aspx">statement issued by the American Psychological Association</a> notes that "<em>Taken together, the evidence clearly supports the position that the social stigma, prejudice, discrimination, and violence associated with not having a heterosexual sexual orientation and the hostile and stressful social environments created thereby adversely affect the psychological, physical, social, and economic well-being of lesbian, gay, and bisexual individuals.</em>" Bans on gay marriage reinforce these stereotypes and contribute to discrimination against gay couples. These stereotypes, in turn, sometimes lead to bullying, harassment, and even violence against gays and gay couples.</p>

<p><a name="__DdeLink__8_472281813"></a><a name="__DdeLink__10_472281813"></a> The Declaration of Independence says, "<em>We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness</em>". If you believe in this principle, as I do, you must conclude that everyone should be entitled to liberty and equality and that freedom should be limited only insofar as is required for everyone else to enjoy liberty.</p>

<p>Conservatives advocating bans on gay marriage cannot show they will be harmed in any way by gay marriages. Many conservatives argue that permitting gay marriage will be corrosive to families and society. However, there is a great body of evidence that contradicts this assertion. A <a href="http://www.aaanet.org/issues/policy-advocacy/Statement-on-Marriage-and-the-Family.cfm">statement issued by the American Anthropological Association</a> states that "<em>The results of more than a century of anthropological research on households, kinship relationships, and families, across cultures and through time, provide no support whatsoever for the view that either civilization or viable social orders depend upon marriage as an exclusively heterosexual institution …..a vast array of family types, including families built upon same-sex partnerships, can contribute to stable and humane societies</em>". I ask those conservatives who reject the vision of liberty for all including gay couples and those turning to religious dogma to consider is the Bible really a good guide for governance? Slavery, stoning, executing whole families for the crimes of one member, mass murder and genocide are <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/imm_bibl.htm">all found in the Bible</a>. Are religious ideologues asking the government to enforce a biblical version of Sharia law?</p>

<p><a name="__DdeLink__140_472281813"></a><a name="__DdeLink__144_472281813"></a><a name="__DdeLink__146_472281813"></a> Gay marriage bans violate the Equal Protection Clause in the 14<sup>th</sup> Amendment, which reads "<em>No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</em>" It's clear that gay marriage bans subject a group to unequal treatment. Discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender discrimination are both very similar, so courts should use the same standard to evaluate both. In <em>Craig v. Boren</em> (1976) the Supreme Court ruled gender discrimination is not permissiable unless it furthers an important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest. Some conservatives have tried to claim that the important government interest being promoted is the government's interest in promoting procreation through well structured marriage laws. While the government <em><span class="c1">may</span></em> have an important interest in maintaining population growth, gay marriage bans are not substantially related to that interest. Gay marriages wouldn't have a negative affect on heterosexual marriages. And gay marriage bans don't guarantee that the institution of marriage will remain strong. Marriage laws clearly have functions other than to encourage procreation. We don't require every married couple to have children. Along with the equal protection issues, laws that limit interstate recognition of gay marriages, such as the Defense of Marriage Act ,contradict the requirement in Article 4 of the Constitution that "<em>full faith and credit shall be given in each state to the public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of every other state</em>".</p>

<p>Gay marriage prohibitions are just wrong. There's no reality-based justification for discriminatory laws such as the the one passed in the North Carolina referendum. Opposition to gay marriage is fueled by religious fundamentalism and demagoguery from conservative political leaders. It is past time to repeal the wrongheaded and unconstitutional prohibitions of gay marriage that infringe the liberties of millions of people throughout America. If you love freedom, it's the right thing to do.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americananthropologicalassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americananthropologicalassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americanpsychologicalassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americanpsychologicalassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/equalprotectionclause" class="p-category" rel="tag">#equalprotectionclause</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/northcarolina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#northcarolina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#americananthropologicalassociation</category>
      <category>#americanpsychologicalassociation</category>
      <category>#equalprotectionclause</category>
      <category>#northcarolina</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
