<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/?q=%23gamergate&amp;offset=10&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>An interesting interview with one of the main targets of #Gamergate connected harassment</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-interesting-interview-with-one-of-the-main-targets-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-interesting-interview-with-one-of-the-main-targets-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 05:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>An interesting interview with one of the main targets of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> connected harassment</p>

<p><a title="" href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/03/that-life-is-over-zoe-quinn-looks-beyond-gamergate/"></a><a href="http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2015/03/that-life-is-over-zoe-quinn-looks-beyond-gamergate/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>gaming/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>03/<wbr></wbr>that-life-is-over-zoe-quinn-looks-beyond-gamergate/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meet the 8chan Board Where Users Harass Feminist Activists and #GamerGate Opponents</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/meet-the-8chan-board-where-users-harass-feminist-activists-and</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/meet-the-8chan-board-where-users-harass-feminist-activists-and</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 05:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><img align="right" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/012115_0533_Meetthe8cha12.jpg" alt=""><span style="font-size:14pt">8chan is a forum website where anyone can create a sub forum, or "chan". Its one defining  feature is its friendliness to trolls, and its extremely lax , anything goes moderation policy. Among the more notable members of this community are a large part of the active members of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/GamerGate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#GamerGate</a>, focused around the /<a href="http://8ch.net/gamergate/index.html">gamergate</a>/ board. However, there is a much more nefarious board, /<a href="http://8ch.net/baphomet/index.html">baphomet</a>/. That board has the purpose of a clearing house for doxing, harassment, trolling, and hacking. Its members care little for trivial things like ethics. The rules for the board note that "If you have remorse for you're  [sic] actions you are not welcome ….We never show mercy during raids " and  "so if you're a attention whoring faggot this is not the place for you".  /Baphomet/ was founded by trolls and script kiddies saddened by the switch of focus of the hacking group Anonymous towards activism and away from nefarious destruction. Many members of the /gamergate/ chan are also /Baphomet/ users.  There is a close relationship between the two boards. /gamergate/ is the clean board that provides a respectiable public image for GG. /Baphomet/ has become the home for GG dirty tricks. Want to know what GG is really like? Lets  look into /baphomet/ a bit more <a href="http://8ch.net/baphomet/index.html"></a><a href="http://8ch.net/baphomet/index.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>8ch.net/<wbr></wbr>baphomet/<wbr></wbr>index.html</a> Note that /baphomet/ is just behind /gamergate/ on the top 25 list of 8chan fora. The top thread is this guy<br /></span></p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>We need to develop beyond ddos and learn how to be a true terror to the SJW [Social Justice Warrior] menace.
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>I'll upload a few of my hacking ebooks here, simply beginnger guides anyone can learn from.
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>Here is a good set of sites to use:
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>….
</em></strong></span>

<span style="font-size:14pt">Oooh... Cool. Terrorizing SJWs. Let's open that thread. 
</span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>&gt;We need to develop beyond ddos<br />I agree, OP.<br />Doxing, Raiding, and DDOS are fine– but every "battle" we're currently enduring would be over by now if at least some of us knew how to hack/crack/program<br /><br />Currently, I only know (x)html(5) & css(3). [and some c++, but not enough to really do anything with…]
</em></strong></span>


 

<span style="font-size:14pt">I would like to be more of a menace to SJWs, but I'm a kidiot loser who doesn't know how to program anything more complex than a VBA macro. Some are making more progress on the whole being criminals thing. 
</span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>If you haven't noticed, a couple targets got their servers rooted (one hasn't noticed yet) and few got their mail hacked too (most haven't noticed, last time I checked).
</em></strong></span>

<span style="font-size:14pt">The 8chaners hacked the email of some activists trying to voice their opinion. Crushing free speech is something that really warms the heart, doesn't it? 
</span>


 </p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>You are free to fuck with colleges if you're so inclined. /baphomet/ has no particular cause or position on any given issue besides the position that we should raid people we want to raid because we think it's funny to do so. There have been debates about whether or not we're just pretending like we don't have a purpose, but ultimately it doesn't matter.
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>This is first and foremost a haven for old, even ancient anons who remember what Anonymous was a decade ago and are reviving–as best we can–that same spirit. We are not political in any sense. If /pol/ would like to raid a target, /pol/ ought to raid a target. If it will be particularly funny, they're welcome to come ask us to help out, but if it looks like it's going to be a bore, or if it isn't funny but is simply a matter of supporting an abstract cause, this isn't really the place for it.
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em> ….
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>We don't care about SJWs for the sake of ideology, we raid them because they're easily offended and react with sob stories. That they overwhelmingly are deserving of raids is beside the point.
</em></strong></span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>However, if you can find a lelworthy way to fuck with schools, go ahead and share.
</em></strong></span>

<span style="font-size:14pt">We don't really have a mission, other than being criminals that destroy things. 
</span></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt"><span style="font-size:14pt"><strong><em>A /baphomet/ take on the LOIC seems like the right way to go, in my opinion.<br />If there ever WAS a /baphomet/-endorsed DDoS client, I think it would need to be able to help resolve the common retarded mistakes that occur with planned ddossing; timezones, primary/secondary targets, fallbacks for meetups if everything turns to shit, etc.<br />My suggestion would be thus:<br />The new LOIC would only be able to function if it was connected to a host, ie the raid leader's own little server, who could update the variables (such as countdown timer, specific URLs, the required number of clients attacking each IP address so maximum DoS occurs across a few places, I dunno…) on people's clients (I'm thinking that the client should be alerted if the leader changes a variable, but they'd have to be edited by the user manually. I don't really want to just surrender my PC to a botnet that could be aimed at ANYTHING…) if/when they changed (by working in conjunction with the driving force of the raid in IRC, ie people from /baphomet/).<br />Being able to generate a session should require an additional piece of software to act as a barrier to fucktards, that newfag idiots would be too retarded to find / too shitscared to download if they found it. That would leave the important shit in the hands of people who actually cared about it, while allowing anyone to join the public botnet (but not fire until the countdown timer hit 0 / other parameters were met)<br />This would allow widespread advertisement of the raid and new LOIC to anywhere that would listen, generating a large group of people all under the 'guidance' of /baphomet/, or a proxy group such as 4chan's /b/ for max lulz and 0 blame<br />Sorry if this makes no sense, I'm slightly very drunk. Anyway, I seem to recall Anonymous using something like this a few years back, but I don't know enough about this shit to be able to pass judgement. Regardless, I think the best way for us to actually advance ourselves as social justice warrior warriors is to gain the (unknowing) support of others.<br />Side note, would it be possible to encourage SJWs into ddossing what they thought was 8chan with a program like I suggested, but really have them hit their own shitty sites? We could then post proof to the owners / domain providers for lulz
</em></strong></span>

<span style="font-size:14pt">A closing 8chan rant. 
</span></p>
<p><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/012115_0533_Meetthe8cha22.png" alt=""></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/computersecurityandtrolling" class="p-category" rel="tag">#computersecurityandtrolling</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gaming" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gaming</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/loic" class="p-category" rel="tag">#loic</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sjw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sjw</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vba" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vba</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#GamerGate</category>
      <category>#computersecurityandtrolling</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gaming</category>
      <category>#loic</category>
      <category>#sjw</category>
      <category>#vba</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#x2019;t Take Trolls as Serious Political Ideologues</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/dont-take-trolls-as-serious-political-ideologues</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/dont-take-trolls-as-serious-political-ideologues</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 08:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><span style="font-size:12pt">The trolling done by members of websites like 4chan and 8chan has been branching out into more mainstream websites. Among the targets of this trolling are many political websites, particularly many in the feminist community. However, as trolling gets farther from the tech <img align="right" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/011715_0817_DontTakeTro12.jpg" alt="">community, which is one of the few Internet communities that really understands trolling and how to properly respond to it, you can see many communities respond very poorly to trolling. On many political communities, one particularly common mistake is to take trolls as somehow representing an honestly presented viewpoint. However, this is a gross misunderstanding of what trolls are. Trolls are simply there to stir up trouble in the get as strong a response as possible their target community. Trolls are not honest brokers of opinion in a community. They are in it to upset people for the lulz. The 4Chan community is targeted many feminist blogs and other feminist communities for trolling. The response in many publications has been to assume that the 4Chan trolls are simply presenting an antifeminist viewpoint in a particularly obnoxious way. However, this is not true. The trolls have simply discovered that elements in the feminist community make a good target for trolling that gets them a desired response. The same trolls of fit a wide variety of targets. Here are some of the targets that were hit by 4chan trolls roughly at the same time as the feminist blogs:<br /></span></p>
<ol><li><span style="font-size:12pt">The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> trolling - 4chan and eight Chan trolls really created the whole <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> thing. I guess you could say this is trolling targeted at the feminist community. But it's not just targeted that community, it's also targeted the tech and gaming community as a whole.
</span></li><li><span style="font-size:12pt">Trolling targeting various conservative and right-wing groups.
</span></li><li><span style="font-size:12pt">The Ebola Chan trolling. 4chan trolls circulated myths about Ebola being spread by Western doctors on forms frequented by many people in the affected countries. This trolling of course, is not because they hate the populations in these countries. Instead, the 4chan trolls know a prank like this will get tons of media coverage and bring in the lulz.
</span></li><li><span style="font-size:12pt">The Apple Wave trolling. 4chan trolls circulated the rumor that claim that owners of iPhones can charge your device by placing it in a microwave.
</span></li><li><span style="font-size:12pt">The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/cutforbieber" class="p-category" rel="tag">#cutforbieber</a> trolling.
</span></li><li><span style="font-size:12pt">And finally, the wide range of swattings and mundane harassment done by the trolls.
</span></li></ol>
<p><span style="font-size:12pt">The one thing that unifies all this stuff is lulz. Lulz is the primary goal of an Internet troll. It is the humor value the troll obtains from causing trouble for someone else. Trolls simply want to see the world burn. The people not familiar with the Internet trolling culture the idea of people who seek destruction and disruption might be a bit hard to understand. But it is what motivates your common Internet troll. If you at all look at sites like 4chan and 8chan , and various other troll hideouts you'll be amazed at the level of effort trolls put in the causing people trouble. Is a passion that motivates and most every day of these guys' lives. They spend months in nursing some of the sock puppet accounts they use in their trolling. A plan intricately detailed operations against the websites they are targeting. But what trolls are not our political ideologues. Sure, trolls are pretty good at pointing out the weaknesses of the communities they are targeting, and they know about limits to the political ideologies advocated by these communities. And they are even better at weapon these weaknesses against the communities. However, they do not particularly care about the outcome of these disputes. It's just another source of lulz for them. And that right there is what many people do not get about trolls.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/computersecurityandtrolling" class="p-category" rel="tag">#computersecurityandtrolling</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#cutforbieber</category>
      <category>#computersecurityandtrolling</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Religions Should Not Be Immune from Criticism and Mockery</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/religions-should-not-be-immune-from-criticism-and-mockery</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/religions-should-not-be-immune-from-criticism-and-mockery</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 06:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><img align="left" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/011315_0655_ReligionsSh1.jpg" alt=""><span style="font-size:14pt">With the aftermath of the shootings at the office of the French satirical magazine Charlie Hebdo, there seems to be a number of people on social media, and on <a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2015/01/10/1356555/-On-not-being-Charlie">left-wing websites like Daly Kos</a> who seem to think the religion should be beyond criticism and mockery. One thing to note, is that contrary to what many of our friendly social justice warriors have said (Yes, I know that talking of SJWs gets a strong response, but that phrase contains the right level of derision for this dumb idea),the magazine in question is not an extremist or racist one and is well within the mainstream of French politics. The magazine has received many awards for its work and its authors are <a href="http://www.cpj.org/blog/2015/01/charlie-hebdo-attack-unites-france-on-free-express.php">well known and respected within the French journalism community</a>.  As the image to the right shows, the mockery towards religion published by those journalists is nondenominational as many major religions get their dose of mockery from Charlie Hebdo. Perhaps it is true that the authors were trolling Islamic extremists to some extent by publishing cartoons of the Prophet. But that does not make the magazine unacceptably racist. Instead of in opposition to racism, but many of the critics the magazine are instead proposing is that religion should be immune from criticism. That religion is something above other ideologies of beliefs should be treated specially. Religion is treated as some type of immutable characteristic of a person like sex or race. Therefore is street is something that is beyond criticism that any dislike of a given religion amounts to bigotry. This is the same sentiment that got political comedian Bill Maher into trouble after criticizing the growth of Islamic extremism in Europe. The thing is religion should not be treated differently than any other community or ideology or belief system. A religion is just an ideology and belief system with sky fairies. Perhaps it is true that criticism of Islam gets used as a cover for actual anti-Arab racists but, that does not mean that there is no such thing as legitimate criticism of the religion and the rising extremism within it. It is also true that rising immigration into Europe from many authoritarian countries has created new type of resident of Europe, and has created a population of many people dispute fundamental tenants of free and democratic society. <a href="http://www.inquisitr.com/1743767/bill-maher-refuses-to-lay-off-islam-slings-more-insults-on-his-own-show/">As was noted in the controversial edition of Bill Maher's show</a>, almost a quarter of British Muslims believe that the government should execute individuals who have converted away from Islam. This type of extremist ideology certainly deserves all the mockery in criticism that can receive. However many people prefer to deny that it exists at all. These people prefer to believe that terrorism is due to a few lone wolf extremists. Islam in general deserves some criticism for creating an environment where extremism is part of the mainstream. It's a lot like the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/GamerGate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#GamerGate</a> stuff I have discussed earlier in this blog. It's clear that an unusual amount of sexism in toxicity has come from the gaming community compared to other similarly sized Internet communities. And likewise is clear that Islam produces lot more extremism than other major world religions. As Bill Maher put it on a recent episode: <em>"Obviously, the vast majority of Muslims would never do anything like this, But they share bad ideas. This is the thing that caused the big ruckus when Ben Affleck was here. Sam Harris said, 'Islam is the motherlode of bad ideas,' and everyone went fucking nuts on this side of the panel. But it is. These two guys who shot up the cartoonists the other day, they were avenging the prophet, they said? A bad idea. Martyrdom? A bad idea. Women as second-class citizens? A bad idea. And unfortunately, the terrorists and the mainstream share a lot of these bad ideas.</em>" People rightfully saw the error in buuut…  <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotAllGamers" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotAllGamers</a>. Sure there are plenty of gamers who are not sexist trogs, but their community is a magnet for problem types. Now see the same with religion. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/billmaher" class="p-category" rel="tag">#billmaher</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/britishmuslims" class="p-category" rel="tag">#britishmuslims</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/charliehebdo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#charliehebdo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/europe" class="p-category" rel="tag">#europe</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#GamerGate</category>
      <category>#NotAllGamers</category>
      <category>#billmaher</category>
      <category>#britishmuslims</category>
      <category>#charliehebdo</category>
      <category>#europe</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intel's Donation to Diversity Efforts Will Not Remove the Taint Of Sexism in the Company</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/intels-donation-to-diversity-efforts-will-not-remove-the-taint</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/intels-donation-to-diversity-efforts-will-not-remove-the-taint</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 04:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A few months ago Intel decided to take a pro-Gamergate stance and the company pulled advertisements from anti-Gamergate publications. It was clear to everyone (except perhaps for Intel's marketing department) that siding with a movement with a severe problem of harassment of women in the tech industry and sexism would damage the company's image. And of course, it did. [caption id="attachment_1427" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4290983579_ed16d588c9_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4290983579_ed16d588c9_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Intel will sell fewer of these. Image via Flickr user  Leonardo Rizzi  &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7xbpVv</a>" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1427" /&gt; Intel will sell fewer of these. Image via Flickr user  Leonardo Rizzi<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/7xbpVv%5B/caption%5DIntel">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7xbpVv[/<wbr></wbr>caption]Intel</a> received an immediate backlash, and Intel's reputation with OEMs and consumers was damaged as a result. Through direct builds of my own and advice to friends and relatives, I was involved in a number of computer purchases since this incident. All run AMD CPUs. The Intel backing of Gamergate was a non-trivial part of this decision. Intel now has a problem, a problem that they tried to fix by throwing money at the issue. Today <a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2015/01/intel-pledges-300-million-to-improve-diversity-in-tech/">Intel announced their intent to donate $300 million to tech diversity initiatives</a>. However, this is not sufficient to relieve Intel of their issue. The fact that Intel would not only back a toxic movement such as GG, but also back one of their most toxic efforts (an attempt to retaliate against journalists who published articles that GG did not like) indicates a severe problem at Intel's culture. A problem that will take much more than money to fix, and until Intel does that, this scandal will be a black mark on the company's record.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/economybusiness" class="p-category" rel="tag">#economybusiness</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gaming" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gaming</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/leonardorizzi" class="p-category" rel="tag">#leonardorizzi</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scienceandtech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scienceandtech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/todayintel" class="p-category" rel="tag">#todayintel</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#economybusiness</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gaming</category>
      <category>#leonardorizzi</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#scienceandtech</category>
      <category>#todayintel</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More on #Gamergate</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-on-gamergate</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-on-gamergate</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 03:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/message-to-any-reasonable-people-attached-to-gamergate-you-are-scoring-a-own-goal/" title="Message to Any Reasonable People Attached to &lt;a href=" http: class="p-category" rel="tag">#GamerGate</a> : You are Scoring an Own Goal"&gt;previous post on <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> got a fair amount of feedback through various sources. A few followups: <br />A comment on the other post stated that the reason for the persistence of GG is because there isn't any other sources of discussion on the important issues brought up, and that attempts to create another venue have failed. The issue with this line of reasoning is that just bringing up issues isn't good enough. You actually have to convince people on them, and GG seems to be doing negative[caption id="attachment_1445" align="alignright" width="225"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4377235346_cef76f16c6_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4377235346_cef76f16c6_o-225x300.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user Clever Cupcakes &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7ENtyW</a>" width="225" height="300" class="size-medium wp-image-1445" /&gt; Image via Flickr user Clever Cupcakes <a href="https://flic.kr/p/7ENtyW%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7ENtyW[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a> publicity on these issues. The high density of problematic people associated with GG make it hard for any legitimate viewpoints presented through that banners to be heard. And GG was really doomed from the beginning when the likes of 4chan took an active role in the movement. It is very hard for a political movement to recover from a bad start and a negative reputation. And a lot of the antics associated GG have served to make things worse on many issues that GGers care about. That is a lot of the reason that I am not a GGer, I have not seen very much positive impact by GG. But I have seen a lot of negative stuff come from it, plus it is undeniable that GG has at the very least provided a flag of convenience for many trolls and sexists. I have not seen many examples where GG has done more harm than good. Take the issue of censorship. This seems to be something that most GGers will say they care about, but they have made it worse. The aftermath of GG gave the advocates of censorship a legitimate grievance to use as a casus belli and it legitimized the viewpoints of many previously insignificant activists.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/clevercupcakes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#clevercupcakes</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gaming" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gaming</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#GamerGate</category>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#clevercupcakes</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gaming</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Message to Any Reasonable People Attached to #GamerGate : You are Scoring an Own Goal</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/message-to-any-reasonable-people-attached-to-gamergate-you-are</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/message-to-any-reasonable-people-attached-to-gamergate-you-are</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 04:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>This post is a consequence of the fact that I've seen an recent uptick in gamergate related stuff in my twitter feed and elsewhere. It is pretty difficult to define what Gamergate is, and as far as I can tell GGers are more closely defined by what they are against than what they are for. The best reasonably neutrally stated sense of what GG is that I can make is that it a coalition of various groups in opposition to encroachment of feminist activists into the gaming community. Furthermore, the movement was formed as a byproduct of conflicts between internet trolls and internet feminist communities. Well before GG started, trolls from 4chan, 8chan and other trolling groups and communities, realized that the feminist community makes a trolling target which produces a good source of lulz. Gamergate, or at least its prelude, was the crown jewel of this trolling campaign. It is not a coincidence that Gamergate formed around many trolling communities; this includes the likes of 4chan, 8chan, Wizardchan, and[caption id="attachment_1380" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4906597504_3fae1326d2_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4906597504_3fae1326d2_o-300x210.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user Sam Howzit &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8tzAuG</a>" width="300" height="210" class="size-medium wp-image-1380" /&gt; Image via Flickr user Sam Howzit <a href="https://flic.kr/p/8tzAuG%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8tzAuG[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a> <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/josephbernstein/gamergates-headquarters-has-been-destroyed-by-trolls#.ymkD0Mvg3">Niko of Death, one of the leaders of the 8chan gamergate community has recently been exposed as connected</a> to the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gay_Nigger_Association_of_America">GNAA</a> trolling crew (GNAA stands for Gay Nigger Association of America). But is is not safe to say that all, or even most, GGers are trolls. Gamergate came out of the effort of trolls to focus anger at internet feminists in the most lulz producing way possible. Namely trolls at 4chan and such saw that the events which served as the prelude to GG were the perfect opportunity. They realized that there were a number of types of people in the gaming community opposed to feminists, and that good lulz was to be had by blurring the lines, and by uniting them in an incoherent and almost comical message, along with adding a good dose of harassment and threats to the mix. It is even better trolling because it has caused some in progressive/feminist circles to defend some pretty bad stuff -- the enemy of my enemy is my friend apparently.  However, critics of feminism are not a uniform group and the trolling that gave rise to GG was good trolling because of this heterogeneity. These critics and the GG community for the most part, be binned into a handful of groups 1) outright trolls 2) fanboys of certain games who respond virulently to criticism of their favorite games, 3) a number of true sexists,4)conservative activists who have little actual ties to the gaming world , and finally 5) the sub-group with reasonable points. This post is aimed at the last group, a group that I've seen enough of to think exists to an extent. This is also the subset of GG that I think is worth engaging with to some degree, a and that I think makes a number of good points (I will detail this later in the post). And to them I have one question. Why <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/GamerGate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#GamerGate</a>? By associating yourself with a community with so many toxic elements you are destroying the credibility of the reasonable points you make. GG has become so toxic and problematic that anything with even the whif of a Gamergate connection is discredited. One last note, just because I am against GG does not mean that I agree with those facing the fiercest criticism by the GGers, other than to decry the harassment they face.  On this post, I will note that I am open to comments on this article. You can comment here, or tweet at me  @Theo_Jones1  With the comments on this post, I'm going to take a pretty light hand with moderation, due to the nature of the subject.</p>
<h1>The Start of Gamergate</h1>
<p>A time line of the start of gamergate is like this <br />*    The fight between 4chan and  internet feminists serves as a substantial backdrop of the whole gamergate issue.<br />*    Quinn (who is also a critic of video games from a feminist perspective) writes her game on depression. The game gets positive press in some publications.<br />*    It comes out that Quinn cheated on her boyfriend with multiple men due to the fact that the now ex-boyfriend leaked chat logs on to 4chan. Some of the men she had relations with worked at some of the publications that reviewed the Depression Quest game, but none of those people were responsible for any of the reviews.There are allegations that the positive reviews of the game came because of Quinn's sexual activity. This echoed to some extent in the community because in many gaming publications there are concerns about issues like payola and other forms of bias. There is no indication that the people who actually wrote the reviews had any .. um .. personal encounters ... with Quinn, and as far as I can tell there seems to be little basis to these allegations. The whole Quinn thing strikes me as just gossip stuff that has little relation to anything important (other than the trouble created by 4chan). I don't care about the personal life of the people who write the software that I use. I just care if the game is any good.<br />*      4chan and others in the internet trolling community, such as GNAA, think that this would be a good chance to stir up come trouble, considering that Quinn is also a vocal feminist.  The assumption seems to be that a war between elements of the gamer community and femminists over gossip BS would be good lulz. The 4chaners cycle through a few hashtags that have a short life span, such as, <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fiveguys" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fiveguys</a>. Readers of internet forums can now enjoy the flame wars on the subject. <br />*      The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> hashtag is created by Adam Baldwin (who seems to be mainly interested in this because of his conservative politics rather than a interest in gaming). The trolls then move to this and 4chaners move to seed and promote the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> hashtag. The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotYourShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotYourShield</a> tag is later created by a mix of 4chaners and 8chaners. <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotYourShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotYourShield</a> is supposed to be for women/minority GGers. The footprint of trolling can be seen in the selection of these tags, which can easily be interpreted as double entandres. One could say that its <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotYourShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotYourShield</a> instead of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotAShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotAShield</a> for a reason. And <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> itself implys a scandal in gaming, but doesn't say what caused the scandal.<br />*      The dispute extends to other feminists who write about gaming. Anita Sarkeesian , who creates a video series criticizing the portrayal of women in games, gets the brunt of this. Sarkeesian faces death threats and intense harassment. If you are interested, this Wa Po article <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/08/29/gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/"></a><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/08/29/gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.washingtonpost.com/<wbr></wbr>news/<wbr></wbr>morning-mix/<wbr></wbr>wp/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>29/<wbr></wbr>gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/<wbr></wbr></a> has one of her videos. I think there is a lot to criticize about her work (there is strong sexism in gaming, and a lack of serious female characters in games but she overplays here and on this to an extent), but nothing excuses the level of harassment she has received.<br />*     The movement grows to become a general reaction to feminists and other forms of what the GGers affectionately call "social justice warriors". <br />*      None of the above should be interpreted as an endorsement of either Sarkeesian or Quinn. On this issue it is dangerous to assume that the enemy of your enemy is your friend. Quinn seems to be an asshole with some fringe political views. Sarkeesian has made a number of claims and arguments in her videos that are problematic, or just outright wrong, and has been caught plagiarizing footage and screenshots from reviews of the games she criticizes. Both are active in the quite toxic internet feminist community that regularly uses many of the tactics rightfully criticized when used by GGers.</p>
<h1>The Toxic Elements of GG</h1><h2>The Trolls</h2>
<p>I think these guys have been discussed quite a bit already. These are the 4chaners, the 8chaners, the wizardchaners, the GNAAers.</p>
<h2>The Ideologues</h2>
<p>Gamergate quickly attracted a lot of ideological conservatives that have little interest in gaming or any of the controversy surrounding it. There is a reason why conservative rags like Brebiart, and Daily Caller have been the only mainstream publications to take a pro-GG side. This people dislike progressives and feminists and are willing to take the side of anyone who also does.</p>
<h2>The Fanboys</h2>
<p>A large number of GGers seem to be there because their favorite games were insulted. This seems to be the reasoning behind such things as the outrage over the Polygon Review of Tropico. Sure it was a stupid review, but there isn't much more you can reasonably say.</p>
<h2>The Sexists</h2>
<p>Within the GG community there seems to be a heavy presence of MRAs and other forms of sexists. This is hugely problematic.</p>
<h1>Who Are the Reasonable GGers and What Do They Say</h1>
<p>Are you one of the people that I mean when I talk of reasonable GGers? Here are some questions that will help you decide<br />*  Do you oppose the harassment and toxic behavior of some elements in your community?<br />*  Do you oppose the use of boycotts as a tool of censorship even when your side is doing it (the attempts to get advertisers to pull the plug on anti-GG publications)?<br />*  Do you accept that there are some issues with sexism in the gaming community?<br />*  When you speak of "gaming journalism bias", do you have something in mind more than some idiot writing a dumb review of a game you like?<br />*  What is your reason for being a GGer?<br />*  When you speak of opposing censorship, does that include ideas you don't like?</p>

<p>The subset of reasonable people in GG are the ones that I think make some good points. For these people the problem seems to be some of the authoritarian tendencies of the feminist/identity politics left.  Rather than mangle their words, I will quote one of the better things I've seen written by GGers. Note that there is not total agreement here, but these are the points of view worth dealing with to some extent.  This article <a href="http://www.gamepolitics.com/2014/12/30/gamergate-political-attitudes-part-two-old-liberals-vs-new-progressives#.VKSSBM3OphE"></a><a href="http://www.gamepolitics.com/2014/12/30/gamergate-political-attitudes-part-two-old-liberals-vs-new-progressives#.VKSSBM3OphE">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.gamepolitics.com/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>30/<wbr></wbr>gamergate-political-attitudes-part-two-old-liberals-vs-new-progressives#.VKSSBM3OphE</a>   attempts to summarize the politics of gamergate. It goes a bit far in trying to find reasonableness where there is none (i.e with MRAs and such in the GG world). However, the end of that article is worth a read.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Political historians have often remarked that the right won the big economic arguments of the 20th century, while the left won the social and cultural ones. Neo-liberalism rolled back economic socialism in the 1980s, and the cultural left beat the moral majority in the 1990s.<br />...<br />Where once social and cultural issues were a source of unity for the left, they now appear to divide it. While many left-leaning GamerGate supporters continue to show strong support for core “cultural left” positions such as abortion and gay marriage, the results also show that they are completely turned off by any of the more recent additions to the progressive agenda – positive discrimination, “call-out culture,” trigger warnings, safe spaces, etc. And, as we saw in my last piece, their level of trust in the left has been severely shaken. </p>

<p>It would be foolish to assume that debates on these issues are limited to gaming. In the past two years, there have been growing signs of quite serious division on the cultural left. It wasn’t just conservatives who were up in arms about Brendan Eich’s firing – liberal publications like The Atlantic and Slate sounded the alarm as well. Alan Dershowitz is no right-winger, nor is columnist Emily Yoffe, yet the former is leading a campaign of Harvard lawyers against the university’s interpretation of Title IX laws, and the latter’s 9-page critique of the same policies went viral. Guardian columnist Nick Cohen is a leading liberal in the UK, and yet an increasing number of his columns are devoted to critiquing what he sees as a growing culture of censorship and “call-outs” [1, 2, 3].</p>

<p>Battle lines are being quietly, warily drawn in the culture wars – not between conservatives and liberals (although conservatives are certainly aware of what’s going on [1, 2, 3, 4] ) – but between liberals and progressives. These two groups, who once appeared indistinguishable, are becoming more so. Liberals are increasingly concerned by what they see as progressives’ embrace of vigilantism. Progressives, by contrast, seem increasingly concerned with the need to change culture by any means possible.</p>
</blockquote><h1>Why The Reasonables Should Disavow GG</h1>
<p>I would agree with a large portion of the previously quote. But people of that nature really should stay clear of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a>. Gamergate has a clear density of outright sexists, trolls, and other types that are bad news. You do not want to give those toxic types a platform. You do not want your reasonable ideas associated with that harassers, and sexists. You want to make it clear that you do not like sexism, while still disputing censorship and authoritarianism. Being part of GG will not help you at all in this. In fact, it will discredit any good idea you have. By promoting a community like gamergate you will score a huge own goal, and will be the biggest help that your opposition could wish for.</p>

<p>Edit to this post: spelling and grammar.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/adambaldwin" class="p-category" rel="tag">#adambaldwin</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/computersecurityandtrolling" class="p-category" rel="tag">#computersecurityandtrolling</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gaming" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gaming</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gnaa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gnaa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/samhowzit" class="p-category" rel="tag">#samhowzit</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#GamerGate</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#fiveguys</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#NotYourShield</category>
      <category>#NotYourShield</category>
      <category>#NotYourShield</category>
      <category>#NotAShield</category>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#adambaldwin</category>
      <category>#computersecurityandtrolling</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gaming</category>
      <category>#gnaa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#samhowzit</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
