<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/bookmarkedpages/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/bookmarkedpages/?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Fetal Attraction: Abortion and the Principle of Charity | Slate Star Codex</title>
      <link>http://slatestarcodex.com/2013/05/30/fetal-attraction-abortion-and-the-principle-of-charity/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/fetal-attraction-abortion-and-the-principle-of-charity-slate-star</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 06:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p><em>"But I’m more optimistic! If you debate pro-lifers on the object-level issues like “Does a woman’s right to privacy outweigh a fetus’ right to life” or some other horrible muddled version of the question like that, then no, you will never be able to make progress. But if you devote yourself to the actual substantive disagreement – which is on the level of what meta-ethics to use or maybe even further back – then you can either change some minds or, at the very least “be confused on a higher level and about more important things”. This continues to be my strategy and I’m pretty happy with how it’s worked out."</em></p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That&#x2019;s Racist! | &#x3B4;&#x3B9;&#x3AC; &#x3C0;&#x3AD;&#x3BD;&#x3C4;&#x3B5; / dia pente</title>
      <link>https://deusdiapente.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/thats-racist/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/thats-racist-dia-pente</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 05:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Anyway, this makes me go back to my religion focus. Why would these social justice movements have rhetoric whose underlying structure is alarmingly religious in nature? Probably because what’s effective socially isn’t restricted to time and space. It’s not that religious-logic is inherently due to religion itself, but it’s due to how our brains are wired for social cohesion and ostracism. It’s probably no coincidence that the most successful social justice movement in the 20th century was spearheaded by a man who earned his doctorate in theology. Religion, civil rights, feminism, pro/anti-semitism, etc. are all inherently political in nature (the strict demarcation of politics and religion is a product of the Enlightenment for — surprise — social purposes. Of course, Islam had no Enlightenment so they are still one and the same for Muslims) and so religion, civil rights, feminism, pro/anti-semitism, etc. are all mind-killers:"</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Sexist' Scientist Tim Hunt: The Real Story - Reason.com</title>
      <link>https://reason.com/archives/2015/07/23/sexist-scientist-tim-hunt-the-real-story/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/sexist-scientist-tim-hunt-the-real-story---reasoncom</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 05:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"This is particularly shameful given that Hunt is not only a great scientist but, by many accounts, a genuine friend to women in science. There are numerous testimonials from women describing him as a caring and inspirational mentor, one who never treated his female students and colleagues differently from their male peers and has aided in their advancement. European Research Council president Jean-Pierre Bourguignon is on record as saying that Hunt "actively supported" the Council’s initiatives to support women in science. The only charge of sexism anyone has tried to pin on him beyond his ill-considered remarks in Seoul is a 2014 interview in which he dared to suggest that the numerical disparities between men and women in science are not necessarily a huge problem. But this hardly means, as fellow UCL scientist David Colquhoun has insinuated on his blog, that Hunt also seriously believes women shouldn’t work in science alongside men. (Ironically, as Mensch has discovered, Colquhoun himself had to field accusations of sexism on Twitter only a few months ago after voicing the heretical opinions that the paucity of women in senior scientific positions was due to different family roles, not sexism"</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture Wars Battle of the Week | Where Worlds Collide</title>
      <link>http://www.kalyr.com/weblog/uncategorized/culture-wars-battle-of-the-week/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/culture-wars-battle-of-the-week-where-worlds-collide</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 03:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Ah yes, the old “It’s just banter” defence. That worked so well when used by racist footballers. My own use of social media follows the principle “Never say on Twitter what you can’t justify to your employer or your mum”. That would have been good advice for Bahar Mustafa, or indeed anyone in a highly visible public position."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Royal Throne of Feels: Popehat on Bahar Mustapha | Where Worlds Collide</title>
      <link>http://www.kalyr.com/weblog/rants/this-royal-throne-of-feels-popehat-on-bahar-mustapha/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-royal-throne-of-feels-popehat-on-bahar-mustapha-where</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 03:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"I have very little time for the speech-policing identity politics driven by postmodernist critical theory that’s taken root in parts of academia and the media; it’s profoundly illiberal. But if freedom of speech is to mean anything at all, it means the right to speak ill-informed complete cobblers that others may find offensive. And the right to ridicule that ill-informed complete cobblers without mercy."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I Upgrade to Mac OS X El Capitan?</title>
      <link>http://lifehacker.com/should-i-upgrade-to-mac-os-x-el-capitan-1733465450</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/should-i-upgrade-to-mac-os-x-el-capitan</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 03:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"One thing in El Capitan you might want to pay attention to is a new security feature called System Integrity Protection (SIP), which has the potential to break some apps. In short, Apple introduced it as a way to limit even the level of access that root users and processes have, and to protect core components of the OS. That means there are some things you won’t be able to do, even if you have and use root. You can read the nitty gritty over at Ars Technica. This also means some applications that leverage root won’t work anymore—one notable example is Bartender, before it was recently updated with El Capitan support. It’s not a huge problem, and you can disable it, but in all reality most people won’t need to and shouldn’t have to. However, some programs may need to be updated before they’ll work—and if you’re using some long-abandoned apps that have worked up to this point and they break, well, they could be dead for good, and you’ll have to make the call to disable it or find an alternative."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Royal Throne of Feels, This Sheltered Isle, This England | Popehat</title>
      <link>https://popehat.com/2015/10/06/this-royal-throne-of-feels-this-sheltered-isle-this-england/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-royal-throne-of-feels-this-sheltered-isle-this-england</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 03:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    
<p>"First, you censorious Guardians of Feels on the Left: if you thought that the norms you created wouldn't be used against your "own side," you're fools. It is apparently your theory that the law is sexist, racist, and every other -ist, driven by privilege and wealth, and that free speech norms serve to protect rich white guys — yet somehow exceptions to free speech norm will be imposed in an egalitarian, progressive way. That is almost indescribably moronic. Go sit in the corner and think about what you have done."</p>
</div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join Uber in a tale of rent seeking and employment law &#x2022; The Register</title>
      <link>http://www.theregister.co.uk/2015/10/07/uber_tale_of_rent_seeking_network_effects_and_employment_law/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/join-uber-in-a-tale-of-rent-seeking-and-employment</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 03:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"The first is one well known to youse guys in the tech industry: network effects. The first fax machine isn't all that much use and every other one added to the network adds to the usefulness of every other one. This is obviously true of Facebitch, of the internet in general and so on: and it's also true, to some extent at least, of the gig and sharing economy behemoths like Airbnb and Uber. The more people that use them the more supply there will be for people to use, attracting more people and so on. So, the game that, as organisations, all of these people are engaging in is the attempt to be the network for whatever it is; eBay for tchotchke, Uber for transportation, Google for ad slinging and Amazon for, erm, tchotchke."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Office 2016 For Mac Is Unstable On El Capitan</title>
      <link>https://www.thurrott.com/cloud/office-365/6389/office-2016-for-mac-is-unstable-on-el-capitan-be-careful-if-you-upgrade</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/office-2016-for-mac-is-unstable-on-el-capitan</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 03:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Today is the day that Apple is releasing El Capitan for users around the globe and if you are thinking about running the latest version of Office 2016 with this new OS, you need to be aware of performance issues. I have been running the GM candidates and the release build of El Capitan since it was first announced by Apple as well as running the release version of Office 2016 for Mac and the experience is atrocious. I am not alone in this either, there is a lengthy thread in Microsoft’s Answer forums that is filled with other users who have the same issue and users on Twitter are quite vocal about problem as well."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polis Fallout Continues Despite Apology for Saying Innocent Students Should Be Expelled - FIRE</title>
      <link>https://www.thefire.org/polis-fallout-continues-despite-apology-for-saying-innocent-students-should-be-expelled/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/polis-fallout-continues-despite-apology-for-saying-innocent-students-should</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 05:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Representative Jared Polis took to his hometown paper, The Daily Camera, last week to apologize for his “spectacularly bad idea” that colleges and universities should expel students at the mere accusation of sexual assault, but the fallout for the Boulder, Colorado representative continues. Polis made the comments—which included the assertion that if 10 students were accused of sexual assault and only “maybe one or two did it,” the university should “get rid of all 10”— while questioning FIRE Legislative and Policy Director Joe Cohn at a congressional hearing earlier this month. That statement, which flies in the face of both constitutional due process protections and common sense, has been widely rebuked. Making matters worse for Polis, his mea culpa has been called halfhearted, as it appears to double down on some downright dangerous ideas about due process."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
