<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Why I am Against GMO Labeling</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-against-gmo-labeling</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-against-gmo-labeling?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am Against GMO Labeling</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-against-gmo-labeling</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-against-gmo-labeling</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In a previous post I discussed the <a title="The Ludditeism of the Anti-GMO Ideologues" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/ludditeism-anti-gmo-ideologues/">bankruptcy of anti-GMO arguments</a>. Now I will discuss why GMO labeling is a terrible idea.</p>
<ol><li>As I showed in my last post there is no scientific basis to fear GMO products.</li>
    <li>The claimed consumer choice benefits of mandatory labeling can be fulfilled by private certifications and currently existing, government ran certification programs</li>
    <li>Due to the dynamics of food markets, mandatory GMO labeling amounts to a defacto GMO ban. This will increase food prices and possibly add to the environmental damage cause by agriculture.</li>
</ol>
<p><!--more-->If you haven't read my previous post on GMOs, let me recap what I said about the health effects of these products.</p>

<p>The claims made by the campaigners against genetically modified foods are simply absurd. This ideology’s claims about the health effects of GMOs are as discredited in the scientific community as creationism or global warming denialism and all major scientific associations of reputethat have looked into the issue disavow it.  Their position that a compound can suddenly become toxic when synthesized due to a genetic modification of a plant, but is not toxic when synthesized by a natural process violates the laws of physics, chemistry and biology. Their understanding of the economics of these products is not much better. These compounds have passed the approval of the FDA and the EPA. Your food is not being poisoned by <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">the Illuminati</span> Monsanto. The <a href="http://www.who.int/foodsafety/publications/biotech/20questions/en/">World Health Organization notes</a>, "GM foods currently available on the international market have passed risk assessments and are not likely to present risks for human health". <a href="http://www.aaas.org/news/aaas-board-directors-legally-mandating-gm-food-labels-could-%E2%80%9Cmislead-and-falsely-alarm">The American Association for the Advancement of Science concluded that</a> "Several current efforts to require labeling of GM foods are not being driven by any credible scientific evidence that these foods are dangerous" and that "GM crops are the most extensively tested crops ever". Their report also noted that labeling could “mislead and falsely alarm consumers”.</p>

<p>All of the claimed consumer choice benefits of GMO labeling can be done by voluntary certification. All products currently sold as organic in the U.S lack GMO products. Private certifications are also very good at assuring that products are prepared in accordance to standards that are sufficient for their consumers. Note that there are many private companies which certify kosher products.</p>

<p>Economies of scale in food production make it inefficient and cost prohibitive for companies to create separate product lines with GMO and non-GMO foods. Therefore, just one of these options will be taken.If the labeling causes a substantial minority of the population to avoid GMO foods then these foods will be forced off the market for everyone. This has already happened in Europe, where GMO labeling is mandatory. In fact, the push for labeling by the anti-GMO movement is just a pretext to regulate these products out of existence.This will harm consumers and the environment because GMO products require less land usage than their competitors. The price of this extra land will be passed on to consumers, along with the price of increased crop loss. This increased land usage will also have substantial environmental impacts. However, there will be no clear economic benefits to this defacto ban on GMO foods.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/epa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#epa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fda" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fda</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/illuminatimonsanto" class="p-category" rel="tag">#illuminatimonsanto</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#epa</category>
      <category>#fda</category>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#illuminatimonsanto</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
