<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>An Interesting Article On Racism in Israel</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>An Interesting Article On Racism in Israel</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><a href="http://www.haaretz.com/mobile/.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2"></a><a href="http://www.haaretz.com/mobile/.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.haaretz.com/<wbr></wbr>mobile/<wbr></wbr>.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2</a></p><p>The linked article features a discussion of the growth of racism in the Isreali school system. A choice quote is as follows.  </p><blockquote><p>“For me, personally, Arabs are something I can’t look at and can’t stand,” a 10th-grade girl from a high school in the central part of the country says in abominable Hebrew. “<strong>I am tremendously racist. I come from a racist home. If I get the chance in the army to shoot one of them, I won’t think twice.</strong> I’m ready to kill someone with my hands, and it’s an Arab. In my education I learned that ... their education is to be terrorists, and there is no belief in them. I live in an area of Arabs, and every day I see these Ishmaelites, who pass by the [bus] station and whistle. I wish them death.”</p></blockquote><p>Emphasis added. </p><p>What type of person thinks being "tremendously racist" is something to brag to journalists about? And what does it say about the nation that churns out students who think like this? Now, viewpoints this extreme seem to still be in the miniority, but they seem way to common. This point of view is also deeply influential on politics, with strong hostility to the "leftists" that oppose the policies of the Isreali government</p><blockquote><p>A year later, however, the incident itself was still remembered in the school. The same student who told Yaron that she won’t think twice if she gets the opportunity “to shoot one of them” when she serves in the army, also said, “As soon as I heard about the quarrel with that leftist girl [Michal], I was ready to throw a brick at her head and kill her. In my opinion, all the leftists are Israel-haters. I personally find it very painful. Those people have no place in our country – both the Arabs and the leftists.”</p></blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
