<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics and Externalities</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/economics-and-externalities</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/economics-and-externalities?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Economics and Externalities</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/economics-and-externalities</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/economics-and-externalities</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 17:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I will discuss the economics of externalities. An externality is a cost of producing something that is not materialized in the price charged (or any other cost) to a willing participant in that transaction. This is problematic because the cost of a thing is highly tied to the level of demand for it. In general, when the cost of something is lower then people buy more of it. When, in the case of an externality, a large part of the cost of something is on other people then the consumers will bear less than the full cost of that thing and will therefore want to buy more of it than is generally socially desirable. Climate change, of course produces an externality. Because a large number of the costs of fossil fuels are on third parties consumers will buy more of these fuels than is desirable, and favor these fuels over alternatives to an extent that is unmerited. Of course, in the real world things are usually not as simple as a simple case where we can place the full weight of the blame for the externality-producing condition on a single person.Even on the climate change issue we can come up with situations where people other than polluters are to blame for some impacts. Take for instance the case of someone who purchases a house in an area that is becoming increasingly flood prone due to climate change, and is flooded out due to that risk. It it clear that this person experienced an externality due to the greenhouse gas pollution, but it is also arguable that the home-buyer was responsible for part of this harm. Policy makers will have to sort out this type of issue when making climate policy. But despite this objection, the externality model is still a good way to theorize about the effects of climate change. </p><p>The government has multiple ways to adjust individual intensives to deal with externalities problem. It could pass a regulation that bans a externality-producing activity. Or it could pass a tax on the activity. The tax could raise the cost of the activity, thereby bringing its paid cost in line with its true cost. It could do a cap and trade type regulation whereby a limit is set on the amount of the activity allowed, and the permits to do the activity are auctioned off. The government could also subsidize the alternative's to the activity. </p><p>The regulation method is at the core of command and control type responses to climate change. These have the possibility of being relativity egalitarian in their distributional impacts. But they also have the possibility of being the most inefficient. These methods mandate the same abatement methods uniformly, and fail to encourage other resolutions to climate change. Local laws and urban planning changes will have a strong role in mitigating climate change. I also think that governments should pass regulations that commit to the shutdown of polluting industries. Additionally, direct regulation and civil litigation is particularly effective at targeting industries that are in countries that do not have an effective climate policy.  I will discuss the role that I think direct regulation should have in an energy policy in an later post.</p><p>The taxing method in the climate change world is known as a carbon tax. It has the benefit of allowing free consumer choice while still providing for a strong incentive to switch. A tax works by directly increasing the cost of the extenality-producing pollution. This is in order to make the effective cost that consumers face when buying products equal to the real cost of the polluting energy involved. Carbon taxes provide incentive to reduce pollution, while still allowing for individual choice. The huge counter argument to a climate policy that relies on carbon taxes is the fact that they provide no guarantee that the CO2 emissions will fall to their target level. This is problematic because the optimal level of CO2 emissions is effectively zero.</p><p>A related option to a carbon tax is a cap and trade program. In a cap and trade system a finite number of permits to pollute are distributed. This provides a stable emissions reduction at the expense of stability of the price of carbon.  Because they target the level of CO2 emissions, not the price of these emissions they have the benefit of being more responsive to economic conditions. If there is high inflation, the real/effective carbon tax will be reduced because the money used to pay the tax is worth less, but with a cap and trade the price will quickly adjust.  Distributing the permits is also a design issue for cap and trade programs. Many cap and trade programs distribute the credits to firms based on past pollution. I believe that this is generally a bad idea and instead the permits should just be auctioned off. Both cap and trade programs and carbon taxes have potential distributional issues. That is, without any attempt to mitigate their effects they have the potential to effect the poor more than the wealthy. </p><p>Subsidies work by reducing the cost of alternatives to the externalities. In regards the the climate change issue the government can fund investment in  clean energy sources, and in energy conservation methods. The reduction of cost of alternative energies will cause consumers to switch over to them. Subsidies have strong distributional benefits, while still allowing more consumer choice is designed right.However, they can also cause overconsumption of energy. Subsidizes can also include methods such as public works projects that build infrastructure. As I will discuss further in the section on French investment in nuclear energy,  subsidizes have one huge advantage. They can overcome the problems of imperfect information and short term bias in investment. Companies are often under pressure to bring forth a short term profit, and this will often mean that they will forgo long-term investments that will cost more in the short run, but bring longer run benefits. Government subsidy policy can overcome this issue and can be used to encourage the longer term investment. Companies also face a high degree of risk due to their lack of knowledge. Some investments have a high possible return, but a high risk. Because companies can not afford a large loss, they will be risk adverse and will forgo high-risk, high-return investments. Government policy can change this. Imperfect information also bites companies in a different way. The profitability of an investment -- particularly in the energy world -- can strongly depend on what the competitors of a company are doing. There are cases where companies can compete in an mutually destructive way, or an uncoordinated way. Government subsidy policy and indirect planning can provide a way to coordinate the actions of firms. This will improve the efficiency of markets. </p><p>In a more controversial economic note I will discuss my opinions on how inequality effects the efficiency of markets. Of course, there are many economists that would disagree with what I am about to say in this paragraph. Purely market based programs have one Achilles' Heel though. Their economic efficiency is dependent on the assumption that monetary value (the amount of money that someone would give up for a benefit) is equal to the associated change in well being. Economists call this a linear welfare function -- with "welfare" in this circumstance referring to well being. This is a questionable assumption. In reality, the relation between market efficiency in the since that advocates of a market-based solution to global warming discuss, and the real welfare of the populace are often in conflict. This conflict is particularly strong when there is high inequality in the economic system.This economic inequality makes prices into something that depends as much on ability to pay as actual need. I also would argue that all preferences are not equal. An wealthy person's preference to convert grains into biofuels to save money on fuel is of much lower value than the preference of a poor person to eat the grains. In regards to how resources should be distributed, my thinking is along the line of the "difference principle" that has been often discussed in the political philosophy literature -- the well worst off groups in society should be maximized, even if this means reduced over all economic production. This factor means that countries who want to conduct an effective climate change policy will also need to enact anti-poverty measures along with their climate change mitigation policy.  Additionally, because global inequality is even higher than the level of inequality that prevails within nations there will necessarily be a role for command and control regulation, and indirect economic planning through subsidizes. Without these more hands on policies the world's poor will face severe harms from the climate change mitigation policies that should help them. Additionally, the effects that inequality has on market efficiency will mean that a much more rapid climate change policy will be needed than what would be justified by a purely economic cost benefit analysis. In reality a sustainable energy plan would need to use all four of the methods of changing incentives. All of these methods have their benefits in some circumstances. </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/achillesheel" class="p-category" rel="tag">#achillesheel</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#achillesheel</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
