<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Is The Economy Separate From the Political System</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-the-economy-separate-from-the-political-system</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-the-economy-separate-from-the-political-system?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Is The Economy Separate From the Political System</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-the-economy-separate-from-the-political-system</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-the-economy-separate-from-the-political-system</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 13:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In this post I will argue that the economy is fundamentally part of the political system and not some separate thing. By extension I will argue that economics should not be considered a separate field but instead  should be considered as part of the theory of politics and political science. <a href="http://economics.about.com/od/economics-basics/a/What-Is-Economics.htm">Lets start with looking at a common definition of economics. </a>  Emphasis added. [caption id="attachment_1454" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/4744388119_4afba167a4_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/4744388119_4afba167a4_o-300x199.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user  JD Hancock &lt;a href=" https: rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8efeia</a>" width="300" height="199" class="size-medium wp-image-1454" /&gt; Image via Flickr user  JD Hancock<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/8efeia%5B/caption%5D" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8efeia[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Simply, and perhaps surprisingly put,<strong> economics is the study of scarcity</strong>. Resources are limited, and every society wants to figure out how to allocate its resources for maximum benefit. The field of economics serves in large part to help answer this resource allocation question. Economists study topics such as:  <br />How prices and quantities of items are determined in market economies  <br />How much value markets create for society  <br />How taxes and regulation affect economic value  <br />Why some goods and services are under-supplied in a market economy  <br />How firms compete and maximize profit  <br />How households decide what to consume, how much to save, and how much to work (or, more generally, how people respond to incentives)  <br />Why some economies grow faster than others  <br />What effect monetary and fiscal policy has on economic well-being  <br />How interest rates are determined</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This definition argues that the allocation of goods under scarcity is the defining factor of economics, and by extension the difference between the general political system and the economy. However, all institutions work to allocate goods under scarcity. Without scarcity there would be no need for a government and anarchism would be a functioning system. Politics is about scarcity as much as economics. Likewise the examples used in the quoted section all assume some kind of market existing outside of the government and political system. But the market is fundamentally a creature of this system. The government decides how contracts will be made (if you think that there is some kind of natural contract law look at how much this law has varied between societies over history).The government sets the broad outlines of what is sold, it sets the question of who has the authority to make decisions within the businesses in the market. The government sets the outlines of property rights, and determines what can be owned, and how this ownership can be obtained. It creates the currency system. Markets cannot exist in a stable fashion without governments. Governments have shaped every economic intuitions. There is no economy or set of economic institutions that is separate from the political system as a whole. There is no distinction between economics and the study of the political system as a whole.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
