<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>The Beginning of Renewable Energy</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Renewable Energy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 07:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>The first energy sources in wide use by human civilization were of course renewable, but in the late 19th century the foundations of the renewable energy industry as we know it were built. While the direct use of energy from wind and water are ancient, solar was the first renewable energy source to be widely researched for electricity production. This early investment in solar was driven primarily by the concerns I <a title="Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply/">mentioned in the last post</a> that coal supplies could run out. French researcher Augustine Mouchot wrote the following</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The time will arrive when the industry of Europe will cease to find those natural resources, so necessary for it. Petroleum springs and coal mines are not inexhaustible but are rapidly diminishing in many places. Will man, then, return to the power of water and wind? Or will he emigrate where the most powerful source of heat sends its rays to all? History will show what will come.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://solarenergy.com/power-panels/history-solar-energy">In 1860 a patent was granted to Mouchot</a> for inventing a system that could generate steam though solar energy and use it to run a motor --- an early concentrated solar energy system. With funding from the French government Mouchot worked on scaling this invention up to an industrial scale. Mouchot created prototype water pumps and refrigration systems using solar energy and worked on deploying this in sunny Algeria. This system relied on a set of parabolic mirrors. However, parabolic mirrors are strongly limited in size and therefore can only have limited production. This doomed Mouchot designs. In 1881 the French Ministry of Public Works comissioned a report on the economics of solar energy produced by Mouchot's method and found the method to not be economically viable. William Adams, then the deputy registrar for the English Crown in Bombay further improved Mouchot's design. He came up with an innovation that underlies most modern concentrated solar energy systems. Adams realized that the limits of system production and mirror size would pretty much go away if instead of simple parabolic mirrors the system used series of mirrors in a flat shape. Flat mirrors can easily be chained together in to a large, connected system. Adams' conducted this chaining by placing the mirrors in a circular arrangement and focusing the mirrors towards central point. This exact setup is known today as a power tower, and is still in widespread use for electricity production.  Adams' system used 17-by-10-inch flat mirrors, and with 72 of these mirrors he could run a conventional  2.5  horsepower steam engine during all daytime hours. He penned a book titled <em>Solar heat: A substitute for fuel in tropical countries for heating steam boilers, and other purposes</em> on this subject. While impressive, this method was not good enough to compete with coal as an energy source with the technology available to Adams. Around this time American engineer John Ericsson came up with a third way to design a concentrated solar system --- a parabolic trough. Through each trough runs a pipe and through the pipe runs water that is boiled by the solar heat. This design has large benefits in terms of cost and is currently the most common method for large scale commercial use. Adams eventually became disenchanted with solar energy and stopped working on the technology due to failure to come up with a practical way to put it to use. Mouchot failed to come up with an improved design of his method. However other researchers persisted with concentrated solar technology. Engineer Charles Tellier created a solar refrigeration method based around an ammonia coolant. The core of this method can be found in modern electric refrigerators, but usually without solar energy. Aubrey Eneas founded the first solar energy company in 1900 and sold solar powered irrigation systems. These system were effective, but their parabolic collectors could easily be damaged by weather, and the company soon failed due to the problem of collectors being damaged beyond repair.  Henry E. Willsie also attempted to commercialize solar power --- focusing on electricity generation. He designed a thermal energy storage system that allowed energy to be produced all day. This system was cost competitive with coal and was marketed as "designed for furnishing power for electric light and power, refrigerating and ice making, for milling and pumping at mines, and for other purposes where large amounts of power are required." However, solar still had one big disadvantage compared to coal. With almost all sustainable energy technologies (even with today's technology) the main cost is up-front. Solar collectors are large and expensive, but they don't need any fuel, and the labor costs involved in their maintenance are small. With coal, building the furnace is cheap , but the coal itself is expensive. This means that solar (and all other sustainable energy technology, including nuclear) have costs that are almost all fixed. That is the cost of running the system at any output is about the same as running it at any output. This increases the risk of an investment in such a tech and as we will see in later posts in this series, it has economic implications for the wide deployment of sustainable energy and the commercial pricing of it.</p>

<p>In 1876 the photovoltaic effect was observed to occur in selenium by William Adams. This discovery enabled the creation of the first solar cells. In 1883 inventor <a href="http://inventors.about.com/od/timelines/a/Photovoltaics.htm">Charles Fritts used that discovery to create the first solar photovoltaic cell</a>. This cell was very expensive and was far from competitive with coal and other fossil fuels. It also was very inefficient at converting sunlight to electricity compared to modern technology. Throughout the early 20th century, researchers refined their knowledge of the theoretical basis of the photovoltaic effect. However, none of these early photovoltaic cells were nearly as efficient as modern ones. Additionally, all of these earily cells were extremely expensive. It wasn't until the development of modern semiconductor fabrication technology that solar PV cells came down to a reasonable price.</p>

<p>Biomass and biofuels energy also had a substantial growth during this period. In fact, the first liquid automotive fuels were not petroleum but biofuels. William K. Vanderbilt favored ethanol due to its higher performance -- particularly in racing. For this reason car racing sports widely use alcohol fuels even today (although this is usually methanol, which is far to dangerous for consumer use). However all commercially viable biofuels (even today) use feed stocks that compete with food production. Due to this issue petroleum soon became the dominant fuel source.This triggered the first research into cellulose based fuels. In 1925 Henry Ford stated that “The fuel of the future is going to come from fruit like that sumac out by the road, or from apples, weeds, sawdust — almost anything.” But celluloseic fuels have turned out to be the renewable energy equivalent to fusion power. Always 30 years away, and always facing key failings. However, fission power actually works, conventional biofuels do not. The modern attempts to implement conventional biofuels have been completely disastrous due to the food versus fuel issue. Furthermore, due to the inherent limits to crop production it is unclear that any method could solve  these issues. I would suggest that biofuel production should be halted and that the production or importation of these fuels should be illegal even for hobbyist uses or research. Heavy research should be put into alternative ways to make synthetic fuels, further discussion of these methods will be discussed in later posts. History shows that our best energy bets can be found in the atom (I will discuss nuclear energy more in a later post),and in solar power.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aubreyeneas" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aubreyeneas</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/charlesfritts" class="p-category" rel="tag">#charlesfritts</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/henryford" class="p-category" rel="tag">#henryford</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/williamadams" class="p-category" rel="tag">#williamadams</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aubreyeneas</category>
      <category>#charlesfritts</category>
      <category>#henryford</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#williamadams</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
