<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>The Legal Basis Behind the Gay Marriage Lawsuits</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Legal Basis Behind the Gay Marriage Lawsuits</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 17:40:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Another day, another lawsuit challenging laws prohibiting gay marriage. <a href="http://www.latinpost.com/articles/16225/20140806/north-dakota-officials-urge-dismissal-lawsuit-challenging-gay-marriage-ban.htm">This time</a> the state of North Dakota is having its law challenged. North Dakota's <span style="color: #000000;">solicitor general has filed a motion disputing the claims in the lawsuit and seeks the lawsuit dismissed. Judging by how other courts have dealt with this issue the solicitor general probably won't get his way. In a post written before the recent lawsuits, <a title="If you love freedom, vote to allow gay marriage" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage/">I argued that gay marriage prohibitions are likely not constitutional, and even if they were should be opposed on policy grounds</a>. In this post I will discus the legal basis for this litigation. The cases are based</span></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1351" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6685160247_5e2fbc8e78_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1351" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6685160247_5e2fbc8e78_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user Janet Lindenmuth &lt;a href=" https: rel="in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>bbKcez</a>" width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via Flickr user Janet Lindenmuth <a href="https://flic.kr/p/bbKcez%5B/caption%5D" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>bbKcez[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p><span style="color: #000000;">around section 1 of the 14th amendment which reads </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p>All persons born or naturalized in the United States, and subject to the jurisdiction thereof, are citizens of the United States and of the State wherein they reside. No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law;<strong> nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasis added. The bolded part is the equal protection clause. The courts interpret this based on three standards of scrutiny.The higher standards are only applied to certain protected classes. For a law that targets a group of people to pass the scrutiny of the courts, the law must meet standards that vary based on the scrutiny test applied.</p>
<ol><li>Strict Scrutiny. This standard is applied to laws that impact a fundamental right (i.e one in the Bill of Rights). More relevant to this case is the fact that this standard is used in regards to some protected classes, particularly race.   To pass this standard the government must have a compelling governmental interest, the legislation must be narrowly tailored to fulfill the interest, and must be the least restrictive means of meeting the interest. This is the most stringent of the standards.</li>
    <li>Intermediate Scrutiny. This is the standard that applies on the basis of sex/gender discrimination, among other protected classes.To pass this standard a law must further important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest</li>
    <li>The third standard is the rational basis test. It has two poorly defined sub-types. The cases where each is used have not been well defined.
<ol><li>Regular rational basis -- this is the generic standard that applies to all laws. It is nearly all permissive. A law has to be rationally related to a legitimate government interest. This legitimate government interest does not need to be the actual reason for the law nor do the costs of the legislation have to be proportionate to the interest.</li>
    <li>Rational basis with teeth. This is a poorly defined heightened version of the rational basis test This adds to the regular rational basis standard by declaring that the interest must be strong enough that a reasonable and impartial legislature could come to the conclusion that the legislation is justified. The gay marriage related cases that have involved rational basis have used this standard.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p>Now we need to figure out which one of these standards to apply to gay marriage. Unfortunately, the Supreme Court has not stated which of these standards applies to gay rights, nor has it provided clear guidelines for determining which groups are protected by which standards. The selection of a scrutiny standard is to an extent arbitrary. I would argue for intermediate scrutiny on the grounds that discrimination against LGBT groups is analogous to discrimination on the basis of sex. We shall see what the courts will do with this issue. So far, the lower courts and state that have dealt with this issue have picked every one of the possibilities. The selection of the scrutiny standard is critical to the outcome of the lawsuits on gay marriage. A determination of strict scrutiny or intermediate scrutiny will close the case in the favor of gay rights. This is because strict scrutiny pretty much is a complete prohibition of discrimination ,and intermediate scrutiny severely bounds and puts strong limits the range of possible discrimination. It is severely unlikely that the states will be able to find the needed important government interest to meet intermediate scrutiny. A determination of rational basis with teeth will favor gay rights, but will leave a possibility that the state could still snatch a victory, as they will have difficulties showing an actual and substantial harm caused by allowing gay marriage. A finding of normal rational basis will be a clear victory for the states, as normal rational basis is nearly all permissive.</p>

<p>It is worth noting that I think that this whole standards of scrutiny system for the equal protection clause is a Rube Goldberg system. I will leave you with thoughts from Justice Stevens on this from <em><a href="http://law2.umkc.edu/faculty/projects/ftrials/conlaw/cleburne.html">City of Cleburne v. Cleburne Living Center</a></em> (1985)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I am inclined to believe that what has become known as the [tiered] analysis of equal protection claims does not describe a completely logical method of deciding cases, but rather is a method the Court has employed to explain decisions that actually apply a single standard in a reasonably consistent fashion." In my own approach to these cases, I have always asked myself whether I could find a "rational basis" for the classification at issue. The term "rational," of course, includes a requirement that an impartial lawmaker could logically believe that the classification would serve a legitimate public purpose that transcends the harm to the members of the disadvantaged class. Thus, the word "rational" -- for me at least -- includes elements of legitimacy and neutrality that must always characterize the performance of the sovereign's duty to govern impartially.</p>

<p>The rational-basis test, properly understood, adequately explains why a law that deprives a person of the right to vote because his skin has a different pigmentation than that of other voters violates the Equal Protection Clause. It would be utterly irrational to limit the franchise on the basis of height or weight; it is equally invalid to limit it on the basis of skin color. None of these attributes has any bearing at all on the citizen's willingness or ability to exercise that civil right. We do not need to apply a special standard, or to apply "strict scrutiny," or even "heightened scrutiny," to decide such cases.</p>

<p>In every equal protection case, we have to ask certain basic questions. What class is harmed by the legislation, and has it been subjected to a "tradition of disfavor" by our laws? What is the public purpose that is being served by the law? What is the characteristic of the disadvantaged class that justifies the disparate treatment? In most cases the answer to these questions will tell us whether the statute has a "rational basis." The answers will result in the virtually automatic invalidation of racial classifications and in the validation of most economic classifications, but they will provide differing results in cases involving classifications based on alienage, gender, or illegitimacy. But that is not because we apply an "intermediate standard of review" in these cases; rather it is because the characteristics of these groups are sometimes relevant and sometimes irrelevant to a valid public purpose, or, more specifically, to the purpose that the challenged laws purportedly intended to serve</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/intermediatescrutiny" class="p-category" rel="tag">#intermediatescrutiny</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/northdakota" class="p-category" rel="tag">#northdakota</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rubegoldberg" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rubegoldberg</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#000000</category>
      <category>#000000</category>
      <category>#intermediatescrutiny</category>
      <category>#northdakota</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#rubegoldberg</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
