<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>The Problems With Using Cost-Benefit Analysis In Climate Change Policy</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Problems With Using Cost-Benefit Analysis In Climate Change Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><i><a href="https://theojones.name/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">This is part of a blog post series on climate change.</a></i>In this post I will discuss how a cost/benefit type analysis of climate change can fail to truly appreciate the harms that it produces. In fact, a climate change policy based on a cost benefit <a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2324660064_1e9550c25b_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2324660064_1e9550c25b_o-300x200.jpg" alt="2324660064_1e9550c25b_o" width="300" height="200" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1450"></a>analysis will contradict fundamental rights, and will clearly violate the concept of equality before the law. Furthermore this type of policy will cause a climate change policy that is much less aggressive than it should be. In this post I will elaborate on these claims. I will give a definition of what I mean by a cost-benefit analysis, I will argue that people actually value other goals more highly than the monetary costs measured by a cost-benefit analysis, I will argue that it makes ethical assumptions that are dubious, and I will show that when applied to the world of climate change it produces severely inegalitarian results. These inegalitarian results create problems involving human rights, and equality before the law. </p>

<p>Now, what do I mean by cost-benefit analysis? I simply mean an analysis of the impacts of climate change based solely on the economic damage it causes. This economic impact is measured in terms of money. This type of analysis is able to measure damage to things other than the markets however. Damage to things that are not traded on the market measured in are terms of how much money people would be willing to give up for them. I.e if the members of a community would be willing to pay $100,000 to preserve a historic building, than the economic value of that building is \$100,000. If the building is then destroyed by an impact of climate change, then $100,000 is added to the impacts of climate change from a cost benefit perspective. Probabilistic impacts are measured using the concept of expected value. The expected value of an event is the product of its cost and the probability that it will occur. If the building has a 25 percent (0.25 probability) of being damaged then the expected value of the damage is $25,000. This type of cost benefit analysis is widely used. Pretty much all estimates of the form "the social cost of CO2 pollution is \$50 per ton of CO2" were created in this way. However, this method has severe flaws. Many proposals suggest building the response to climate change around this analysis, and conducting a "market-based" response by setting the carbon price at a level consistent with the cost of the pollution determined by the cost-benefit analysis.  </p>

<p>However, this method has clear flaws. The first is that it gives higher priority to the interests of the wealthy. Since this analysis is fundamentally based on <em>economic</em> damage and the amount of money that people would give up to advert the damage it weights the interests of the wealthy very highly. It also downgrades the interest of the poor. Because climate change is a global phenomenon and because global economic inequality is very lopsided, this effect is stark. The interests of someone earning the median American wage (about $50,000) is weighted over 130 times more than the interests on someone earning a dollar a day ($365 per year). The impacts of climate change (along with some strategies for mitigating it) fall disproportionately on the poor. Because of this the poor will get a raw deal with any climate change policy built around a cost-benefit analysis. Furthermore, this huge discrepancy conflicts with the notion of equality before the law. A just system should treat the interests of all equally and in a neutral fashion. The cost-benefit analysis method does not come close to doing this.  </p>

<p>Furthermore, the ethical assumptions behind the cost-benefit analysis method are dubious. There are three major assumptions behind the use of cost-benefit analysis</p>
<ol><li>The type of material wealth usually measured with money is a good proxy for the types of harms created by climate change  </li>
<li>All preferences of equal strength are equally worthy of concern by the political system  </li>
<li>Maximizing total well being (as measured by monetary value) is a good value to peruse </li>
</ol>
<p>All three of these points are dubious. I believe that political policies should be judged based on what a neutral observer would judge of the situation. Of course, with something global like climate change there are no truly neutral observers. However, we can appeal to a thought experiment like Rawls' original position where people are asked to judge policy options based on the assumption that they lack knowledge of their position in society, and therefore could be anyone in society. Under conditions like this people would probably not choose a social structure that maximizes well being (contradicting point 3). The idea of utility maximization embedded in the cost-benefit analysis method makes the errornous assumption that utilities and preferences of people are things that can be easily quantified and added up. Such an assumption is dubious. Even if it were not, I would contend that most people would want to avoid situations of being severely disadvantaged. I contend that people in such a thought experiment should instead  choose a situation where the policies enacted are the most widely acceptable even if this results in lower over all well being or a lower expected value of wealth. I would also contend that net wealth or material well being is not what people desire, wealth is a means not a end so taking it as a goal is superficial. I would prefer freedom (in a broad based sense) to wealth; "Give me liberty, or give me death!". Of course, defining liberty is a task of its own. I reject libertarian notions of freedom that define freedom purely in terms of some type of non-interference without any effective abilities preserved. I would contend that people are free to the extent that they have the widest range of abilities and capabilities to act that are not subject to and are protected from the risk of uncontrolled interference by others. Among these abilities priority should be given to fundamental rights. The capibilities of concern should be those that would be highlighted by a neutral party.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
