<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>What to Do About Immigration</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-immigration</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-immigration?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>What to Do About Immigration</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-immigration</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-immigration</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 09:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>The current U.S immigration policy is a total disaster. It is economically inefficient, it is a moral crisis. It is an inherently unjust system. America's immigration policy exacerbates global poverty and through its impact on the world economy costs trillions of dollars.<a href="http://www.cgdev.org/publication/economics-and-emigration-trillion-dollar-bills-sidewalk-working-paper-264"> On a global scale immigration restrictions cost 50-150% of world GDP. </a> The U.S immigration policy subjects millions to severe harms, and removes economic opportunity from many more. An internal policy this harmful would not be tolerated. I believe that immigration policy, like all other major economic issues, should be judged based on its impact on the whole world, not just on its domestic impacts. That is, even if U.S citizens were on the whole benefited by the status quo the immigration system would need reform if the current system harmed the world as a whole. Due to the vast inefficiency of the current immigration system. The only broadly justifiable rationale of immigration restriction are ones aimed at mitigating real externalities that are globally harmful. I propose a radical shift in policy. I believe that the U.S should shift to a policy of free migration. I believe that the U.S should give any law abiding immigrant to the country a work permit with minimal restrictions. Non-work entrance (with similar permissions to tourist and educations visas) should be granted visa free. Work permits should be granted with a minimal set of fees and taxes. Indirect controls on migration -- such as through regulations and subsidies that favor citizens over non-citizens should be reduced. A much more streamlined path to citizenship should be created that should give citizenship to all who have held paid employment for a sufficiently long period of time. I will expand on this in future blog posts.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
