<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>What to Do About Poverty</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-poverty</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-poverty?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>What to Do About Poverty</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-poverty</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-poverty</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2014 21:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>50 years ago this month Lyndon Johnson gave his War on Poverty speech, which was the beginning of most of the U.S government's anti-poverty programs. While these programs have made a clear dent in poverty, they have not come close to eliminating poverty. We need to do more. In this post I will detail how America can solve the poverty issue.</p>
<ol><li>The U.S government should commit to alleviating unemployment and maintaining full employment. This should include
<ol><li>The creation of a Works Progress Administration style jobs program that would be able to offer every unemployed person who is willing and able to work a job at a living wage. This program would employ the workers on infrastructure programs, providing public services, and projects done in collaboration with private non-profit groups. This program should continue even after the effects of the recession are over.</li>
    <li>The government should provide grants to unemployed workers and low income individuals who intend to start a business. This program would evaluate proposals based on their cost, the number of people employed by the businesses, and the benefit to the public that would be created by the proposals.</li>
    <li>The U.S government should aggressively use monetary policy to encourage private investment. This should include a continuation of the zero interest rate policy -- possibly indefinitely.</li>
    <li>The government should aggressively use fiscal policy to keep the economy at full employment. This should include increased deficits when the economy is sluggish and reduced deficits/ surpluses when there is a high risk of inflation.</li>
</ol></li> <br /><li>The current set of anti-poverty programs<a title="The Best Way to Eliminate Poverty in the United States" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140326141202/&lt;a%20href=" https: rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>17/<wbr></wbr>best-way-eliminate-poverty-united-states/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt; should be replaced with a basic income program that would provide a universal cash grant to all U.S adult citizens that is delivered unconditionally and without means testing  .</li>
    <li><a title="What should be done with the U.S health care system?" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140326141811/&lt;a%20href=" https: rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>01/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>done-u-s-health-care-system/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;A universal health care system should be adopted. </li>
</ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lyndonjohnson" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lyndonjohnson</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worksprogressadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worksprogressadministration</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#lyndonjohnson</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#worksprogressadministration</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
