<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Why Research Should be Funded Without the Patent System</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-research-should-be-funded-without-the-patent-system</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-research-should-be-funded-without-the-patent-system?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why Research Should be Funded Without the Patent System</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-research-should-be-funded-without-the-patent-system</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-research-should-be-funded-without-the-patent-system</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2014 16:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The patent system is an amazingly inefficient method to fund research. Patents drive up the costs of pharmaceuticals and other products, they increase market concentration, they harm consumers and they misdirect research efforts away from basic research. This inefficiency comes from three sources. The first is that the patent system is fundamentally a monopoly grant. Monopolies by their nature can charge way more than the cost that something takes to produce. This hurts consumers. The second issue is that research funding produces an economic issue that is similar to that faced in funding public goods like parks and roads. There is a large fixed cost in research that has to be paid regardless of whether 1 person uses a product derived from it or 1 million people benefit from the research. The third issue is that the patent system biases research funding towards research that will result in a marketable product in the short term. However, the basic research that will result in the next generation's innovations gets the short shrift in this system. I argue that the patent system should be replaced  <br /><!--more--></p>
<p>The patent system is fundamentally a monopoly grant. It gives the inventor the exclusive right to manufacture the invention (even if it was independently discovered by someone else) and excludes all others. The economic effect of this is simple; prices are driven up. A manufacturer in a competitive market can only charge just above the cost of manufacture -- including the cost of outbidding the alternative uses for the resources needed in production. However, a company in a concentrated market can charge whatever consumers are willing to pay. In many markets -- in particular the pharmaceutical business --  what people will pay for a product and what it takes to bring it into production are very different numbers. Because of this many consumers will not be able to access these products, or at least will be overcharged. The empirical evidence for this can be seen in the vast price differences between generic drugs and similar drugs under patent protection.Generic drugs usually cost between  <a href="http://www.healthsmart.com/SmarterHealth/GenericvsBrandDrugs.aspx">30-80% less than their name brand counterparts</a>.When this cost difference results in patients being unable to access the drugs that they need, the effects can be dire. Furthermore, this system encourages businesses to waste resources on gaining and maintaining patent rights. Patent litigation is expensive and the patent system encourages the formation of patent trolls which abuse this system for their profit. Drug companies spend large amounts of money on creating variants of already existing drugs in order to extend their patent rights - even when there is little added benefit to the copycat drugs. The patent system also encourages an industry of lobbying that only makes the system more inefficient.</p><p>Think of a park. A typical park has a large fixed cost --- a cost that must be paid for anyone to use it. However, once this fixed cost is paid then many people can use the park. In fact, the most efficient way to use the park is to allow as many people as possible to access it, once the fixed cost is paid.  It is for this reason that parks are usually government funded with free access, or at least low-cost admission. Research faces a similar issue. There is a cost to making a discovery, but once its made an unlimited number of people can benefit from it. </p><p>The patent system also encourages a disproportionate focus on research that has has a high chance of resulting in the short term production of a patentable product . This is because a patent only can protect  a particular product or method. There is no way that the patent system can be used to reward basic research that does not result directly in a product. This is a severe flaw because basic research can result in long term benefits for industry and the public. </p><p>The alternative to the patent system is public funding of research. One objection to government funding of research is maintaining its independence, while still allowing the public some say in how the funding is allocated. I will propose a system of government research funding that handles both of these goals well. My proposal focuses on what I will call independent funding organizations. These organizations would be ran independently from the government. A voucher would be made available to every resident of the U.S that could be used to fund these organizations. The organizations would of course be regulated to prevent waste and misuse of funds. But the variety of organizations in existence and their decentralized funding source would limit political interference while still encouraging public accountability.         </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
