<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/affordablecareact</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/affordablecareact?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Halbig vs. Burwell: Are the ACA Insurance Subsidies Only for Plans Bought on State Government Ran Exchanges?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/halbig-vs-burwell-are-the-aca-insurance-subsidies-only-for</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/halbig-vs-burwell-are-the-aca-insurance-subsidies-only-for</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2014 23:32:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><em>Halbig vs. Burwell</em> <a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2014/06/26/1309717/-ACA-Signups-Halbig-v-Burwell-Potential-Disaster-Ahead">is a case making its way through the courts involving the Affordable Care Act subsidies</a> for individual insurance plans. It seems that the raw wording of the of the Act seems to limit the subsidies to just the exchanges that are ran by state governments i.e not healthcare.gov (see below for the relevant text of the law) However, the subsidies could still be salvaged if it could be shown that the intent of Congress differed from this. Still this would be a bit of a unclear path to a legal victory for the administration as the text of a law usually takes priority over its intent. Additionally even the intent is unclear. It is <a href="http://www.californiahealthline.org/road-to-reform/2013/could-this-little-watched-court-case-sink-obamacare">entirely possible that</a> Congress (or at least some of its members) could have intended to limit the subsidy to the participating states in order to prod states to participate. It seems that the merits of this challenge to the implementation of the ACA is strong, and the case has a substantial chance of success.</p><p>Below is the text of the relavent portion of the law (with emphasis added)  </p><blockquote>
<p>The premium assistance amount determined under this subsection with respect to any coverage month is the amount equal to the lesser of—  <br />(A) the monthly premiums for such month for 1 or more qualified health plans offered in the individual market within a State which cover the taxpayer, the taxpayer's spouse, or any dependent (as defined in section 152) of the taxpayer <strong><em>and which were enrolled in through an Exchange established by the State under 1311 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act,</em></strong> or<br />(B) the excess (if any) of<br />(i) the adjusted monthly premium for such month for the applicable second lowest cost silver plan with respect to the taxpayer, over<br />(ii) an amount equal to 1/12 of the product of the applicable percentage and the taxpayer's household income for the taxable year.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aca" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aca</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/affordablecareact" class="p-category" rel="tag">#affordablecareact</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aca</category>
      <category>#affordablecareact</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
