<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Arrhenius and Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/arrhenius-and-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/arrhenius-and-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 16:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a><br /></em>The first scientist that theorized the possibility that the combustion of coal fuels could result in a global increase in temperature was chemist Svante Arrhenius,</p>

<p><a href="http://www.aip.org/history/climate/co2.htm">who in 1896 theorized that coal burning could warm the climate at a scale similar to the effect caused by geologic sources</a>, such as volcanoes. He first estimated that a carbon dioxide increase sufficient to double CO2, and thereby increase global temperatures by 5 degrees Celsius, would take a few thousand years. By 1908, he had reduced this estimate to a few hundred years. However, Arrhenius' model of the climate was simplistic and the possibility that human activity and changes in CO2 level could increase global temperature was disregarded until the 1950s.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/4314542?uid=3739552&uid=2&uid=4&uid=3739256&sid=21104511473153">Arrhenius was primarily focused on the causes of the Quaternary glaciation cycles</a> and was the first known author to calculate how CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere change global temperatures. He soon expanded his work to human industrial emissions and calculated that these emissions have a substantial ability to increase global temperature. The greenhouse effect though was discovered by French scientist Joseph Fourier in 1824, but Fourier never related CO2 concentrations to global climate in a reliable fashion. Fourier and other early researchers on the greenhouse effect never realized the impact that the effect could have on ground temperatures.</p>

<p>Arrhenius guessed that natural fluctuations in CO2, such as those that have historically shifted glaciation are driven by changes in the frequency of volcanoes. This is correct for periods of millions of years. However this is not true for the shorter term changes Arrhenius was interested in. It is now known that he got the magnitude of these historical shifts in temperature correct, but was incorrect about they formed. These short term shifts were driven by the CO2 stored in oceans, the atmosphere, and the biomass of ecosystems. Changes in temperature that resulted in glaciation were also driven by other factors like changes in the Earth's orbit. CO2 though does have the ability to act as a powerful feedback that amplifies these exogenous changes.</p>

<p>Now lets discuss how Arrhenius calculated how human impacts would change the climate. All objects emit light based on their temperature. This is known as black-body radiation. The light emitted by the Earth is mostly in the infrared. The light emitted by the much hotter Sun is in wavelengths that range from the ultraviolet to the infrared. The hotter an object is, the more energy it emits through light. There is an equilibrium between the energy contained in the incoming light from the Sun, and the energy leaving the Earth. This is because all energy present in the Earth must come from somewhere and energy can never be created nor destroyed. Because of this temperatures will rise and fall until the level of energy coming out of the Earth equals the amount coming into it. To see why this forms an equilibrium imagine 1) a world where less energy comes into the earth than out of it, and 2) a world where more energy comes into the earth than out of it. In condition 1 the Earth will lose energy through the light it outputs, this will reduce the temperature of the planet and therefore cause a return to the equilibrium. The same thing, only in the opposite direction, happens in situation 2. The state of this equilibrium sets the global temperature. Greenhouse gasses can shift this equilibrium by absorbing some of the light emitted by the Earth, and re-emitting it back at the Earth. This effectively reduces the light emission by the Earth forcing the temperature upwards. Core greenhouse gases in the Earth's climate are carbon dioxide and water vapor but there are a range of more minor greenhouse gasses. Arrhenius only took into account CO2 and H20 in his model. Based on this Arrhenius derived a mathematical model of the global climate. He found that the temperature varies with respect to CO2 concentration according to the following rule.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>if the quantity of carbonic acid [CO2] increases in geometric progression, the augmentation of the temperature will increase nearly in arithmetic progression.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In equation form this means</p>

<p>ΔT = α Ln(C/C_0)</p>

<p>Where ΔT is the change in temperature,α is a constant, C is the final concentration of CO2, and C_0 is the final concentration of CO2. The constant α was empirically determined.</p>

<p>There were of course gaps in his model. For example cloud cover plays no role in it. The role of feed-backs and forgings is very limited. Arrhenius though thought that Climate Change would be a positive gift to future generations ,in contrast to the views of the vast majority of modern scientists. <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=1t45AAAAMAAJ&printsec=frontcover#v=onepage&q&f=false">He wrote that</a> and argued that the change would rule out the possibility of a future ice age, and the negative consequences of such an ice age.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We often hear lamentations that the coal stored up in the earth is wasted by the present generation without any thought of the future, and we are terrified by the awful destruction of life and property which has followed the volcanic eruptions of our days. We may find a kind of consolation in the consideration that here, as in every other case, there is good mixed with the evil. By the influence of the increasing percentage of carbonic acid in the atmosphere, we may hope to enjoy ages with more equable and better climates, especially as regards the colder regions of the earth, ages when the earth will bring forth much more abundant crops than at present, for the benefit of rapidly propagating mankind.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Arrhenius also thought that this change would come much more slowly. He underestimated the rate of industrialization by a wide margin and thought that it would take 3000 years for human impacts to double CO2. However, in actuality emissions increased so rapidly that it is possible that the doubleing could occur with in the 21st century if there are no policy changes made to reduce these emissions. However, the history of climate change research, a history that goes back over a century challenges the notion that global warming is a new concept dreamed up by tree huggers and Al Gore with scientists jumping on the propaganda bandwagon.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#algore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/josephfourier" class="p-category" rel="tag">#josephfourier</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#v</category>
      <category>#algore</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#josephfourier</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Climate Change Science New?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/is-climate-change-science-new</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/is-climate-change-science-new</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 13:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Is the idea of global warming a new concept--just a fad-- something dreamed up by tree huggers and Al Gore with scientists jumping on the propaganda bandwagon? Climate change denialists, like <a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/">Anthony Watts</a> [1. See for instance this article <a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2011/06/25/the-end-is-near-for-faith-in-agw/"></a><a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2011/06/25/the-end-is-near-for-faith-in-agw/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>wattsupwiththat.com/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>25/<wbr></wbr>the-end-is-near-for-faith-in-agw/<wbr></wbr></a>], would have you believe that. But the truth is scientists have been studying it for more than 100 years.</p>

<p>The first scientist that theorized the possibility that the combustion of coal fuels could result in a global increase in temperature was chemist Svante Arrhenius,</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_105" align="alignright" width="239"] Svante Arrhenius (<a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Arrhenius2.jpg">Image from Wikimedia Commons</a>)[/caption]</p>

<p><a href="http://www.aip.org/history/climate/co2.htm">who in 1896 theorized that coal burning could warm the climate at a scale similar to the effect caused by geologic sources</a>, such as volcanoes. He first estimated that a carbon dioxide increase sufficient to double CO2, and thereby increase global temperatures by 5 degrees Celsius, would take a few thousand years. By 1908, he had reduced this estimate to a few hundred years. However, Arrhenius' model of the climate was simplistic and the possibility that human activity and changes in CO2 level could increase global temperature was disregarded until the 1950s.</p>

<p>During that decade, new models were created that added support to this theory, but the evidence was still not conclusive. In the late 1970s, this began to change. Computers allowed the creation of accurate and detailed estimates of the possibility of human-caused climate change, and these estimates were calculated and widely accepted. In 1979, the United States National Academy of Sciences released a report warning of human-caused climate change [2. Archer, David, and Stefan Rahmstorf. The climate crisis: an introductory guide to climate change. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2010. Page x.], marking the first general acceptance of this theory.</p>

<p>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) was created in 1988 to study the possibility of climate change and its impacts. The first IPCC report, published in 1990, found that a human-caused increase in global temperatures was likely, but not conclusive. The IPCC also found that the evidence should be conclusive within a decade. In their 2007 assessment on the physical science basis of climate change, the fourth and most recent assessment available at this time, the IPCC found that levels of three greenhouse gasses, carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrous oxide, in the atmosphere had increased dramatically since the Industrial Revolution. According to the IPCC, these increases in greenhouse gasses have warmed and changed the climate and are human caused with a very high probability. Out of the three, the effect of carbon dioxide is the most significant.</p>

<p>Over 97 percent of climate scientists agree that human-caused climate change is happening and has the potential to cause severe harm. Some might say that this means nothing. But I believe that when 97 percent of scientists believe something, we should listen, especially when there is a whole century of evidence to back them up.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#algore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/industrialrevolution" class="p-category" rel="tag">#industrialrevolution</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#algore</category>
      <category>#industrialrevolution</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
