<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/associatedpress</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/associatedpress?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Collapse of I-5 Bridge in Washington Shows the Need to Improve Infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/collapse-of-i-5-bridge-in-washington-shows-the-need-to</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/collapse-of-i-5-bridge-in-washington-shows-the-need-to</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 10:06:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Interstate 5 bridge over the Skagit River in Washington state <a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/05/23/1211354/-I-5-bridge-over-Skagit-River-collapses-cars-with-people-in-water">collapsed last week</a> causing no deaths, but the collapse injured <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/05/24/washington-bridge-collapse_n_3331536.html">at least three people</a>. It is clear that the officials responsible for maintaining the bridge did not have the funding needed to keep the bridge system in good repair. This incident showcases the need for a massive, Works Progress Administration style push to repair our infrastructure.</p>

<p>Before I go into what needs to be done with our infrastructure, let's first review what happened in Washington .As reported by KOMO.News, a local television station, a Washington Department of Transportation spokesperson <a href="http://www.komonews.com/news/local/Cars-bodies-in-Skagit-River-after-I-5-Bridge-collapse--208760201.html">was not aware when the bridge was last inspected</a>. Furthermore, the Federal Highway Administration classified the bridge as "functionally obsolete" because it had an outdated design that does not meet current standards for new bridge construction. From KOMO,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Bart Treece with WDOT was unsure when the bridge was last inspected.  <br />"All of our bridges in the area are pretty old," he said.  <br />The bridge is not considered structurally deficient but is listed as being "functionally obsolete" - a category meaning that their design is outdated, such as having narrow shoulders are low clearance underneath, according to a database compiled by the Federal Highway Administration.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There were other issues with the bridge and many others in the state.A 1992 federal report <a href="http://uglybridges.com/1589303">recommended that the I-5 bridge be replaced</a> at a cost of 8.3 million dollars. <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20131029033245/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>blogs.asce.org/<wbr></wbr>govrel/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>21/<wbr></wbr>washington-state-report-card-released-today/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;37 percent of the state's bridges have been in use for a time frame exceeding their designed lifespan. According to the Seattle Times,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The bridge, built in 1955, has a sufficiency rating of 57.4 out of 100, according to federal records. That is well below the statewide average rating of 80, according to an Associated Press analysis of federal data, but 759 bridges in the state have a lower sufficiency score.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The fact that the I-5 Bridge and many like it have not received needed maintenance shows the need for new investment in infrastructure. The government needs to commit o<a href="http://www.infrastructurereportcard.org/a/#p/bridges/investment-and-funding">ver 120 billion dollars</a> to fix our bridges. <a href="http://www.infrastructurereportcard.org/a/#p/bridges/overview">Budgets for future road repairs need</a> to be increased by 8 billion dollars per year. Despite the clear facts, politicians have done just the opposite.  As the graph I open my blog post with shows, spending on infrastructure has actually decreased during the ongoing recession.</p>

<p>To supplement and complete infrastructure investment the federal government should enact a Works Progress Administration style jobs push. The government should pledge to hire anyone willing and able to work at minimum wage and put those hired to work on public projects, including infrastructure improvements.This program should continue even after unemployment is lowered to regular levels. A major push on infrastructure will create many jobs and many workers will be hired to complete the construction work. The current high level of unemployment shows that there is much surplus economic  capacity able to be put to work.</p>

<p>In a depressed economy the United States government can increase spending without the need for increased taxation or other ill effects. The deficit is not a limiting factor for government investment. A country with its own, floating, non-convertable (a currency where the issuer does not pledge to convert currency for a commodity on demand) currency is not constrained in its government spending by absolute debt or deficit levels. The<a href="http://neweconomicperspectives.org/2012/01/mmp-blog-31-functional-finance-monetary.html"> only constraints on spending are the effects that the spending has on inflation, unemployment, demand</a> and other economic outcomes.</p>

<p>Any complaints that the debt would be increased by infrastructure improvements are not grounds to let our roads and bridges rot. There are many needed infrastructure improvements. The government should start on them as soon as possible.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/associatedpress" class="p-category" rel="tag">#associatedpress</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/federalhighwayadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#federalhighwayadministration</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/seattletimes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#seattletimes</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worksprogressadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worksprogressadministration</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#p</category>
      <category>#p</category>
      <category>#associatedpress</category>
      <category>#federalhighwayadministration</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#seattletimes</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#worksprogressadministration</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
