<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/michaelmann</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/michaelmann?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Political Foundations of Denialism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-political-foundations-of-denialism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-political-foundations-of-denialism</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 08:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>Just being able to define denialism does not tell us why denialist theories gain public support. I will analyze three possible reasons that denialist theories gain popularity: psychological biases, political biases, and deliberate misinformation campaigns by businesses that could be harmed by environmental regulation. I will show that all three factors play a part in climate change denialism and the news media plays a role in all three sources of denialism.</p>

<p><a href="http://scienceblogs.com/denialism/about/">Mark Hoofnagle argues</a> that a primary cause of denialism of all types is psychological biases, in particular the Dunning-Kruger effect. The Dunning-Kruger effect shows that individuals who lack knowledge in a field have a tendency to both have an over-inflated sense of their own knowledge and, more importantly, are unable to recognize true skill in that field. Hoofnagle says this bias allows “cranks” to appear who are unable to judge sources of information and instead believe and spread incorrect information. In the climate change issue, the Dunning-Kruger effect can help explain why individuals and media personalities with no science background will believe and promote incorrect theories about climatology.</p>

<p>Just as the Dunning-Kruger effect explanation would suggest, climate change cranks often show great inability to notice general trends in climate research and to detect expertise in the field. For example well-known climate change denialist Anthony Watts <a href="http://www.donotlink.com/pYV">discussed the “global cooling alarmism” of the 1970s</a> and argues that the popularity of the now discredited global cooling theory was similar to the current popularity of global warming theories. Watts provides a list of articles that he believes shows this-- all but two of which are popular works from newspapers and magazines, such as <em>Time</em>. However, a quick review of the relevant climatology of the time shows that Watts' claim is clearly incorrect, and that belief in imminent global cooling was a clear minority position.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">Linguist and progressive political analyst George Lakoff argues </a>that ideological bias can reduce an individual's belief in scientific facts. According to Lakoff, there is an ideologically significant difference between two forms of causation: direct causation and systemic causation. According to Lakoff:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Any application of force to something or someone that always produces an immediate  <br />change to that thing or person is direct causation....Systemic causation, because it is less obvious, is more important to understand. A systemic cause may be one of a number of multiple causes. It may require some special conditions. It may be indirect, working through a network of more direct causes. It may be probabilistic, occurring with a significantly high probability.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many areas of science that face large denialist ideology, including climate change, are dominated by systemic causation. Systemic causation is generally emphasized by the left in the political discourse, while both progressives and conservatives emphasize direct causation. Differences about causation can explain much of the opposition to climate change regulation that comes from conservatives (See Lakoff's book “Whose Freedom?” pages 118-130).</p>

<p>A third possible cause of the prevalence of denialist theories is industry-funded campaigns. Climate scientist Michael Mann argues that climate change denialism is largely politically motivated and caused by business interests with a financial stake in pollution regulation. The largest of these interests are the oil, gas, and coal industries. Mann, who has published some of the most controversial work on climate change and has faced substantial criticism from the popular press for his work, uses his own experience as a case study in in his book <em>The Hockey Stick and the Climate Wars: Dispatches from the Front Lines</em>. He discusses the vitriolic attacks that he received after publishing a paper introducing the "hockey stick" graph, which showed the dramatic increase in global temperatures after the industrial revolution.</p>

<p>The news media generally has four major roles that relate to climate change coverage. <br />There is the obvious informational role where viewers of media are told about an issue. There are also three more subtle roles: the agenda setting role, the framing role, and the priming role. As discussed in the paper <em>The agenda-setting function of mass media</em>, by agenda setting the media has the power to change not only direct opinions on an issue, but also opinions on “how much importance to attach to that issue”. <a href="http://www.utwente.nl/cw/theorieenoverzicht/Theory%20Clusters/Mass%20Media/Framing.doc">By framing the media determines how viewers perceive the wider social context of an issue</a>. Framing tells the viewer how to think about an issue. <a href="http://www.utwente.nl/cw/theorieenoverzicht/Theory%20Clusters/Mass%20Media/Priming.doc/">In priming, the media tells the viewer what prior context should be used to interpret the issue.</a> The way that the media carries out all three of its roles amplifies climate change denialism.</p>

<p>There are two types of claims relating to climate change that journalists and the media cover: positive claims and normative claims. A positive claim discusses how the world is and/or what the physical state of the world is. A normative claim discusses what the world should be like, or in other words, what the ethical course of action is in a given situation [1. See <em>The Science and Politics of Global Climate <br /><br />Change:A Guide to the Debate</em> for a good discussion of this]. Positive claims are at their core the domain of science and often have definite or clear right or <br />wrong answers that most experts agree upon. Positive claims can be easily resolved by empirical testing of scientific theories and observation. They are often the domain of philosophy and politics. Scientific results can inform debates over ethics and politics, but will never by themselves resolve these debates. At best, science can remove some options from consideration, but cannot tell us how to create policy or what the ethical life should be. It is possible that a good explanation of a thing may lead to both a scientific and ethical theory. I don't believe in a strict is-ought barrier. But the two domains are different to a degree. A different way of putting this is that, a full theory of climate change, will need to explain both the direct effects of CO2 emissions, and what we should do about it in the political realm. Scientists know a lot about the first question, but we know less about the second one. Even in regards to the purely factual elements of climate change responce -- such as economics -- our knowledge has many limits.</p>

<p>Because of these differences, journalists should cover positive and normative claims differently.The objective way for a journalist to cover a normative claim about ethics or politics is through a balanced approach. Each side in a philosophical or political debate should be given equal weight. However, the objective way to cover a positive claim is to give weight to arguments in proportion to the evidence on each side of the issue. Fringe ideas with weak evidence should not be given equal weight to strong ideas backed by evidence. Guidance on how journalists should judge the merits of different scientific claims can be found in a field that has encountered similar issues in determining when a scientific theory is worthy of attention-- the legal system. In <em>Daubert v. Merrell Dow Pharmaceuticals</em> (1993), the U.S. Supreme Court found that five traits should be used to determine if a scientific result is worthy of being entered as evidence in a legal case. According to the court, good science should be: 1) empirically testable, 2) published and peer-reviewed, 3) free of an error rate that limits its applicability or usefulness, 4) held to standards and controls regarding collection of data, and 5) should be generally accepted by the relevant scientific community.</p>

<p>All three of the theoretical models of how denialism can occur relate to the functioning of the media. In the Dunning-Kruger effect model of denialism, the media is important as prominent media personalities are vectors for dubious theories. In this view, the role of the media is one of lack of knowledge – it takes a certain level of expertise in science to even be able to tell what a science expert sounds like. Denialism comes through the informational role of the media.Journalists, politicians, and media personalities who deal with science often lack the expertise to tell opinion or propaganda from real science. Prominent media personalities often become cranks in a field and promote dubious theories to an unsuspecting audience. Media personalities have high charisma and a large, loyal audience, but often have little ability to evaluate science, or who is even a credible source of information on a scientific issue. For example, Hoofnagle argues that TV host Oprah Winfrey has become a promoter of denialist theories in medicine that lack scientific merit due to this phenomenon. Oprah's guests discussing medical issues have been a mix of qualified medical experts and non-expert writers promoting long debunked theories, such as a link between childhood vaccinations and autism, and the host seems to be unable to tell which are which. The media affects the interplay between political ideology and denialism in two ways. First, the framing effect is critical in the weighing of different forms of causation and how individual freedom is viewed. Furthermore, the media and journalists are often hesitant to contradict the standard opinions of one of the major political parties-- even if the balance of scientific facts contradicts that conventional wisdom. Media actions are the path through which industry attempts to influence public opinion to gain currency. For the public to view these attempts at influence as significant, or credible, a source of information that is reliable to the public must promote them and that's where the news media comes in. The agenda setting role is used in a way that makes the reality of human-caused climate change appear to be something that is in doubt and unimportant. The media generally does not give environmental issues the coverage and importance that they deserve. Climate change coverage in the news media on the four major television networks dropped between 2011 and 2012, even though the effects of climate change are becoming more drastic.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/georgelakoff" class="p-category" rel="tag">#georgelakoff</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/michaelmann" class="p-category" rel="tag">#michaelmann</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/oprahwinfrey" class="p-category" rel="tag">#oprahwinfrey</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/whosefreedom" class="p-category" rel="tag">#whosefreedom</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#georgelakoff</category>
      <category>#michaelmann</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#oprahwinfrey</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#whosefreedom</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of Climate Change Denialism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-anatomy-of-climate-change-denialism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-anatomy-of-climate-change-denialism</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 15:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em><a href="http://scienceblogs.com/denialism/about/">According to science blogger Mark Hoofnagle</a>, “Denialism is the employment of rhetorical <br />tactics to give the appearance of argument or legitimate debate, when in actuality there is none.” He argues that these techniques are primarily <strong>“conspiracy, selectivity (cherry-picking), fake experts, impossible expectations (also known as moving goalposts), and general fallacies of logic.</strong>” Emphasis as in original source.</p>

<p>Climate scientist Michael Mann states that climate change denialist arguments fall into “six stages of denial”, in his book <em>The Hockey Stick and the Climate Wars: Dispatches from the Front Lines</em>. Climate change denialists have shifted down the stages of denial as the evidence for the mainstream view on climate change has become stronger-- but all six claims are regularly made. I argue that popular works and political commentators are the most likely to be in the first stages of denial and academic works in the social sciences are the most likely to use the arguments in the higher stages. The first stage is claims that argue that “CO2 is not actually increasing”. However, the rise in CO2 claimed by mainstream researchers has been confirmed by study after study and can be predicted by basic chemistry and physics relations. So, denialists have gradually had to abandon this argument. They then switched to claiming, as Mann puts it, “The increase has no impact on the climate since there is no convincing evidence of warming”. The warming effect of CO2 increases is a bit harder to calculate and predict accurately, but decades of  research on climate change since the 1970s has created a scientific consensus that human produced CO2 is causing potentially harmful levels of warming, so this argument has been slowly abandoned.In the next two steps, denialists try to claim that most observed warming is natural: “3) Even if there is warming, it is due to natural causes 4) Even if the warming cannot be explained by natural causes, the human impact is small, and the impact of continued greenhouse gas emissions will be minor.” But humans have been shown to be the cause of almost all climate change. Scientists have been better able to predict the effects of CO 2 emissions and the effects that they will have on the climate. “5) ...the changes are generally going to be good for us 6) ...it's too late to do anything about it , and/or a technological fix is bound to come along...“ These are the most nuanced of the “stages of denial”. All six of the steps in the “stages of denial” have been shown to be incorrect and are considered to be false by the great majority of scientists. Therefore, an argument that makes any of these claims can be classified as climate change denialism. A viewpoint on climate change that disputes these claims of denialists can be interpreted as concurring with the mainstream scientific view.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/co" class="p-category" rel="tag">#co</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/markhoofnagle" class="p-category" rel="tag">#markhoofnagle</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/michaelmann" class="p-category" rel="tag">#michaelmann</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#co</category>
      <category>#markhoofnagle</category>
      <category>#michaelmann</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
