<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/old?offset=50</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old?offset=50&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 07:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em style="color: #222222;">This post is part of a series <a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #3465a4;" title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a></em>Concerns about the sustainability of fossil fuel energy have a long history that goes back almost 150 years. However, some of these early concerns were focused not on the environmental impact of coal or other fossil fuels, but were instead focused on the risk that we could run out of these fuels. Additionally, concerns about the environmental impact of coal are almost as old as the widespread consumption of the fuel.</p>

<p>In 1865 the <a href="http://www.econlib.org/library/YPDBooks/Jevons/jvnCQ.html">economist William Stanley Jevons penned his book</a> <em>The Coal Question; An Inquiry Concerning the Progress of the Nation, and the Probable Exhaustion of Our Coal Mines</em>. In that book Jevons argued that England would run out of domestic coal supplies, and would therefore either be dependent on imports, or would have to cut back on industrialization. He argued that this would be a long-run threat to Great Britain's status as a global power. Jevons predicted that the U.K had only 90 billions tons of coal available in 1865. If economic growth persisted at the rate he guessed, this coal would be exhausted by the end of the 20th century and the country would be dependent on imported fossil fuels. He made the following projection of coal consumption, production, and imports, from 1870 to 1970.</p>

<p>These predictions largely came true. The U.K <a href="http://www.coal.gov.uk/media//286DC/CA-AnnualReport-0607.pdf">only has about 400 million tons of coal left</a>. Production of coal peaked during World War 1. However, consumption of coal has not budged. The Association for UK Coal Importers estimates that Britain consumed 60.7 million tons of coal in 2013, 49.4 million of which were imported. <a href="http://www.coalimp.org.uk/4.html">They further guess that</a> "Proven world coal reserves amount to around 900 billion tonnes". However, other sources indicate that coal production <a href="http://e360.yale.edu/feature/peak_coal_why_the_industrys_dominance_may_soon_be_over/2777/">will likely peak around 2020</a>, even without explicit policy to reduce coal use.</p>

<p>Jevons though that reductions in the supply of coal would cause dramatic rises in its price, "<span style="color: #333333;">The exhaustion of our mines will be marked </span><i style="color: #333333;">pari passu</i><span style="color: #333333;"> by a rising cost or value of coal; and when the price has risen to a certain amount comparatively to the price in other countries, our main branches of trade will be doomed" (Chapter V, paragraph 2). However, coal prices have been surprisingly stable over history. <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0301421511000474">A study of the cost of coal in the United States between </a><span style="color: #2e2e2e;"><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0301421511000474">1882 and 2006 found</a> that "The price of coal appears to fluctuate more or less randomly" and that there is no general long term trend in the cost of the mineral. Coal has become a global market so this cost is quite uniform across the world. </span></span></p>

<p>Jevons also examined the "supposed substitutes of coal" -- energy through wind, water, and biomass -- and considered them to be less than satisfactory, saying "The first great requisite of motive power is, that it shall be wholly at our command, to be exerted when and where and in what degree we desire" (paragraph 13 of Chapter VIII). This concern is today known as the intermittentcy problem -- wind, water, and solar energy sources can not be produced on demand. Jevons claimed that deploying these sources would mean "carrying the work to the power, not the power to the work" (paragraph 23 of Chapter VIII). It is fair to say that we now know ways to <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/renewable-energy-baseload-power-advanced.htm">mitigate the intermittentcy problem of renewable energy sources</a>, such as an electric grid coupled with storage and a mix of power sources (although this comes at a substantial price tag), plus modern scientists now know how to harness nuclear power (which lacks the intermittency issue all together). However, despite the advances in technology made since 1865, intermittency is still a non-trivial problem for wind, water, and solar energy sources, and a strong argument in favor of nuclear power.</p>

<p>In <em>The Coal Question </em>Jevons introduced his famous paradox --- the argument that increasing the efficiency of energy usage actually increases the usage of energy. This comes from the fact that energy is a cost of using a good or service. Energy efficiency reduces this cost.  What do consumers do when the cost of something they want goes down? They consume more of it. For this reason a pure focus on energy efficiency is insufficient to restrain excessive consumption of fossil fuels. Jevons's paradox is well known but its implications are unappreciated.</p>

<p>Irrespective of its supply, concerns about the environmental impact of coal are as old as its use. <a href="http://66.147.244.135/~enviror4/ancient/middle-ages/">In </a><span style="color: #333333;"><a href="http://66.147.244.135/~enviror4/ancient/middle-ages/">1306 King </a>Edward I restricted the burning of coal inorder to limit air pollution. In the 17th century <span style="color: #333340;">John Evelyn correctly identified coal burning as the source of London's air pollution and wrote <em>Fumifugium: Or, the Inconvenience of the Aer, and Smoake of London Dissipated</em>, a policy proposal to the King and Parliament  on the matter. He described the pollution of London as follows <em>“The immoderate use of, and indulgence to, sea-coale in the city of London exposes it to one of the fowlest inconveniences and reproaches that can possibly befall so noble and otherwise incomparable City… Whilst they are belching it forth their sooty jaws, the City of London resembles the face rather of Mount Aetna, the Court of Vulcan… or the suburbs of Hell than an assembly of rational creatures” </em> He called the presence of this pollution a "pernicious Nuance" and noted that the responsible coal has "a kind of virulent or arsenical vapour arising from it”. He noted that other cities, such as Paris did not have a pollution problem as horrendous. In Evelyn's opinion, not only was this smog a nuisance, but it also posed health risks. He recommended containing the bad air (keep in mind that the miasma theory of disease was in use in the 17th century ) produced by this smoke by planting “odiferous flowers” to "tinge the air". These flowers were eventually planted. This solution of course failed to contain the smoke, and London retained its pollution problem. In 1873 London <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140305113926/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.bloombergview.com:80/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>2013-10-31/<wbr></wbr>china-s-smog-can-t-compete-with-london-s-pea-soup</a>"&gt;suffered a "Black Fog" that covered the city in a thick smoky haze, limited visibility in some areas to a few feet, and caused about 700 deaths. In response a Smoke Abatement Committee was formed to come up with policy measures to contain the problem.<a href="http://www.1902encyclopedia.com/S/SMO/smoke-abatement.html">The Committee recommended</a> a policy of abatement of the problem through installing filters on industrial equipment, a transition to liquid fuels, use of natural gas as an alternative to coal,  and a switch to forms of coal that burn cleaner. As a testament to how wide spread the problem of coal pollution is, the Committee notes a history of past technology innovations, and legislation  to mitigate this issue.  </span></span></p>

<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>In 1785 the first smoke-abating invention was patented by James Watt, who, as the inventor of the steam-engine, is responsible for so many boiler fires and so much consump-tion of coal. In 1815 Cutler patented the first would-be smokeless grate for domestic purposes; and his principle of feeding underneath was afterwards adopted by Dr Neil Arnott in a grate which has now been in use in one form or another for more than half a century. There is now a vast number of such inventions, good and bad. In 1819 the attention of parliament was directed to the question, and a select committee was appointed "to inquire how far persons using steam-engines and furnaces could erect them in a manner less prejudicial to public health and comfort." This committee gave an encouraging report. In 1843 another select committee recommended the introduction of a bill prohibiting the production of smoke from furnaces and steam-engines. In 1845 yet another select committee reported that such an Act could not in the existing state of affairs be made to apply to dwelling-houses.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/blackfog" class="p-category" rel="tag">#blackfog</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/citywhilst" class="p-category" rel="tag">#citywhilst</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/london" class="p-category" rel="tag">#london</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/smokeabatementcommittee" class="p-category" rel="tag">#smokeabatementcommittee</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#3465a4</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#2e2e2e</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#333340</category>
      <category>#blackfog</category>
      <category>#citywhilst</category>
      <category>#london</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#smokeabatementcommittee</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Correct Was the First Climate Change Prediction?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-correct-was-the-first-climate-change-prediction</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-correct-was-the-first-climate-change-prediction</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 03:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em><br /><a title="Arrhenius and Climate Change" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/arrhenius-and-climate-change/">In the last post</a>, I discussed the very first research on climate change --- the work of Svante Arrhenius, but how close to modern knowledge did he get? On the relation between CO2 levels and temperature he was quite close. Modern estimates of the climate sensitivity are approximately 3-4.5 degrees Celsius per doubling of CO2. The IPCC <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/publications_ipcc_fourth_assessment_report_synthesis_report.htm">says the following</a> on the issue of climate sensitivity to CO2 increases,it is "likely to be in the range 2 to 4.5°C with a best estimate of about 3°C, and is very unlikely to be less than 1.5°C. Values substantially higher than 4.5°C cannot be excluded, but agreement of models with observations is not as good for those values."</p>

<p>But he was far off on what the impacts of these shifts would be. Unlike Arrhenius, almost all modern researchers would say that the effects of climate change will be gravely harmful. <br />Climate change is harmful because human civilization has adapted to a relatively stable climate. A shift away from that climate will be extremely disruptive to humanity. The melting of ice will disrupt infrastructure. Rising temperatures will disrupt agriculture, and will make some crops impossible to grow where they have been grown for centuries. Climate change is also having a vast impact on natural ecosystems. It, along with other human impacts, are bringing forth a fifth mass extinction. A level of disruption to the natural world on par with the KT event that killed the dinosaurs. Ocean acidification will cause further disruption to the natural world, and will harm many species of importance to the seafood industry. The increased prevalence of extremely hot days will have negative impacts on human health. <br />Lets go deeper into some of these effects, starting with agriculture. While there are some conditions where some crops may benefit from climate change (for example due to a longer growing season, or increased efficiency of photosynthesis due to more CO2), these positive impacts are almost entirely outweighed by negative counterparts. For many crops climate change will trigger a faster, shorter growth period. This may sound like a good thing but its not. Crops will produce a lot less yield during this fast growth period. All crops have an optimal temperature where they grow the best. Global warming can reduce the area that is available at this optimal climate. Climate change can cause droughts that will reduce the water available for crops. Global warming can also trigger an increase in destructive weather events. The prevalence of pests and parasites will be increased. Many fish critical to the seafood industry favor low temperatures, and will be harmed by global warming. The poorest parts of the world will be hit the hardest by these changes (<a href="http://www.epa.gov/climatechange/impacts-adaptation/agriculture.html"></a><a href="http://www.epa.gov/climatechange/impacts-adaptation/agriculture.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.epa.gov/<wbr></wbr>climatechange/<wbr></wbr>impacts-adaptation/<wbr></wbr>agriculture.html</a>).</p>

<p>And of course he was way off on the situation of how quickly these changes would occur. <br />A graph of the real world shift in global temperature is as follows</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_163" align="alignright" width="300"] Land temperature with 1- and 10-year running averages. The shaded regions are the one- and two-standard deviation uncertainties calculated including both statistical and spatial sampling errors. Prior land results from the other groups are also plotted. The NASA GISS record had a land mask applied; the HadCRU curve is the simple land average, not the hemispheric-weighted one. Image and caption from Berkeley Earth <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130723044740/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>berkeleyearth.org:80/<wbr></wbr>results-summary/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;<a href="http://berkeleyearth.org/results-summary/%5B/caption">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>berkeleyearth.org/<wbr></wbr>results-summary/<wbr></wbr>[/<wbr></wbr>caption</a>]</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/berkeleyearth" class="p-category" rel="tag">#berkeleyearth</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/kt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#kt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unlikearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unlikearrhenius</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#berkeleyearth</category>
      <category>#kt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unlikearrhenius</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrhenius and Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/arrhenius-and-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/arrhenius-and-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 16:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a><br /></em>The first scientist that theorized the possibility that the combustion of coal fuels could result in a global increase in temperature was chemist Svante Arrhenius,</p>

<p><a href="http://www.aip.org/history/climate/co2.htm">who in 1896 theorized that coal burning could warm the climate at a scale similar to the effect caused by geologic sources</a>, such as volcanoes. He first estimated that a carbon dioxide increase sufficient to double CO2, and thereby increase global temperatures by 5 degrees Celsius, would take a few thousand years. By 1908, he had reduced this estimate to a few hundred years. However, Arrhenius' model of the climate was simplistic and the possibility that human activity and changes in CO2 level could increase global temperature was disregarded until the 1950s.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/4314542?uid=3739552&uid=2&uid=4&uid=3739256&sid=21104511473153">Arrhenius was primarily focused on the causes of the Quaternary glaciation cycles</a> and was the first known author to calculate how CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere change global temperatures. He soon expanded his work to human industrial emissions and calculated that these emissions have a substantial ability to increase global temperature. The greenhouse effect though was discovered by French scientist Joseph Fourier in 1824, but Fourier never related CO2 concentrations to global climate in a reliable fashion. Fourier and other early researchers on the greenhouse effect never realized the impact that the effect could have on ground temperatures.</p>

<p>Arrhenius guessed that natural fluctuations in CO2, such as those that have historically shifted glaciation are driven by changes in the frequency of volcanoes. This is correct for periods of millions of years. However this is not true for the shorter term changes Arrhenius was interested in. It is now known that he got the magnitude of these historical shifts in temperature correct, but was incorrect about they formed. These short term shifts were driven by the CO2 stored in oceans, the atmosphere, and the biomass of ecosystems. Changes in temperature that resulted in glaciation were also driven by other factors like changes in the Earth's orbit. CO2 though does have the ability to act as a powerful feedback that amplifies these exogenous changes.</p>

<p>Now lets discuss how Arrhenius calculated how human impacts would change the climate. All objects emit light based on their temperature. This is known as black-body radiation. The light emitted by the Earth is mostly in the infrared. The light emitted by the much hotter Sun is in wavelengths that range from the ultraviolet to the infrared. The hotter an object is, the more energy it emits through light. There is an equilibrium between the energy contained in the incoming light from the Sun, and the energy leaving the Earth. This is because all energy present in the Earth must come from somewhere and energy can never be created nor destroyed. Because of this temperatures will rise and fall until the level of energy coming out of the Earth equals the amount coming into it. To see why this forms an equilibrium imagine 1) a world where less energy comes into the earth than out of it, and 2) a world where more energy comes into the earth than out of it. In condition 1 the Earth will lose energy through the light it outputs, this will reduce the temperature of the planet and therefore cause a return to the equilibrium. The same thing, only in the opposite direction, happens in situation 2. The state of this equilibrium sets the global temperature. Greenhouse gasses can shift this equilibrium by absorbing some of the light emitted by the Earth, and re-emitting it back at the Earth. This effectively reduces the light emission by the Earth forcing the temperature upwards. Core greenhouse gases in the Earth's climate are carbon dioxide and water vapor but there are a range of more minor greenhouse gasses. Arrhenius only took into account CO2 and H20 in his model. Based on this Arrhenius derived a mathematical model of the global climate. He found that the temperature varies with respect to CO2 concentration according to the following rule.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>if the quantity of carbonic acid [CO2] increases in geometric progression, the augmentation of the temperature will increase nearly in arithmetic progression.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In equation form this means</p>

<p>ΔT = α Ln(C/C_0)</p>

<p>Where ΔT is the change in temperature,α is a constant, C is the final concentration of CO2, and C_0 is the final concentration of CO2. The constant α was empirically determined.</p>

<p>There were of course gaps in his model. For example cloud cover plays no role in it. The role of feed-backs and forgings is very limited. Arrhenius though thought that Climate Change would be a positive gift to future generations ,in contrast to the views of the vast majority of modern scientists. <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=1t45AAAAMAAJ&printsec=frontcover#v=onepage&q&f=false">He wrote that</a> and argued that the change would rule out the possibility of a future ice age, and the negative consequences of such an ice age.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We often hear lamentations that the coal stored up in the earth is wasted by the present generation without any thought of the future, and we are terrified by the awful destruction of life and property which has followed the volcanic eruptions of our days. We may find a kind of consolation in the consideration that here, as in every other case, there is good mixed with the evil. By the influence of the increasing percentage of carbonic acid in the atmosphere, we may hope to enjoy ages with more equable and better climates, especially as regards the colder regions of the earth, ages when the earth will bring forth much more abundant crops than at present, for the benefit of rapidly propagating mankind.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Arrhenius also thought that this change would come much more slowly. He underestimated the rate of industrialization by a wide margin and thought that it would take 3000 years for human impacts to double CO2. However, in actuality emissions increased so rapidly that it is possible that the doubleing could occur with in the 21st century if there are no policy changes made to reduce these emissions. However, the history of climate change research, a history that goes back over a century challenges the notion that global warming is a new concept dreamed up by tree huggers and Al Gore with scientists jumping on the propaganda bandwagon.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#algore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/josephfourier" class="p-category" rel="tag">#josephfourier</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#v</category>
      <category>#algore</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#josephfourier</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 12:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I will be writing a series of blog posts on the history of the politics of sustainable energy. Here is an outline of the posts that I will write.</p>

<p><strong>The First Climate Change Researchers? </strong> <br />1. <a title="Arrhenius and Climate Change" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/arrhenius-and-climate-change/">Arrhenius and Climate Change</a> <br />2. <a title="How Correct Was the First Climate Change Prediction?" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/how-correct-was-the-first-climate-change-prediction/">How Correct Was the First Climate Change Prediction? <br /></a>3.<a title="Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply/"> Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply</a> <br />4. <a title="The Beginning of Renewable Energy" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy/">The Beginning of Renewable Energy.</a> <br />5. Early Economic Thought on Externalities</p>

<p><strong>Energy Policy During the World Wars</strong> <br />1. What Modern Climate Change Policy Makers Can Learn From Economics Policy During the Wars <br />2. Inflation and "Voluntary" Savings During World War 1 <br />3. The Federal Fuel Administration and World War 1 Energy Rationing <br />4. How Economic Policy was Done Better During World War 2 <br />5. Synthetic Oil <br />6. The Manhattan Project and Civilian Energy <br />7. The Great Depression and Energy Infrastructure <br />8. The Great Depression and Conservation</p>

<p><strong>Sustainable Energy Policy After the Wars </strong> <br />1. Our Friend the Atom: Research Into Nuclear Power in The U.S <br />2. The Soviet Union and Nuclear Energy <br />3. The Oil Crisis of the 1970s <br />4. Renewable Energy and The Oil Crisis <br />5. The Messmer Plan --- How France Converted to Nuclear to Reduce Oil Usage <br />6. The Reagan Administration, the End of the Oil Crisis, and Natural Gas <br />7. The Birth of The Environmental Movement. <br />8. The Chernobyl Disaster <br />9. Three Mile Island <br />10. The Formation of Anti-Nuclear Sentiments and The End of The Nuclear Golden Age <br />11. <a href="https://theojones.name/the-environmental-movements-greatest-own-goal/">The Environmental Movement's Greatest Own Goal?</a> <br />12. Nixon and the EPA</p>

<p><strong>Modern Climate Science</strong> <br />1. Climate Change Science Before the 70s <br />2. Climate Change Science During The 70s <br />3. Modern Ecology <br />4. The Latest Mass Extinction? <br />5. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/climate-change-science-now/" title="Climate Change Science Now">Climate Change Science Now</a> <br />6. The IPCC</p>

<p><strong>The Birth of Climate Change Denialism </strong> <br />1. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-political-foundations-of-denialism/" title="The Political Foundations of Denialism">The Political Foundations of Denialism</a> <br />2. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-anatomy-of-climate-change-denialism/" title="The Anatomy of Climate Change Denialism">The Anatomy of Climate Change Denialism</a> <br />3. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-birth-of-anti-environmentalism/" title="The Birth of Anti-environmentalism">Anti-environmentalism</a> <br />4. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/politics-media-and-the-public-opinion-on-climate-change/" title="Politics, Media, and the Public Opinion on Climate Change">Politics, Media and Climate Change</a> <br />5. Industry and Climate Change <br />6. Conservative Politics and Climate Change <br />7. Is libertarianism compatible with our Knowledge of Climate Change? <br />8. Special Interests and Energy Policy <br />9.<a title="Are only some political ideologies compatible with science?" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/are-only-some-political-ideologies-compatible-with-science/">Are only some political ideologies compatible with science?</a></p>

<p><strong>The Response to Climate Change</strong> <br />1. Energy Independence <br />2. Energy Policy During the Clinton Administration <br />3. The Biofuels Disaster <br />4. The 2007 Food Price Crisis <br />5. Energy Policy During the Bush Administration <br />6. Can Climate Change be Separated From Other Economic Issues? <br />7. Carbon Taxes and Carbon Pricing <br />8. Are We On the Verge of Repeating the Problems of World War 1 Economic Policy <br />9. The Hansen Proposal -- A Case Study in Carbon Pricing and Its Weaknesses <br />10. Equality, Justice and Climate Change <br />11.<a href="https://theojones.name/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy/">The Problems With Using Cost-Benefit Analysis In Climate Change Policy</a> <br />12. Identity Politics and Energy <br />13. Direct Regulation Reconsidered. <br />14. How to Convert to Sustainable Energy <br />15. Regional Politics and Energy</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/epa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#epa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#epa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Delivery and Energy Production Should Be Separated</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/energy-delivery-and-energy-production-should-be-separated</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/energy-delivery-and-energy-production-should-be-separated</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>In this post I will contend that energy utilities really do two distinct things that can and should be separate. The first is producing energy. The second is distributing that electricity. Separating these two roles will vastly improve the competitiveness of the electricity markets and will have benefits in regard to climate change and pollution. It would improve consumer choice , and allow consumers greater choice in what energy is consumed and how it is produced. However in reality, most utilities are also the main producers of the electricity that they distribute. As I will discuss towards the end of the post, this change would be <br />
Electricity production is a natural monopoly -- that is the lowest cost market outcome is one electricity utility serving an entire community. This of course has problems, a monopoly can of course over charge consumers. Monopolies charge based on what the consumer is willing to pay while a firm in a competitive market charges based on the actual cost. Additionally, a monopoly can abuse their power to gain market share of other related markets. This is in effect what most utilities have done with energy production. Because they are the sole distributor of electricity it is easy for them to make themselves the main producer of it. This not only increases costs to consumers, but also reduces their choice. If a consumer wants an energy plan heavy on a given energy source, or billed in a certain way, it may be very difficult to arrange that in the current system. In a more competitive energy market, there would be many energy producers each vying for the dollars of consumers. They would not have to wait for the sluggishness of one utility company for a new method to arrive. There would be an explosion of energy plans and energy sources, and types of billing. Want a energy plan centered on nuclear power, but no fossil fuels? Tough to find under current conditions, but perhaps not so tough under a more competitive arrangement. Want a energy plan billed on a fixed monthly rate -- like how internet is billed? Very few utilities offer such a thing, but it might be more easy to find that type of thing in a more competitive market. More examples of how this would work could be envisioned. <br />
Such a change would also have positive implications for the environment. Remember the issue about net metering of solar production at home? There is a great public benefit to allowing consumers to sell back energy they produce. But the types of net metering that regulators commonly implement have a severe flaw. They enable people to produce energy at low-value, off peak times and use the grid as a free battery. Separating energy production from distribution would solve this dilemma. People with home solar systems would sell their energy production to a energy production company, and a reasonable agreed upon value that takes into account the level of demand for the energy. But the distribution utility would charge a fee for the connection to the grid. This would prevent people from producing low value energy in-order to use the grid as a free battery. But it would reward people who use clean energy production at home to produce valuable energy. There are other clean energy production benefits of such a change. There would be a great opportunity for energy producers to experiment with clean energy sources, and sell this production to consumers who are willing to be early adopters. This is in contrast to utilities which can take many years to adapt to a change. <br />
This change would be easy to implement. Instead of dealing with one power company, consumers would pay two companies. Consumers would pay a utility to hook their house to the grid. This would likely be billed as a flat monthly fee. They would then find a energy production company that has a plan that they like. The billing for this would vary from plan to plan. Despite the increased complexity of this setup, consumers would greatly benefit.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uber Frenzy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/uber-frenzy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/uber-frenzy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 13:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>What is the deal with the people who are fawning over "ride sharing" (read: unregulated taxi) services like Uber, and Lyft? I've seen lots of people who think these services will bring forth a transportation utopia and replace the need to own your own car. The companies themselves (and many of their supporters) think they have an uniquely "disruptive" service that . These types of services are pretty much more efficient taxi services. Taxi services where people use their own private cars, and mostly work part time. They bring up the exact same problems and limitations that other taxi services have.</p><p>They are a way to hire a driver to take you some place -- only in this case the hiring is done through a computer, allowing more rapid adjustment of pricing and more ability to select the driver you want to ride with. The companies claim that this minor difference is enough to make them exempt from the same regulations that bind normal taxis. Lyft went far enough to <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/07/lyft-defies-new-york-city-taxi-agencys-ban-to-launch-friday/">defy</a> a order from the New York City Taxi and Limousine Commission, and an associated order from the New York State Supreme Court, until the state's attorney general o<a href="http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-lyft-nyc-20140711-story.html">btained a second court order</a> that would have subjected individual drivers to legal risk. As Eric Schneiderman, the New York attorney general put it "Lyft decided to move ahead and simply ignore state and local laws." Their legal justification is the absurd claim that they are not taxis, but are instead "ride sharing" firms. Ride sharing companies that have paid drivers on staff, that can drive you to where you want on demand, and that you pay based on the distance taken. Not exactly carpooling.</p><p>People who should know better are in on the Uber worship frenzy. Take Paul Krugman's <a href="http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/07/15/life-without-cars/">thoughts on the magic disruptor</a>.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Anyway: the big benefit from new IT-mediated car services will come if they make it possible for lots of people — and not just people in Manhattan — to live without owning their own cars. And if you think about it, you can see how that might work.</p>
</blockquote><p>Taxis, even "IT-mediated" ones need human drivers -- at least until Google releases their car to market. Human drivers are expensive. <a href="https://www.lyft.com/drivers">Lyft claims</a> that their drivers can "MAKE $35/HR DRIVING WITH LYFT". In an advertisement ran on the Bing search engine Uber claims their drivers can "Make Up To $40/hr In Fares". It goes without saying that few can afford this on a regular basis. This is why taxis have not replaced personal cars, not that they aren't sufficiently "IT-mediated". Replacing your car with a taxi or "ride sharing service" just isn't practical.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Right now, if you live in places without exceptionally good public transportation, it’s very difficult to manage without a car. Yet when you think about it, for most people owning a car is quite wasteful. It’s an expensive item of equipment that sits idle most of the time; it requires parking (and often a parking structure) both at origin and at destination; it requires maintenance and is a big hassle all around.</p>
</blockquote><p>Wasteful is hiring a large portion of the population at $35 per hour just to drive others around. All of these benefits can be reached by mass transit construction, at a cost that is actually reasonable to consumers.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/make" class="p-category" rel="tag">#make</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#make</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Stupidity: Don't Write Stuff About Technical Topics When You Have No Idea What You Are Talking About</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/ai-stupidity-dont-write-stuff-about-technical-topics-when-you</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/ai-stupidity-dont-write-stuff-about-technical-topics-when-you</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 09:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>There are some factual errors that are tolerable. There are some other errors that are so wrong that anyone publishes an article with them doesn't know what they are talking about, and thus can be safely ignored as a credible source. One subject where people are very good at making themselves sound like idiots is artificial intelligence. There was the vast media attention given to <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/06/09/software_passes_turing_test/">"Captain Cyborg" Kevin Warwick's chat bot</a>, even though ol professor cyborg is a known crackpot in the AI world.</p><p>However, the press still doesn't realize the difference between a computer program that applies a few simple rules to bodies of text, and genuine intelligence.</p><p><a href="http://jezebel.com/instagram-apologizes-for-deleting-plus-size-womans-acco-1605831194">Today's AI PEBAC comes</a> from an article on a liberal blog about someone who got banned from Instagram for seemingly no good reason. The ID10t error comes from the following paragraph.  </p><blockquote>
<p>And before people start computer-splaining about how these companies use an automated system to deal with reports, you can hold your breath. We already know. That system is fucked up. If companies like Facebook can manage to come up with software that knows to spam you with ads for baby clothes right at the time you "liked" your old roommate's post announcing she was pregnant, they sure as shit should be able to come up with a system that doesn't arbitrarily discriminate on who gets deleted and who stays. But thanks for the IT lesson anyway.</p>
</blockquote><p>Why am I writing flamage about this particular passage? This stupidity didn't just stay put. It spread to other websites. I've seen that particular passage quoted as truth -- with all seriousness -- on Huff Post and other news websites. And this vision that it is somehow easy to create a moderation bot that is as good as a human mod and that doesn't fuck up is stupid. A moderation bot is written by the application of a few simple mathematical rules to text processing. In particular these bots often take into account the words used in the posts. The frequency of the varous words can be compared to the frequency of the words in pasts that have been banned by human users. If the bot determines that the text of a suspect user has similar word frequency to known trolls then the banhammer will drop. These programs also often take into account the ratio of complaints, and downvotes to actual account activity, and number of followers. The impression that it shows any deeper intelligence is simply the ELIZA effect. Humans are good at seeing some type of intelligence where none exists. Such as the author of the linked post who thinks that moderation bots express sexism, and can willingly fat shame and intentionally offend Tumblr users (an easy AI problem). As for the "software that knows to spam you with ads for baby clothes right at the time you 'liked' your old roommate's post announcing she was pregnant", those use the exact same methods that the moderation software does. They are also quite error prone, but you tend not to notice their failures as much. The typical person will ignore an irrelevant ad, but will definitely notice the banhammer.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/eliza" class="p-category" rel="tag">#eliza</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/huffpost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#huffpost</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/it" class="p-category" rel="tag">#it</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#eliza</category>
      <category>#huffpost</category>
      <category>#it</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Separatists Likely Responsible for Crashed Airliner in Ukraine</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/separatists-likely-responsible-for-crashed-airliner-in-ukraine</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/separatists-likely-responsible-for-crashed-airliner-in-ukraine</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 05:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/17/world/europe/ukraine-malaysia-airlines-crash/index.html?hpt=hp_t1">A passenger jet crashed</a>in eastern Ukraine today with 295 deaths, most likely due to a missile strike. The Ukrainian government has already blamed the attack on separatists that it identifies as terrorists. There is strong evidence to back up the Kiev's claim. Kiev also claims direct Russian military involvement in the incident. The separatists have seized 9K37 Buk-M1 missile systems and <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/ukraine-separatists-have-shot-down-multiple-aircraft-over-the-past-month-2014-7">have already used these to shoot down military aircraft</a>. Eyewitness accounts<a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/UkrainianConflict/comments/2ayy7e/buk_in_snizhne_today/"> provide evidence</a> that these were deployed near where the airliner crashed.<a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/07/17/world/europe/malaysia-airlines-crash-missile/index.html?iid=article_sidebar"> Buk-M1 missiles are consistent</a> with the airliner's flight-path, altitude, and the damage done. Because the separatists lack aircraft the Ukrainian army would be unlikely to widely deploy anti-aircraft missiles. Further evidence of separatist involvement comes from the fact that separatist forces quickly seized the flight data recorder of the airliner and are in progress of transporting it to Russia. Recordings and online discussions from the separatists seems to also confirm their responsibility.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/UkrainianConflict/comments/2ayy7e/buk_in_snizhne_today/">The following photo</a> (via a Ukranian Reddit user) shows a Buk-M1 launcher in Snizhne, a city near the crash site. <br /><br /><a href="http://ukrain.bazaza.net/207606/">Other accounts</a> seem to confirm the presence of Buk-M1 launchers in Snizhne. Before the airliner was hit, the separatists pledged to <a href="http://www.vesti.ru/doc.html?id=1741703">use the Buk-M1 launchers to protect their airspace</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://abcnews.go.com/International/malaysian-air-loses-contact-passenger-plane-ukraine/story?id=24599558">A statement by Ukraine's Foreign Ministry</a> describes the following details about the crash.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>According to the General Staff of Ukrainian Armed Forces, the airplane was shot down by the Russian Buk missile system as the liner was flying at an altitude of 10,000 meters. Ukraine has no long-range air defense missile systems in this area. The plane was shot down, because the Russian air defense systems was affording protection to Russian mercenaries and terrorists in this area. Ukraine will present the evidence of Russian military involvement into the Boeing crash.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ukraine's Security Service posted but later removed a intercepted intercepted phone call that <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150613142805/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.youtube.com/<wbr></wbr>watch?v=skL_1RcLRCA</a>"&gt;seems to indicate separatist involvement.</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en">
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Ukraine?src=hash"></a><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Ukraine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Ukraine</a>'s security services posted audio of Russian fighters discussing how they shot down <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MH17?src=hash"></a><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/MH17" class="p-category" rel="tag">#MH17</a> jetliner <a href="http://t.co/1jNqcwEhsu"></a><a href="http://t.co/1jNqcwEhsu">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>t.co/<wbr></wbr>1jNqcwEhsu</a></p>

<p>— Ukraine Reporter (@StateOfUkraine) <a href="https://twitter.com/StateOfUkraine/statuses/489845900790218752">July 17, 2014</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<p>A translated transcript of the discussion <a href="http://arstechnica.com/civis/viewtopic.php?p=27230025#p27230025">can be found in this forum discussion</a>.</p>

<p>Igor Ivanovich Strelkov, a top commander of the sepratist forces took responsibility for downing the plane when he was still under the impression that it was Ukrainian saying, "We warned - do not fly in our skies".</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en">
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Russia?src=hash"></a><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Russia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Russia</a>'n cmdr Strelkov commented on downed <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MH17?src=hash"></a><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/MH17" class="p-category" rel="tag">#MH17</a> (thinking it was Ukrainian): "We warned - do not fly in our skies" <a href="http://t.co/hkXoaD3xvT">pic.twitter.com/hkXoaD3xvT</a></p>

<p>— Ukraine Reporter (@StateOfUkraine) <a href="https://twitter.com/StateOfUkraine/statuses/489802664264212480">July 17, 2014</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/igorivanovichstrelkov" class="p-category" rel="tag">#igorivanovichstrelkov</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/russianbuk" class="p-category" rel="tag">#russianbuk</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ukraineforeignministry" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ukraineforeignministry</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ukrainesecurityservice" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ukrainesecurityservice</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Ukraine</category>
      <category>#MH17</category>
      <category>#p27230025</category>
      <category>#Russia</category>
      <category>#MH17</category>
      <category>#igorivanovichstrelkov</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#russianbuk</category>
      <category>#ukraineforeignministry</category>
      <category>#ukrainesecurityservice</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Do About Immigration</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-immigration</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/what-to-do-about-immigration</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 09:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>The current U.S immigration policy is a total disaster. It is economically inefficient, it is a moral crisis. It is an inherently unjust system. America's immigration policy exacerbates global poverty and through its impact on the world economy costs trillions of dollars.<a href="http://www.cgdev.org/publication/economics-and-emigration-trillion-dollar-bills-sidewalk-working-paper-264"> On a global scale immigration restrictions cost 50-150% of world GDP. </a> The U.S immigration policy subjects millions to severe harms, and removes economic opportunity from many more. An internal policy this harmful would not be tolerated. I believe that immigration policy, like all other major economic issues, should be judged based on its impact on the whole world, not just on its domestic impacts. That is, even if U.S citizens were on the whole benefited by the status quo the immigration system would need reform if the current system harmed the world as a whole. Due to the vast inefficiency of the current immigration system. The only broadly justifiable rationale of immigration restriction are ones aimed at mitigating real externalities that are globally harmful. I propose a radical shift in policy. I believe that the U.S should shift to a policy of free migration. I believe that the U.S should give any law abiding immigrant to the country a work permit with minimal restrictions. Non-work entrance (with similar permissions to tourist and educations visas) should be granted visa free. Work permits should be granted with a minimal set of fees and taxes. Indirect controls on migration -- such as through regulations and subsidies that favor citizens over non-citizens should be reduced. A much more streamlined path to citizenship should be created that should give citizenship to all who have held paid employment for a sufficiently long period of time. I will expand on this in future blog posts.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal of America</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-ideal-of-america-1</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-ideal-of-america-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2014 16:41:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <div title="Page 1">
<p>[caption id="attachment_317" align="alignright" width="203"] Unveiling of the Statue of Liberty Enlightening the World (1886) by Edward Moran[/caption]</p>

<p>What are the values that have made America and Americans different? An American can be of any race, creed, religion, philosophy, or ethnicity. The United States has never been a country of one religious or ethnic group, and Americans have many diverse political philosophies. The ideal of America has been that of a country where immigrants from throughout the world could come and make a good life and where Americans from all socioeconomic backgrounds could move up the economic ladder, or at the least attain a good education and provide for themselves and their families if they work hard. America has always been a melting pot and a nation of diversity. America is a home for persons of all types­­ there is no one stereotypical real American.</p>

<p>Americans enjoy freedom of speech and religion and live under a legal system that protects these basic individual rights. What makes a real American is the strong belief in these values and the freedoms that come with being a citizen of the United States, as well as respect for those values and freedoms. The United States was founded to be a country where the most famous lines of the Declaration of Independence -- a document ratified 237 years ago today -- ring true, where “<em>We hold these truths to be self­ evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>America was founded to be a nation of laws, not men, where there would never be a European­style aristocracy and where all were equal in rights and opportunity. These values are inherently both communal and individual as both liberty and equality involve the relations between individuals to other individuals in society. Because of this, the power of community has been at the heart of what makes America great. While these values and hopes have never been fully implemented, and there are still great inequities in American society, these values form the heart and soul of America and its people.</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>The fact that America is a nation of diversity can be seen in where Americans have come from. There have been Americans that have come from almost all cultural groups in the world.</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. British Puritans and Pilgrims migrated to the New World for religious liberty and settled in New England and founded the colonies of Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Connecticut. Quaker immigrants settled Pennsylvania looking for religious freedom. Pennsylvania after Quaker settlement was the first colony to provide religious freedom to all and soon became home to individuals of many religions. The Dutch founded what is now New York City, but this land was eventually absorbed into the British Empire. New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Delaware attracted many Irish, German and Scandinavian immigrants. By 1790 almost one half of the American population was not of British ancestry. Restrictions on immigration and importation of goods imposed by the British were a significant cause of the American Revolution. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “<em>He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither</em>... “</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>After independence, the United States immigration laws were extremely permissive. The Naturalization Act of 1790, which was the first U. S. immigration law, placed no restrictions on immigration and allowed free whites to obtain citizenship after two years of residency in the United States. In the 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had a free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, and immigrants from Asia. This migration was its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. The inscription on the Statue of Liberty greeted the immigrants entering the country through Ellis Island with the following poem written by Emma Lazarus and titled The New Colossus. It summed up America's values toward immigrants,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Not like the brazen giant of Greek fame, With conquering limbs astride from land to land; Here at our sea­washed, sunset gates shall stand A mighty woman with a torch, whose flame Is the imprisoned lightning, and her name Mother of Exiles. From her beacon­ hand Glows world­ wide welcome; her mild eyes command The air-­bridged harbor that twin cities frame. 'Keep, ancient lands, your storied pomp!' cries she With silent lips. 'Give me your tired, your poor, Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free, The wretched refuse of your teeming shore. Send these, the homeless, tempest ­tossed to me, I lift my lamp beside the golden door!'”</p>
</blockquote><div title="Page 3">
<p>America was open to immigrants throughout the world and was a nation of opportunities. It is clear that this history has made the United States a nation of diversity created by immigrants from all over the world. This American history of immigration is what makes being American not about what religious or ethnic group you are part of, but about the American values of liberty and equality that are so eloquently summed up by The New Colossus. American values have always been to create a nation where people from throughout the world could come to experience liberty and opportunity. What makes an American is therefore belief in these values, the values that have attracted and brought so many immigrants to the United States.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The core values of America that shape and created the nation are liberty and equality. These values have drawn immigrants to the nation since the Puritans, Pilgrims and Quakers first set foot in the New World looking for religious liberty. It is these values that define what being an American is and form the basis of the American community. America was founded to be a place where no king could arbitrarily interfere with basic liberties. Freedom and equality come hand in hand and cannot exist without each other.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>Freedom in the American community means not being dominated over, and living in a community with other citizens that are equal in rights and opportunities. American poet and author Walt Whitman defined freedom as follows, “<em>Freedom --­ to walk free and own no superior.</em>“ and said this of being a citizen of America, “<em>Neither a servant nor a master am I</em>.” These values have motivated American activists throughout the nation's history to fight for what is right and to fight to bring liberty and equal opportunity to all.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The founders of the United States saw freedom and equality as inherently linked. Excessive inequality could result in aristocracy and would be corrosive to society and freedom. But freedom was inherently linked with accepting that all men are created equal. Alexis de Tocqueville, a famous French author who wrote about the early United States, said, “<em>Grant me thirty years of equal division of inheritances and a free press, and I will provide you with a republic.</em>” In the Federalist #10, James Madison stated that “<em>the most common and durable source of factions has been the various and unequal distribution of property. Those who hold and those who are without property have ever formed distinct interests in society.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 4">
<p>The struggle for freedom and equality for all has defined the United States throughout its history and defines what it means to be an American. The biggest questions in American history have been “what is liberty?” and “what is the proper relation between liberty and order?” and the biggest struggles in American history have involved expanding freedom and equality. The greatest victories in these struggles have come in four waves. The first wave of this struggle came with the Revolutionary War and the formation of the new United States government. The second wave of the American struggle for freedom for all came with the U.S Civil War and its aftermath. The third wave of this struggle came with the Great Depression, the New Deal and the Second World War and its aftermath. The fourth wave was the Civil Rights Movement. The Declaration of Independence was the statement of the core values of America and its people. However, the realization that “<em>all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights</em>” came throughout the history of the United States and is still not entirely complete. The Declaration of Independence stated that the role of government ought to be to protect these rights and that a just government is based around the consent of the governed. After independence, American society became the closest in existence to a society without an aristocracy. A government was created that was the closest thing to a republic of laws, not men, that existed in the world. About a decade after the end of the revolution, a constitution was ratified that created a new national government for the United States. In its Preamble the Constitution stated its purpose as follows, “<em>to form a more perfect Union, establish Justice, insure domestic Tranquility, provide for the common defense, promote the general Welfare, and secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity.</em>” Shortly thereafter, a second great American document was created, the Bill of Rights. This document protected many fundamental rights from government violation. Through many years of existence and legal interpretation, the Bill of Rights became a great American document that has played a large role in determining the nature of American freedom and liberty and has been at the heart of the shared American historical and cultural heritage. These documents are part of what makes America what it is and Americans who they are.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The history of the Civil War and reconstruction resulted in a great expansion of liberty, the end of slavery, and the expansion of the rights of citizenship to many Americans who did not receive those liberties before. The legal changes that happened during this period are most dramatically reflected in the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, which reads in part, “<em>No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</em>” The 14th Amendment's declaration that all are equal before the law put the Declaration of Independence's most famous value into the constitution. It stated that all Americans have rights that must be protected by law. Furthermore, the Civil War and its aftermath helped define what it means to be American by creating an American national identity. Americans were Americans first and foremost instead of residents of their states first and foremost.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The New Deal era and the aftermath of World War II brought a new era in the expansion of rights in the United States. During the New Deal, it was realized that liberty included certain economic rights and that protecting the liberty of the population included giving everyone economic opportunities. In a tradition that went back to the nation's founding, it was realized that excessive concentrations of wealth were harmful and made it difficult to maintain the conditions needed for freedom to continue. The Second World War and its aftermath saw the exportation of the American values of freedom for all to the rest of the world. During the war, President Franklin D. Roosevelt made his Four Freedoms speech in which he stated that freedom of speech, freedom of religion, freedom from fear, and freedom from want were human rights that ought to be protected for all persons everywhere in the world. This speech served to be an inspiration for the development of the United Nations after the war, and the expansion of human rights to everyone throughout the world. The civil rights movement that started in the 1950s expanded the horizons of American liberty and freedom. The formal racial segregation and discrimination of the Jim Crow era was ended and economic discrimination was reduced. Courts made important civil rights and civil liberties decisions that expanded liberty and equality for all. Economic programs such Lyndon Johnson's Great Society expanded opportunity and alleviated poverty. During the 1970s and 80s women's rights were established and expanded., in a large part due to court victories won by activists.</p>
<div title="Page 6"><div title="Page 6">America is a nation of diversity created by a history of immigration, a nation not made of any one cultural or religious group. This nation has been a place where people of all kinds came for a better life throughout its entire history. This has been true since even before U.S independence. From Quaker and Puritan immigrants looking for religious freedom, to the immigrants of Ellis Island to modern immigrants, people have come to America looking for freedom. America has been a nation of ideals and laws, not of men or aristocracy, throughout its history. These values of freedom and equality have inspired struggle for all of America's history. While these struggles have never created a perfect union, America has become more perfect and a greater home to the blessings of liberty over its history. What makes a real American is not simply who you are, but it is our shared values and the belief that you have the freedom and opportunity to become all that you want to be, as long as you don't violate the freedoms and liberties of others. It is this belief in liberty and equality for all that makes America great and makes being an American great. The constitution gives Americans certain rights and our freedom and liberty are guaranteed. But what makes an American a real American is the respect for these values and the respect for the struggle that secured these freedoms, as well as a determination to continue to protect and fight for these values.</div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/civilwar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#civilwar</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newdeal" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newdeal</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyorkcity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyorkcity</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#10</category>
      <category>#civilwar</category>
      <category>#newdeal</category>
      <category>#newyorkcity</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
