<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Can Morality Be Derived Without Special Assumptions</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/can-morality-be-derived-without-special-assumptions</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/can-morality-be-derived-without-special-assumptions</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 22:59:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/contract.jpg"><img class="  wp-image-2419 aligncenter" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/contract.jpg" alt="contract" width="638" height="327"></a>In a previous post<a href="https://www.theojones.name/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-in-philosophy/">, I discussed what special assumptions</a> are needed to do logical reasoning about philosophy and factual matters. In that post I said some special assumption the bridge the is-ought problem would be needed. In this post I will discuss whatever that is really true, my conclusion will be quite possibly not. I believe that one could make an argument for moral realism somewhat <a href="http://bloggingheads.tv/videos/2346?in=49:59&out=58:34">along the lines of what Steve Pinker has said in an interview</a>. In effect the argument is that morality comes from basic elements of game theory is tempered by a social contract. Game theory is a inherent part of the world as applied by mathematics. The elements of game theory are likely to result in the prisoner’s dilemma type situations that result in moral reasoning are produced by inherent parts of how the laws of physics, chemistry, and biology work on the world. It’s a hybrid between traditional social contract type theories, and traditional moral realism. But in order to operate, such a moral theory doesn’t require any real assumptions beyond what is already known by way of science or other factual information.</p>

<p>This point of view has a few benefits. The first real benefit this point of view is that it avoids the problem of being too demanding. A lot of ethical and political theories have a huge issue that they tend to conform pretty poorly to human nature. Social contract type theories tend not to have this issue. The fact that they are produced by game theoretic bargaining between parties tends to eliminate this issue out of hand. A social contract type theory will tend to lack both the harsh moralizing that deontological ethical theories tend to provide, and the extreme demandingness of traditional utilitarianism.</p>

<p>The next benefit of this is that it’s a moral realist point of view. The elements of game theory embedded in this point of view exist independently of the subjective viewpoints of observers. This implies that morality itself, in some part, exists in a way this is independent of the subjective views of observers. This is both intuitively pleasing, and goes along with the many <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Normative-Web-Argument-Moral-Realism/dp/019958138X/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&qid=1434835336&sr=8-8&keywords=moral+realism">strong arguments for moral realism</a>.</p>

<p>Furthermore, the substantial sympathy I expressed in the previous post towards some form of preference utilitarianism, is in my opinion somewhat justified by this point of view. I think through a social contract something that looks a lot like fairly traditional preference utilitarianism will emerge, although, perhaps bounded by the Lockean proviso. And even better, this result will most likely emerge only as applied to the world of political philosophy – the place where the over demandingness of traditional utilitarianism does not rear its ugly head. In the world of politics, an assistance that everyone’s preferences be weighted equally by the state is not unreasonable. A derivatization of preference utilitarianism from contract theory is also able to resolve some of the most troubling dilemmas brought up by traditional utilitarianism. Issues like what types of preferences count for the purposes of moral reasoning, and how to deal with things like future generations. From the point of view of raw utilitarianism, there are no obvious solutions to such issues. However, from a social contract type point of view, it’s quite possible to reason through such problems. It’s a potentially a very clean and very elegant solution.</p>

<p><strong>Image credit <a href="https://flic.kr/p/9mjRKW">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>9mjRKW</a></strong><br /><strong> Flickr User Steve Snodgrass</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#philosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#philosophy</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a interesting blog on philosophy https...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-is-a-interesting-blog-on-philosophy-https</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-is-a-interesting-blog-on-philosophy-https</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 05:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>This is a interesting blog on philosophy <br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com</a></p>

<p>Some of the more interesting articles:<br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/2010/07/01/the-normative-web-an-argument-for-moral-realism-by-terance-cuneo/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2010/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>01/<wbr></wbr>the-normative-web-an-argument-for-moral-realism-by-terance-cuneo/<wbr></wbr></a><br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/2011/05/20/the-debate-over-moral-realism/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>20/<wbr></wbr>the-debate-over-moral-realism/<wbr></wbr></a><br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/2011/07/19/the-isought-gap-how-do-we-get-ought-from-is/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>19/<wbr></wbr>the-isought-gap-how-do-we-get-ought-from-is/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#philosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#philosophy</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Basic Assumptions of Mine about Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o.jpg" alt="486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o" width="769" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2463"></a>I am almost a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Positivism">positivist</a>/empiricist in my philosophical beliefs, I believe that about the only reliable source of knowledge is observation, the scientific method, and the repeated refinement of theories through science. This applies even for human society. My one difference from this view is the belief that just raw observation isn't sufficient. There is the need for bridge assumptions in order to translate mere observations into explanatory theories and moral judgements. Additionally, some basic metaphysical assumptions are needed. The list of such assumptions should be as short as possible, and as much of the heavy lifting should be loaded on to observation. But these bridge assumptions are needed as just pure observation is not enough. A pile of data is not a theory and is not an explanation of the world. Mere observation is not sufficient to produce knowledge. Results need to be merged into something greater than their parts. Correlations between different results need to be drawn together into a greater theory. All this requires interpretation, and there needs to be rules that to interpretation. Likewise there have to be a few basic assumptions about how the world works in order to make science workable. Ethics is another thing where mere data isn't enough. The is-ought gap needs to be bridged. Therefore a basic assumption about how to turn facts about how the world is to ethical judgments is needed. As follows in the rest of this blog post is a rough overview of what my basic assumptions about the world is like. Additionally, a positivist/empiricist worldview without bridge assumptions will be unavoidably self-contradictory. There is no way that empiricism itself can be confirmed through mere observation.</p>
<ol><li>Physicalism --- all objects that exist follow laws of physics that exist independently of the subjective views of observers. My preferred variant of this is the mathematical universe hypothesis, the idea that the universe is a mathematical structure.</li>
    <li>The basic rules of logic.</li>
    <li>The scientific method. For this I prefer something along the lines of Popperlian falseificationsim. This is the idea that science is the repeated refinement of falsifiable theories through observation.</li>
    <li>A rule regarding ethics. I prefer preference utilitarianism – the idea that the moral set of actions is the one that results in the longest long-run preference satisfaction when aggregated over all individuals.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: Flickr user Seth de l'Isle  <a href="https://flic.kr/p/JX2US">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>JX2US</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#philosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#philosophy</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
