<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/secondcircuit</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/secondcircuit?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>GMO Labeling and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gmo-labeling-and-the-first-amendment</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gmo-labeling-and-the-first-amendment</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 21:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Vermont passed a law requiring the labeling of GMO products a few months ago. The law won't take effect until 2016, but there is already litigation about the constitutionality of the legislation. In this post I will argue that the labeling law most likely violates the protections of the First Amendment. Due to the <a href="http://hstlj.org/articles/a-brief-history-of-the-commercial-speech-doctrine-with-some-implications-for-tobacco-regulation/">commercial speech doctrine</a> courts have ruled that advertising (including product labeling) is protected by the Constitution, although to a lesser extent than other forms of speech. The courts have not precisely delineated a boundary for when law makers can regulate commercial speech, but have generally found that</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1327" align="alignnone" width="646"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2835892559_d94c45ff7e_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1327 size-large" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2835892559_d94c45ff7e_o-1024x768.jpg" alt="Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances." width="646" height="485"></a> Image Via Flickr (user david__jones) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5jAG4i%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5jAG4i[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>there must be a provable harm (or at least possible harm) to the consumer. Courts have given little weight to subjective consumer preferences, leaving the fulfillment of those to the market. There are some trends in the major Supreme Court cases on the subject such as <em>Virginia State Board of Pharmacy v. Virginia Citizens Consumer Council</em>, and <em>Central Hudson Gas v. Public Service Commission of New York</em></p>
<ol><li>The general standard for commercial speech cases is intermediate scrutiny. This also is the standard that applies to time place and manner speech restrictions (like city noise laws), sex/gender discrimination( among other protected classes).To pass this standard a law must further important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest</li>
    <li>Lawmakers have broad power to ban false advertising and advertising for illegal products.</li>
    <li>Advertising over electronic media receives lower protection than adverting in traditional publications.</li>
    <li>Prior restraint is permissible in the realm of commercial speech</li>
    <li>There is a wide scope for disclosure regulations, but there still needs to be a substantial government interest involved. Justifications based on consumer choice in the absence of tangible harm are usually not sufficient.</li>
</ol>
<p>The most similar case to the GMO one is <em>International Dairy Foods Association v. Amestoy</em> which came before the Second Circuit. This case involved a Vermont labeling law mandating that dairy products produced by cows treated with the rBST hormone be labeled. The government made no claims of a safety risk before the court, and the plaintiffs in that case entered evidence indicating that there was no safety risk. The trial court opinion noted that the government “does not claim that health or safety concerns prompted the passage of the Vermont Labeling Law,” and that there defense is based around "strong consumer interest and the public's ‘right to know’". The Second Circuit found that this interest in consumer choice is not a substantial interest. There may have been animal welfare justifications for the law made in the public discourse, but neither side made such arguments before the court, so that issue was never considered. However, a consumer survey was entered as evidence that indicated that such issues were a reason why consumers may have wanted to avoid rBST products, but none of these responces ammounted to a full argument on this basis (other than noting that the cows were “Producing enough milk already.”) The court found that the most common consumer reasons included</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>(1) They consider the use of a genetically-engineered hormone in the production unnatural;  (2) they believe that use of the hormone will result in increased milk production and lower milk prices, thereby hurting small dairy farmers;  (3) they believe that the use of rBST is harmful to cows and potentially harmful to humans;  and, (4) they feel that there is a lack of knowledge regarding the long-term effects of rBST.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The situation with GMO labeling is even less favorable. There are no reasonable safety arguments that could be used against GMO products. As the GMO products targeted are plants there are not any animal welfare arguments either. This leaves the consumer choice argument, which courts have already rejected as problematic. Allowing abstract preferences that have no basis in fact into the law produces severely paradoxical results when used to justify limits on fundamental rights. Imagine if such preferences were allowed into the other areas of law where the intermediate scrutiny standard was used. The results would be clearly unacceptable. Satisfying subjective consumer preferences in an efficient way are what markets are good at. If there is a consumer demand for notice about GMO products, then a voluntary (and perhaps privately owned) certification system should serve the purpose (with the producers paying the full cost of maintaining the system through fees).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyork" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyork</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/secondcircuit" class="p-category" rel="tag">#secondcircuit</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vermontlabelinglaw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vermontlabelinglaw</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#newyork</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#secondcircuit</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vermontlabelinglaw</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
