<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?offset=110</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?offset=110&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Gawker and Trolls</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gawker-and-trolls</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gawker-and-trolls</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 08:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>You may have seen the hubhub about Gawker media and its troll problem. In short the trolls are flooding its sites with porn images. This is part of a campaign by 4chan. Writers of the sites are outraged and demanding a</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1330" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6288497038_5d4e68c0b5_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1330" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/6288497038_5d4e68c0b5_o-300x201.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Tama Leaver) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>azGc5J</a>" width="300" height="201" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Tama Leaver) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/azGc5J%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>azGc5J[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>soloution to the issue. In short they want to make sure that they do not have to moderate the trollage. This however may be an impractical goal. It is very difficult for a</p>

<p>website to deal with a troll issue short of human moderation. A suggested alternative method is IP banning, but this cannot deal with a persistent and skilled troll (and 4chan counts). Also, IP banning rules out users that use systems like Tor. This means that such a system will hurt real users.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ip" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ip</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tamaleaver" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tamaleaver</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#ip</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#tamaleaver</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Inflation Overestimated?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-inflation-overestimated</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/is-inflation-overestimated</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 04:43:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It is a common argument among libertarians and other conservatives that the official statistics are dramatically understating the level of inflation in the economy. However, I will argue that the opposite is most likely the truth. The government is probably <i>overestimating</i> the level of inflation. This is because most measures of inflation look at a fixed basket of products and monitor how the price of the basket changes over time. However, in the world of real</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1320" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1320" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC</a> " width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/42PQoC%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>consumers,  price isn't the only thing that is changing, the basket itself is. As technology improves, consumers begin to buy other products that were not even on the market at the time. There is a substantial economic value to this ability to use this technology and most economic measures of real GDP don't take this value into account. Therefore, they over estimate the level of inflation in the economy.</p>

<p>The yearly change in real GDP can be described as follows:</p>

<p>RealChange = NominalChange - InflationRate</p>

<p>Inflation is calculated in terms of the real GDP. One inflation measure, the GDP deflator works as follows. Economists calculate what it would cost to buy the goods and services produced in the economy last year in both the dollars of this year and last year. The change can be taken as the imputed level of inflation. We have already seen the problem with this type of method. The products bought by consumers are not constant. The other major measure of inflation is not much better. The CPI is created by forming a basket of goods that represents typical consumer spending, and tracking how this basket of goods changes over time. Nether measure takes changes in technology into account.</p>

<p>There are two reasons why this is inaccurate.</p>
<ol><li>Technology change has great economic value. If the consumers of this year were allowed to pay a fee to access the technology of next year, this would likely be a substantial amount (although a difficult to calculate one at that).</li>
    <li>The items subject to the lowest level of technological change tend to be ones with the lowest reduction in price.</li>
</ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/dustinmoore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#dustinmoore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#dustinmoore</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Political Questions</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/debt-and-political-questions</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/debt-and-political-questions</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 19:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In this post I will argue that lawsuits in U.S courts by vulture funds against governmental defaults, <a href="http://en.mercopress.com/2014/08/16/global-trade-union-summit-condemns-actions-of-vulture-funds-against-argentina">like the litigation that recently forced Argentina into default</a>, should be dismissed due to separation of powers under the political question doctrine. The political question doctrine declares that some questions before the courts cannot be heard because hearing them would step on a fundamental role of the political branches. In <i>Baker v. Carr</i> the U.S supreme</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1336" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/4123495075_dd9a64af31_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1336" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/4123495075_dd9a64af31_o-300x200.jpg" alt="Image via flickr (user Orin Zebest) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7hnZqF</a>" width="300" height="200" /&gt; Image via flickr (user Orin Zebest) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/7hnZqF%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7hnZqF[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>court found that the doctrine prevents the courts from hearing a case when any of the following conditions are met</p>
<ol><li>"Textually demonstrable constitutional commitment of the issue to a coordinate political department;"</li>
    <li>"A lack of judicially discoverable and manageable standards for resolving it;"</li>
    <li>"The impossibility of deciding without an initial policy determination of a kind clearly for nonjudicial discretion;"</li>
    <li>"The impossibility of a court's undertaking independent resolution without expressing lack of the respect due coordinate branches of government;"</li>
    <li>"An unusual need for unquestioning adherence to a political decision already made;"</li>
    <li>"The potentiality of embarrassment from multifarious pronouncements by various departments on one question."</li>
</ol>
<p>In the area of foreign policy, this doctrine has been used by the courts to dismiss legal claims that involve the legal status of Taiwan, and the legality of military actions.</p>

<p>The litigant suing Argentina is a vulture fund. Vulture funds buy distressed debt that is near or in default. They then collect on this debt at a large profit. They are debt collectors for governments. <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jun/27/us-vulture-funds-argentina-bankruptcy">All creditors other than the group of vulture funds suing Argentina</a> settled the debt at a loss .</p>

<p>In the case of lawsuit at question in the Argentina debt case, the judiciary is taking up questions of international relations and public finance that fundamentally belong in the political branches. A lawsuit that forces a country into the risk of default has clear foreign policy consequences, and is almost entirely a foreign policy question. The case requires the courts to make a determination of the relative importance of debt payment over other obligations of the government of Argentina. This is also an inherently political decision. The court's actions in this case is already causing the U.S government international embarrassment. Such a decision should of never of been made.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/argentina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#argentina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/orinzebest" class="p-category" rel="tag">#orinzebest</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#argentina</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#orinzebest</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Problems With Using Cost-Benefit Analysis In Climate Change Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 00:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><i><a href="https://theojones.name/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">This is part of a blog post series on climate change.</a></i>In this post I will discuss how a cost/benefit type analysis of climate change can fail to truly appreciate the harms that it produces. In fact, a climate change policy based on a cost benefit <a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2324660064_1e9550c25b_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2324660064_1e9550c25b_o-300x200.jpg" alt="2324660064_1e9550c25b_o" width="300" height="200" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1450"></a>analysis will contradict fundamental rights, and will clearly violate the concept of equality before the law. Furthermore this type of policy will cause a climate change policy that is much less aggressive than it should be. In this post I will elaborate on these claims. I will give a definition of what I mean by a cost-benefit analysis, I will argue that people actually value other goals more highly than the monetary costs measured by a cost-benefit analysis, I will argue that it makes ethical assumptions that are dubious, and I will show that when applied to the world of climate change it produces severely inegalitarian results. These inegalitarian results create problems involving human rights, and equality before the law. </p>

<p>Now, what do I mean by cost-benefit analysis? I simply mean an analysis of the impacts of climate change based solely on the economic damage it causes. This economic impact is measured in terms of money. This type of analysis is able to measure damage to things other than the markets however. Damage to things that are not traded on the market measured in are terms of how much money people would be willing to give up for them. I.e if the members of a community would be willing to pay $100,000 to preserve a historic building, than the economic value of that building is \$100,000. If the building is then destroyed by an impact of climate change, then $100,000 is added to the impacts of climate change from a cost benefit perspective. Probabilistic impacts are measured using the concept of expected value. The expected value of an event is the product of its cost and the probability that it will occur. If the building has a 25 percent (0.25 probability) of being damaged then the expected value of the damage is $25,000. This type of cost benefit analysis is widely used. Pretty much all estimates of the form "the social cost of CO2 pollution is \$50 per ton of CO2" were created in this way. However, this method has severe flaws. Many proposals suggest building the response to climate change around this analysis, and conducting a "market-based" response by setting the carbon price at a level consistent with the cost of the pollution determined by the cost-benefit analysis.  </p>

<p>However, this method has clear flaws. The first is that it gives higher priority to the interests of the wealthy. Since this analysis is fundamentally based on <em>economic</em> damage and the amount of money that people would give up to advert the damage it weights the interests of the wealthy very highly. It also downgrades the interest of the poor. Because climate change is a global phenomenon and because global economic inequality is very lopsided, this effect is stark. The interests of someone earning the median American wage (about $50,000) is weighted over 130 times more than the interests on someone earning a dollar a day ($365 per year). The impacts of climate change (along with some strategies for mitigating it) fall disproportionately on the poor. Because of this the poor will get a raw deal with any climate change policy built around a cost-benefit analysis. Furthermore, this huge discrepancy conflicts with the notion of equality before the law. A just system should treat the interests of all equally and in a neutral fashion. The cost-benefit analysis method does not come close to doing this.  </p>

<p>Furthermore, the ethical assumptions behind the cost-benefit analysis method are dubious. There are three major assumptions behind the use of cost-benefit analysis</p>
<ol><li>The type of material wealth usually measured with money is a good proxy for the types of harms created by climate change  </li>
<li>All preferences of equal strength are equally worthy of concern by the political system  </li>
<li>Maximizing total well being (as measured by monetary value) is a good value to peruse </li>
</ol>
<p>All three of these points are dubious. I believe that political policies should be judged based on what a neutral observer would judge of the situation. Of course, with something global like climate change there are no truly neutral observers. However, we can appeal to a thought experiment like Rawls' original position where people are asked to judge policy options based on the assumption that they lack knowledge of their position in society, and therefore could be anyone in society. Under conditions like this people would probably not choose a social structure that maximizes well being (contradicting point 3). The idea of utility maximization embedded in the cost-benefit analysis method makes the errornous assumption that utilities and preferences of people are things that can be easily quantified and added up. Such an assumption is dubious. Even if it were not, I would contend that most people would want to avoid situations of being severely disadvantaged. I contend that people in such a thought experiment should instead  choose a situation where the policies enacted are the most widely acceptable even if this results in lower over all well being or a lower expected value of wealth. I would also contend that net wealth or material well being is not what people desire, wealth is a means not a end so taking it as a goal is superficial. I would prefer freedom (in a broad based sense) to wealth; "Give me liberty, or give me death!". Of course, defining liberty is a task of its own. I reject libertarian notions of freedom that define freedom purely in terms of some type of non-interference without any effective abilities preserved. I would contend that people are free to the extent that they have the widest range of abilities and capabilities to act that are not subject to and are protected from the risk of uncontrolled interference by others. Among these abilities priority should be given to fundamental rights. The capibilities of concern should be those that would be highlighted by a neutral party.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Environmental Movement&#x2019;s Greatest Own Goal?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-environmental-movements-greatest-own-goal</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-environmental-movements-greatest-own-goal</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 13:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><i><a href="https://theojones.name/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">This is part of a blog post series on climate change.</a></i>In this post I am using a new way of doing citations that I will use in some of my longer posts. The citations can be found at the end notes/</p>

<p>The opposition to the development of nuclear energy was probably one of the worst mistakes the movement has ever made. A rapid conversion to nuclear energy in the 1970s – like the one France did – would have vastly reduced greenhouse gas emissions. France’s per capita greenhouse gas emissions (mostly due to cars, and heating fuel) is substantially less than the EU average, and a little over a third of the GHG emissions of the United States. [1] Renewable</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1338" align="alignright" width="362"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8798177880_bbd8aa5b9f_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1338" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8798177880_bbd8aa5b9f_o-300x198.jpg" alt="Photo Credit: Conleth Brady / IAEA  &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>epsXL5</a>" width="362" height="239" /&gt; Photo Credit: Conleth Brady / IAEA A view from the helicopter window as IAEA Director General Yukiya Amano arrives at the Kalinin Nuclear Power Plant during his official visit to Moscow. 18 May 2013 <a href="https://flic.kr/p/epsXL5%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>epsXL5[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>sources have higher environmental impact than nuclear due to the large levels of natural resources needed to make wind and solar collectors, and due to the land-use of renewable sources. Nuclear is at cost parity with fossil fuels (even unsubsidized), while renewable still cost substantially more than traditional sources. The environmental opposition to nuclear energy has largely come out of two places. 1) the opposition to nuclear weapons (note the ”peace” in ”Greenpeace”), 2) a general technophobia. I will discuss both of these trends in this section. The relation between opposition to nuclear weapons, and the opposition to nuclear energy certainly exists for Greenpeace. The group was founded in part to oppose a nuclear weapons test on the Alaskan island of Amchitka. There were some concerns that this test could trigger geologic events like earthquakes or tsunamis. Greenpeace eventually formed out a group of (mostly Quaker) protesters opposing this event. Some of their tactics were opposed by established environmental groups – like the Sierra Club. Greenpeace’s website declares that <i>”motivated by their vision of a green and peaceful world, a small team of activists set sail from Vancouver, Canada in an old fishing boat. These activists, the founders of Greenpeace, believed a few individuals could make a difference... Amchitka was the last refuge for 3,000 endangered sea otters, and home to bald eagles, peregrine falcons, and other wildlife.”</i>[2].After this fissure with the environmental movement they eventually formed their own organization. Even today Greenpeace’s states that their mission includes the following goal ”<i>Working for disarmament and peace by reducing dependence on finite resources and calling for the elimination of all nuclear weapons.</i>” [3]. The group has even recently been involved in anti-war protests. In June of 2014 the group conducted a protest against NSA surveillance, and the construction of a new NSA data center [4]. Greenpeace is opposed to civilian nuclear energy and considers nuclear energy as a potential source of nuclear proflarition. They argue that the ability of nuclear energy to mitigate climate change is minor. They argue that the energy source has a high risk of accident, argue that nuclear energy has strong environmental impacts, and that nuclear energy is plagued by slow construction times, and dramatic cost overruns. They also argue that it competes with renewable energy for funding. I will discuss the ability for nuclear energy to mitigate climate change elsewhere, – in short it is very large. In fact it is possible to create a climate mitigation strategy that largely reilyes on nuclear energy. The construction times of nuclear energy are not a product of the technology but instead a product of the regulatory environment and finance. Nuclear energy construction times in France during the 1970s were around two years – similar to the construction times of renewable energy projects. Construction times in the U.S in the 50s and 60s were also around two years. There have been no major accidents at any of these projects. A major difference between these projects and modern ones is that these rapidly completed projects were generally publicly owned. Public or quasi-public ownership may be the preferable way to manage energy projects. With nuclear energy there is a general conflict of interest with the profit role and the public safety role. This produces a risk of an extrenality cost, and this is only mitigated by a expensive regulatory process. Public ownership avoids this conflict of interest. I would also argue that similar conflicts of interest have the potential to occur with renewable energy. There will be a large number of subsidies and government funding available to privately owned renewable energy firms, and it will be a tough regulatory challenge to provide that these funds are well-used. Later, I will discuss a proposal for quasi-public ownership of energy infrastructure that still allows for reasonable market pressure. In reality the opposition to nuclear energy has been one of the largest delays in the mitigation of climate change.</p>

<p>To the credit of Greenpeace, they have been one of the most vocal proponents of action on climate change. They call climate change ”the number one threat facing our planet”. They argue for a rapid mitigation of the threat. In their plan developed nation emissions would be reduced by 40 percent by 2020 and global emissions would be reduced to near zero. The group has also been a major contributor to activism on other environmental issues.<br />There is another source of opposition to nuclear energy. A general opposi tion of projects perceived to be non-”natural” over projects perceived to have a ”natural” basis. Even when the more ”natural” project is worse for the environment. This comes with a general embrace of pseudoscience within the more hardline elements environmental community, and a general opposition to technology. A lot of this conception of ”naturalness” comes from a vague perception of semi-vitalism – a belief that living/”natural” things have some property beyond their mere chemical composition. There is no scientific evidence for such a claim, but it is common/implied in arguments for ”alternative” (read: useless) medicine, organic foods (the certification for these foods is a mix of things that do some good, and things that are net harmful), opposition to the use of pesticides (which often net help the environment by reducing land use) and other issues. This perception, I believe, is at the core of a lot of the opposition to technological innovations among environmental groups. This is the most clear in the arguments against GMO crops.<br />The claims made by the campaigners against genetically modified foods are simply absurd. This ideology’s claims about the health effects of GMOs are as discredited in the scientific community as creationism or global warming denialism and all major scientific associations of repute that have looked into the issue disavow it. Their position that a compound can suddenly become toxic when synthesized due to a genetic modification of a plant, but is not toxic when synthesized by a natural process violates the laws of physics, chemistry and biology (It is worth noting that the BT toxin – a common product of genetic modification – is also a commonly used pest control in organic food, due to the fact that it is produced in the bacterium <i>Bacillus thuringiensis</i>) Their understanding of the economics of these products is not much better. These compounds have passed the approval of the FDA and the EPA. our food is not being poisoned by Monsanto (or the Illuminati, or whoever else the people at Natural News are blaming today). While Monsanto and its ilk have business practices that are very good, the same can be said of major players in almost every industry in the world. In my opinion this ”movement” is just dressed-up ludditeism – both in the modern sense of general technophobia, and in the sense of the historical Luddite movement’s belief that the abuses of sweatshops were an inevitable outcome of the automation of textile production.<br />Technophobia is a core undercurrent of the anti-GMO ideology. When you read their discussions about ”frankenfoods” (of course ignoring the fact that almost all domesticated plants and animals differ greatly from their wild relatives) they are employing the idea that new technology is inherently bad and dangerous, while the ”natural” is inherently good and safe. Nothing of the kind is true. Technology has a great ability to improve our standard of living and there are many things that ”natural” Of course there are also harmful synthetic products.I put the word ”natural” in quotes because man-made things and ”natural” products are created by the same laws of physics. In reality,<br />everything in this universe is natural. To the anti-GMO activist, ”natural” just means created with recently invented technology and this technology is scary.<br />Like the historical Luddites who blamed technology for the ills of the textile industry, when these issues were really created by unethical business practices,anti-GMO activists claim that the bad behavior of business is the unavoidable result of technology. These activists (rightly) criticize the patent litigation of Monsanto. However, instead of seeing this as another symptom of a broken patent system, they inexplicably blame the technology. These activists (rightly) see a greedy monopolist in Monsanto but they blame the technology instead of calling for anti-trust reform. This attitude will only serve to hold back the progress made possible by technology, without dealing with the systemic issues that allowed these unethicalbusiness practices. Rest assured that even without GMO foods, these economic issues will continue to wreak havoc in other sectors of the economy.A common third way approach to the GMO issue is labling. Now I will discuss why GMO labeling is a terrible idea. There is no scientific basis to fear GMO products.The claimed consumer choice benefits of mandatory labeling can be fulfilled by private certifications and currently existing, government ran certification programs.Due to the dynamics of food markets, mandatory GMO labeling amounts to a defacto GMO ban. This will increase food prices and possibly add to the environmental damage cause by agriculture.The World Health Organization notes ”GM foods currently available on the international market have passed risk assessments and are not likely to present risks for human health”.The American Association for the Advancement of Science concluded that ”Several current efforts to require labeling of GM foods are not being driven by any credible scientific evidence that these foods are dangerous” and that ”GM crops are the most extensively tested crops ever”.Their report also noted that labeling could mislead and falsely alarm consumers.<br />All of the claimed consumer choice benefits of GMO labeling can be done by voluntary certification. All products currently sold as organic in the U.S lack GMO products. Private certifications are also very good at assuring that products are prepared in accordance to standards that are sufficient for their consumers. Note that there are many private companies which certify kosher products. Economies of scale in food production make it inefficient and cost prohibitive for companies to create separate product lines with GMO and non-GMO foods. Therefore, just one of these options will be taken.If the labeling causes a substantial minority of the population to avoid GMO foods then these foods will be forced off the market for everyone. This has already happened in Europe, where GMO labeling is mandatory. In fact, the push for labeling by the anti-GMO movement is just a pretext to regulate these products out of existence.This will harm consumers and the environment because GMO products require less land usage than their competitors. The price of this extra land will be passed on to consumers, along with the price of increased crop loss. This increased land usage will also have substantial environmental impacts. However, there will be no clear economic benefits to this defacto ban on GMO foods.</p>

<p>References<br />[1] “List of countries by carbon dioxide emissions per capita,” Aug.2014.<br /><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List"></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=List">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>en.wikipedia.org/<wbr></wbr>w/<wbr></wbr>index.php?title=List</a><em>of</em>countries<em>by</em>carbon<em>dioxide</em>emissions<em>per</em>capita&oldid=608243516<br />[2] “Our history.” [Online]. Available:<br />campaigns/history/ <a href="http://www.greenpeace.org/usa/en/"></a><a href="http://www.greenpeace.org/usa/en/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.greenpeace.org/<wbr></wbr>usa/<wbr></wbr>en/<wbr></wbr></a><br />[3] “Who we are.” [Online]. Available:<br /><a href="http://www.greenpeace.org/international/en/about/our-mission/"></a><a href="http://www.greenpeace.org/international/en/about/our-mission/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.greenpeace.org/<wbr></wbr>international/<wbr></wbr>en/<wbr></wbr>about/<wbr></wbr>our-mission/<wbr></wbr></a><br />[4] J. Mullin, “Airship flies above NSA data center, decries illegal spying<br />below,” Jun. 2014. [Online]. Available: <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/06/airship-flies-above-nsa-data-center-decries-illegal-spying-below/"></a><a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/06/airship-flies-above-nsa-data-center-decries-illegal-spying-below/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>tech-policy/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>airship-flies-above-nsa-data-center-decries-illegal-spying-below/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/epa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#epa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/france" class="p-category" rel="tag">#france</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/nsa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#nsa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#epa</category>
      <category>#france</category>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#nsa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Ferguson Incident</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-ferguson-incident</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-ferguson-incident</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 00:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>That the shot person was a suspect in a robbery is interesting. I've always thought that neither story in the case adds up and that there is some missing detail. However, it is clear that the cops clearly used vastly excessive force. </p><p>1) The cops' story that Brown attacked Wilson to take his gun seems extremely unlikely to begin with, and contradicts witness testimony. <br />
2) However, I find it implausible that the cops would shoot someone for no apparent reason. That would very unusual, even for cops.</p><p>If Brown was a suspect in a robbery it would explain what happened (even if he had noting to do with it). Note that I am not justifying the clearly excessive force used in that case and in its aftermath.</p><p>I would also say that the focus on the past actions of the actors in this type of case is irrelevant. This goes on both sides to a degree. If the possible involvement in the robbery is not directly related, then it is not really that worthy of discussion. I will note however that  its as related as the claims by activists that Brown was a gentle giant who wouldn't hurt a fly. I.e not very related (my suggested policy towards robbers is NOT shoot on sight). But if activists get to bring up Brown's character I have no huge problem with the cops publishing a police report that puts Brown's character into question (the evidence of his involvement does seem pretty compelling, see <a href="http://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2014/08/15/Mike-Brown-called-robbery-suspect-in-police-report/9901408112725/ph2/"></a><a href="http://www.upi.com/Top_News/US/2014/08/15/Mike-Brown-called-robbery-suspect-in-police-report/9901408112725/ph2/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.upi.com/<wbr></wbr>Top_News/<wbr></wbr>US/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>15/<wbr></wbr>Mike-Brown-called-robbery-suspect-in-police-report/<wbr></wbr>9901408112725/<wbr></wbr>ph2/<wbr></wbr></a>) <br />
The police report (released today) about the robbery that Brown allegedly was involved in should have been public record put on internet anyways.</p><p>Also, what this type of case makes me think is that cops have too much experience. And that dealing with the worst the world has to offer creates a cop culture that is toxic to the public interest. To see this go to any forum that is targeted to the police community. The discussion at the following link is a good case study in this <a href="http://theerant.yuku.com/topic/68862/FDNY-EMTs-official-complaint-against-NYPD-of-EDP-Handling#.U-8E-3XoJhE"></a><a href="http://theerant.yuku.com/topic/68862/FDNY-EMTs-official-complaint-against-NYPD-of-EDP-Handling#.U-8E-3XoJhE">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theerant.yuku.com/<wbr></wbr>topic/<wbr></wbr>68862/<wbr></wbr>FDNY-EMTs-official-complaint-against-NYPD-of-EDP-Handling#.U-8E-3XoJhE</a> Because one EMT ratted them out, about half the cops on that forum want to "hammer" all emergency medical workers. The only reservation of many of the people there who don't is that screwing with EMTs would look bad to the public and bring a lot of crap down on them. There are a few people that talk of "rotten apples", but it seems that by "rotten apple" they mean "snitch". The comments on the following article are also "good" <a href="http://www.policeone.com/use-of-force/articles/7385823-Video-NY-man-dies-in-struggle-during-arrest/"></a><a href="http://www.policeone.com/use-of-force/articles/7385823-Video-NY-man-dies-in-struggle-during-arrest/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.policeone.com/<wbr></wbr>use-of-force/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>7385823-Video-NY-man-dies-in-struggle-during-arrest/<wbr></wbr></a></p><p>The police become something separate and above the regular population. Just trying to regulate the system won't work because the culture will fight all attempts at limiting abuse. I think that the best way to deal with this type of thing would be to in a way de-professionalize the police system. Make it so that most cops aren't career cops. I envision a system where people become cops for a few years and then go back to a different job. It could be one option in a universal national service system. The police roles that need professionals could be part time to the extent possible. This would limit the emergence of a cop culture that is separate from the general culture, and would therefore make it easier to regulate the few remaining bad apples out of existence.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/emt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#emt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#emt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regular Expression To Convert Wordpress Style Urls to Ghost Urls</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/regular-expression-to-convert-wordpress-style-urls-to-ghost-urls</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/regular-expression-to-convert-wordpress-style-urls-to-ghost-urls</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 23:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>It took me a while to come up with a regular expression to convert wordpress urls (index.php/year/month/day/title) to the ghost urls  This is the corrosponding redirect line in my Nginx config. </p><p>rewrite "/index.php/([0-9]{4})/([0-9]{2})/([0-9]{2})/(.*)" /$4 permanent;</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Server Installation/ New Blogging Engine / Web and Mail on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/new-server-installation-new-blogging-engine-web-and-mail-on</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/new-server-installation-new-blogging-engine-web-and-mail-on</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 11:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>As you have have noticed from some of the recent posts, and the bit of downtime I have done some reconfiguration of this website. I switched the blog engine from wordpress to ghost. I have also switched from Debian to Ubuntu (and made a few other changes). Some details about the new config are as follows. The new setup is based on the ghost image from Digital Ocean (the host of the VPS that this website runs on). I will discuss why I made this change later.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1318" align="alignright" width="226"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/31436961_33399f4066_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1318" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/31436961_33399f4066_o-226x300.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user sylvar) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3M87z</a>" width="226" height="300" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user sylvar) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/3M87z%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3M87z[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>I use the mosh remote connection system rather than Openssh to remotely manage the server. The instructions <a href="http://mosh.mit.edu/">available on the Mosh website</a> work well for this installation.</p>

<p>Mosh<br />$ sudo apt-get install python-software-properties</p>

<p>$ sudo add-apt-repository ppa:keithw/mosh</p>

<p>$ sudo apt-get update</p>

<p>$ sudo apt-get install mosh</p>

<p><a href="http://www.linuxscrew.com/2012/04/11/why-mosh-is-better-than-ssh/">Mosh has multiple clear benefits.</a> 1) it handles special sequences like control-c better than ssh (i.e it dosn't wait for the current task to finish), 2) it can handle network disconnects and IP address changes, 3)its executable runs as a normal user, minimizing security issues, and 4) it handles lagged terminals better. It is worth noting that Mosh is not a complete replacement for SSH, it still uses SSH for authentication.</p>

<p>Using mosh from the client side is simple.</p>

<p>$mosh root@server</p>

<p>It may be a good idea to swap OpenSSH for the lighter weight dropbear if you don't use Mosh.Install Dropbear</p>

<p>$ apt-get install dropbear</p>

<p>Edit<br />/etc/default/dropbear</p>

<p>Set <em>NO_START=0 </em><br />This option makes dropbear run on boot.</p>

<p>Also set <em>DROPBEAR<em>EXTRA</em>ARGS="-a"</em>.</p>

<p>If you installed dropbear remove the openssh server if it is present.</p>

<p>$ apt-get remove openssh-server</p>

<p>Reboot.</p>

<p>You may want to create a non-root user at this point. This has some security advantages (mostly in the case of multi user systems). You can see some articles on this as follows<br /><a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/34915/what-is-the-actual-value-of-disabling-remote-root-login-using-ssh"></a><a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/34915/what-is-the-actual-value-of-disabling-remote-root-login-using-ssh">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>security.stackexchange.com/<wbr></wbr>questions/<wbr></wbr>34915/<wbr></wbr>what-is-the-actual-value-of-disabling-remote-root-login-using-ssh</a><br /><a href="https://linuxacademy.com/blog/linux/when-you-should-and-should-not-disable-root-login/"></a><a href="https://linuxacademy.com/blog/linux/when-you-should-and-should-not-disable-root-login/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>linuxacademy.com/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>linux/<wbr></wbr>when-you-should-and-should-not-disable-root-login/<wbr></wbr></a></p>

<p>It can be done as the following:<br />useradd theo</p>

<p>I use the UFW firewall. Two good articles on this are as follows.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-setup-a-firewall-with-ufw-on-an-ubuntu-and-debian-cloud-server"></a><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-setup-a-firewall-with-ufw-on-an-ubuntu-and-debian-cloud-server">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.digitalocean.com/<wbr></wbr>community/<wbr></wbr>tutorials/<wbr></wbr>how-to-setup-a-firewall-with-ufw-on-an-ubuntu-and-debian-cloud-server</a><br /><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-and-use-mosh-on-a-vps"></a><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-and-use-mosh-on-a-vps">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.digitalocean.com/<wbr></wbr>community/<wbr></wbr>tutorials/<wbr></wbr>how-to-install-and-use-mosh-on-a-vps</a></p>

<p>Here is a summary of what I did.<br />$apt-get install ufw</p>

<p>The above command installs UFW. This is often installed by defauly</p>

<p>$ ufw allow 22</p>

<p>The above command allows ssh to pass through the firewall.</p>

<p>$ufw allow 60000:61000/udp</p>

<p>The above command allows mosh to pass through.</p>

<p>Edit /etc/default/ufw and adjust ipv6 settings</p>

<p>The following two commands sets all defaults to deny, for both outgoing and incoming traffic<br />$sudo ufw default deny incoming</p>

<p>$sudo ufw default deny outgoing</p>

<p>Start UFW</p>

<p>sudo ufw disable --- just in case its on<br />sudo ufw enable</p>

<p>ufw allow out 53</p>

<p>The above allows outgoing DNS traffic</p>

<p>ufw allow http --- web<br />ufw allow out http<br />ufw allow https --- web over ssl<br />ufw allow out https</p>

<p>ufw allow smtp -- to send/receive email<br />ufw allow out smtp</p>

<p>ufw allow imap -- pick up email</p>

<p>I poked around with an alternate setup for a LEMP Stack. Here are some notes<br /><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-14-04"></a><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-14-04">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.digitalocean.com/<wbr></wbr>community/<wbr></wbr>tutorials/<wbr></wbr>how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-on-ubuntu-14-04</a></p>

<p>apt-get update && apt-get upgrade</p>

<p>apt-get install nginx</p>

<p>apt-get install mysql-server<br />mysql_install_db<br />mysql_secure_installation --- run through the wizard</p>

<p>apt-get install php5-fpm php5-mysql</p>

<p>Configure PHP<br />nano /etc/php5/fpm/php.ini</p>

<p>set<br />cgi.fix_pathinfo=0</p>

<p>edit /etc/nginx/nginx.conf</p>

<p>under http add<br />fastcgi_buffers 8 16k;<br />fastcgi_buffer_size 32k;</p>

<p>Set NGINx config<br />See notes</p>

<p>Automatic updates<br /><a href="http://www.richud.com/wiki/Ubuntu">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.richud.com/<wbr></wbr>wiki/<wbr></wbr>Ubuntu</a><em>Enable</em>Automatic_Updates<br /><a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/14.04/serverguide/automatic-updates.html"></a><a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/14.04/serverguide/automatic-updates.html">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>help.ubuntu.com/<wbr></wbr>14.04/<wbr></wbr>serverguide/<wbr></wbr>automatic-updates.html</a><br />apt-get install unattended-upgrades<br />edit /etc/apt/apt.conf.d/50unattended-upgrades</p>

<p>At the very least enable security updates (should be enabled by default)<br />uncomment the "${distro<em>id}:${distro</em>codename}-updates"; line to enable other updates.</p>

<p>edit /etc/apt/apt.conf.d/10periodic<br />set<br />APT::Periodic::Update-Package-Lists "1";<br />APT::Periodic::Download-Upgradeable-Packages "1";<br />APT::Periodic::AutocleanInterval "7";<br />APT::Periodic::Unattended-Upgrade "1";</p>

<p>Email<br /><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-a-postfix-e-mail-server-with-dovecot"></a><a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-a-postfix-e-mail-server-with-dovecot">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.digitalocean.com/<wbr></wbr>community/<wbr></wbr>tutorials/<wbr></wbr>how-to-set-up-a-postfix-e-mail-server-with-dovecot</a><br />sudo openssl req -x509 -nodes -days 365 -newkey rsa:2048 -keyout /etc/ssl/private/mail.key -out /etc/ssl/certs/mailcert.pem<br />sudo openssl req -nodes -days 365 -newkey rsa:2048 -keyout /etc/ssl/private/mail.key -out mailcert.csr</p>

<p>aptitude remove exim4 && aptitude install postfix && postfix stop<br />Install as internet site and follow wizard (although config will be cleared)<br />Edit<br />/etc/postfix/master.cf</p>

<p>set<br />submission inet n - - - - smtpd<br />-o syslog<em>name=postfix/submission<br />-o smtpd</em>tls<em>wrappermode=no<br />-o smtpd</em>tls<em>security</em>level=encrypt<br />-o smtpd<em>sasl</em>auth<em>enable=yes<br />-o smtpd</em>recipient<em>restrictions=permit</em>mynetworks,permit<em>sasl</em>authenticated,reject<br />-o milter<em>macro</em>daemon<em>name=ORIGINATING<br />-o smtpd</em>sasl<em>type=dovecot<br />-o smtpd</em>sasl_path=private/auth</p>

<p>wipe main.cf (copy it to a new folder if nesarry)<br />cp /etc/postfix/main.cf /etc/postfix/main.cf.orig<br />rm /etc/postfix/main.cf</p>

<p>Set<br />myhostname = mail.domain.com<br />myorigin = /etc/mailname<br />mydestination = mail.domain.com, domain.com, localhost, localhost.localdomain<br />relayhost =<br />mynetworks = 127.0.0.0/8 [::ffff:127.0.0.0]/104 [::1]/128<br />mailbox_size_limit = 0<br />recipient<em>delimiter = +<br />inet</em>interfaces = all<br />alias<em>maps = hash:/etc/aliases<br />alias</em>database = hash:/etc/aliases<br />smtpd_tls_cert_file=/etc/ssl/certs/mailcert.pem<br />smtpd_tls_key_file=/etc/ssl/private/mail.key<br />smtpd_use_tls=yes<br />smtpd_tls_session_cache_database = btree:${data<em>directory}/smtpd</em>scache<br />smtp_tls_session_cache_database = btree:${data<em>directory}/smtp</em>scache<br />smtpd_tls_security_level=may<br />smtpd_tls_protocols = !SSLv2, !SSLv3<br />local_recipient_maps = proxy:unix:passwd.byname $alias_maps</p>

<p>edit /etc/aliases and set the file's content as the following<br />mailer-daemon: postmaster<br />postmaster: root<br />nobody: root<br />hostmaster: root<br />usenet: root<br />news: root<br />webmaster: root<br />www: root<br />ftp: root<br />abuse: root<br />root: theo</p>

<p>newaliases</p>

<p>aptitude install dovecot-core dovecot-imapd</p>

<p>clear /etc/dovecot/dovecot.conf<br />rm /etc/dovecot/dovecot.conf</p>

<p>create /etc/dovecot/dovecot.conf<br />disable_plaintext_auth = no<br />mail_privileged_group = mail<br />mail<em>location = mbox:~/mail:INBOX=/var/mail/%u<br />userdb {<br />driver = passwd<br />}<br />passdb {<br />args = %s<br />driver = pam<br />}<br />protocols = " imap"<br />protocol imap {<br />mail</em>plugins = " autocreate"<br />}<br />plugin {<br />autocreate = Trash<br />autocreate2 = Sent<br />autosubscribe = Trash<br />autosubscribe2 = Sent<br />}<br />service auth {<br />unix<em>listener /var/spool/postfix/private/auth {<br />group = postfix<br />mode = 0660<br />user = postfix<br />}<br />}<br />ssl=required<br />ssl</em>cert =<a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/digitalocean" class="p-category" rel="tag">#digitalocean</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/installdropbear" class="p-category" rel="tag">#installdropbear</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ssh" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ssh</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ufw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ufw</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p>
</div>]]></description>
      <category>#digitalocean</category>
      <category>#installdropbear</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#ssh</category>
      <category>#ufw</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Notes on System Administration Commands on Debian</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/some-notes-on-system-administration-commands-on-debian</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/some-notes-on-system-administration-commands-on-debian</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 04:25:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><strong>Restart Nginx</strong></p><p>/etc/init.d/nginx restart</p><p><strong>Website Speed Test</strong></p><p><a href="http://tools.pingdom.com/fpt/"></a><a href="http://tools.pingdom.com/fpt/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>tools.pingdom.com/<wbr></wbr>fpt/<wbr></wbr></a></p><p><strong>GNU Screen Tutorial</strong> <br /><a href="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/285795-taking-command-of-the-terminal-with-gnu-screen-"></a><a href="https://www.linux.com/learn/tutorials/285795-taking-command-of-the-terminal-with-gnu-screen-">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.linux.com/<wbr></wbr>learn/<wbr></wbr>tutorials/<wbr></wbr>285795-taking-command-of-the-terminal-with-gnu-screen-</a></p><blockquote>
<p>For an easy reference, here's a list of the most common screen commands that you'll want to know. This isn't exhaustive, but it should be enough for most users to get started using screen happily for most use cases.</p>

<p>Start Screen: screen  <br />Detatch Screen: Ctrl-a d  <br />Re-attach Screen: screen -x or screen -x PID  <br />Split Horizontally: Ctrl-a S  <br />Split Vertically: Ctrl-a |  <br />Move Between Windows: Ctrl-a Tab  <br />Name Session: Ctrl-a A  <br />Log Session: Ctrl-a H  <br />Note Session: Ctrl-a h</p>
</blockquote><p><strong>MySql Config Wizard</strong> <br /><a href="https://tools.percona.com/wizard"></a><a href="https://tools.percona.com/wizard">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>tools.percona.com/<wbr></wbr>wizard</a></p><p><strong>MySQL Database Creation</strong> <br /><a href="http://www.debuntu.org/how-to-create-a-mysql-database-and-set-privileges-to-a-user/"></a><a href="http://www.debuntu.org/how-to-create-a-mysql-database-and-set-privileges-to-a-user/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.debuntu.org/<wbr></wbr>how-to-create-a-mysql-database-and-set-privileges-to-a-user/<wbr></wbr></a></p><p>To login: <br />
 mysql -u root -p
To Create DB : <br />
mysql&gt; create database exampledb; <br />
Create User: <br />
mysql&gt; grant usage on <em>.</em> to user@localhost identified by 'passwd'; <br />
mysql&gt; grant all privileges on exampledb.* to user@localhost ;</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/reattachscreen" class="p-category" rel="tag">#reattachscreen</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/restartnginx" class="p-category" rel="tag">#restartnginx</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/startscreen" class="p-category" rel="tag">#startscreen</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/websitespeedtest" class="p-category" rel="tag">#websitespeedtest</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#reattachscreen</category>
      <category>#restartnginx</category>
      <category>#startscreen</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#websitespeedtest</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Wordpress Plugins I've Started Using</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/two-wordpress-plugins-ive-started-using</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/two-wordpress-plugins-ive-started-using</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 03:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><a href="http://wordpress.org/plugins/remove-query-strings-from-static-resources/"><strong>Remove Query Strings From Static Resources <br /></strong></a></p><blockquote>
<p>This plugin will remove any query strings from static resources like CSS & JS files, and will improve your speed scores in services like PageSpeed, YSlow, Pingdoom and GTmetrix.</p>

<p>Resources with a “?” or “&” in the URL are not cached by some proxy caching servers, and moving the query string and encode the parameters into the URL will increase your WordPress site performance grade significant.</p>
</blockquote><p><strong><a href="http://wordpress.org/plugins/wp-fastest-cache/">WP Fastest Cache</a></strong></p><blockquote>
<p>This plugin creates static html files from your dynamic WordPress blog. When a page is rendered, php and mysql are used. Therefor, system needs RAM and CPU. If many visitors come to a site, system uses lots of RAM and CPU so page is rendered so slowly. In this case, you need a cache system not to render page again and again. Cache system generates a static html file and saves. Other users reach to static html page.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/cpu" class="p-category" rel="tag">#cpu</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ram" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ram</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/url" class="p-category" rel="tag">#url</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#cpu</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#ram</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#url</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
