<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?offset=100</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?_t=rss&amp;offset=100" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Robots Will Replace the Jobs of Waitstaff (and Others)</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/robots-will-replace-the-jobs-of-waitstaff-and-others</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/robots-will-replace-the-jobs-of-waitstaff-and-others</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 10:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>This blog post was inspired by two articles that I've read. One discusses <a href="http://www.spacedaily.com/reports/At_Hong_Kong_High_Tech_Cafe_Everything_Is_Served_With_Microchips_999.html">a restaurant in Hong Kong</a> which is almost fully automated. The orders are taken and the food is delivered by robots. [caption id="attachment_1447" align="alignright" width="211"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/3441244946_f5fbfe7fc7_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/3441244946_f5fbfe7fc7_o-211x300.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user  Christelle &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>6f6heq</a>" width="211" height="300" class="size-medium wp-image-1447" /&gt; Image via Flickr user  Christelle<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/6f6heq%5B/caption%5DThe">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>6f6heq[/<wbr></wbr>caption]The</a> only human workers are the chefs, and those conducting maintenance on the robots. The second is <a href="http://pando.com/2014/07/17/new-san-francisco-billboard-warns-workers-theyll-be-replaced-by-ipads-if-they-demand-a-fair-wage/">about a advertising campaign</a> against the San Francisco minimum wage increase with a billboard that reads "San Francisco, meet your minimum wage replacement." The ad then shows an iPad with the text "May I take your Order". The thing is, minimum wage or not, a computer will be taking your order eventually. The tech used in the Hong Kong establishment is not mature by any means -- the maintenance of the robots takes more time and money than human workers -- and that restaurant relies on the novelty of being futuristic. However, one thing that computer technology is good at is becoming better and cheaper over time. It is close to inevitable that there will be robots of the future that are cheaper and better than the humans that they will replace. Robot waitstaff will not make (as many) errors as humans, and will be able to have a much  wider knowledge of the tastes of patrons than a human. Pretty much all non-creative work will be at some danger of automation in the near future.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hongkong" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hongkong</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sanfrancisco" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sanfrancisco</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#hongkong</category>
      <category>#sanfrancisco</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you should not be concerned about the Ebola Case in the U.K</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-you-should-not-be-concerned-about-the-ebola-case</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-you-should-not-be-concerned-about-the-ebola-case</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 04:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-30628349">According to the BBC</a>, a woman living in Glasgow, U.K has contracted Ebola. It is probably clear at this point that substantial public alarm will occur as a result of this as has happened in the United States and elsewhere that Ebola has spread to. However, individuals in developed have little to fear from the virus for various reasons.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1314" align="alignright" width="384"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/15653404835_7999f5f384_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1314" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/15653404835_7999f5f384_o-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Army Medicine) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>pReMUg</a> "Kristie Yeakle, right, bio safety officer,, evaluates two students as they sanitize their personal protective equipment during training at the San Antonio Military Medical Center in San Antonio, Texas, Oct. 24, 2014."" width="384" height="256" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Army Medicine) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/pReMUg">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>pReMUg</a> "Kristie Yeakle, right, bio safety officer,, evaluates two students as they sanitize their personal protective equipment during training at the San Antonio Military Medical Center in San Antonio, Texas, Oct. 24, 2014."[/caption]</p>

<p>In this post I will list five reasons why Ebola should be low on the list of threats to your safety.<br />1. Ebola has a low infectivity. It <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/health/2014/10/02/352983774/no-seriously-how-contagious-is-ebola">is estimated</a> that, even in the favorable conditions the disease experiences in West Africa, a typical Ebola victim infects just two other individuals. This is much lower than other major diseases, and this means that aggressive actions by public health officials can easily contain the disease. Interestingly, the main factor that makes Ebola notable is also the factor that suppresses the disease's ability to infect. Contrary to most depictions in science fiction, extreme leathality reduces the ability for a disease to spread. If the host of a virus is dead or incapacitated, then the host isn't spreading the virus.<br />2. Compared to other major diseases, there have been relatively few deaths and infections caused by Ebola. The number of individuals throughout the world who have been infected by Ebola is around 20,000. About 70 percent of them have died. However, this number of infections and deaths is dwarfed by more mundane diseases such as AIDS, Influenza, Malaria, and many others. A lot of the Ebola panic can be accounted for by peoples' inability to prioritize the risk of infrequent but dramatic events.<br />3. Reasonably effective health care systems have had a solid history of controlling Ebola outbreaks. Every developed nation to have had an Ebola case has controlled it with only a few additional infections occurring. Even nations with relatively weak healthcare systems, such as Nigeria, have contained Ebola outbreaks.<br />4. The main contributor to the spread of Ebola in developing nations is a lack of basic resources and a public that is ill informed about the basic nature of disease spread. The medical and sanitation systems of the nations most effected by Ebola are strongly lacking and these systems face a widespread lack of basic equipment and personnel. In many of the most severely affected locations there is widespread Ebola denialism.<br />5. Ebola is poorly adapted to spread in human hosts. The native host of the disease is the fruit bat, and its symptoms are not optimized for optimal spread in humans.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aids" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aids</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/armymedicine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#armymedicine</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ebolacase" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ebolacase</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westafrica" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westafrica</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aids</category>
      <category>#armymedicine</category>
      <category>#ebolacase</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westafrica</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Client Side Data Validation; or How Security Flaws Can Get Into Software</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/client-side-data-validation-or-how-security-flaws-can-get</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/client-side-data-validation-or-how-security-flaws-can-get</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 06:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There is a reason why attacks like the Sony breach still happen. Hacking is fundamentally about having the creativity and knowledge to put well known methods together into a well designed overall line of attack. The things that hackers exploit are mistakes that are easy to make, and the people who build a network have to get lucky all the time. But the people attacking it have to just</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1318" align="alignright" width="226"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/31436961_33399f4066_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1318" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/31436961_33399f4066_o-226x300.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user sylvar) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3M87z</a>" width="226" height="300" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user sylvar) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/3M87z%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3M87z[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>get lucky a few times. Hacking may involve some technical skill, but the people that crack computer networks have more creativity than technical wizardy. And with the likes of Sony, you can't rule out the possibility of technical incompetence. But there is a reason why these exploits keep being present in the frequency that they do, and that reason is simple -- programmers and network designers don't know security and thereby make even very simple errors in the systems they design. One simple error is client side validation, trusting a calculation made on a remote device that could be completely under the control of an attacker. The problems with this type of design is clear, programmers are putting their security on the hacker's computer, but this error keeps on being made. Take this thread on Stack Exchange for instance <a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/76974/verify-client-side-created-data"></a><a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/76974/verify-client-side-created-data">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>security.stackexchange.com/<wbr></wbr>questions/<wbr></wbr>76974/<wbr></wbr>verify-client-side-created-data</a></p>

<p>The OP in question here has a simple issue. "<em>I have a Java applet, which records the whole screen of the user and uploads the images to the server. If one would be able to (and many people could, I know) falsify the screen recording they could cheat legitimate users of the system out of their money, so there are incentives.</em>". The problem, of course, is that there is no way to make that type of design secure. Since the java applet is under the user's control, a user could make any change to the screen shot. A design that relies on the proper behavior of a remote system is inherently insecure. But such designs keep being made.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/stackexchange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#stackexchange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#stackexchange</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Marginal Cost?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/zero-marginal-cost</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/zero-marginal-cost</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Jeremy Rifkin's book <i>The Zero Marginal Cost Society: The Internet of Things, the Collaborative Commons, and the Eclipse of Capitalism</i> has received quite a bit of attention. He has also written some editorials on the Huffington Post, and has been interviews by multiple media sources. However, his core argument borders on the absurd. And perhaps the incredulity that the press has taken showcases a wider problem. Rifkin argues that the transition to products and</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1320" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1320" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/1989719848_9c7242ebf0_o-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC</a> " width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Dustin Moore) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/42PQoC%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>42PQoC[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>services that are dominated by fixed costs will provide a fundamental economic problem. However, the economics behind this view is deeply problematic. The idea that a high dependence on fixed costs provides an insurmountable economic issue is based on the idea that the prices in a competitive market tend towards the marginal cost (the non-fixed cost). This is the result of some simple economic models, but the real pricing behavior of businesses is way different. The problem of how businesses can effectively account for high fixed costs in their pricing is effectively solved. The second major part of Rifkin's argument is that the problems he expects to occur with the wider economy have already happened in the knowledge industries (music, videos, news, ect.). However, he omits a a key difference. Knowledge industries don't just have high fixed costs, they also have a second issue; non-excludeability. Information wants to be free and the copying of media cannot be effectively controlled without producing severe problems. The development of information technology exacerbates this problem because with the internet anyone can become a publisher. However, the physical industries that are tending towards low marginal costs do not have anything like this problem. Therefore, the situation of the knowledge industries cannot be extrapolated further.</p>

<p>It is clear that technology is expanding the role of fixed costs in the economy. Sustainable energy (both nuclear and renewable) tends to be dominated by fixed costs. The cost to run a nuclear power plant at all is about the same as the cost to run it at full capacity. Automation is replacing labor in many industries, and the cost involved with the robots is largely fixed. The services provided by internet service providers are also dominated by fixed costs. Many other examples could be named. Rifkin is perhaps correct to see a trend towards However, the economic problem of how to deal with them in the pricing of products is also not new. While some simple economic models tend to indicate that a competitive market tends towards the marginal cost (which would be insufficient to cover the rising fixed costs), the real world is different. Real businesses price their products based on cost-plus pricing. They take both the fixed and marginal costs, plus the desired profit into account when setting their prices. Real world businesses are capital constrained and will not invest in a sector of the economy if they do not see a net profit. This profit must be on top of both the fixed and marginal costs. Now, how can a business price a product based around a high fixed cost? Simple. There are two options, both of which are in wide use in current markets</p>
<ol><li>The businesses could simply charge a fixed cost to each user, and allow the users to use as much of their share as they want. This is roughly how internet usage is billed. Users pay a monthly fee, and get to use the internet with that access. This method of paying for the fixed costs effectively divides up the fixed cost among each of the users.</li>
    <li>Businesses could charge the average unit cost of the good. Think of a toll road. The costs involved in running a road are effectively fixed up the the point where the road becomes congested. Most toll roads charge a fee for each use of the road. This fee is set on the basis of the average cost per trip (both fixed and marginal cost combined).</li>
</ol>
<p>The problem of pricing low marginal cost goods is effectively dealt with every day by businesses around the world. The rise of fixed costs will not bring down the world. What about Rifkin's comparison to the changes in knowledge industries? Excludeability is the problem there, not high fixed costs. With the internet, it is impossible to prevent someone from copying a work and distributing it. People throughout the world can simultaneously posses a piece of information, and with the internet copying this information is trivial. Copyright, the only widely used way to exclude access to this knowledge is falling apart under this pressure. However, it is perfectly easy to exclude someone from using the power grid, or from using most of the physical services that having growing fixed costs. What happened in the knowledge industries is irrelevant to the wider economy.</p>

<p>it is to a degree amazing that the press did not bring up these issues when covering the book. But the press coverage of technical issues is abismial. The coverage on this subject is no exception.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/collaborativecommons" class="p-category" rel="tag">#collaborativecommons</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/dustinmoore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#dustinmoore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/huffingtonpost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#huffingtonpost</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#collaborativecommons</category>
      <category>#dustinmoore</category>
      <category>#huffingtonpost</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Should the Energy Grid Be Ran?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-should-the-energy-grid-be-ran</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-should-the-energy-grid-be-ran</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 23:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The way in which the U.S energy grid is ran is severely flawed. Energy pricing is unrelated to consumer demand. This creates many problems. It encourages consumers (and even more importantly industry) to use energy without concern for the impacts on the grid.<br />The way in which the U.S energy grid is ran is severely flawed. Energy pricing is unrelated to consumer demand. This creates many problems. With a power grid</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1322" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1322" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o-300x178.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H</a>" width="300" height="178" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/e8B95H%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>the only thing that matters isn't raw energy production, it is the time frame during which the energy is produced, not all energy production is equally valuable. It encourages consumers (and even more importantly industry) to use energy without concern for the impacts on the grid. It encourages the formation of energy producers with a parasitic business model that is based around dumping as much energy on the grid as possible, regardless of whether this is actually useful production. By extension it wastes the money of consumers and results in higher prices for them. This setup also distorts the energy sources used by producers. The current energy system also merges two unrelated things, producing the energy and distributing it. This creates a wide range of inefficiencies. I will propose four simple changes</p>
<ol><li>Prevent energy producing companies from also owning the distribution systems for energy</li>
    <li>Set up a two stage system for energy purchase by consumers. Along with dealing with the energy distributor, consumers will also select an energy producer to buy from. (energy producers could still buy from a wholesale market). Consumers with their own energy production (such as a home solar setup) would sell this energy to a producer</li>
    <li>Allow energy producers to experiment with a wide range of energy pricing methods</li>
    <li>The energy distribution companies should charge a flat fee for the use of the grid.</li>
</ol>
<p>Why should you care about this? Simple. The structure of the energy grid has a wide range of impacts. How it conducts its pricing affects the mix of energy sources used. If this is set wrong, both consumers and the public may suffer. If energy companies use their power over distribution to affect production, consumers will lose. Inefficient management of the energy grid may slow deployment of sustainable energy, and energy storage tech. The concentration of energy production into a single hand will also remove choice from consumers, and reduce the level of competition in the energy markets.</p>

<p>Slate did an article about something called "Demand Destruction". They make it sound like something that is the result of people just switching over to home-produced electricity, thereby becoming independent of the grid and leaving the power company in the dust. In reality, truly off-grid systems are extremely rare -- and expensive at almost $3.20 a kilowatt hour (mostly batteries and energy storage, commercial energy storage is much cheaper than home energy storage, but energy storage in general is quite expensive). The source of the problem is malformed renewable energy incentive laws that force power companies to pay all energy production an equal rate -- even if the energy is produced at an off-peak time that has little use. This enables a business model that I will call "Grid Leeching". This business model takes advantage of a simple fact. Electricity companies are required to pay and receive payment based on energy produced. But consumers don't want raw energy; they want power -- a constant flow of energy. energy is much cheaper to produce than power. Individuals and businesses buy cheap solar production systems that are designed to barf large amounts of off-peak energy on to the grid. The electricity company is required to pay full price for this energy. The grid leechers then get to use the power grid for their actual power needs practically free of charge. These cheap solar systems can sell for as little as $2 a watt average production or about the equivalent to 15 cents a kilowatt hour. Around this has developed a little market of companies that specialize in attaching leeches to the grid. One of these profiled is SolarCity, which rents out these cheap solar systems. This is very destructive to the grid. The only way that a electricity company can make up for this type of thing is to run load-following power plants -- usually natural gas -- in an inefficient, and rapidily fluctuating way. This happens while the leechers are drawing power while not paying anything on the net. The leechers only give back low quality, off-peak energy.</p>

<p>What can be done about this. It is simple: fluctuate energy charges, and energy production payouts based on the current demand. When there is little energy demand, pay the producers of energy less (and charge the consumers less). When energy demand is high, pay producers more and charge consumers more. Charge a flat monthly fee for a connection to the grid (based on the maximum current the user is allowed to draw). This will put the grid leechers out of business, because their core business model of dumping energy on the grid at low-demand times will no longer work. This will encourage companies to produce constant power (or even better, demand following energy), and will encourage consumers to modulate their energy usage during peak demand times. This may reduce the incentives for renewable energy deployment. However, the current model encourages the formation of grid leechers, instead of actually productive renewable energy firms. Furthermore, it puts nuclear energy (one of the best sources of baseload power) at a disadvantage. Sustainable energy should be directly subsidized at very large levels.</p>

<p>I will contend that energy utilities really do two distinct things that can and should be separate. The first is producing energy. The second is distributing that electricity. Separating these two roles will vastly improve the competitiveness of the electricity markets and will have benefits in regard to climate change and pollution. It would improve consumer choice , and allow consumers greater choice in what energy is consumed and how it is produced. However in reality, most utilities are also the main producers of the electricity that they distribute. As I will discuss towards the end of the post, this change would be<br />Electricity production is a natural monopoly — that is the lowest cost market outcome is one electricity utility serving an entire community. This of course has problems, a monopoly can of course over charge consumers. Monopolies charge based on what the consumer is willing to pay while a firm in a competitive market charges based on the actual cost. Additionally, a monopoly can abuse their power to gain market share of other related markets. This is in effect what most utilities have done with energy production. Because they are the sole distributor of electricity it is easy for them to make themselves the main producer of it. This not only increases costs to consumers, but also reduces their choice. If a consumer wants an energy plan heavy on a given energy source, or billed in a certain way, it may be very difficult to arrange that in the current system. In a more competitive energy market, there would be many energy producers each vying for the dollars of consumers. They would not have to wait for the sluggishness of one utility company for a new method to arrive. There would be an explosion of energy plans and energy sources, and types of billing. Want a energy plan centered on nuclear power, but no fossil fuels? Tough to find under current conditions, but perhaps not so tough under a more competitive arrangement. Want a energy plan billed on a fixed monthly rate — like how internet is billed? Very few utilities offer such a thing, but it might be more easy to find that type of thing in a more competitive market. More examples of how this would work could be envisioned.<br />Such a change would also have positive implications for the environment. Remember the issue about net metering of solar production at home? There is a great public benefit to allowing consumers to sell back energy they produce. But the types of net metering that regulators commonly implement have a severe flaw. They enable people to produce energy at low-value, off peak times and use the grid as a free battery. Separating energy production from distribution would solve this dilemma. People with home solar systems would sell their energy production to a energy production company, and a reasonable agreed upon value that takes into account the level of demand for the energy. But the distribution utility would charge a fee for the connection to the grid. This would prevent people from producing low value energy in-order to use the grid as a free battery. But it would reward people who use clean energy production at home to produce valuable energy. There are other clean energy production benefits of such a change. There would be a great opportunity for energy producers to experiment with clean energy sources, and sell this production to consumers who are willing to be early adopters. This is in contrast to utilities which can take many years to adapt to a change.</p>

<p>This change would be easy to implement. Instead of dealing with one power company, consumers would pay two companies. Consumers would pay a utility to hook their house to the grid. This would likely be billed as a flat monthly fee. They would then find a energy production company that has a plan that they like. The billing for this would vary from plan to plan. Despite the increased complexity of this setup, consumers would greatly benefit.</p>

<p>In this blog post I have proposed a way to reform the energy grid. This proposal will benefit consumers. It will result in increased consumer choice. And it will result in lower prices and a more efficient market.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind Mapping Tool That I Use on Arch Linux</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mind-mapping-tool-that-i-use-on-arch-linux</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mind-mapping-tool-that-i-use-on-arch-linux</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 08:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I use the free mind mind mapping program on Arch. It can be installed with the freemind package. The other major linux mind mapping program is xmind, but there are problems getting it to work on Arch.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC:"UK embassy apologises for 'burning White House' tweet"</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/bbcuk-embassy-apologises-for-burning-white-house-tweet</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/bbcuk-embassy-apologises-for-burning-white-house-tweet</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>Commemorating the 200th anniversary of burning the White House. Only sparklers this time! <a href="http://t.co/QIDBQTBmmL">pic.twitter.com/QIDBQTBmmL</a></p>
<p>— British Embassy (@UKinUSA) <a href="https://twitter.com/UKinUSA/statuses/503668849750056960">August 24, 2014</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p><script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-28929626"></a><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-us-canada-28929626">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.bbc.com/<wbr></wbr>news/<wbr></wbr>world-us-canada-28929626</a></p><blockquote><p>The British embassy in Washington has apologised after tweeting a picture of a White House cake surrounded by sparklers, "commemorating" the burning of the building 200 years ago.The US presidential residence was set on fire by British forces in 1814 during the "War of 1812" with the United States.
  ....
  The embassy later said: "Apologies for earlier Tweet."</p></blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/whitehouse" class="p-category" rel="tag">#whitehouse</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#whitehouse</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Brokers and Epsilon</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/data-brokers-and-epsilon</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/data-brokers-and-epsilon</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 00:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Today the CBS 60 Minutes program aired a segment on "data brokers" like Epsilon. The CEO of that company was interviewed on that show and highlighted the firm's openness and noted that consumers can request a "summary" of the data that they have on consumers. What was not noted in that segment is that this request can only be made by snail-mail (odd for a tech company, the form can be found here <a href="http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-info/marketing-data-summary-request"></a><a href="http://www.epsilon.com/consumer-info/marketing-data-summary-request">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.epsilon.com/<wbr></wbr>consumer-info/<wbr></wbr>marketing-data-summary-request</a>). Also, they need a voided check.It seems they are trying to</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1325" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/9663345203_959c0b91c6_o-1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1325" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/9663345203_959c0b91c6_o-1-300x225.jpg" alt="Image via flickr (user Intel Free Press) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>fHVaS4</a>" width="300" height="225" /&gt; Image via flickr (user Intel Free Press) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/fHVaS4%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>fHVaS4[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>make this process as difficult as possible. I am going to mail this request tomorrow to see what I get back.</p>

<p>Here is their excuse for it</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The mail process is designed to ensure security and to verify identity. Since we are matching your name and address to our database, we can be confident that we are mailing your information to you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A justification for an obtuse process based on privacy rings a bit hollow for this company. I mean, they are selling my information.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In addition, by conducting this process through the mail, we believe that more consumers will have an opportunity to make a/this Marketing Data Summary request. Some consumers may not feel comfortable using other methods to verify their identity on the internet. We believe that conducting this process through the mail allows the greatest number of consumers access to their reports.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This does not explain why snail-mail is the <em>only</em> method.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/cbs" class="p-category" rel="tag">#cbs</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/intelfreepress" class="p-category" rel="tag">#intelfreepress</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/marketingdatasummary" class="p-category" rel="tag">#marketingdatasummary</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#cbs</category>
      <category>#intelfreepress</category>
      <category>#marketingdatasummary</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GMO Labeling and the First Amendment</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gmo-labeling-and-the-first-amendment</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/gmo-labeling-and-the-first-amendment</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 21:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Vermont passed a law requiring the labeling of GMO products a few months ago. The law won't take effect until 2016, but there is already litigation about the constitutionality of the legislation. In this post I will argue that the labeling law most likely violates the protections of the First Amendment. Due to the <a href="http://hstlj.org/articles/a-brief-history-of-the-commercial-speech-doctrine-with-some-implications-for-tobacco-regulation/">commercial speech doctrine</a> courts have ruled that advertising (including product labeling) is protected by the Constitution, although to a lesser extent than other forms of speech. The courts have not precisely delineated a boundary for when law makers can regulate commercial speech, but have generally found that</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1327" align="alignnone" width="646"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2835892559_d94c45ff7e_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1327 size-large" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/2835892559_d94c45ff7e_o-1024x768.jpg" alt="Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances." width="646" height="485"></a> Image Via Flickr (user david__jones) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5jAG4i%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5jAG4i[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>there must be a provable harm (or at least possible harm) to the consumer. Courts have given little weight to subjective consumer preferences, leaving the fulfillment of those to the market. There are some trends in the major Supreme Court cases on the subject such as <em>Virginia State Board of Pharmacy v. Virginia Citizens Consumer Council</em>, and <em>Central Hudson Gas v. Public Service Commission of New York</em></p>
<ol><li>The general standard for commercial speech cases is intermediate scrutiny. This also is the standard that applies to time place and manner speech restrictions (like city noise laws), sex/gender discrimination( among other protected classes).To pass this standard a law must further important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest</li>
    <li>Lawmakers have broad power to ban false advertising and advertising for illegal products.</li>
    <li>Advertising over electronic media receives lower protection than adverting in traditional publications.</li>
    <li>Prior restraint is permissible in the realm of commercial speech</li>
    <li>There is a wide scope for disclosure regulations, but there still needs to be a substantial government interest involved. Justifications based on consumer choice in the absence of tangible harm are usually not sufficient.</li>
</ol>
<p>The most similar case to the GMO one is <em>International Dairy Foods Association v. Amestoy</em> which came before the Second Circuit. This case involved a Vermont labeling law mandating that dairy products produced by cows treated with the rBST hormone be labeled. The government made no claims of a safety risk before the court, and the plaintiffs in that case entered evidence indicating that there was no safety risk. The trial court opinion noted that the government “does not claim that health or safety concerns prompted the passage of the Vermont Labeling Law,” and that there defense is based around "strong consumer interest and the public's ‘right to know’". The Second Circuit found that this interest in consumer choice is not a substantial interest. There may have been animal welfare justifications for the law made in the public discourse, but neither side made such arguments before the court, so that issue was never considered. However, a consumer survey was entered as evidence that indicated that such issues were a reason why consumers may have wanted to avoid rBST products, but none of these responces ammounted to a full argument on this basis (other than noting that the cows were “Producing enough milk already.”) The court found that the most common consumer reasons included</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>(1) They consider the use of a genetically-engineered hormone in the production unnatural;  (2) they believe that use of the hormone will result in increased milk production and lower milk prices, thereby hurting small dairy farmers;  (3) they believe that the use of rBST is harmful to cows and potentially harmful to humans;  and, (4) they feel that there is a lack of knowledge regarding the long-term effects of rBST.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>The situation with GMO labeling is even less favorable. There are no reasonable safety arguments that could be used against GMO products. As the GMO products targeted are plants there are not any animal welfare arguments either. This leaves the consumer choice argument, which courts have already rejected as problematic. Allowing abstract preferences that have no basis in fact into the law produces severely paradoxical results when used to justify limits on fundamental rights. Imagine if such preferences were allowed into the other areas of law where the intermediate scrutiny standard was used. The results would be clearly unacceptable. Satisfying subjective consumer preferences in an efficient way are what markets are good at. If there is a consumer demand for notice about GMO products, then a voluntary (and perhaps privately owned) certification system should serve the purpose (with the producers paying the full cost of maintaining the system through fees).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyork" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyork</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/secondcircuit" class="p-category" rel="tag">#secondcircuit</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vermontlabelinglaw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vermontlabelinglaw</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#newyork</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#secondcircuit</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vermontlabelinglaw</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Interesting Article On Racism in Israel</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/an-interesting-article-on-racism-in-israel</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 18:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><a href="http://www.haaretz.com/mobile/.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2"></a><a href="http://www.haaretz.com/mobile/.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.haaretz.com/<wbr></wbr>mobile/<wbr></wbr>.premium-1.611822?v=C1FFA498A4B3F60AC8696D3A46E2F4D2</a></p><p>The linked article features a discussion of the growth of racism in the Isreali school system. A choice quote is as follows.  </p><blockquote><p>“For me, personally, Arabs are something I can’t look at and can’t stand,” a 10th-grade girl from a high school in the central part of the country says in abominable Hebrew. “<strong>I am tremendously racist. I come from a racist home. If I get the chance in the army to shoot one of them, I won’t think twice.</strong> I’m ready to kill someone with my hands, and it’s an Arab. In my education I learned that ... their education is to be terrorists, and there is no belief in them. I live in an area of Arabs, and every day I see these Ishmaelites, who pass by the [bus] station and whistle. I wish them death.”</p></blockquote><p>Emphasis added. </p><p>What type of person thinks being "tremendously racist" is something to brag to journalists about? And what does it say about the nation that churns out students who think like this? Now, viewpoints this extreme seem to still be in the miniority, but they seem way to common. This point of view is also deeply influential on politics, with strong hostility to the "leftists" that oppose the policies of the Isreali government</p><blockquote><p>A year later, however, the incident itself was still remembered in the school. The same student who told Yaron that she won’t think twice if she gets the opportunity “to shoot one of them” when she serves in the army, also said, “As soon as I heard about the quarrel with that leftist girl [Michal], I was ready to throw a brick at her head and kill her. In my opinion, all the leftists are Israel-haters. I personally find it very painful. Those people have no place in our country – both the Arabs and the leftists.”</p></blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
