<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?offset=60</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?offset=60&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Via https storify com a man in black...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/via-https-storify-com-a-man-in-black</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/via-https-storify-com-a-man-in-black</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 06:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Via <a href="https://storify.com/a_man_in_black/patreon-and-common-carrier-sociopathy">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>storify.com/<wbr></wbr>a_man_in_black/<wbr></wbr>patreon-and-common-carrier-sociopathy</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/resize.png"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/resize.png" alt="resize" width="429" height="401" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2326"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seen on a tabloid in the grocery store...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/seen-on-a-tabloid-in-the-grocery-store</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/seen-on-a-tabloid-in-the-grocery-store</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 06:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Seen on a tabloid in the grocery store. Looks like the good ol GOP noise machine is getting fired up. <br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Office-Lens_20150602_175624_processed1.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Office-Lens_20150602_175624_processed1-300x218.jpg" alt="Office Lens_20150602_175624_processed(1)" width="300" height="218" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2324"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gop" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gop</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gop</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New photos more at https www flickr com...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-more-at-https-www-flickr-com</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-more-at-https-www-flickr-com</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 04:40:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>New photos (more at <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/721576540417405750">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>721576540417405750</a> )<br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0549.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0549.jpg" alt="DSCN0549" width="1500" height="1125" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2321"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0557.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0557.jpg" alt="DSCN0557" width="1500" height="1125" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2322"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Causes of Internet Trolling</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/causes-of-internet-trolling</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/causes-of-internet-trolling</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 05:05:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I think that issues with harassment, trolling and such on the internet are more common than in the offline world for two reasons. The first is that there is less accountability in the online world. Identities on the Internet are easily replaceable and expendable. This is not simply anonymity. Anonymity and accountability can coexist to a large degree. It is possible to be tied to an identity that is not your real name while still having a lot of stake in the continued reputation of that identity. The lack of accountability on the Internet is due to the lack of consequences for bad behavior. When a troll can just re-create a sock puppet account on the community he was banned from in order to troll again that's lack of accountability. When a Russian spammer can spew junk from easily replaceable IP addresses, that's lack of accountability. And the persistent lack of accountability and the easy replace ability of online identities is a major enabling factor in Internet harassment. If identities on the Internet had a strong cost to them trolls could no longer create burner accounts and would be substantially limited the damage he could do. Internet identity is a weird thing, sloughs few goods that is not scarce enough for the good of the public. If internet identities were scarcer, there would be less trolling. In the long run, although it is somewhat impractical to implement in the short term, the solution will be to make Internet identities scarcer. Create an Internet authentication service, which sells Internet identities and their authentication for a substantial but not prohibitive amount of money, like let's say, $50. This would prevent burner accounts. This may be a good role for a government agency. It would make banning users from Internet communities more effective. It would make it possible for different Internet communities to blacklist persistent trolls in a coordinated way. And it would add a substantial cost to trolling. The second factor that I think is huge and the growth of trolling and Internet harassment is the rise of content silos like Facebook and twitter. These websites are parked in the weird intermediate between web hosts/ISPs true Internet communities. A true Internet community like a forum or mailing list is perfectly able to just ban problem users, there are no shared subcommunities with different values. There are alternate routes for controversial speech. Web hosts in the other hand don't even need to deal with the content moderation issue. And web host, quite frankly, shouldn't even deal with what their users post as long as it's legal. There are limited ways that one user of a web host could damage the others. Content silos exist in a weird double state. They are too much like web hosts to be able to affect consistent moderation, they are close enough to proper Internet communities for problem users to be able to cause trouble for others. In short, content silos are the perfect outlet for the troll. They have very limited accountability for their actions, but plenty of room to do damage. As far as I can tell about the only way to prevent this effect is to get rid of such content silos. Centralizing massive amounts of Internet communities like the way that Facebook, twitter, Reddit and such does was bound to be a recipe for disaster. Content silos should be replaced with the decentralized web of yesteryear. Separate communities have their own websites that are isolated from others. The personal website should return. And decentralized protocols should replace the task done by social networking systems like messaging, contact management and profiles. This would allow more fine-grained control the side of the users, a more difficult situation for trolls.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ip" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ip</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#ip</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another set of photos https www flickr com...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/another-set-of-photos-https-www-flickr-com</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/another-set-of-photos-https-www-flickr-com</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 02:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Another set of photos <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157653387890540">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157653387890540</a></p>

<p><a href="https://flic.kr/p/sYqBGJ">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>sYqBGJ</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos of mine https www flickr com photos...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/photos-of-mine-https-www-flickr-com-photos</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/photos-of-mine-https-www-flickr-com-photos</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 02:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Photos of mine<br /><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157653988753415">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157653988753415</a><br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/tNTVHf">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>tNTVHf</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It seems to my like a large part...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/it-seems-to-my-like-a-large-part</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/it-seems-to-my-like-a-large-part</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 05:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It seems to my like a large part of many left/progressive movements are now undergoing a tendency to put solidarity with others sharing their viewpoints ahead of actual good policy. I have also noted a recent uptick in people from the left who think that attacking another member of the movement (even when he is wrong) is about as bad as opposing it outright.  You see this when members of the femminist community go out of their way to defend toxic members of their community (see this article for an example <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/users/2015/05/bahar_mustafa_at_goldsmiths_university_ironic_misandry_claims_its_first.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.slate.com/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>technology/<wbr></wbr>users/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>bahar_mustafa_at_goldsmiths_university_ironic_misandry_claims_its_first.html</a> )You see this with environmentalists who wagon circle  on issues like GMOs when the facts indicate that the anti-GMO position is stupid.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New photos https www flickr com photos 132940671@N06...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-https-www-flickr-com-photos-132940671n06</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-https-www-flickr-com-photos-132940671n06</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 01:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>New photos <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157653458690578">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157653458690578</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0493web.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2309" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0493web.jpg" alt="DSCN0493web" width="2284" height="1713"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tesla home battery has been getting a...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-tesla-home-battery-has-been-getting-a</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-tesla-home-battery-has-been-getting-a</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 06:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Tesla home battery has been getting a lot of attention. Will it resolve the intermittentcy problem for solar? Probably not. Its too expensive.<br /><a href="http://ideas.4brad.com/does-tesla-new-home-storage-battery-suggest-amazing-breakthrough">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ideas.4brad.com/<wbr></wbr>does-tesla-new-home-storage-battery-suggest-amazing-breakthrough</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is very interesting because, at present, battery grid storage is not generally economical. The problem is the cost of the batteries. While batteries can be as much as 90% efficient, they wear out the more you use and recharge them. Batteries vary a lot in how many cycles they will deliver, and this varies according to how you use the battery (ie. do you drain it all the way, or use only the middle of the range, etc.) If your battery will deliver 1,000 cycles using 60% of its range (from 20% to 80%) and costs $400/kwh, then you will get 600kwh over the lifetime of a kwh unit, or 66 cents per kwh (presuming no residual value.) That’s not an economical cost for energy anywhere, except perhaps off-grid. (You also lose a cent or two from losses in the system.) If you can get down to 9 cents/kwh, plus 1 cent for losses, you get parity with the typical grid. However, this is modified by some important caveats:</p>

<p>If you have a grid with very different prices during the day, you can charge your batteries at the night price and use them during the daytime peak. You might pay 7 cents at night and avoid 21 cent prices in the day, so a battery cost of 14 cents/kwh is break-even.<br />You get a backup power system for times when the grid is off. How valuable that is varies on who you are. For many it’s worth several hundred dollars. (But not too many as you can get a generator as backup and most people don’t.)<br />Because battery prices are dropping fast, a battery pack today will lose value quickly, even before it physically degrades. And yes, in spite of what you might imagine in terms of “who cares, as long as it’s working,” that matters.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/battery" class="p-category" rel="tag">#battery</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/renewable" class="p-category" rel="tag">#renewable</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/solar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#solar</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#battery</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#renewable</category>
      <category>#solar</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why give cranks the benefit of the doubt?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-give-cranks-the-benefit-of-the-doubt</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-give-cranks-the-benefit-of-the-doubt</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 06:18:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In issues like the "debate" over GMOs I've seen a pattern where extreme charity is given to the arguments of the antiscience side. Let's take a person who thinks GMOs cause health issues clearly, by the plain language of how he phrases things indicates that he thinks that method of genetic modification introduces the health risk. It's a blatantly absurd position. Genetic modification is a method to synthesize compounds. A chemical compound is the same thing the matter how it was synthesized. BT toxin from a GMO corn plant is unequivocally the exact same compound is BT toxin collected from <em>B. thuringiensis </em>bacteria. This is completely without doubt. For a chemical that have "memory" of how it was synthesized or its past would contradict a vast swath of physics, chemistry, and biology. However, it is quite common this type of debate for the other side to rephrase his argument away from the plain language of it but towards a more plausible but different argument. Those scientifically literate people will tend to interpret the statement not as what its plain language says of compounds having "memory" but will instead interpret it as some kind of a claim at BT toxin itself is dangerous. (Which is itself an extremely doubtful claim that contradict quite a bit of scientific research, and known mechanism of how the toxin works against insects) Of course, this cannot be what most of the GMO health risk types mean, as they have no objection to the use of <em>B. thuringiensis </em>bacteria and the toxin it produces in organic agriculture. They must mean the prime face absurd claim that chemical compounds remember their past. Why should anyone do this charitable interpretation of what they are saying? Me? I am now at the point where I assume people exposing crank viewpoints mean what they say and say what they mean. If you say something that's clearly in contradiction with a large swath of science, I'm going to assume very vastly ignorant,or  are engaging in outright science denialism. I think, reason why a lot of people reinterpret what crackpots have to say, is because the claims of antiscience types are so absurd they immediately assume no one could seriously mean them. But, there are vastly ignorant or deluded people out there. There are people who put their preconceptions before any reasonable logic. There are people who don't understand the basics of chemistry and physics. There are Luddite types that have an extreme knee-jerk opposition to technology. It's time to take them seriously.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bt</category>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
