<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?offset=180</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized?_t=rss&amp;offset=180" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Latest in the NSA Spying Scandal</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-latest-in-the-nsa-spying-scandal</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-latest-in-the-nsa-spying-scandal</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 20:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Via Slashdot</p>

<p> </p>
<div class="rpuEmbedCode"><div class="rpuArticle rpuNoTitle rpuRepost-a3105a84c51c5040532a2ee00605a3fd-top" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<p><script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1UX26" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite"></a><a href="http://s.tt/1UX26" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>NSA Infects Much U.S. Tech Before it Even Ships</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1UX26" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">slashdot</a>)</p>
<p class="rpuSnip">  
Even the most dramatic accusations of improper or criminal behavior appear to understate the actual digital-espionage methods of the National Security Agency (NSA), according to a series of stories published over the weekend by German daily Der Spiegel…  
</p></div></div><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><!--more--><!--break--><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode"><div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-a3105a84c51c5040532a2ee00605a3fd-bottom" style="display:none;"> </div><div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: <a href="http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/f472f8f610977d87447344ceeaa78c2e" >http:/<wbr />/<wbr />www.repost.us/<wbr />article-preview/<wbr />hash/<wbr />f472f8f610977d87447344ceeaa78c2e</a> --></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Would the Ideal Distributed Social Networking Application Look Like?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/what-would-the-ideal-distributed-social-networking-application-look-like</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/what-would-the-ideal-distributed-social-networking-application-look-like</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 15:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Current centralized social networking websites, such as Facebook have many flaws.They have persistent privacy issues and breaches. Their moderation policies are often problematic and applied arbitrarily. These systems are vulnerable to censorship and government manipulation.</p>

<p>The risks of this to privacy are shown by the NSA leaks. The risks to free speech are shown by how, <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2238519/Facebook-bans-picture-woman-reclining-bathtub--shows-elbow.html">when under pressure from the Turkish government Facebook restricted posts advocating Kurdish independence</a> and "Any attack on Ataturk [Turkey's first president]". With a centralized structure these issues of government interference are almost unavoidable. The nature of these networks also means that there is little ability for the user to modify and customize the interface because all of the code runs on the server, and because this code is not open source. This is part of the reason why Facebook has to roll out interface changes to all users, often with many dissatisfied users. Some projects have tried to improve the Facebook interface by running client-side software that modifies the HTML and JavaScript produced by Facebook, <a href="http://socialfixer.com/blog/2013/12/18/social-fixer-is-partly-broken-heres-why/">but this method is error prone</a>.A distributed social network built around a single protocol that allows different implementations of the system, running on different servers would fix these issues. This network would be like email. You can run your own mail server (like I do) and different mail servers can communicate with each other.You can choose from different email providers. A decentralized social network would lessen all of the issues I discussed. If individuals run their own servers, governments would have a hard time controlling these servers. A decentralized system would allow many different implementations and configurations of the system to run. The users would be allowed to choose from the configuration that best suits their wants. They would also be able to chose from different hosts of the system. In the rest of this post I will discuss the problems with currently produced decentralized systems and the design elements that should underlie a good social networking system.</p>
<h2>What are the problems with current decentralized social networks?</h2>
<p>Wikipedia has a fairly exhaustive list of current decentralized social networks. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_software_and_protocols_for_distributed_social_networking"></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>en.wikipedia.org/<wbr></wbr>wiki/<wbr></wbr>Comparison</a><em>of</em>software<em>and</em>protocols<em>for</em>distributed<em>social</em>networking</p>

<p>I have tried many of these systems and looked into others and none of them fit my needs or are likely to be competitors to Facebook. The largest projects Diaspora,Friendica and StatusNet are very difficult to install and configure. These projects often unnecessarily run their messages through other protocols, such as XMPP. This adds extra complexity to the system and its implementation. Other projects are defunct and have no active development. Others lack critical features and do not plan to add them in the future.</p>
<h3>What does a good network have?</h3>
<p>First I will discuss what I think a social networking application is. Then I will discuss the particular traits that one should have.</p>
<h4> What is a social network?</h4>
<p>Social networking applications are at their core messaging systems. They allow people to broadcast a message to a group of friends and/or subscribers to a page. They allow people to communicate with each other through private messages. Social networks create a easy way for users to communicate a profile about themselves. Blogging engines, like Wordpress are often confused with social networking applications</p>
<h4>Ease of use</h4>
<p>The first feature that a good social network should have is ease of use. It should be easy to use the webpage client for the network and it should be easy to install a server for the network. But by easy to use I mean <a href="http://www.over-yonder.net/~fullermd/rants/userfriendly/2"><strong>easy to learn</strong>, not easy to use without learning</a>. Easy to use without learning is the unfortunate interface design methodology employed by many businesses, including Facebook.However, it can most clearly be found in Apple's products and to a lesser extent in Microsoft's. Computers are complex devices and the easy to use without learning design methodology tries to hide this complexity from the user. This design attempts to create smart computers, but dumb users. However,easy to use without learning design hurts users in the long run. It kills the flexibility of a system, it creates software that second guesses the user at every point and this design discourages user learning, churning out "computer illiterate" users.It also adds to software complexity and bloat. The easy to learn design methodology admits that computers are complex. Users are expected to know a bit about how the system works and why they are doing what they are doing. This design allows simple flexible systems which cover many use cases.</p>
<h4>Simplicity</h4>
<p>The corollary of ease of use is simplicity. The network, and the protocol that underlies it should be as simple as possible.</p>
<h4>Split Layout and Message Data, Keep Layout on the Recipient's Side</h4>
<p>One of the reasons that Myspace collapsed is that it allowed users to change the way that their profiles looked to other users. New social networks should clearly avoid this mistake by separating the content messages, statuses and profiles from their layout. A distributed social network should allow each user to apply a theme that sets how the system displays to them but that does not affect the theme and layout shown to other users.</p>
<h4>....But allow a Wikitext Style Formatting</h4>
<p>However, Facebook went to the opposite extreme and disallowed almost all formatting codes in messages. It is not possible to add a hyperlink to a Facebook status/message, nor is it possible to bold or italicize text.A good alternative to this would be to allow the use of a formatting language like <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150623033701/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.wikicreole.org/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;WikiCreole.</p>
<h4>Detailed Privacy Settings and Post Clusters</h4>
<p>A good social networking application should have much more powerful privacy options. These should revolve around what I call "post clusters". Users should be able to categorize their friends into sub groups and set posts to be only viewable by some of these groups. A large reason why social networks that are targeted at specific purposes, like LinkedIn thrive is in part due to the poor privacy options found in most social networks. People want to broadcast different messages to business colleagues than they want to broadcast to friends. Most social networks do not allow this type of fine grained control, so users instead use different networks for each purpose.</p>

<p>As an additional privacy feature, the ideal social networking system should allow a way to anonymously send messages. The protocol of the network should also allow the use of privacy system, such as Tor.</p>
<h4>Spam Filtering</h4>
<p>Any communications network will have to face the issue of how to deal with spam. A distributed network will have to do this without adding centralization or risking user privacy. In my opinion, the best way to deal with spam would be something along the lines of<a href="http://www.templetons.com/brad/spam/endspam.html"> Brad Templeton's throttle relay proposal for email</a>. This method could be made even more powerful because a new social network would have a completely new protocol that could take into account the spam issue.</p>
<h4>Built in Encryption</h4>
<p>Encryption is necessary for privacy in a modern application. A social network should encrypt all communications between servers. It should also have client side encryption as an option, but because client side encryption can be difficult to use, it should not be mandatory for all users.</p>
<h4>Extensibility, Plugins and Themes</h4>
<p>A distributed social network should have a wordpress-style support for themes and plugins. This would greatly improve the flexibility of the system and would allow it to be customized to fit user needs.</p>
<h4>Email Replacement</h4>
<p><a href="http://paulgraham.com/ambitious.html">In an essay Paul Graham notes that email is largely used as a todo list and discusses how this role can be replaced</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>.... my inbox is a todo list, and email is the way things get onto it. But it is a disastrously bad todo list.</p>

<p>I'm open to different types of solutions to this problem, but I suspect that tweaking the inbox is not enough, and that email has to be replaced with a new protocol.  ....</p>

<p>As a todo list protocol, the new protocol should give more power to the recipient than email does. I want there to be more restrictions on what someone can put on my todo list. And when someone can put something on my todo list, I want them to tell me more about what they want from me. Do they want me to do something beyond just reading some text? How important is it? .....When does it have to be done?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A social networking system would have a-lot of the functionality needed for this to-do list. Therefore, it is possible that a to-do list protocol could be built on top of a well-designed social networking system. Current social networks have displaced much of the messaging role of email. A well-designed one could replace email wholesale.</p>
<h4>WordPress Style Business Model</h4>
<p>I assume that even if it were possible most users would not run their own servers. Therefore, there is a need for a hosted version of the application. How WordPress does could be of inspiration. WordPress provides a opensource content management system that users can run on their own, but also provides a hosted form of the blogging engine (wordpress.com).</p>
<h4>Split Server and Client</h4>
<p>When looking at the description of what a social network is you may see that there are two distinct tasks that a distributed social networking application must complete.</p>
<ol><li>A server which handles transmitting messages between programs and other servers. This is a role roughly equivalent to that of an email server.</li>
    <li>A client which displays and messages in a way that is useful for the user. This is roughly equivalent to the role of an email client, like Thunderbird or Gmail.</li>
</ol>
<p>These two roles should be two separate programs that are written to work well together.This separates the implementation of a system from its interface. This separation would make many features which would be difficult to implement in a web based client only system easy to implement. Interfaces can become obsolete quickly but protocols can last longer. The email protocol, which was designed in the 1970s is still in use, even though the original clients for email are long dead.A clear separation between server and client will extend the life of a social networking system by expanding its flexibility.</p>
<h4>New Protocol</h4>
<p>Social networks are fundamentally different from other systems. Therefore,a new protocol, one dedicated to running these networks is needed. Many previous attempts to create a decentralized social network have free loaded on already existing protocols. This only serves to create a hard to use, overly complicated system. It does not simplify the work needed to create a social network, but instead makes the lives of their designers more complex.A protocol dedicated to social networks will create a platform that programmers can work with, not against.</p>
<h4>Open Source</h4>
<p>Opensource is the only way to create a decentralized network that avoids all of the pitfalls of a centralized network.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bradtempleton" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bradtempleton</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/emailreplacement" class="p-category" rel="tag">#emailreplacement</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/opensource" class="p-category" rel="tag">#opensource</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/paulgraham" class="p-category" rel="tag">#paulgraham</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bradtempleton</category>
      <category>#emailreplacement</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#opensource</category>
      <category>#paulgraham</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Mac?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/what-is-a-mac</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/what-is-a-mac</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 20:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Study: Twitter Discussions Reflect Political Polarization on Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-study-twitter-discussions-reflect-political-polarization-on-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-study-twitter-discussions-reflect-political-polarization-on-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 15:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A <a href="http://eprints.nottingham.ac.uk/2236/">study published this month</a> ,<em>Climate change on Twitter: topics, communities and conversations about the 2013 IPCC report</em>, looked into the debate about climate change on Twitter around the release of the latest Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change assessment.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_843" align="alignright" width="238"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:GRES-2.jpg"></a> Image Via Wikipedia.Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.[/caption]</p>

<p>They analysed the content of  tweets that mentioned the IPCC. Most Twitter posts on climate change  Among their findings is the discovery of a clear political polarization in online discussions of this issue. The discussions largely fit into four topics, "relation to science, political campaigns, geography, and social meanings of climate change". Of particular frequency in this discussion is the debate over the carbon tax bill in Australia. The debate over the accuracy of the science strongly follows these political lines. The following two example tweets given in the paper illustrate this.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Australian" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Australian</a> PM thinks that if he doesn't read the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/IPCC" class="p-category" rel="tag">#IPCC</a> report then <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> is still crap. That's the way this government works.</p>
</blockquote><blockquote>
<p>Global Warming Scam unravelling by the day. IPCC exposed as corrupt liars. <a href="http://t.co/rotD07eIEX"></a><a href="http://t.co/rotD07eIEX">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>t.co/<wbr></wbr>rotD07eIEX</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/auspol" class="p-category" rel="tag">#auspol</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ausvotes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ausvotes</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the United States tweets followed liberal and conservative lines with conservative tweets outnumbering liberal ones two to one. The authors state that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The dominance of conservative-leaning hashtags in the US provide support for the theory that the country’s climate debate is in danger of becoming so polarized as to be described as a “logic schism”, in a similar manner to struggles over President Obama’s healthcare program.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/globalwarmingscam" class="p-category" rel="tag">#globalwarmingscam</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviawikipedia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviawikipedia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/us" class="p-category" rel="tag">#us</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Australian</category>
      <category>#IPCC</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#auspol</category>
      <category>#ausvotes</category>
      <category>#globalwarmingscam</category>
      <category>#imageviawikipedia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#us</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A List of Good Linux Distros for Desktop Use By Experience Needed, From Noob Friendly to Intermediate to Advanced</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-list-of-good-linux-distros-for-desktop-use-by</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-list-of-good-linux-distros-for-desktop-use-by</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 16:22:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <h2 style="text-align: center;">Noob Friendly</h2><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold Bug Talk Show Host Peter Schiff Infiltrated Walmart Protest to Disrupt Event</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/gold-bug-talk-show-host-peter-schiff-infiltrated-walmart-protest</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/gold-bug-talk-show-host-peter-schiff-infiltrated-walmart-protest</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 15:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Peter Schiff is a libertarian talkshow host who promotes dubious predictions of imminent hyperinflation -- predictions which never seem to materialize. Well it turns out that <a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2013/12/21/1264469/-Millionaire-Oligarch-Poses-as-Walmart-Protestor-Harrasses-Shoppers-to-Discredit-Mock-Employees">he showed up at a Wallmart protest and disrupted</a> it. Schiff released the following video  </p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/LLr5oWfoWRY" height="360" width="600" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>He claimed to be a Wallmart worker and harassed shoppers and requested that they give him 15% of what they spent at the store. He held signs that stated "15 for 15 contributions" and mocked shoppers who said they didn't have the money. He shouted the slogans "higher prices for higher wages" and "We are counting on you to pay higher prices!"</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Quantitative Easing Increase Economic Inequality? No.</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/does-quantitative-easing-increase-economic-inequality-no</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/does-quantitative-easing-increase-economic-inequality-no</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2013 14:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>On a few online discussion forums I have seen the claim that the Federal Reserve's Quantitative Easing program increases economic inequality. This is far from the truth. Let's first discuss what the Fed is doing.QE is just an asset swap. Bondholders trade a bond for currency/reserves. The reserves pay less interest, so the wealth of their holders is actually <em>reduced </em>over the long run, but the reserves are easier to spend/more liquid. This liquidity is why bond holders are willing to make this swap.In my opinion this has little tangible economic impact, but it does serve to push long term interest down slightly.How does this affect inequality? If anything it serves to reduce it.  <br /><!--more--></p>
<p>The wealthy hold the great majority of financial assets in the economy. Below is <a href="http://www2.ucsc.edu/whorulesamerica/power/wealth.html">a table that shows how financial assets are distributed in the United States</a>  </p><table class="data allrules" cellspacing="0"><tbody><tr align="center" valign="top"><th class="border_none"></th>  
<th class="border_none" colspan="3">Financial (Non-Home) Wealth</th>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="subheading corner"></td>  
<td class="subheading">Top 1 percent</td>  
<td class="subheading">Next 19 percent</td>  
<td class="subheading">Bottom 80 percent</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">1983</td>  
<td>42.9%</td>  
<td>48.4%</td>  
<td>8.7%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">1989</td>  
<td>46.9%</td>  
<td>46.5%</td>  
<td>6.6%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">1992</td>  
<td>45.6%</td>  
<td>46.7%</td>  
<td>7.7%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">1995</td>  
<td>47.2%</td>  
<td>45.9%</td>  
<td>7.0%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">1998</td>  
<td>47.3%</td>  
<td>43.6%</td>  
<td>9.1%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">2001</td>  
<td>39.7%</td>  
<td>51.5%</td>  
<td>8.7%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">2004</td>  
<td>42.2%</td>  
<td>50.3%</td>  
<td>7.5%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">2007</td>  
<td>42.7%</td>  
<td>50.3%</td>  
<td>7.0%</td>  
</tr><tr align="center" valign="top"><td class="row_heading" align="left">2010</td>  
<td>42.1%</td>  
<td>53.5%</td>  
<td>4.7%</td>  
</tr></tbody></table><p>These assets are generally devalued by QE, while borrowers benefit from the reduction in interest rates.Note that debt generally has a relatively even distribution. This is why QE can be expected to reduce inequality, not expand it, if there is any effect at all.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/qe" class="p-category" rel="tag">#qe</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#qe</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Booting to Blank Screen</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/linux-booting-to-blank-screen</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/linux-booting-to-blank-screen</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 21:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>On my laptop I've encountered an issue where Linux would would boot to a blank screen. I found that my issue related to the display backlight control. I found that adding either of the following two kernel parameters would fix the issue. <br /><em>acpi_backlight=vendor <br />
nomodeset</em></p><p>Try acpi_backlight=vendor first because nomodeset disables 3d acceleration.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am Against GMO Labeling</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-against-gmo-labeling</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-against-gmo-labeling</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 22:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In a previous post I discussed the <a title="The Ludditeism of the Anti-GMO Ideologues" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/ludditeism-anti-gmo-ideologues/">bankruptcy of anti-GMO arguments</a>. Now I will discuss why GMO labeling is a terrible idea.</p>
<ol><li>As I showed in my last post there is no scientific basis to fear GMO products.</li>
    <li>The claimed consumer choice benefits of mandatory labeling can be fulfilled by private certifications and currently existing, government ran certification programs</li>
    <li>Due to the dynamics of food markets, mandatory GMO labeling amounts to a defacto GMO ban. This will increase food prices and possibly add to the environmental damage cause by agriculture.</li>
</ol>
<p><!--more-->If you haven't read my previous post on GMOs, let me recap what I said about the health effects of these products.</p>

<p>The claims made by the campaigners against genetically modified foods are simply absurd. This ideology’s claims about the health effects of GMOs are as discredited in the scientific community as creationism or global warming denialism and all major scientific associations of reputethat have looked into the issue disavow it.  Their position that a compound can suddenly become toxic when synthesized due to a genetic modification of a plant, but is not toxic when synthesized by a natural process violates the laws of physics, chemistry and biology. Their understanding of the economics of these products is not much better. These compounds have passed the approval of the FDA and the EPA. Your food is not being poisoned by <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">the Illuminati</span> Monsanto. The <a href="http://www.who.int/foodsafety/publications/biotech/20questions/en/">World Health Organization notes</a>, "GM foods currently available on the international market have passed risk assessments and are not likely to present risks for human health". <a href="http://www.aaas.org/news/aaas-board-directors-legally-mandating-gm-food-labels-could-%E2%80%9Cmislead-and-falsely-alarm">The American Association for the Advancement of Science concluded that</a> "Several current efforts to require labeling of GM foods are not being driven by any credible scientific evidence that these foods are dangerous" and that "GM crops are the most extensively tested crops ever". Their report also noted that labeling could “mislead and falsely alarm consumers”.</p>

<p>All of the claimed consumer choice benefits of GMO labeling can be done by voluntary certification. All products currently sold as organic in the U.S lack GMO products. Private certifications are also very good at assuring that products are prepared in accordance to standards that are sufficient for their consumers. Note that there are many private companies which certify kosher products.</p>

<p>Economies of scale in food production make it inefficient and cost prohibitive for companies to create separate product lines with GMO and non-GMO foods. Therefore, just one of these options will be taken.If the labeling causes a substantial minority of the population to avoid GMO foods then these foods will be forced off the market for everyone. This has already happened in Europe, where GMO labeling is mandatory. In fact, the push for labeling by the anti-GMO movement is just a pretext to regulate these products out of existence.This will harm consumers and the environment because GMO products require less land usage than their competitors. The price of this extra land will be passed on to consumers, along with the price of increased crop loss. This increased land usage will also have substantial environmental impacts. However, there will be no clear economic benefits to this defacto ban on GMO foods.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/epa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#epa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fda" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fda</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/illuminatimonsanto" class="p-category" rel="tag">#illuminatimonsanto</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#epa</category>
      <category>#fda</category>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#illuminatimonsanto</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Libertarian Holiday Cheer</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/libertarian-holiday-cheer</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/libertarian-holiday-cheer</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 15:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Think that Ebenezer Scrooge is a paragon of greed? Well there are many libertarians that would tell you that Scrooge represents the real spirit of the holiday season. Let's start with the Von Mises Instute's <a href="http://archive.mises.org/4460/scrooge-defended/">often reposted</a> classic "<a href="http://mises.org/daily/110">Scrooge Defended</a>". Apparently "his business benefits his employees, society, and himself" -- well at least himself. But that's all that matters to a libertarian businessman.  </p><blockquote>
<p>The fact is, if Cratchit's skills were worth more to anyone than the fifteen shillings Scrooge pays him weekly, there would be someone glad to offer it to him. Since no one has, and since Cratchit's profit-maximizing boss is hardly a man to pay for nothing, Cratchit must be worth exactly his present wages.</p>
</blockquote><p>In glorious Libertopia employees are able to know of all possible job openings and are able to effortlessly switch from job to job at no cost. Employers know about the abilities of every possible employee in existence. Also, Libertopia has no unemployment and everyone has capital available in unlimited quanties, so they can start their own businesses. However, the real world does not work that way.  </p><blockquote>
<p>No doubt Cratchit needs—i.e., wants—more, to support his family and care for Tiny Tim.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Food is just a "want" in Libertopia.  <br /><!--more--></p>
<blockquote>
<p>As for that one lump of coal Scrooge allows him, it bears emphasis that Cratchit has not been chained to his chilly desk. If he stays there, he shows by his behavior that he prefers his present wages-plus-comfort package to any other he has found, or supposes himself likely to find.</p>
</blockquote><p>Its ok to be an asshole to others if they have no other options.  </p><blockquote>
<p>More notorious even than his miserly ways are Scrooge's cynical words. "Are there no prisons," he jibes when solicited for charity, "and the Union workhouses?"Terrible, right? Lacking in compassion? Not necessarily. As Scrooge observes, he supports those institutions with his taxes. Already forced to help those who can't or won't help themselves, it is not unreasonable for him to balk at volunteering additional funds for their extra comfort.</p>
</blockquote><p>Nothing says "extra comfort" like a prison or a workhouse.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Dickens doesn't mention Scrooge's satisfied customers, but there must have been plenty of them for Scrooge to have gotten so rich.</p>
</blockquote><p>We all know that the only way that bankers can get rich is by having lots of satisfied customers.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Scrooge is said to hound debtors so relentlessly that—as the Ghost of Christmas Yet To Be is able to show him—an indebted couple rejoices at his demise.</p>
</blockquote><p>Sounds like we have ourselves a banker.  </p><blockquote>
<p>This canard is triply absurd. First, a businessman as keen as Scrooge would prefer to delay payment to protect his investment rather than take possession of possibly useless collateral.</p>
</blockquote><p>Looks like this libertarian has not done very much business with banks lately.</p><p>Next lets look at the Forbes article "<a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/fredsmith/2013/07/17/charles-dickens-ebenezer-scrooge-was-the-ultimate-job-creator/">Charles Dickens' Ebenezer Scrooge Was The Ultimate Job Creator</a>".  </p><blockquote>
<p>The Scrooges of the world were the stewards of the scarce capital—the seed corn prosperity—of that earlier Industrial Age. Ensuring that it was used wisely and honestly was critical to the wealthier England in which Dickens lived.</p>
</blockquote><p>I don't recall reading about how Scrooge invested his wealth on useful investments. I do remember reading about some one who hoarded wealth and gold. Remember that ones spending is someone else's income. Money saved is not money earned.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Every so often, a talented and enterprising individual would launch a new business.....But in this closely knit community, success placed cultural demands on the entrepreneur. He would be expected to make place in his business for an out-of-luck Uncle Bill or Aunt Sally.</p>

<p>Often, that entrepreneur would give into such cultural pressures and add these individuals to his payroll and the operation’s efficiency would decline, often leading to its collapse.</p>
</blockquote><p>Hear that? If a business does not treat its employees and customers like dirt it will shut down. Not being an asshole is like graft.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ebenezerscrooge" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ebenezerscrooge</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/industrialage" class="p-category" rel="tag">#industrialage</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tinytim" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tinytim</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vonmisesinstute" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vonmisesinstute</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#ebenezerscrooge</category>
      <category>#industrialage</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#tinytim</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vonmisesinstute</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
