<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all?offset=230</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all?offset=230&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Are only some political ideologies compatible with science?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/are-only-some-political-ideologies-compatible-with-science</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/are-only-some-political-ideologies-compatible-with-science</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 19:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>In this post I will discuss the question of the political neutrality of science --- not in the climate change sceptic meaning of "scientists with grant money worshipping Al Gore -- but in meaning of asking if all political ideologies are compatible with  science. I will conclude that there are in fact some political ideologies that are so incompatible and these ideologies are therefore inherently prone to denialism. These are ideologies that theorize that an at least roughly ideal way of structuring society is possible and known, and that the goal of politics is to bring this society into existence. I will further argue that such ideologies are common. I will also argue that ideologies that argue for the continuous contesting of government policies and social structures are the most compatible with science and that one example of such an ideology that fits that bill is liberalism (defined in a philosophical sense that i will discuss later, not in the commonly used political sense). I argue that there are broadly three common political philosophies in the  United States: conservativism (made up of three ideologies that I will call social conservativism, reactionary conservativism and axiomatic libertarianism), liberalism (with subdivisions that I will call individualist liberalism, right-liberalism/consequentialist libertarianism, civic republicanism, and populist liberalism), and leftism (with various varients that I will discuss later). As I will discuss later   I will now futher discuss what I mean by these ideologies:</p>

<p>I would define conservativism as the political theory that contends that the either current or past institutions, or a part of this structure, is the ideal way to run society. Conservatism contends that these institutions need to be fought for and preserved. I think that conservativism has three broad types. The first is social conservatism , which contends that the social institutions, ie religion and the like, are at the core of an ideal society. This ideology tends to emphasize a strong degree of social conventionalism and adherence to and preservation of conventions and social norms, including norms of social status.This ideology demands a strong degree of social conformity, and rejection of behaviors termed deviant. It endorses traditional authority and obedience to this authority. Reactionary conservatism is similar but advocates returning to an old version of these institutions and rolling back reforms of them. Axiomatic libertarianism are the variants of libertarianism that advocate that the free market and the business system are the ideal institution that should run society. These libertarians argue that this can be known apriori, without the need for factual questioning. This line of reasoning can be seen most directly in the libertarianism of Ayn Rand, and of the more hardline variants of Austrian School libertarianism (eg. Von Mises and other followers of praxology).</p>

<p>Next I will discuss the nature of liberalism. Now, I do not define liberalism in the sense commonly used in American politics as a different word for left wing politics, or do I use the commonly proposed alternate definition that defines it as synonymous with libertarianism. Instead I will define it as the ideologies that argue for the ability for systematic challenging and questioning of social institutions and political power. It contends that their is no known approximately ideal institution or set of laws (and there will never be), and that the best we can do is allow for a wide range of  individual freedom, and ability to change institutions as our knowledge improves. If this happens we will have the best ability to eliminate social ills through improvements in our knowledge of the world. In my opinion liberalism has four variants. The first is individualist liberalism which works through maximizing the range of human rights that can be exercised without interference and by maximizing the effective capacity to use these rights. Right-liberalism/consquentilist libertarianism, is similar to individualist liberalism, but denies that the effective capacity to use the rights is necessary, as long as there is no direct interference, or constraints on use of rights. Civic republicanism opposes arbitrary power, and opposes all forms of interference that does not follow the interests and values of those that are subjected to it. Under this view all power and institutional policies must be subjected to effective means of contestment and public debate. Structural inequality must be opposed and conditions where one person is subject to the arbitrary will of another must be minimized, freedom from this type of domination is at the core of liberty in this view. Populist liberalism contends that all institutions must be subject to democracy and should follow the will of the people as determined by a fair democratic process that allows all voices to be heard equally.</p>

<p>The third political category, what I call leftism, is less a single ideology but instead a grouping of somewhat related left-wing ideologies. The commonality of these is that they are the set of non-liberal, but left wing ideologies. These ideologies tend to believe that there is a form of perfect justice that can be implemented. The first ideology I put in this category is what I would call leftist-populism. To define this I will go with the following <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Populism">definition of populism as an ideology that</a> "pits a virtuous and homogeneous people against a set of elites and dangerous ‘others’ who were together depicted as depriving (or attempting to deprive) the sovereign people of their rights, values, prosperity, identity, and voice". Leftist-populism extends this by assuming a struggle between the oppressed populace and the oppressor group. The next type of leftist ideology that I will discuss is identity politics leftism. This ideology focus on the struggle between an oppressed social group and the oppressing society. There are also radical forms of environmentalism that fall into the leftist category.</p>

<p>What does this have to do with acceptance of science? Well, science is fundamentally about questioning knowledge. This often means questioning knowledge that also bares on the functioning of institutions in society.A political ideology that is compatible with science must also allow for questioning of the institutions in society, and for questioning of the actions of the political system. It is not possible to neatly divide questions into the scientific and into the political. Open debate of knowledge in one area must mean open debate in the other. An ideology that believes that there is a perfect way to organize a society and that any one who questions it must be evil or otherwise flawed, is one that is also fundamentally incompatible with the knowledge produced by science.</p>

<p>As I will discuss in a later post, there is a strong historical relation between a liberal political system, and the development of science. The relative liberalism of the Renaissance in Italy gave birth to science as we know it today. The development of science fostered the development of political liberalism during the Enlightenment. The Enlightenment created a culture of questioning that enveloped both science and politics and that greatly expanded the scope of human knowledge and prosperity. It is impossible to have the benefits of science without an open and liberal political culture. The history of the Soviet Union shows this. Its economy lagged in large part due to the USSR's inability to take the knowledge produced by science into running its economy. This eventually was a major contributor to the downfall of the Soviet Union.</p>

<p>With regards to social conservativism some of this questioning will involve knowledge that challenges traditional values and institutions. With regards to the axiomatic libertarian perspective on conservativism this means that scientific discoveries will sometimes challenge the legitimacy of the market. And as I will discuss in a later post in this series, conservative ideologies have a general inability to take into account what has been termed <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">systemic causation</a>. Due to these factors it is not difficult to see where conservative denialism of climate change originates from.</p>

<p>However, it is possible to see how a left wing form of denialism can emerge based on leftism. Those ideologies tend to identify politics in terms of a simple oppressor-oppressed system. When scientific knowledge challenges the assumptions then denialsim can emerge.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/austrianschool" class="p-category" rel="tag">#austrianschool</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aynrand" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aynrand</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sovietunion" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sovietunion</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vonmises" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vonmises</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#austrianschool</category>
      <category>#aynrand</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#sovietunion</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vonmises</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Renewable Energy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 07:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>The first energy sources in wide use by human civilization were of course renewable, but in the late 19th century the foundations of the renewable energy industry as we know it were built. While the direct use of energy from wind and water are ancient, solar was the first renewable energy source to be widely researched for electricity production. This early investment in solar was driven primarily by the concerns I <a title="Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply/">mentioned in the last post</a> that coal supplies could run out. French researcher Augustine Mouchot wrote the following</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The time will arrive when the industry of Europe will cease to find those natural resources, so necessary for it. Petroleum springs and coal mines are not inexhaustible but are rapidly diminishing in many places. Will man, then, return to the power of water and wind? Or will he emigrate where the most powerful source of heat sends its rays to all? History will show what will come.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://solarenergy.com/power-panels/history-solar-energy">In 1860 a patent was granted to Mouchot</a> for inventing a system that could generate steam though solar energy and use it to run a motor --- an early concentrated solar energy system. With funding from the French government Mouchot worked on scaling this invention up to an industrial scale. Mouchot created prototype water pumps and refrigration systems using solar energy and worked on deploying this in sunny Algeria. This system relied on a set of parabolic mirrors. However, parabolic mirrors are strongly limited in size and therefore can only have limited production. This doomed Mouchot designs. In 1881 the French Ministry of Public Works comissioned a report on the economics of solar energy produced by Mouchot's method and found the method to not be economically viable. William Adams, then the deputy registrar for the English Crown in Bombay further improved Mouchot's design. He came up with an innovation that underlies most modern concentrated solar energy systems. Adams realized that the limits of system production and mirror size would pretty much go away if instead of simple parabolic mirrors the system used series of mirrors in a flat shape. Flat mirrors can easily be chained together in to a large, connected system. Adams' conducted this chaining by placing the mirrors in a circular arrangement and focusing the mirrors towards central point. This exact setup is known today as a power tower, and is still in widespread use for electricity production.  Adams' system used 17-by-10-inch flat mirrors, and with 72 of these mirrors he could run a conventional  2.5  horsepower steam engine during all daytime hours. He penned a book titled <em>Solar heat: A substitute for fuel in tropical countries for heating steam boilers, and other purposes</em> on this subject. While impressive, this method was not good enough to compete with coal as an energy source with the technology available to Adams. Around this time American engineer John Ericsson came up with a third way to design a concentrated solar system --- a parabolic trough. Through each trough runs a pipe and through the pipe runs water that is boiled by the solar heat. This design has large benefits in terms of cost and is currently the most common method for large scale commercial use. Adams eventually became disenchanted with solar energy and stopped working on the technology due to failure to come up with a practical way to put it to use. Mouchot failed to come up with an improved design of his method. However other researchers persisted with concentrated solar technology. Engineer Charles Tellier created a solar refrigeration method based around an ammonia coolant. The core of this method can be found in modern electric refrigerators, but usually without solar energy. Aubrey Eneas founded the first solar energy company in 1900 and sold solar powered irrigation systems. These system were effective, but their parabolic collectors could easily be damaged by weather, and the company soon failed due to the problem of collectors being damaged beyond repair.  Henry E. Willsie also attempted to commercialize solar power --- focusing on electricity generation. He designed a thermal energy storage system that allowed energy to be produced all day. This system was cost competitive with coal and was marketed as "designed for furnishing power for electric light and power, refrigerating and ice making, for milling and pumping at mines, and for other purposes where large amounts of power are required." However, solar still had one big disadvantage compared to coal. With almost all sustainable energy technologies (even with today's technology) the main cost is up-front. Solar collectors are large and expensive, but they don't need any fuel, and the labor costs involved in their maintenance are small. With coal, building the furnace is cheap , but the coal itself is expensive. This means that solar (and all other sustainable energy technology, including nuclear) have costs that are almost all fixed. That is the cost of running the system at any output is about the same as running it at any output. This increases the risk of an investment in such a tech and as we will see in later posts in this series, it has economic implications for the wide deployment of sustainable energy and the commercial pricing of it.</p>

<p>In 1876 the photovoltaic effect was observed to occur in selenium by William Adams. This discovery enabled the creation of the first solar cells. In 1883 inventor <a href="http://inventors.about.com/od/timelines/a/Photovoltaics.htm">Charles Fritts used that discovery to create the first solar photovoltaic cell</a>. This cell was very expensive and was far from competitive with coal and other fossil fuels. It also was very inefficient at converting sunlight to electricity compared to modern technology. Throughout the early 20th century, researchers refined their knowledge of the theoretical basis of the photovoltaic effect. However, none of these early photovoltaic cells were nearly as efficient as modern ones. Additionally, all of these earily cells were extremely expensive. It wasn't until the development of modern semiconductor fabrication technology that solar PV cells came down to a reasonable price.</p>

<p>Biomass and biofuels energy also had a substantial growth during this period. In fact, the first liquid automotive fuels were not petroleum but biofuels. William K. Vanderbilt favored ethanol due to its higher performance -- particularly in racing. For this reason car racing sports widely use alcohol fuels even today (although this is usually methanol, which is far to dangerous for consumer use). However all commercially viable biofuels (even today) use feed stocks that compete with food production. Due to this issue petroleum soon became the dominant fuel source.This triggered the first research into cellulose based fuels. In 1925 Henry Ford stated that “The fuel of the future is going to come from fruit like that sumac out by the road, or from apples, weeds, sawdust — almost anything.” But celluloseic fuels have turned out to be the renewable energy equivalent to fusion power. Always 30 years away, and always facing key failings. However, fission power actually works, conventional biofuels do not. The modern attempts to implement conventional biofuels have been completely disastrous due to the food versus fuel issue. Furthermore, due to the inherent limits to crop production it is unclear that any method could solve  these issues. I would suggest that biofuel production should be halted and that the production or importation of these fuels should be illegal even for hobbyist uses or research. Heavy research should be put into alternative ways to make synthetic fuels, further discussion of these methods will be discussed in later posts. History shows that our best energy bets can be found in the atom (I will discuss nuclear energy more in a later post),and in solar power.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aubreyeneas" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aubreyeneas</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/charlesfritts" class="p-category" rel="tag">#charlesfritts</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/henryford" class="p-category" rel="tag">#henryford</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/williamadams" class="p-category" rel="tag">#williamadams</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aubreyeneas</category>
      <category>#charlesfritts</category>
      <category>#henryford</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#williamadams</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Core Opinions on Fiscal Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/my-core-opinions-on-fiscal-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/my-core-opinions-on-fiscal-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 09:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I consider my economic beliefs generally in the <a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Post-Keynesian_economics">Post-Keynesian camp</a> (same general category as MMT but I'm not fully convinced of a few of the oddities of MMT over similar approaches).</p><p>1) Money is pretty much a product of the government and the taxation system. Money and markets can't exist outside of the state and pre-state economies were non-monetary gift economies. <br />
2) Government Bonds and currency (including bank reserves) are for all intensive purposes equivalent when a government issues its own currency and floats its currency freely (without any peg or gold standard or the like) . <br />
3) The only role that the issue of bonds serves in the economy over currency is interest rate targeting, a role that could easily be taken over by paying interest on bank reserves and funding the deficit by currency issue. <br />
4) A government with its own and floating currency can not be forced into involuntary default (as long as its debts are in its currency). <br />
5) Government deficits (when the government has its own and floating currency) have no impact beyond changing aggregate demand. They should only be judged by their impacts on unemployment, inflation and the like. <br />
6) Because of the previous, taxes can effectively be taken as destroying money, and spending can be taken as effectively creating money because currency is another government debt that isn't terribly different than bonds. However, this is not the way that governments usually account for their spending. But for all practical purposes taxing money out of the economy is the same as destroying it. <br />
7) All money is credit and all financial assets are a liability of some actor in the economy. Currency is a government liability that can be redeemed on tax day. A buyer, seller, and bank are involved in all transactions. <br />
8) Government spending creates financial assets. It does not crowd out private demand for a finite source of them. However, producing too many financial assets may produce inflation. <br />
9) The money multiplier is a meaningless accounting formality. The money supply is set by the level of demand that prevails at the current government policy and interest rate. Banks have ways of getting funding regardless of their current reserves (such as borrowing from the Fed). <br />
10) Financial regulation is critical to limiting lending by banks. <br />
11) The interest rate is a product of the central bank, and there is no natural interest rate. <br />
12) There is no natural level of unemployment, and by the right mix of policies a government can create full employment at all times. <br />
13) Taxes should be kept as the lowest rate that does not produce excessive inflation, given the current level of spending. <br />
14) Governments should run deficits to fight high unemployment and surpluses to fight inflation.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/governmentbonds" class="p-category" rel="tag">#governmentbonds</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mmt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mmt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#governmentbonds</category>
      <category>#mmt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 07:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em style="color: #222222;">This post is part of a series <a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #3465a4;" title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a></em>Concerns about the sustainability of fossil fuel energy have a long history that goes back almost 150 years. However, some of these early concerns were focused not on the environmental impact of coal or other fossil fuels, but were instead focused on the risk that we could run out of these fuels. Additionally, concerns about the environmental impact of coal are almost as old as the widespread consumption of the fuel.</p>

<p>In 1865 the <a href="http://www.econlib.org/library/YPDBooks/Jevons/jvnCQ.html">economist William Stanley Jevons penned his book</a> <em>The Coal Question; An Inquiry Concerning the Progress of the Nation, and the Probable Exhaustion of Our Coal Mines</em>. In that book Jevons argued that England would run out of domestic coal supplies, and would therefore either be dependent on imports, or would have to cut back on industrialization. He argued that this would be a long-run threat to Great Britain's status as a global power. Jevons predicted that the U.K had only 90 billions tons of coal available in 1865. If economic growth persisted at the rate he guessed, this coal would be exhausted by the end of the 20th century and the country would be dependent on imported fossil fuels. He made the following projection of coal consumption, production, and imports, from 1870 to 1970.</p>

<p>These predictions largely came true. The U.K <a href="http://www.coal.gov.uk/media//286DC/CA-AnnualReport-0607.pdf">only has about 400 million tons of coal left</a>. Production of coal peaked during World War 1. However, consumption of coal has not budged. The Association for UK Coal Importers estimates that Britain consumed 60.7 million tons of coal in 2013, 49.4 million of which were imported. <a href="http://www.coalimp.org.uk/4.html">They further guess that</a> "Proven world coal reserves amount to around 900 billion tonnes". However, other sources indicate that coal production <a href="http://e360.yale.edu/feature/peak_coal_why_the_industrys_dominance_may_soon_be_over/2777/">will likely peak around 2020</a>, even without explicit policy to reduce coal use.</p>

<p>Jevons though that reductions in the supply of coal would cause dramatic rises in its price, "<span style="color: #333333;">The exhaustion of our mines will be marked </span><i style="color: #333333;">pari passu</i><span style="color: #333333;"> by a rising cost or value of coal; and when the price has risen to a certain amount comparatively to the price in other countries, our main branches of trade will be doomed" (Chapter V, paragraph 2). However, coal prices have been surprisingly stable over history. <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0301421511000474">A study of the cost of coal in the United States between </a><span style="color: #2e2e2e;"><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0301421511000474">1882 and 2006 found</a> that "The price of coal appears to fluctuate more or less randomly" and that there is no general long term trend in the cost of the mineral. Coal has become a global market so this cost is quite uniform across the world. </span></span></p>

<p>Jevons also examined the "supposed substitutes of coal" -- energy through wind, water, and biomass -- and considered them to be less than satisfactory, saying "The first great requisite of motive power is, that it shall be wholly at our command, to be exerted when and where and in what degree we desire" (paragraph 13 of Chapter VIII). This concern is today known as the intermittentcy problem -- wind, water, and solar energy sources can not be produced on demand. Jevons claimed that deploying these sources would mean "carrying the work to the power, not the power to the work" (paragraph 23 of Chapter VIII). It is fair to say that we now know ways to <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/renewable-energy-baseload-power-advanced.htm">mitigate the intermittentcy problem of renewable energy sources</a>, such as an electric grid coupled with storage and a mix of power sources (although this comes at a substantial price tag), plus modern scientists now know how to harness nuclear power (which lacks the intermittency issue all together). However, despite the advances in technology made since 1865, intermittency is still a non-trivial problem for wind, water, and solar energy sources, and a strong argument in favor of nuclear power.</p>

<p>In <em>The Coal Question </em>Jevons introduced his famous paradox --- the argument that increasing the efficiency of energy usage actually increases the usage of energy. This comes from the fact that energy is a cost of using a good or service. Energy efficiency reduces this cost.  What do consumers do when the cost of something they want goes down? They consume more of it. For this reason a pure focus on energy efficiency is insufficient to restrain excessive consumption of fossil fuels. Jevons's paradox is well known but its implications are unappreciated.</p>

<p>Irrespective of its supply, concerns about the environmental impact of coal are as old as its use. <a href="http://66.147.244.135/~enviror4/ancient/middle-ages/">In </a><span style="color: #333333;"><a href="http://66.147.244.135/~enviror4/ancient/middle-ages/">1306 King </a>Edward I restricted the burning of coal inorder to limit air pollution. In the 17th century <span style="color: #333340;">John Evelyn correctly identified coal burning as the source of London's air pollution and wrote <em>Fumifugium: Or, the Inconvenience of the Aer, and Smoake of London Dissipated</em>, a policy proposal to the King and Parliament  on the matter. He described the pollution of London as follows <em>“The immoderate use of, and indulgence to, sea-coale in the city of London exposes it to one of the fowlest inconveniences and reproaches that can possibly befall so noble and otherwise incomparable City… Whilst they are belching it forth their sooty jaws, the City of London resembles the face rather of Mount Aetna, the Court of Vulcan… or the suburbs of Hell than an assembly of rational creatures” </em> He called the presence of this pollution a "pernicious Nuance" and noted that the responsible coal has "a kind of virulent or arsenical vapour arising from it”. He noted that other cities, such as Paris did not have a pollution problem as horrendous. In Evelyn's opinion, not only was this smog a nuisance, but it also posed health risks. He recommended containing the bad air (keep in mind that the miasma theory of disease was in use in the 17th century ) produced by this smoke by planting “odiferous flowers” to "tinge the air". These flowers were eventually planted. This solution of course failed to contain the smoke, and London retained its pollution problem. In 1873 London <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140305113926/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.bloombergview.com:80/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>2013-10-31/<wbr></wbr>china-s-smog-can-t-compete-with-london-s-pea-soup</a>"&gt;suffered a "Black Fog" that covered the city in a thick smoky haze, limited visibility in some areas to a few feet, and caused about 700 deaths. In response a Smoke Abatement Committee was formed to come up with policy measures to contain the problem.<a href="http://www.1902encyclopedia.com/S/SMO/smoke-abatement.html">The Committee recommended</a> a policy of abatement of the problem through installing filters on industrial equipment, a transition to liquid fuels, use of natural gas as an alternative to coal,  and a switch to forms of coal that burn cleaner. As a testament to how wide spread the problem of coal pollution is, the Committee notes a history of past technology innovations, and legislation  to mitigate this issue.  </span></span></p>

<p> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>In 1785 the first smoke-abating invention was patented by James Watt, who, as the inventor of the steam-engine, is responsible for so many boiler fires and so much consump-tion of coal. In 1815 Cutler patented the first would-be smokeless grate for domestic purposes; and his principle of feeding underneath was afterwards adopted by Dr Neil Arnott in a grate which has now been in use in one form or another for more than half a century. There is now a vast number of such inventions, good and bad. In 1819 the attention of parliament was directed to the question, and a select committee was appointed "to inquire how far persons using steam-engines and furnaces could erect them in a manner less prejudicial to public health and comfort." This committee gave an encouraging report. In 1843 another select committee recommended the introduction of a bill prohibiting the production of smoke from furnaces and steam-engines. In 1845 yet another select committee reported that such an Act could not in the existing state of affairs be made to apply to dwelling-houses.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/blackfog" class="p-category" rel="tag">#blackfog</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/citywhilst" class="p-category" rel="tag">#citywhilst</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/london" class="p-category" rel="tag">#london</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/smokeabatementcommittee" class="p-category" rel="tag">#smokeabatementcommittee</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#3465a4</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#2e2e2e</category>
      <category>#333333</category>
      <category>#333340</category>
      <category>#blackfog</category>
      <category>#citywhilst</category>
      <category>#london</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#smokeabatementcommittee</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Correct Was the First Climate Change Prediction?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-correct-was-the-first-climate-change-prediction</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-correct-was-the-first-climate-change-prediction</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 03:53:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em><br /><a title="Arrhenius and Climate Change" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/arrhenius-and-climate-change/">In the last post</a>, I discussed the very first research on climate change --- the work of Svante Arrhenius, but how close to modern knowledge did he get? On the relation between CO2 levels and temperature he was quite close. Modern estimates of the climate sensitivity are approximately 3-4.5 degrees Celsius per doubling of CO2. The IPCC <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/publications_ipcc_fourth_assessment_report_synthesis_report.htm">says the following</a> on the issue of climate sensitivity to CO2 increases,it is "likely to be in the range 2 to 4.5°C with a best estimate of about 3°C, and is very unlikely to be less than 1.5°C. Values substantially higher than 4.5°C cannot be excluded, but agreement of models with observations is not as good for those values."</p>

<p>But he was far off on what the impacts of these shifts would be. Unlike Arrhenius, almost all modern researchers would say that the effects of climate change will be gravely harmful. <br />Climate change is harmful because human civilization has adapted to a relatively stable climate. A shift away from that climate will be extremely disruptive to humanity. The melting of ice will disrupt infrastructure. Rising temperatures will disrupt agriculture, and will make some crops impossible to grow where they have been grown for centuries. Climate change is also having a vast impact on natural ecosystems. It, along with other human impacts, are bringing forth a fifth mass extinction. A level of disruption to the natural world on par with the KT event that killed the dinosaurs. Ocean acidification will cause further disruption to the natural world, and will harm many species of importance to the seafood industry. The increased prevalence of extremely hot days will have negative impacts on human health. <br />Lets go deeper into some of these effects, starting with agriculture. While there are some conditions where some crops may benefit from climate change (for example due to a longer growing season, or increased efficiency of photosynthesis due to more CO2), these positive impacts are almost entirely outweighed by negative counterparts. For many crops climate change will trigger a faster, shorter growth period. This may sound like a good thing but its not. Crops will produce a lot less yield during this fast growth period. All crops have an optimal temperature where they grow the best. Global warming can reduce the area that is available at this optimal climate. Climate change can cause droughts that will reduce the water available for crops. Global warming can also trigger an increase in destructive weather events. The prevalence of pests and parasites will be increased. Many fish critical to the seafood industry favor low temperatures, and will be harmed by global warming. The poorest parts of the world will be hit the hardest by these changes (<a href="http://www.epa.gov/climatechange/impacts-adaptation/agriculture.html"></a><a href="http://www.epa.gov/climatechange/impacts-adaptation/agriculture.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.epa.gov/<wbr></wbr>climatechange/<wbr></wbr>impacts-adaptation/<wbr></wbr>agriculture.html</a>).</p>

<p>And of course he was way off on the situation of how quickly these changes would occur. <br />A graph of the real world shift in global temperature is as follows</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_163" align="alignright" width="300"] Land temperature with 1- and 10-year running averages. The shaded regions are the one- and two-standard deviation uncertainties calculated including both statistical and spatial sampling errors. Prior land results from the other groups are also plotted. The NASA GISS record had a land mask applied; the HadCRU curve is the simple land average, not the hemispheric-weighted one. Image and caption from Berkeley Earth <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130723044740/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>berkeleyearth.org:80/<wbr></wbr>results-summary/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;<a href="http://berkeleyearth.org/results-summary/%5B/caption">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>berkeleyearth.org/<wbr></wbr>results-summary/<wbr></wbr>[/<wbr></wbr>caption</a>]</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/berkeleyearth" class="p-category" rel="tag">#berkeleyearth</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/kt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#kt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unlikearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unlikearrhenius</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#berkeleyearth</category>
      <category>#kt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unlikearrhenius</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrhenius and Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/arrhenius-and-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/arrhenius-and-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 16:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a><br /></em>The first scientist that theorized the possibility that the combustion of coal fuels could result in a global increase in temperature was chemist Svante Arrhenius,</p>

<p><a href="http://www.aip.org/history/climate/co2.htm">who in 1896 theorized that coal burning could warm the climate at a scale similar to the effect caused by geologic sources</a>, such as volcanoes. He first estimated that a carbon dioxide increase sufficient to double CO2, and thereby increase global temperatures by 5 degrees Celsius, would take a few thousand years. By 1908, he had reduced this estimate to a few hundred years. However, Arrhenius' model of the climate was simplistic and the possibility that human activity and changes in CO2 level could increase global temperature was disregarded until the 1950s.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/4314542?uid=3739552&uid=2&uid=4&uid=3739256&sid=21104511473153">Arrhenius was primarily focused on the causes of the Quaternary glaciation cycles</a> and was the first known author to calculate how CO2 concentrations in the atmosphere change global temperatures. He soon expanded his work to human industrial emissions and calculated that these emissions have a substantial ability to increase global temperature. The greenhouse effect though was discovered by French scientist Joseph Fourier in 1824, but Fourier never related CO2 concentrations to global climate in a reliable fashion. Fourier and other early researchers on the greenhouse effect never realized the impact that the effect could have on ground temperatures.</p>

<p>Arrhenius guessed that natural fluctuations in CO2, such as those that have historically shifted glaciation are driven by changes in the frequency of volcanoes. This is correct for periods of millions of years. However this is not true for the shorter term changes Arrhenius was interested in. It is now known that he got the magnitude of these historical shifts in temperature correct, but was incorrect about they formed. These short term shifts were driven by the CO2 stored in oceans, the atmosphere, and the biomass of ecosystems. Changes in temperature that resulted in glaciation were also driven by other factors like changes in the Earth's orbit. CO2 though does have the ability to act as a powerful feedback that amplifies these exogenous changes.</p>

<p>Now lets discuss how Arrhenius calculated how human impacts would change the climate. All objects emit light based on their temperature. This is known as black-body radiation. The light emitted by the Earth is mostly in the infrared. The light emitted by the much hotter Sun is in wavelengths that range from the ultraviolet to the infrared. The hotter an object is, the more energy it emits through light. There is an equilibrium between the energy contained in the incoming light from the Sun, and the energy leaving the Earth. This is because all energy present in the Earth must come from somewhere and energy can never be created nor destroyed. Because of this temperatures will rise and fall until the level of energy coming out of the Earth equals the amount coming into it. To see why this forms an equilibrium imagine 1) a world where less energy comes into the earth than out of it, and 2) a world where more energy comes into the earth than out of it. In condition 1 the Earth will lose energy through the light it outputs, this will reduce the temperature of the planet and therefore cause a return to the equilibrium. The same thing, only in the opposite direction, happens in situation 2. The state of this equilibrium sets the global temperature. Greenhouse gasses can shift this equilibrium by absorbing some of the light emitted by the Earth, and re-emitting it back at the Earth. This effectively reduces the light emission by the Earth forcing the temperature upwards. Core greenhouse gases in the Earth's climate are carbon dioxide and water vapor but there are a range of more minor greenhouse gasses. Arrhenius only took into account CO2 and H20 in his model. Based on this Arrhenius derived a mathematical model of the global climate. He found that the temperature varies with respect to CO2 concentration according to the following rule.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>if the quantity of carbonic acid [CO2] increases in geometric progression, the augmentation of the temperature will increase nearly in arithmetic progression.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In equation form this means</p>

<p>ΔT = α Ln(C/C_0)</p>

<p>Where ΔT is the change in temperature,α is a constant, C is the final concentration of CO2, and C_0 is the final concentration of CO2. The constant α was empirically determined.</p>

<p>There were of course gaps in his model. For example cloud cover plays no role in it. The role of feed-backs and forgings is very limited. Arrhenius though thought that Climate Change would be a positive gift to future generations ,in contrast to the views of the vast majority of modern scientists. <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=1t45AAAAMAAJ&printsec=frontcover#v=onepage&q&f=false">He wrote that</a> and argued that the change would rule out the possibility of a future ice age, and the negative consequences of such an ice age.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We often hear lamentations that the coal stored up in the earth is wasted by the present generation without any thought of the future, and we are terrified by the awful destruction of life and property which has followed the volcanic eruptions of our days. We may find a kind of consolation in the consideration that here, as in every other case, there is good mixed with the evil. By the influence of the increasing percentage of carbonic acid in the atmosphere, we may hope to enjoy ages with more equable and better climates, especially as regards the colder regions of the earth, ages when the earth will bring forth much more abundant crops than at present, for the benefit of rapidly propagating mankind.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Arrhenius also thought that this change would come much more slowly. He underestimated the rate of industrialization by a wide margin and thought that it would take 3000 years for human impacts to double CO2. However, in actuality emissions increased so rapidly that it is possible that the doubleing could occur with in the 21st century if there are no policy changes made to reduce these emissions. However, the history of climate change research, a history that goes back over a century challenges the notion that global warming is a new concept dreamed up by tree huggers and Al Gore with scientists jumping on the propaganda bandwagon.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#algore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/josephfourier" class="p-category" rel="tag">#josephfourier</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#v</category>
      <category>#algore</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#josephfourier</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2014 12:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I will be writing a series of blog posts on the history of the politics of sustainable energy. Here is an outline of the posts that I will write.</p>

<p><strong>The First Climate Change Researchers? </strong> <br />1. <a title="Arrhenius and Climate Change" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/arrhenius-and-climate-change/">Arrhenius and Climate Change</a> <br />2. <a title="How Correct Was the First Climate Change Prediction?" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/how-correct-was-the-first-climate-change-prediction/">How Correct Was the First Climate Change Prediction? <br /></a>3.<a title="Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply/"> Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply</a> <br />4. <a title="The Beginning of Renewable Energy" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy/">The Beginning of Renewable Energy.</a> <br />5. Early Economic Thought on Externalities</p>

<p><strong>Energy Policy During the World Wars</strong> <br />1. What Modern Climate Change Policy Makers Can Learn From Economics Policy During the Wars <br />2. Inflation and "Voluntary" Savings During World War 1 <br />3. The Federal Fuel Administration and World War 1 Energy Rationing <br />4. How Economic Policy was Done Better During World War 2 <br />5. Synthetic Oil <br />6. The Manhattan Project and Civilian Energy <br />7. The Great Depression and Energy Infrastructure <br />8. The Great Depression and Conservation</p>

<p><strong>Sustainable Energy Policy After the Wars </strong> <br />1. Our Friend the Atom: Research Into Nuclear Power in The U.S <br />2. The Soviet Union and Nuclear Energy <br />3. The Oil Crisis of the 1970s <br />4. Renewable Energy and The Oil Crisis <br />5. The Messmer Plan --- How France Converted to Nuclear to Reduce Oil Usage <br />6. The Reagan Administration, the End of the Oil Crisis, and Natural Gas <br />7. The Birth of The Environmental Movement. <br />8. The Chernobyl Disaster <br />9. Three Mile Island <br />10. The Formation of Anti-Nuclear Sentiments and The End of The Nuclear Golden Age <br />11. <a href="https://theojones.name/the-environmental-movements-greatest-own-goal/">The Environmental Movement's Greatest Own Goal?</a> <br />12. Nixon and the EPA</p>

<p><strong>Modern Climate Science</strong> <br />1. Climate Change Science Before the 70s <br />2. Climate Change Science During The 70s <br />3. Modern Ecology <br />4. The Latest Mass Extinction? <br />5. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/climate-change-science-now/" title="Climate Change Science Now">Climate Change Science Now</a> <br />6. The IPCC</p>

<p><strong>The Birth of Climate Change Denialism </strong> <br />1. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-political-foundations-of-denialism/" title="The Political Foundations of Denialism">The Political Foundations of Denialism</a> <br />2. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-anatomy-of-climate-change-denialism/" title="The Anatomy of Climate Change Denialism">The Anatomy of Climate Change Denialism</a> <br />3. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/the-birth-of-anti-environmentalism/" title="The Birth of Anti-environmentalism">Anti-environmentalism</a> <br />4. <a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/politics-media-and-the-public-opinion-on-climate-change/" title="Politics, Media, and the Public Opinion on Climate Change">Politics, Media and Climate Change</a> <br />5. Industry and Climate Change <br />6. Conservative Politics and Climate Change <br />7. Is libertarianism compatible with our Knowledge of Climate Change? <br />8. Special Interests and Energy Policy <br />9.<a title="Are only some political ideologies compatible with science?" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/are-only-some-political-ideologies-compatible-with-science/">Are only some political ideologies compatible with science?</a></p>

<p><strong>The Response to Climate Change</strong> <br />1. Energy Independence <br />2. Energy Policy During the Clinton Administration <br />3. The Biofuels Disaster <br />4. The 2007 Food Price Crisis <br />5. Energy Policy During the Bush Administration <br />6. Can Climate Change be Separated From Other Economic Issues? <br />7. Carbon Taxes and Carbon Pricing <br />8. Are We On the Verge of Repeating the Problems of World War 1 Economic Policy <br />9. The Hansen Proposal -- A Case Study in Carbon Pricing and Its Weaknesses <br />10. Equality, Justice and Climate Change <br />11.<a href="https://theojones.name/the-problems-with-using-cost-benefit-analysis-in-climate-change-policy/">The Problems With Using Cost-Benefit Analysis In Climate Change Policy</a> <br />12. Identity Politics and Energy <br />13. Direct Regulation Reconsidered. <br />14. How to Convert to Sustainable Energy <br />15. Regional Politics and Energy</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/epa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#epa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#epa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Delivery and Energy Production Should Be Separated</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/energy-delivery-and-energy-production-should-be-separated</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/energy-delivery-and-energy-production-should-be-separated</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>In this post I will contend that energy utilities really do two distinct things that can and should be separate. The first is producing energy. The second is distributing that electricity. Separating these two roles will vastly improve the competitiveness of the electricity markets and will have benefits in regard to climate change and pollution. It would improve consumer choice , and allow consumers greater choice in what energy is consumed and how it is produced. However in reality, most utilities are also the main producers of the electricity that they distribute. As I will discuss towards the end of the post, this change would be <br />
Electricity production is a natural monopoly -- that is the lowest cost market outcome is one electricity utility serving an entire community. This of course has problems, a monopoly can of course over charge consumers. Monopolies charge based on what the consumer is willing to pay while a firm in a competitive market charges based on the actual cost. Additionally, a monopoly can abuse their power to gain market share of other related markets. This is in effect what most utilities have done with energy production. Because they are the sole distributor of electricity it is easy for them to make themselves the main producer of it. This not only increases costs to consumers, but also reduces their choice. If a consumer wants an energy plan heavy on a given energy source, or billed in a certain way, it may be very difficult to arrange that in the current system. In a more competitive energy market, there would be many energy producers each vying for the dollars of consumers. They would not have to wait for the sluggishness of one utility company for a new method to arrive. There would be an explosion of energy plans and energy sources, and types of billing. Want a energy plan centered on nuclear power, but no fossil fuels? Tough to find under current conditions, but perhaps not so tough under a more competitive arrangement. Want a energy plan billed on a fixed monthly rate -- like how internet is billed? Very few utilities offer such a thing, but it might be more easy to find that type of thing in a more competitive market. More examples of how this would work could be envisioned. <br />
Such a change would also have positive implications for the environment. Remember the issue about net metering of solar production at home? There is a great public benefit to allowing consumers to sell back energy they produce. But the types of net metering that regulators commonly implement have a severe flaw. They enable people to produce energy at low-value, off peak times and use the grid as a free battery. Separating energy production from distribution would solve this dilemma. People with home solar systems would sell their energy production to a energy production company, and a reasonable agreed upon value that takes into account the level of demand for the energy. But the distribution utility would charge a fee for the connection to the grid. This would prevent people from producing low value energy in-order to use the grid as a free battery. But it would reward people who use clean energy production at home to produce valuable energy. There are other clean energy production benefits of such a change. There would be a great opportunity for energy producers to experiment with clean energy sources, and sell this production to consumers who are willing to be early adopters. This is in contrast to utilities which can take many years to adapt to a change. <br />
This change would be easy to implement. Instead of dealing with one power company, consumers would pay two companies. Consumers would pay a utility to hook their house to the grid. This would likely be billed as a flat monthly fee. They would then find a energy production company that has a plan that they like. The billing for this would vary from plan to plan. Despite the increased complexity of this setup, consumers would greatly benefit.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uber Frenzy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/uber-frenzy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/uber-frenzy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2014 13:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>What is the deal with the people who are fawning over "ride sharing" (read: unregulated taxi) services like Uber, and Lyft? I've seen lots of people who think these services will bring forth a transportation utopia and replace the need to own your own car. The companies themselves (and many of their supporters) think they have an uniquely "disruptive" service that . These types of services are pretty much more efficient taxi services. Taxi services where people use their own private cars, and mostly work part time. They bring up the exact same problems and limitations that other taxi services have.</p><p>They are a way to hire a driver to take you some place -- only in this case the hiring is done through a computer, allowing more rapid adjustment of pricing and more ability to select the driver you want to ride with. The companies claim that this minor difference is enough to make them exempt from the same regulations that bind normal taxis. Lyft went far enough to <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2014/07/lyft-defies-new-york-city-taxi-agencys-ban-to-launch-friday/">defy</a> a order from the New York City Taxi and Limousine Commission, and an associated order from the New York State Supreme Court, until the state's attorney general o<a href="http://www.latimes.com/business/technology/la-fi-tn-lyft-nyc-20140711-story.html">btained a second court order</a> that would have subjected individual drivers to legal risk. As Eric Schneiderman, the New York attorney general put it "Lyft decided to move ahead and simply ignore state and local laws." Their legal justification is the absurd claim that they are not taxis, but are instead "ride sharing" firms. Ride sharing companies that have paid drivers on staff, that can drive you to where you want on demand, and that you pay based on the distance taken. Not exactly carpooling.</p><p>People who should know better are in on the Uber worship frenzy. Take Paul Krugman's <a href="http://krugman.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/07/15/life-without-cars/">thoughts on the magic disruptor</a>.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Anyway: the big benefit from new IT-mediated car services will come if they make it possible for lots of people — and not just people in Manhattan — to live without owning their own cars. And if you think about it, you can see how that might work.</p>
</blockquote><p>Taxis, even "IT-mediated" ones need human drivers -- at least until Google releases their car to market. Human drivers are expensive. <a href="https://www.lyft.com/drivers">Lyft claims</a> that their drivers can "MAKE $35/HR DRIVING WITH LYFT". In an advertisement ran on the Bing search engine Uber claims their drivers can "Make Up To $40/hr In Fares". It goes without saying that few can afford this on a regular basis. This is why taxis have not replaced personal cars, not that they aren't sufficiently "IT-mediated". Replacing your car with a taxi or "ride sharing service" just isn't practical.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Right now, if you live in places without exceptionally good public transportation, it’s very difficult to manage without a car. Yet when you think about it, for most people owning a car is quite wasteful. It’s an expensive item of equipment that sits idle most of the time; it requires parking (and often a parking structure) both at origin and at destination; it requires maintenance and is a big hassle all around.</p>
</blockquote><p>Wasteful is hiring a large portion of the population at $35 per hour just to drive others around. All of these benefits can be reached by mass transit construction, at a cost that is actually reasonable to consumers.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/make" class="p-category" rel="tag">#make</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#make</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Stupidity: Don't Write Stuff About Technical Topics When You Have No Idea What You Are Talking About</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/ai-stupidity-dont-write-stuff-about-technical-topics-when-you</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/ai-stupidity-dont-write-stuff-about-technical-topics-when-you</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 09:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>There are some factual errors that are tolerable. There are some other errors that are so wrong that anyone publishes an article with them doesn't know what they are talking about, and thus can be safely ignored as a credible source. One subject where people are very good at making themselves sound like idiots is artificial intelligence. There was the vast media attention given to <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/06/09/software_passes_turing_test/">"Captain Cyborg" Kevin Warwick's chat bot</a>, even though ol professor cyborg is a known crackpot in the AI world.</p><p>However, the press still doesn't realize the difference between a computer program that applies a few simple rules to bodies of text, and genuine intelligence.</p><p><a href="http://jezebel.com/instagram-apologizes-for-deleting-plus-size-womans-acco-1605831194">Today's AI PEBAC comes</a> from an article on a liberal blog about someone who got banned from Instagram for seemingly no good reason. The ID10t error comes from the following paragraph.  </p><blockquote>
<p>And before people start computer-splaining about how these companies use an automated system to deal with reports, you can hold your breath. We already know. That system is fucked up. If companies like Facebook can manage to come up with software that knows to spam you with ads for baby clothes right at the time you "liked" your old roommate's post announcing she was pregnant, they sure as shit should be able to come up with a system that doesn't arbitrarily discriminate on who gets deleted and who stays. But thanks for the IT lesson anyway.</p>
</blockquote><p>Why am I writing flamage about this particular passage? This stupidity didn't just stay put. It spread to other websites. I've seen that particular passage quoted as truth -- with all seriousness -- on Huff Post and other news websites. And this vision that it is somehow easy to create a moderation bot that is as good as a human mod and that doesn't fuck up is stupid. A moderation bot is written by the application of a few simple mathematical rules to text processing. In particular these bots often take into account the words used in the posts. The frequency of the varous words can be compared to the frequency of the words in pasts that have been banned by human users. If the bot determines that the text of a suspect user has similar word frequency to known trolls then the banhammer will drop. These programs also often take into account the ratio of complaints, and downvotes to actual account activity, and number of followers. The impression that it shows any deeper intelligence is simply the ELIZA effect. Humans are good at seeing some type of intelligence where none exists. Such as the author of the linked post who thinks that moderation bots express sexism, and can willingly fat shame and intentionally offend Tumblr users (an easy AI problem). As for the "software that knows to spam you with ads for baby clothes right at the time you 'liked' your old roommate's post announcing she was pregnant", those use the exact same methods that the moderation software does. They are also quite error prone, but you tend not to notice their failures as much. The typical person will ignore an irrelevant ad, but will definitely notice the banhammer.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/eliza" class="p-category" rel="tag">#eliza</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/huffpost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#huffpost</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/it" class="p-category" rel="tag">#it</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#eliza</category>
      <category>#huffpost</category>
      <category>#it</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
