<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all?offset=20</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all?_t=rss&amp;offset=20" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>&#x2018;You are also ordered not to post any further information about the [plaintiff]&#x2019; - The Washington Post</title>
      <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2015/08/24/you-are-also-ordered-not-to-post-any-further-information-about-the-plaintiff/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/you-are-also-ordered-not-to-post-any-further-information</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 04:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Now the story behind this case is considerably higher-profile than the ones I’ve written about before: The post that led to the order is at the heart of the so-called 'Gamergate' controversy, which some readers might be acquainted with. Eron Gjoni was briefly romantically involved with Chelsea Van Valkenburg, a computer game developer who used the pen name Zoe Quinn, and who I am told has recently changed her name legally to Zoe Quinn. (The case was entered into the court system under the name Van Valkerburg rather than Van Valkenburg or Quinn, so the briefs use Van Valkerburg.) After they broke up, Gjoni wrote a series of blog posts about Van Valkenburg, in which he accused her — whether or not accurately — of mistreating him in various ways during his relationship. This post in turn led to various accusations about supposed misdeeds in the video gaming industry, and various threats of violence against Van Valkenburg by people who have apparently taken Gjoni’s side."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citation Games By the United Nations&#x2019; #CyberViolence &#x2014; Medium</title>
      <link>https://medium.com/@KingFrostFive/citation-games-by-the-united-nations-cyberviolence-e8bb1336c8d1</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/citation-games-by-the-united-nations-cyberviolence-medium</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 04:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Two clear instances show near word for word similarities as that paragraph because it’s all originating from the Associated Press. There is no difficulty in finding this and there are a multitude of sources one can use for their material. Yet to do use it and not give credit is when you step into plagiarism. It’s not the only time this happens either. The other major instance forgets to scrub the EFF mentioning themselves in the body."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting The UN Broadband Commission's "Cyberviolence" Report | Popehat</title>
      <link>https://popehat.com/2015/09/28/revisiting-the-un-broadband-commissions-cyberviolence-report</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/revisiting-the-un-broadband-commissions-cyberviolence-report-popehat</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 04:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"The UN and other multinational organizations are increasingly plagued by authoritarian regimes trying to set up ostensibly neutral rules that would allow them to suppress dissent. China, Russia, and Saudi Arabia recently pushed for a UN agency to have more authority over the internet, and in turn cede that control to member states. This would make it much easier for totalitarian regimes to stop online dissent and find dissenters. Also, I did not emphasize clearly enough that the global experience with blasphemy law shows that it is disproportionately used against ethnic and religious minorities in countries with authoritarian governments, and should be seen less as a sincere effort to protect the good name of Mohammed and more as a way to increase state power over those minorities. In short, when it comes to potential speech restrictions, working with the UN carries substantial risk that the rules you propose will be used abusively by the strong against the weak, and by totalitarian governments against dissenters. If you find that improbable, consider what use, say, Saudia Arabia could make of a very flexible international norm against online "harassment," given their brutal enforcement of narrow sexual norms."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title/>
      <link>https://reason.com/blog/2015/08/21/republican-party-white-identity-politics</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/are-republicans-becoming-the-party-of-white-identity-politics--</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 04:38:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>" In Europe, meanwhile, straight, white, Christian men and women have become their own sort of special-interest group, and one whose particular identity politics now form a core tenet of right-populist political movements. Could the same thing happen here? The Federalist's Ben Domenech is worried that it could, with the rise of GOP presidential candidate Donald Trump representing the proverbial canary in the coal mine. "Donald Trump could transform the Republican Party into a coalition focused on white identity politics," reads the subhead on Domenech's article. 'We've seen this in Europe, and it's bad.' "</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Causation and Anti-Science </title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>In previous posts I have mentioned George Lakoff's ideas about how misunderstanding systemic causation contributes to science denialism. He describes <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">his ideas at HuffPo</a> and academically in <a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/17524030903529749">a 2010 paper </a>(as usual, full citation at end of post). Lakoff differentiates between two types of causation; systemic and direct. Direct causation is the type of non-probablistic causation that occurs when you shove a box. The box moves, and it will move pretty much every time you shove it. Systemic causation instead involves shifting the probability distribution of events. Climate change does not make a hurricane of a given strength at a given location an unvoidable occurance, in the same way that pushing the box make its movement unavoidable. However, it does make certan types of hurricanes more likely, and therefore can be said to cause hurricanes. A lot of science involves systemic causation. And the fields of science where the causation involved is the most systemic and probabilistic tend to be the biggest denialism magnets. Think climate change or evolution. Why does the role of systemic causation tend to correlate with tendiencies to deny the science? Lakoff seems to think the cause is political ideology.  In his opinion, conservative/libertarian political beliefs tend to have more difficulties with systemic causation. </p><p>However, I doubt this ideological explanation. It is wrong (and perhaps actively dangerous)  for roughly the reasons that <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1744-540X.2007.00466.x/abstract;jsessionid=EB663E5ADD49D613AFCC5CED88563015.f02t03">Steve Pinker points out</a>. Conservatives use arguements that reily on systemic causation all the time, particulary in regards to economic policy. And it is particulary dangerous to treat ideological framing as a goal of political discourse, instead of an all to common discription of it. Such a goal involves a brain-rotting mixing of normative goals and positive description of how the world works. Read Lakoff's writings on GMOs and nuclear energy to see the mind-rot in action.  </p><p>Instead I propose two other explinations of how systemic causation relates to denialism</p><ol><li>The fact that denialism relies on the asymmetry of difficulty in creating reasonable sounding, but incorrect arguements, and refuting them. </li>
<li>The fact that complex systems create emergent properties that often go aganist the intuitions and herististuics that underlie a lot of human reasoning.</li>
</ol><p>Lets start with point one.</p><p><img src="http://www.theojones.name/file/339c444f4e618040977c19a343fd4d1c" alt="The amount of energy necessary to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude bigger than to produce it width=" height="239"></p><p><em>Image via <a href="https://jasonapril.wordpress.com/2014/06/05/the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/"></a><a href="https://jasonapril.wordpress.com/2014/06/05/the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>jasonapril.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/<wbr></wbr></a></em></p><p> </p><p>The claims that climate change deniers and creationists and their ilk make reily on very subtle misconseptions. The misconceptions are pretty beleiveable to a non-expert, and a full explination of why the misconception is wrong can take a lot of effort. Go to SKS or a similar website that rebuts climate change deniers. Look at the section where they list their rebuttials to these arguements <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php"></a><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a> . Note that the rebuttal is usually at least a few times longer than the claim itself.  But it is only a certan type of science that follows the bullshit asymtery rule. Sciences that involve a lot of systemic causation. Complex systems can behave in some pretty subtle ways. Ways that are not ovious, and that take a lot of effort to understand and predict. Due to the Dunning-Kruger effect, and such, it can take quite a bit of knowledge to even be able tell good arguements from bad ones. Add bias, and the generally poor quality of human reasoning, and it becomes easy to talk from <a href="http://imgur.com/cNFqi">Mt. Stupid</a>. </p><p>But when was the last time you saw a math denialist? Not recently? The reason for that is the fact that math does not follow the bullshit asymmetry rule. Its hard to come up with a reasonable sounding, but wrong mathmatical arguement. And when you do come up with one the reason why it is wrong is usually pretty simple. It has actually  become a bit of a game in the math community to come up with invalid "proofs" that seem pleasing. Usually the "proof" is of a clearly absurd claim, like 1=2. Take the following example from Wikipedia. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero"></a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>en.wikipedia.org/<wbr></wbr>wiki/<wbr></wbr>Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero</a></p><p>Let a and b be be equal non-zero quantities.</p><p>$$a=b$$</p><p>Multiply  both sides of the above equation by a. This results in </p><p>$$a^2 = ab$$</p><p>Subtract </p><p>$$b^2$$</p><p>from both sides, resulting in </p><p>$$a^2 - b^2 = ab - b^2$$</p><p>Factor both sides</p><p>$$(a-b)(a+b) = b(a-b)$$ </p><p>Divide both sides by </p><p>$$(a-b) $$</p><p>Resulting in </p><p>$$a + b = b$$ </p><p>Because we know that a = b</p><p>$$ b + b = b $$ </p><p>$$2b = b$ </p><p>$$2 = 1$$ </p><p>The issue with this is simple, there was an implicit division by zero in the "proof" </p><p> </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialism</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lakoff" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lakoff</a> </p><p>Lakoff, George. "Why it matters how we frame the environment." Environmental Communication 4.1 (2010): 70-81.</p><p>Pinker, Steven, and George Lakoff. "Does language frame politics?." Public Policy Research 14.1 (2007): 59-71.</p><p> </p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Division</category>
      <category>#Division</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#denialism</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#lakoff</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change and the Effectiveness of Geoengineering</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/rate-of-change-and-geoengineering</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/rate-of-change-and-geoengineering</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 23:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Geoengineering refers to proposals to ameliorate global warming by causing a man-made cooling effect. This may have the potential to blunt some of the more destructive effects of climate change. I'm not entirely opposed to the idea, as it might be good for blunting some of the worse effects of climate change. It is probably better than doing nothing, although is a worse option than keeping emissions at their current rate. It serves as a middle ground between actually dealing with the issue by reducing emissions, and doing noting about the problem. What this post is about is why it isn't a good alternative to emissions reduction.</p><p>The ultimate problem with climate change/global warming isn't that the climate is warming, or even that it is switching to a different climate pattern. The problem is the rate of change at which this is happening. Its that the new climate will have new weather patterns, and that our infrastructure, and the locations of human populations are suited for the old ones. It is even possible that the new weather patterns could be at least as "good" as the old ones. But the problem is the disparity between how our infrastructure and society is set up, and what the climate patterns look like.</p><p>Temperature is one of many variables that sets what the climate and the weather patterns of the world look like. It is the one that is currently being modified by greenhouse gas pollution. Geoengineering will have the effect of adjusting the temperature in a way that offsets the effects of greenhouse gasses on temperature. But, it will also have the effect of modifying other key aspects of the global climate. These modifications mean that we will not end up with the same climate that we had before the introduction of greenhouse gas pollution after geoengineering. The net change may be less drastic. But it will not be non zero. Geoengineering offsets the effects of human activity on one climate variable at the expense of poking at others. This means that we will still have a substantial climate change even after geoengineering.</p><p>What could some of that climate change in a post-geoengineering world look like? A 2009 paper by Robock et al looked at some of those issues (see the end of this post for a full citation). </p><p><a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2009GL039209/full">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>onlinelibrary.wiley.com/<wbr></wbr>doi/<wbr></wbr>10.1029/<wbr></wbr>2009GL039209/<wbr></wbr>full</a></p><p>In particular, they looked at one commonly proposed method, stratospheric aerosol injection. They write:</p><blockquote><p>Anthropogenic stratospheric aerosol injection would cool the planet, stop the melting of sea ice and land-based glaciers, slow sea level rise, and increase the terrestrial carbon sink, but produce regional drought, ozone depletion, less sunlight for solar power, and make skies less blue.</p></blockquote><p> </p><p> </p><p><span style="color: #222222; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;">Robock, Alan, et al. "Benefits, risks, and costs of stratospheric geoengineering." </span><em style="color: #222222; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;">Geophysical Research Letters</em><span style="color: #222222; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;"> 36.19 (2009).</span></p><p> </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/geoengineering" class="p-category" rel="tag">#geoengineering</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#geoengineering</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can I manage a lot of scanned documents? - Ask Leo!</title>
      <link>https://askleo.com/how-can-i-manage-a-lot-of-scanned-documents/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-can-i-manage-a-lot-of-scanned-documents--</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 04:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"I’ve talked and written before about how I strive to be as paperless as possible. I get documents electronically whenever possible. Bills, receipts, and much more come to me in the form of bits rather than on sheets of paper. One of the biggest reasons I do this is that I can do something with bits much more easily than I can with paper: I can back them up. With paper, unless you burn more paper with a copy machine, you have exactly and only one copy. With electronic documents, you can have as many copies as you care to create. I think for most of my electronic documents, about half a dozen machines in something like three or four states would all have to implode simultaneously for me to actually lose something – and those include not just my machines but some that are owned by some pretty large companies. So, what do I do when I actually get paper? Needless to say, I scan it, but it’s how I scan and how I manage my documents after that where things get kind of interesting."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#x2018;Some of the best feminists are men&#x2019;</title>
      <link>http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/actress-emma-watson-criticised-for-comments-about-men-and-feminism/story-fnk822dn-1227550109978?pg=1#comments</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-of-the-best-feminists-are-men</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 04:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <p>Q: How do feminists form a firing squad?<br />A: In a circle.</p><p> </p><p><a href="http://www.news.com.au/entertainment/celebrity-life/actress-emma-watson-criticised-for-comments-about-men-and-feminism/story-fnk822dn-1227550109978?pg=1#comments">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.news.com.au/<wbr></wbr>entertainment/<wbr></wbr>celebrity-life/<wbr></wbr>actress-emma-watson-criticised-for-comments-about-men-and-feminism/<wbr></wbr>story-fnk822dn-1227550109978?pg=1#comments</a></p><blockquote><p><br />"ACTRESS Emma Watson has come under fire on social media for saying some of the best feminists are men.<br />In an interview with The Guardian about sexism in the film industry, Watson said women are 'just as guilty of discriminating against women' as men."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
      <category>#comments</category>
      <category>#comments</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark LynasHow land-inefficient is organic agriculture? - Mark Lynas</title>
      <link>http://www.marklynas.org/2012/07/how-land-inefficient-is-organic-agriculture/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/mark-lynashow-land-inefficient-is-organic-agriculture---mark-lynas</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 20:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"So I think my case is made. Organic agriculture is significantly less efficient in land-use terms than conventional. (And the picture could be even worse than -34% in comparative terms, given that indirect land use was not taken into account in the Nature study.) On the other hand, there is no compelling scientific evidence that GM crops are in any way more dangerous than their conventional alternatives, and therefore they do not require labelling."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should I really go paperless?</title>
      <link>http://ask-leo.com/should_i_really_go_paperless.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/should-i-really-go-paperless</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 20:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>" recently heard from someone that they had essentially done the opposite of going paperless. They'd reverted from digital tools and gone back to paper for most of their tasks. Needless to say, I had something to say on the topic. Smile I think that there are some serious advantages to going digital if it's done properly. In fact, I'll give you three very specific reasons why digital is better than paper in many (if not most) situations. The first one is, to me, so compelling that it alone would be enough. (And if you're a regular reader, you'll recognize it immediately.) I'll also discuss some situations where paper really is better."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
