<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/profile/tjones2?offset=160</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/profile/tjones2?_t=rss&amp;offset=160" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title> Natural food luddites spread disease http www...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/natural-food-luddites-spread-disease-http-www</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/natural-food-luddites-spread-disease-http-www</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 21:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>"Natural food" luddites spread disease.<br /><a href="http://www.foodsafetynews.com/2015/05/campylobacter-cases-linked-to-raw-milk-reported-in-young-indiana-children/#.VWtx6E_BzRY">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.foodsafetynews.com/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>campylobacter-cases-linked-to-raw-milk-reported-in-young-indiana-children/<wbr></wbr>#.VWtx6E_BzRY</a><br />"Several Campylobacter Cases Linked to Raw Milk Reported in Indiana"<br />I think it would be a good idea to just ban the commercial sale of raw milk all together and mandate that all milk (and other pasteurizeable foodstuffs) should be pasteurized.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/foodsafety" class="p-category" rel="tag">#foodsafety</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#foodsafety</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamergaters and Protectionists</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergaters-and-protectionists</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergaters-and-protectionists</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 09:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The closest thing to a Gamergater/MRA/Redpiller that I know of is a protectionist/nationalist. Protectionists think immigrants/foreigners will kill their jobs if given the chance to compete in "their" market and that immigrants will wreck their culture. Therefore, they want to close off markets and keep the foreigners out. In effect they believe that there is a constant amount of income available in the economy and any new competitors will automatically mean less for them. Gaters/MRAs imported (ha) these protectionist arguments and aimed them at women. They believe that allowing women in to the tech market will destroy their share of that pie that it will make them unemployed, and that creating new markets for products that women like will destroy the availability of the products that men want. Its why <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> started as an attack on Zoe Quinn – the author of a video game on depression. The gaters took this as a pretty direct threat against the continued existence of the games they like. Its why they are in general opposed to any game that isn't the latest "<em>Call of Murder XIIV: Personal Revenge".</em>  Its why gaters are paranoid about SJWs. They are convinced that the two communities cannot coexist in any way.   To counteract this threat they act like a corrupt union official who harasses migrant workers, in-order to protect his workers. It also means that the arguments against protectionism will work almost unmodified against MRAs. Apply your good old friend comparative advantage, and you can show and allowing women to compete in the market under equal conditions will make both men and women better off. The Gamergater/MRA fallacy that its a zero sum game is just wrong. But it's a werid newish type of sexism.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/zoequinn" class="p-category" rel="tag">#zoequinn</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#zoequinn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Should the Economic Impacts of Climate Change on the Future Be Accounted For?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-the-economic-impacts-of-climate-change-on-the</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-the-economic-impacts-of-climate-change-on-the</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 07:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There is a substantial debate within the climate change policy world about how to do accounting for the future damage caused by the impacts of climate change. A common method used in accounting and finance for a lot of investments is discounting. In short, people have a time preference for money – ie. a dollar today is better than a dollar two years from now. For people to want to put money away towards an investment, the investment would need to pay off in excess of its nominal return. The amount required will increase over time, with this time preference setting the "natural" interest rate. <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg3/en/ch3s3-5-3-3.html">The IPCC discusses a number of estimates at the economic cost of climate change</a> and changes in the use of discounting (or the lack thereof), and the discount rate can change estimates of the social cost of climate change by an order of magnitude. I'm not convinced that traditional discounting is the right way to approach something like climate change. There are paradoxes on both extremes of the discounting issue.  Sure, if you don't discount you get weird paradoxes like a dollar 100 years from now being worth a dollar today. But if you do discount you get the inverse issue, harms to future generations being valued as almost meaningless. My suggested alternative to discounting would have three rules. The first would be to minimize relative proportional generational sacrifice. Ie. a loss of 1% of GDP this year would be worth it to avoid a 1.1% reduction in 2050 GDP, or to avoid concurrent 0.6% losses for two years in a row. But it wouldn't be worth it to avoid a 0.9% reduction in 2050 GDP, even if 0.9% of 2050 GDP is 1 trillion dollars and 1% of GDP this year is 100 billion. To avoid issues that occur when you apply flat rules to the far future, I would limit this to overlapping generations. An event 500 years from today wouldn't count for policy today, because it is extremely unlikely that there will be a person alive today who will have a lifespan that overlaps with someone who will be alive 500 years now. My third rule would be to adjust for marginal utility – the fact that money in the pockets of lower income people and countries is meeting more urgent needs than money in the pockets of the wealthy. Therefore, both climate change impacts and mitigation efforts that disproportionately hurt the poor should be disfavored.</p>

<p>To see how a discount rate can result in future risks/benefits being valued as almost nothing, take this thought experiment. Let's say, you are given 100 (inflation adjusted) dollars every year for the next 50 years. How much are these future dollars worth in present value under a 2% discount (a fairly small one), and a 15% discount (a common rate used in development economics).</p>

<p><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/053115_0759_HowShouldth1.png" alt=""></p>

<p>It seems to me that it is extremely ethically problematic to assume that a cost 50 years in the future is about 1/3 as important as one today. Such an assumption clearly reduces the rationale to take action on climate change.  While time preference may have a strong role to play for individual decision making, it has problems for government policy making. Governments should follow the interests of all subject to the impacts of their authority. Future generations are as much subject to the authority of a government as currently living people. Governments should weight everyone's interests equally. This means that discounting on the scale of government policy has extreme issues and that a small discount, if any should be used. That is the solution to the problem of a dollar today being worth a dollar 100 years from now. It is, on the scale of government policy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On reducing blogging engine bloat.</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-reducing-blogging-engine-bloat</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-reducing-blogging-engine-bloat</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2015 07:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I've switched between blogging engines a few times for this site (there are still some broken links and images from the transition). WordPress, what I'm on now, has a good bit of bloat. Simpler blogging engines, like Ghost, go too far in the other direction, and lack critical features.  I haven't been able to find a blogging engine that hits a good in-between. Personally, I feel that the way to hit that in-between in modularity.  The old UNIX Philosophy of "do one thing and do it well". Plugins are how modularity should be reached. Create a simple core blogging engine (the functionality level of Ghost would be a good target) and add the rest as optional plugins. Now, you might note that WordPress plugins often add a lot of bugs, have a lot of security holes, and are often written by people who don't know what they are doing. And you would be right. However, there is no reason why such plugins can't be maintained in the same source tree as the core software with the help of actual developers. Just put any frequently used plugin in the tree as an officially supported feature set. A user can also easily swap out the official implementation of a feature with an alternative.   This would provide the perfect mix of flexibility and simplicity.  It would allow more officially supported features but users who don't want a feature don't have to put up with the BS that comes with it.  This is a rough analogue of the development method of the classical UNIXes and the BSDs.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/blogging" class="p-category" rel="tag">#blogging</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ghost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ghost</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unix" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unix</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unixphilosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unixphilosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/wordpress" class="p-category" rel="tag">#wordpress</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#blogging</category>
      <category>#ghost</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unix</category>
      <category>#unixphilosophy</category>
      <category>#wordpress</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Law enforcement needs to take internet harassment as...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/law-enforcement-needs-to-take-internet-harassment-as</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/law-enforcement-needs-to-take-internet-harassment-as</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 14:44:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Law enforcement needs to take internet harassment as a serious crime, instead of a minor annoyance. They should actually put resources into busting the people who send death threats, and who phone in SWATings. I would rather see 10 of them get one year than one of them get 10. Because I have a feeling that the threat of getting busted will have little impact until it happens to them. And I would also bet that its an impressively small number of people responsible for most net harassment. When you read a story about a SWATer getting arrested, he did it a lot of times.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/internetharassment" class="p-category" rel="tag">#internetharassment</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#internetharassment</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here is a list of all the projects...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/here-is-a-list-of-all-the-projects</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/here-is-a-list-of-all-the-projects</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 14:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Here is a list of all the projects Sourceforge took over. <br /><a href="http://sourceforge.net/u/sf-editor1/profile/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>sourceforge.net/<wbr></wbr>u/<wbr></wbr>sf-editor1/<wbr></wbr>profile/<wbr></wbr></a><br />Look at all the "abandoned" software that they owned. Like WordPress, Audacity, Open Office, Apache HTTP Server and Eclipse.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/openoffice" class="p-category" rel="tag">#openoffice</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sourceforge" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sourceforge</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#openoffice</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#sourceforge</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As an anti poverty measure the minimum wage...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/as-an-anti-poverty-measure-the-minimum-wage</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/as-an-anti-poverty-measure-the-minimum-wage</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 14:09:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>As an anti-poverty measure the minimum wage is a pretty inefficient instrument. It has a lot of economic side effects, and at high rates serves to reduce bargaining power on non-wage elements of employment due. That last fact might explain why unions are U-turning on the issue --- at least as regards to their workers.<br /><a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2015/05/27/los_angeles_15_minimum_wage_labor_unions_want_to_be_exempt_from_it.html?utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+Trending+Content&utm_content=5566813204d3014d00000001&utm_medium=trueAnthem&utm_source=twitter">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.slate.com/<wbr></wbr>blogs/<wbr></wbr>moneybox/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>27/<wbr></wbr>los_angeles_15_minimum_wage_labor_unions_want_to_be_exempt_from_it.html?utm_campaign=trueAnthem:+Trending+Content&utm_content=5566813204d3014d00000001&utm_medium=trueAnthem&utm_source=twitter</a><br />And Warren Buffet was right to suggest an increase in the earned income tax credit as an alternative  --- although I would favor a straight basic income (the ENTC is effectively a partial basic income with a work requirement)<br /><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/better-than-raising-the-minimum-wage-1432249927?mod=trending_now_1">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.wsj.com/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>better-than-raising-the-minimum-wage-1432249927?mod=trending_now_1</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/poverty" class="p-category" rel="tag">#poverty</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#poverty</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The #Gamergate mascot comes from the 4chan ...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gamergate-mascot-comes-from-the-4chan-</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gamergate-mascot-comes-from-the-4chan-</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 06:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> mascot comes from the 4chan "picclo dick" rape joke.<br /><a href="https://www.fastcodesign.com/3037941/the-secret-meaning-behind-gamergates-branding#3">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.fastcodesign.com/<wbr></wbr>3037941/<wbr></wbr>the-secret-meaning-behind-gamergates-branding#3</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The meme is based around an animated GIF called “Piccolo Dick,” which shows the Dragon Ball anime character Piccolo sodomizing Vegeta, another character from the series. Banned by many internet forums, posters began to abstract the image to the point that the colors alone were easily associated with the meme.....The image first appeared on 4chan in the 2000s and was frequently reposted by forum trolls, who spoke of giving a "daily dose" of the graphic to forum members, who’d then reply with the catchphrase "Thanks, doc," according to the meme encyclopedia Know Your Meme. Soon, the image was banned, and users began to post other purple-and-green images understood to be a reference to the forbidden GIF...... in the initial forum discussion that led to the Vivian James design, a draft of the Vivian character with her distinctive color palette got plenty of "thanks, doc" replies, as did an anonymous illustrator who a few days later posted a first draft of the now standard GamerGate logo, showing a stylized video game controller with purple and green G’s.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#3</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A beef of mine in the world of...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/a-beef-of-mine-in-the-world-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/a-beef-of-mine-in-the-world-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 01:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A beef of mine in the world of politics is the rise of ideologies that are just apriori hairballs. They try to get high level claims from logical deduction with little input from outside facts or data. Examples would be the "praxology" or Austrian school libertarians (and other related ideologies like that of Ayn Rand), many religions, and the type of third wave feminism seen on Tumblr.  But this type of deductive analysis never works for something as complex as human society. You get conflicts with the factual world quite a bit, and many conflicts with science (see libertarian climate change deniers, or "postmodernism/poststructuralism" in the feminist world). Ideally, a political philosophy should instead bridge the is-ought gap with the fewest assumptions possible and from then on rely to the fullest extent possible on scientifically knowable results about the economy and society.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/femminism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#femminism</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/libertarians" class="p-category" rel="tag">#libertarians</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politicalphilosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politicalphilosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/religion" class="p-category" rel="tag">#religion</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#femminism</category>
      <category>#libertarians</category>
      <category>#politicalphilosophy</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#religion</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here's a heads up. Sourceforge is now loading the opensource projects they host with malware</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/heres-a-heads-up-sourceforge-is-now-loading-the-opensource</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/heres-a-heads-up-sourceforge-is-now-loading-the-opensource</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 22:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Here's a heads up. Sourceforge is now loading the opensource projects they host with malware. DON'T download from there. They weren't hacked. They have been crapware pushing for a long time. Previously, they waited for developer permission, but now they are being more aggressive and hitting projects without permission. They claim that the projects affected, such as GIMP, were "abandoned" <a href="http://sourceforge.net/blog/gimp-win-project-wasnt-hijacked-just-abandoned/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>sourceforge.net/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>gimp-win-project-wasnt-hijacked-just-abandoned/<wbr></wbr></a>  ; an excuse that is dubious at best.  Even if it were "abandoned" that's not an excuse to junk up  their binaries. And look at the junk they are bundling. Malware companies don't even try to come up with names that look legit. "Funnel Delivery", really? Sounds like something involved in Foie Gras production. A lot of older projects still use them, even though there are now better options around legacy projects started off using them as their main form of hosting. Its hard to switch something that big. (although Sourceforge has become scummy enough to make it worth it)<br /><a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2015/05/sourceforge-grabs-gimp-for-windows-account-wraps-installer-in-bundle-pushing-adware/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>information-technology/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>sourceforge-grabs-gimp-for-windows-account-wraps-installer-in-bundle-pushing-adware/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/informationtechnology" class="p-category" rel="tag">#informationtechnology</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/malware" class="p-category" rel="tag">#malware</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sourceforge" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sourceforge</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/windows" class="p-category" rel="tag">#windows</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#informationtechnology</category>
      <category>#malware</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#sourceforge</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#windows</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
