<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>An advertisement-driven business model is inherently toxic for web media companies</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-advertisement-driven-business-model-is-inherently-toxic-for-web-media</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-advertisement-driven-business-model-is-inherently-toxic-for-web-media?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>An advertisement-driven business model is inherently toxic for web media companies</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-advertisement-driven-business-model-is-inherently-toxic-for-web-media</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-advertisement-driven-business-model-is-inherently-toxic-for-web-media</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 01:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I'm of the opinion that an advertisement-driven business model is inherently toxic for web media companies. I've seen a number of websites go downhill after they moved away from subscriptions and towards ads. <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/OutOfTheLoop/comments/3bxduw/why_was_riama_along_with_a_number_of_other_large/">Reddit's issues</a> come out of an attempt to monetize the site. Ads make the users the product, cause the company to prefer over-all traffic over quality of content, and force the company to target the types of users that are the most subject to monetization (even if it means driving away other users, as a non-monetized user is worthless to you).  They drive the kind of clickbait trash that infests the likes of Buzzfeed, Outbrain, and Tabula. This is the type of stuff that is mocked by <em>The Onion's</em> <a href="http://www.clickhole.com/about">Clickhole</a> spinoff.</p>

<p>I say "web media companies" for a reason. The limitations of the print medium make a mostly-ad business model very difficult to pull off. Printing costs a lot more than web hosting. The print medium also makes the equivalent to clickbait much harder to pull off. There is no print equivalent to Outbrain that can teleport you an additional issue of the <em>Clickbait Daily</em> at will.  Users must to some degree seek out the publication and value its reputation.</p>

<p>Traffic seeking is a problem driven by advertising. Ads pay in proportion to traffic, not quality of content. They demand users, and users that click. In an ad driven world, writing becomes a world of obtaining clicks and reselling them. The obtaining clicks is often conducted through social media, and places like Outbrain, as google has cracked down on blatant clickbait and trash content through efforts such as the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Penguin">Penguin </a>and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Panda">Panda</a> adjustments to their ranking method, and <a href="http://www.fastcolabs.com/3015422/why-is-google-highligting-long-form-articles">through favoring longer articles</a> over shorter ones.</p>

<p>The alternatives to ads are a subscription model, the shareware/soft paywall model,  a product selling model, or the Wikipedia . In a subscription model the website charges its users. The traditional way to do this is through a paywall. Users get a few free articles, and then get cut off until they subscribe.  An even better alternative would be a shareware model. This is anaglious to the "shareware" software of old, which contained a nag screen for payment. Replace ads with a nag for subscription. This is what I think could work for a lot of sites. Some sites may also be able to sell secondary products, like books, and the like. However, I think this has some difficulties for most sites, particularly as the market for products of that kind tends to be limited. And then there is the Wikipedia model, of volunteer labor for content production. The limitations of such a method are obvious. But it works for even some very large websites.</p>

<p>The above said, I am not saying that ads have no place in the world of the web. They can be a good secondary source of revenue.  But, I am saying that reputable publications should not use them as their primary form of website monetization. An ad-driven revenue stream produces toxic incentives for website owners.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
