<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Criticism Versus Aggression</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/criticism-versus-aggression</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/criticism-versus-aggression?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Criticism Versus Aggression</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/criticism-versus-aggression</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/criticism-versus-aggression</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 04:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><font style="line-height:150%" size="1"><strong><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_1.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-2506" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_1.jpg" alt="7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_1" width="289" height="390"></a>!!!!!!Trigger Warning!!!!!!</strong><br />This post may contain discussion of at least one of the following<br /><br />Swearing, Rape, Abuse (physical, mental, emotional, verbal, sexual),Child abuse/pedophilia ,Self-injurious behavior (self-harm, eating disorders, etc.) ,Talk of drug use (legal, illegal or psychiatric)<br />,Suicide ,Descriptions/pictures of medical procedures (even if they don’t contain blood or gore),Descriptions/pictures of violence or warfare (including instruments of violence, such as knives or guns)<br />,Corpses, skulls or skeletons ,Needles ,Discussions of -isms, shaming, or hatred of any kind (racism, classism, hatred of cultures/ethnicities that differ from your own, sexism, hatred of sexualities or genders that differ from your own, anti-multiple, non-vanilla shaming, sex positive shaming, fat shaming/body image shaming, neuroatypical shaming) ,Any time slurs are used (this includes words like “stupid” or “dumb”, which are still widely considered to be socially acceptable) ,Trans* degendering, or anti-trans* views of bodies ,Dismissal of lived oppressions, marginalization, illness or differences ,Kidnapping (forceful deprivation of/disregard for personal autonomy) ,Discussions of sex (even consensual)<br />,Death or dying ,Spiders ,Insects ,Snakes ,Vomit ,Pregnancy/childbirth ,Blood ,Serious injury<br />,Trypophobia ,Scarification ,Nazi paraphernalia ,Slimy things ,Anything that might inspire intrusive thoughts in people with OCD<br /><br />!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!</font>The above comes from an actual list of possibly "triggering" types of material via <a href="http://privilege101.tumblr.com/triggers.html" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>privilege101.tumblr.com/<wbr></wbr>triggers.html</a></p>

<p>There has been a substantial tendency on the in recent political movements (particularly from the left) to redefine criticism as coercion  and coercion as criticism.</p>

<p>The redefining of criticism as coercion comes from the recent tendency to paint disagreeable speech as the direct equivalent of a personal confrontation, or a personal intrusion.  This ideological viewpoint holds that literature that takes place in a world of inequality and oppression contributes to furthering it. This is the main fuel behind the "trigger warning" movement and the "safe place" movement.</p>

<p>The concept of "trigger warnings" paints speech as a direct threat to psychological well being. Under the trigger warning point of view attempts to hide disagreeable or discomforting material found in college courses behind a warning, often with the additional demand that students be allowed to opt out of possibly "triggering" material. The related "safe place" movement attempts to treat the possibility of exposure to new ideas, or worse yet ideas that directly contradict one's preconceptions, as a direct threat to personal safety.</p>

<p>The alternative to such a threat, of course, is to create "safe places" where no one will face any challenge to their beliefs. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/17/opinion/the-new-college-campus.html?_r=0">An article in the New York Times discusses the furor </a>that arose when a debate at Brown University between a feminist and a libertarian occurred. Feminist activists were horrified at such a possibility. In the words of one senior at the school "Bringing in a speaker like that could serve to invalidate people’s experiences.” Activists rushed to create a safe place where those "damaged" by the possibility of hearing viewpoints other than their own could repair. This safe place "was equipped with cookies, coloring books, bubbles, Play-Doh, calming music, pillows, blankets and a video of frolicking puppies, as well as students and staff members trained to deal with trauma."</p>

<p><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/the-trigger-happy-generation-1432245600">The range of "triggering" material includes </a>quite a few classics,<a href="http://columbiaspectator.com/opinion/2015/04/30/our-identities-matter-core-classrooms"> one editorial written by students at Colombia singled out Ovid’s epic poem “Metamorphoses</a>" as particularly harmful "like so many texts in the Western canon it contains triggering and offensive material that marginalizes student identities in the classroom."  The authors furthermore went on to note that such works contain “histories and narratives of exclusion and oppression... difficult to read and discuss as a [rape] survivor, a person of color, or a student from a low-income background” and worse of all a student faced with such triggering material "completely disengaged from the class discussion as a means of self-preservation. She did not feel safe in the class.”</p>

<p>As a university student who probably qualifies as a low-income peasant in the eyes of the typical student at Ivy League universities like Colombia , I can solidly state that avoiding Roman literature is not a matter of self-preservation. Nor is it a matter of feeling safe. In fact, this type of rhetoric is exactly the issue with the "trigger warning" movement . They have confused being comfortable with feeling safe. And at some point exposure to new concepts will make one feel uncomfortable. But its a dubious type of safety that is gained by putting your head in the sand in order to avoid new ideas. Speech is not coercion, nor is it a threat to safety.</p>

<p>(I have a feeling that for many Ivy League students, the line defining low income versus regular income looks something like this <a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/photos/455847-rich-kids-of-instagram" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>knowyourmeme.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>455847-rich-kids-of-instagram</a>)</p>

<p>In fact, exposure to new ideas is at the core of democratic discourse. The only mode of decision making compatible with democracy on a large scale is rational deliberation. And rational deliberation takes exposure to different proposals and ideas. Some of them may be controversial. Some of them may even be "triggering". And this exposure requires a strong degree of freedom of speech and discussion over policy. The Ancient Athenians considered isogoria -- freedom of speech and the right to contribute to political discourse, to be one of two defining features of democracy (the other being political equality or isonomia)</p>

<p>When pressed, advocates will attempt to defend the world of  in terms of the well being of sufferers of  mental illnesses like PTSD. But this claim becomes absurd when you evaluate the actions of the advocates of such policies and the reality of mental health care. With a physical illness you CAN assume that fulfilling any reasonable request made by the patient would help him. You just can't assume that with a mental illness. In fact its well known in the relevant scientific literature that avoidance is commonly requested by PTSD patients, but actively HARMFUL. It makes the illness worse. Avoidance is so common in PTSD that its considered one of the classic symptoms of the illness (see for instance, <a href="http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/ccp/66/3/586/" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>psycnet.apa.org/<wbr></wbr>journals/<wbr></wbr>ccp/<wbr></wbr>66/<wbr></wbr>3/<wbr></wbr>586/<wbr></wbr></a>). In fact, the opposite of avoidance is helpful. A common therapy for PTSD involves gradual intentional exposure to triggers. By facilitating avoidance behavior you are being the opposite of compassionate (remember the rule of medicine: "first do no harm"). I seriously couldn't find a single peer-reviewed paper from a relevant field (psychology,medicine, neuroscience, biology, etc) that advocated the types of trigger warnings you see on college campuses and on internet blogs. About the only papers advocating it I could find were from humanities and women's studies and such and were by authors that had no relevant expertise. Here are few other relevant papers on the topic<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0005796700000887" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>S0005796700000887</a><br />"A prospective investigation of the role of cognitive factors in persistent Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) after physical or sexual assault"<br />This paper's abstract notes "avoidance/safety seeking" as a maladaptive control strategy .<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0005796700000930" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>S0005796700000930</a><br />"Cognitive-behavior therapy vs exposure therapy in the treatment of PTSD in refugees"<br />This study finds that exposure therapy is similar in effectiveness to regular talk therapy.<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0005796796000198" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>0005796796000198</a><br />"Early avoidance of traumatic stimuli predicts chronicity of intrusive thoughts following burn injury"<br />Pretty much what this paper says is that avoidance tendencies strongly correlate with more severe PTSD symptoms, and the impact of avoidance can last for months.</p>

<p>This brings us to the second prong of this post. Just as many on the hard left have been effective in defining speech as harmful aggression (or "micro-aggression") they have also been effective in defining actual coercion as speech. In many subsets of the feminist/social justice community doxxing and similar behaviors have become common. Attempts to get people expressing disfavored opinions fired, or removed from unrelated positions have become quite common (with the Brendan Eich incident being a prominent example of this). Activists have attempted to get platforms with strong market concentration (like Twitter and Facebook) to shut down speech they don't like.</p>

<p>Even worse, they have tried to brand harassing/ trying to shut down speech they don't like as a legitimate for of criticism. "Freedom of speech is not freedom from consequences " is a common refrain among this type. These people view the government as the only authority that can censor in any meaningful way. Freedom of speech in this point of view is merely a constraint on government power -- like separation of powers -- and not an individual right in its own end.  And its an absurd claim, one that would be rejected in almost any other area of policy by the same people. Ability to censor comes from power. And many private actors have plenty of power.  Consequences imposed can certainly affect one's freedom of speech. The worst part of this is they have been able to massively change public opinion  on the nature of freedom of speech.</p>

<p>However, the two tendencies; branding speech as coercion and coercion as speech are strongly connected. Once you view hearing speech you don't like as a form of personal assault, it follows that speech is a source of power. And like all forms of coercion it is one that can be used badly. In this point of view speech much be directed so that it serves the public interest. Its an illiberal, authoritarian, anti-democratic, and very dangerous point of view. Its ultimately a pre-modern point of view that rejects rationality, and harkens back to the ancient tendency to treat insults as threats to honor that deserve a violent response. But it has gained a lot of traction and needs to be resisted.</p>

<p>Image via: <a href="http://blog.simplejustice.us/2014/12/17/the-environmental-cleanup-of-toxic-academia/" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>blog.simplejustice.us/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>17/<wbr></wbr>the-environmental-cleanup-of-toxic-academia/<wbr></wbr></a></p>

<p>Facebook thread (and attached email image) created by a student who wanted out of her finals because she was "traumatized" and triggered by the events in Ferguson. That thread explains a lot of the problem here. That student seems to live in a social media bubble of people who not only truly believe that that student's request was reasonable, but also think that the professor was unreasonable by rejecting it. And even worse, the people who should be the reasonable adults in the room are doing noting about it. The article notes cases where professors have dropped material due to this nonsense, and the "traumatized" student's mother is apparently "proud" of her.</p>

<p>More of it is as follows (click to enlarge)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Facebook.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-2510 alignleft" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Facebook-300x179.jpg" alt="Facebook" width="300" height="179"></a></p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_2.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-2511 alignleft" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_2-208x300.jpg" alt="7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_2" width="208" height="300"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
