<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>How Should a Basic Income Handle Immigration?</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-a-basic-income-handle-immigration</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-a-basic-income-handle-immigration?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>How Should a Basic Income Handle Immigration?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-a-basic-income-handle-immigration</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-a-basic-income-handle-immigration</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 18:23:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I am a fan of eliminating poverty through a basic income -- give everyone a set amount of money as an income floor. This has strong efficiency benefits over traditional welfare. However, immigration poses a problem for the design of such a program. You don't want to create the type of condition that exists in Qatar where there is a strong welfare state for citizens  but an extremely marginalized migrant population. You also don't want to attract people migrating for the explicit purpose of collecting the payments.  Nor is it a good idea to restrict immigration. There is also the issue of citizens who go abroad for an extended period of time. The solution is to phase in the payments based on time spent in residence, and to gradually reduce payments when the individual is living abroad. A phase in of five years is reasonable. But it should be a phase-in, not an abrupt start/stop because you want to help people as much as possible without creating perverse incentives. For the phase in I would suggest the following ratios over time</p>
<ul><li>First year immigrants should receive no payment</li>
    <li>Second year immigrants should get 1/4 of the full payment , third year immigrants should get 1/2, fourth year immigrants should get 3/4 of the full payment, and fifth year immigrants should get the full payment</li>
</ul>
<p>People who move abroad should face the inverse pattern. They should face no impact for year one, but from then on should lose 1/4th of the full payment, until year five when they receive nothing. Upon returning, they should receive a 1/4th per year phase in to restore the payments.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
