<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>How Should the Economic Impacts of Climate Change on the Future Be Accounted For?</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-the-economic-impacts-of-climate-change-on-the</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-the-economic-impacts-of-climate-change-on-the?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>How Should the Economic Impacts of Climate Change on the Future Be Accounted For?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-the-economic-impacts-of-climate-change-on-the</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-should-the-economic-impacts-of-climate-change-on-the</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 07:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There is a substantial debate within the climate change policy world about how to do accounting for the future damage caused by the impacts of climate change. A common method used in accounting and finance for a lot of investments is discounting. In short, people have a time preference for money – ie. a dollar today is better than a dollar two years from now. For people to want to put money away towards an investment, the investment would need to pay off in excess of its nominal return. The amount required will increase over time, with this time preference setting the "natural" interest rate. <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg3/en/ch3s3-5-3-3.html">The IPCC discusses a number of estimates at the economic cost of climate change</a> and changes in the use of discounting (or the lack thereof), and the discount rate can change estimates of the social cost of climate change by an order of magnitude. I'm not convinced that traditional discounting is the right way to approach something like climate change. There are paradoxes on both extremes of the discounting issue.  Sure, if you don't discount you get weird paradoxes like a dollar 100 years from now being worth a dollar today. But if you do discount you get the inverse issue, harms to future generations being valued as almost meaningless. My suggested alternative to discounting would have three rules. The first would be to minimize relative proportional generational sacrifice. Ie. a loss of 1% of GDP this year would be worth it to avoid a 1.1% reduction in 2050 GDP, or to avoid concurrent 0.6% losses for two years in a row. But it wouldn't be worth it to avoid a 0.9% reduction in 2050 GDP, even if 0.9% of 2050 GDP is 1 trillion dollars and 1% of GDP this year is 100 billion. To avoid issues that occur when you apply flat rules to the far future, I would limit this to overlapping generations. An event 500 years from today wouldn't count for policy today, because it is extremely unlikely that there will be a person alive today who will have a lifespan that overlaps with someone who will be alive 500 years now. My third rule would be to adjust for marginal utility – the fact that money in the pockets of lower income people and countries is meeting more urgent needs than money in the pockets of the wealthy. Therefore, both climate change impacts and mitigation efforts that disproportionately hurt the poor should be disfavored.</p>

<p>To see how a discount rate can result in future risks/benefits being valued as almost nothing, take this thought experiment. Let's say, you are given 100 (inflation adjusted) dollars every year for the next 50 years. How much are these future dollars worth in present value under a 2% discount (a fairly small one), and a 15% discount (a common rate used in development economics).</p>

<p><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/053115_0759_HowShouldth1.png" alt=""></p>

<p>It seems to me that it is extremely ethically problematic to assume that a cost 50 years in the future is about 1/3 as important as one today. Such an assumption clearly reduces the rationale to take action on climate change.  While time preference may have a strong role to play for individual decision making, it has problems for government policy making. Governments should follow the interests of all subject to the impacts of their authority. Future generations are as much subject to the authority of a government as currently living people. Governments should weight everyone's interests equally. This means that discounting on the scale of government policy has extreme issues and that a small discount, if any should be used. That is the solution to the problem of a dollar today being worth a dollar 100 years from now. It is, on the scale of government policy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
