<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Indiana is considering a RFRA clone</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Indiana is considering a RFRA clone</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/indiana-is-considering-a-rfra-clone</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 06:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Indiana legislature is considering a law that is very similar to the federal Religious Freedom Restoration Act.  The bill provides that religious belief exempts one from regulations, even neutral ones, unless the government produces a compelling need. Neither the Indiana bill nor its federal twin are particular to any type of regulation and include everything from anti-discrimination laws to drug possession laws (the original inspiration for the federal RFRA). I don't think either law is a good idea. The idea of religious exemptions from neutral laws is almost always a bad idea. This is a good issue to actually read the bill on, and to read (or at least Wikipedia) some of the relevant court opinions. <a href="https://iga.in.gov/static-documents/9/2/b/a/92bab197/SB0101.05.ENRS.pdf">The bill is only four generously spaced pages long</a>.  The media coverage on this subject is pretty error ridden and contains a lot of misconceptions about what the bill actually says. The religious should not be exempted from neutral laws on the basis of religious belief and I oppose it. But, a lot of people fundamentally misunderstand what the bill actually says. A number of media outlets have claimed that it's an anti-gay bill (even though it does not directly touch on that subject, <a href="http://www.indystar.com/story/opinion/readers/2015/03/07/indiana-needs-religious-freedom-legislation/24477303/">and it likely will not affect anti-discrimination law in any meaningful way</a>). The point of this post will be to clarify a bit of the legal background, and to summarize the bill.  The Supreme Court has made it pretty clear that that the First Amendment does not allow people to ignore neutral laws on the basis of religious belief (with a handful of exceptions. See, for example, <em>Employment Division v. Smith</em>. The goal of RFRAs is to override that ruling (the federal RFRA was actually spawned by that ruling) and make actions conducted as a product of religious belief protected. Now, I strongly believe that SCOTUS got it right in Smith, and that RFRAs are fundamentally a bad idea, but the final decision belongs with the legislative branch.  Lets look at what the 11-section Indiana bill (which is likely to pass) actually says as I go through a brief summary</p>
<ul><li>Section 1: Says that the bill applies to all government laws and regulations, even ones made prior to the enactment of it. 
</li><li>Section 2: Only regulations particularly exempted by law are exempt.
</li><li>Section 3: Definitions. Says that regulators are not allowed to use unconstutional provisions to work around the bill with particular mention of the establishment clause of the first amendment. 
</li><li>Section 4: More definitions. Pretty obvious and straightforward stuff. 
</li><li>Section 5. Defines "exercise of religion" as "any exercise of religion, whether or not compelled by, or central to, a system of religious belief". 
</li><li>Section 6: Defines "government entity". 
</li><li>Section 7: Defines "Person", includes corporations, but so does the federal RFRA.
</li><li>Section 8: States that a governmental entity may not substantially burden a person's exercise of religion unless it meets strict scrutiny
</li><li>Section 9: People can sue over violations of the law. 
</li><li>Section 10: Government agencies can be ordered to pay damages to those affected. 
</li><li>Section 11: The bill does not limit the actions of private actors, only government actions, laws and regulations.
</li></ul>
<p>Section 8 is the core of the bill and most of the definition sections are mostly boilerplate. This legislation is likely not just a useless repetition of current law. It goes far beyond what the Constitution mandates and even with the federal RFRA, a state RFRA has some effect. In <em>City of Boerne v. Flores</em> the Supreme Court struck down the part of the federal RFRA that applies to the states. But panicking over a state RFRA is a bit too much because we have a decade's worth of litigation over its federal version and good caselaw on what it means.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/firstamendment" class="p-category" rel="tag">#firstamendment</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rfra" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rfra</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scotus" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scotus</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/supremecourt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#supremecourt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#firstamendment</category>
      <category>#rfra</category>
      <category>#scotus</category>
      <category>#supremecourt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
