<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Look at this Reddit post which seems to...</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/look-at-this-reddit-post-which-seems-to</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/look-at-this-reddit-post-which-seems-to?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Look at this Reddit post which seems to...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/look-at-this-reddit-post-which-seems-to</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/look-at-this-reddit-post-which-seems-to</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 04:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Look at this Reddit post, which seems to be from former Reddit CEO Yishan Wong.I get the real feeling that Reddit is falling apart at the seams, and I'm not sure it will be able to recover.<br /><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/3dautm/content_policy_update_ama_thursday_july_16th_1pm/ct3n7hc" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.reddit.com/<wbr></wbr>r/<wbr></wbr>announcements/<wbr></wbr>comments/<wbr></wbr>3dautm/<wbr></wbr>content_policy_update_ama_thursday_july_16th_1pm/<wbr></wbr>ct3n7hc</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Ellen was more or less inclined to continue upholding my free-speech policies. /r/fatpeoplehate was banned for inciting off-site harassment, not discussing fat-shaming. What all the white-power racist-sexist neckbeards don't understand is that with her at the head of the company, the company would be immune to accusations of promoting sexism and racism: she is literally Silicon Valley's #1 Feminist Hero, so any "SJWs" would have a hard time attacking the company for intentionally creating a bastion (heh) of sexist/racist content. She probably would have tolerated your existence so long as you didn't cause any problems - I know that her long-term strategies were to find ways to surface and publicize reddit's good parts - allowing the bad parts to exist but keeping them out of the spotlight. It would have been very principled - the CEO of reddit, who once sued her previous employer for sexual discrimination, upholds free speech and tolerates the ugly side of humanity because it is so important to maintaining a platform for open discourse. It would have been unassailable.<br />Well, now she's gone (you did it reddit!), and /u/spez has the moral authority as a co-founder to move ahead with the purge. We tried to let you govern yourselves and you failed, so now The Man is going to set some Rules. Admittedly, I can't say I'm terribly upset.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#1</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
