<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>On Chipotle Price Increases</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-chipotle-price-increases</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-chipotle-price-increases?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>On Chipotle Price Increases</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-chipotle-price-increases</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-chipotle-price-increases</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 03:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The following article price increases in San Francisco by food chain Chipotle has gone viral, Huffington Post linked to it, and I've seen it on Facebook and quite a few other social media sources I use.<br /><a href="http://www.takepart.com/article/2015/07/12/chipotle-minimum-wage?cmpid=tp-ptnr-huffpost" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.takepart.com/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>chipotle-minimum-wage?cmpid=tp-ptnr-huffpost</a><br />In this post I'll do an analysis of where this article goes wrong. Let's first jump to the fairly idiotic section towards the middle of the article.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But before conservative economists use the beloved chain—which has ditched GMOs and is working toward preservative-free tortillas—</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There are two quite stupid things with this line. The first is that the article offers seems to think that GMOs and preservatives are somehow relevant to the discussion of minimum wages. But even more seriously, is the fairly inane idea that appears all throughout this article that an increase in the minimum wage will have no effect on prices. Since labor costs are quite a substantial factor in overall business costs, increase in those costs have a fairly direct impact on prices. As far as I know, this is not reasonably disputed by any economist conservative or liberal. Pretty much the entire academic debate on minimum wage policy involves auxiliary effects of minimum wages such as effects on the overall employment level. You will see in the next quote that the article authors' understanding of what those effects on the price level might be definitely confused at best. And at the worst totally nonsensical.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So, Why Should You Care? One of the common arguments against raising the minimum wage is tied to price increases for consumers. If this cyclical effect were to take place in every industry, the result would be pure inflation. That has critics asking, what good is making a dollar more for minimum wage workers if every purchase also costs a dollar more?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This at once is  a severe understanding of what pretty much a reasonable economic model on the subject says, and probably a total misunderstanding of what the "critics" actually believe. Of course, it won't be purely inflationary. In the worst case, where there  is perfect pass through from the company to consumers. What will happen will be an up tick in prices that will mostly wind up in the income of the workers. It will not be purely inflationary in the nonsensical way described in the article because the percentage increase in the wages will exceed the increase in the price level caused by the wage increase. And even though the article author suggests otherwise, I don't see any reasonable way in which there can be no price increase.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
