<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>On the Game of Thrones Rape Scene Issue</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>On the Game of Thrones Rape Scene Issue</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3245498261_093141423b_b.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3245498261_093141423b_b.jpg" alt="3245498261_093141423b_b" width="1024" height="683" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2458"></a> </p>

<p>I've been seeing this issue invade Twitter and Facebook. I don't really have enough knowledge to evaluate the substance of the claim that the rape in the GOT episode was too much (I'm not a GOT watcher). But I'll chime in on the issue with a few points</p>

<p><strong>Note: When I talk of things like "free speech", "censorship" and "rights" in this post I mean ethics, not law. A number of the ethical rules I suggest regarding free speech would be difficult to encode into law.<br /></strong></p>

<p>1) Everyone has the right to criticize the media they watch. Others retain the right to dismiss the criticism as wrong headed. Criticism is not censorship.</p>

<p>2) Consumers of media have to right to not watch a TV show if they don't like it, or think that part of it is beyond the pale, or if they think it downplays rape. Even if wrong headed and irrational, the exercise of this preference is not censorship.</p>

<p>3) Censorship happens when this criticism turns into outside pressure, with two types of pressure counting. Direct coercion -- ie. by law and indirect coercion by deprivation of a generally shared resource.</p>

<p>4) I don't consider a publisher that exercises direct editorial control (such as a TV station) to be a generally shared resource. I'm fine if consumers try to lobby TV stations and other such publishers to make media that they like.</p>

<p>5) Things like YouTube, Twitter, and such are generally shared resources. I would consider an attempt to pressure YouTube into dropping clips of the rape scene to be an attempt at censorship, and unethical.</p>

<p>6) It seems to me like a lot of activists are under the impression that the best way to "avoid downplaying" rape is to purge the media and the arts of all references to it. Its a very ostrich head in sand way of looking at the issue and one that probably serves to actually downplay the issue. Rape happens, and art should reflect that.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>:Flickr user Sarah Reid <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5WN2yz" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5WN2yz</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#tv</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
