<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>On the Recent Gay Marriage Decision</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-recent-gay-marriage-decision</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-recent-gay-marriage-decision?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>On the Recent Gay Marriage Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-recent-gay-marriage-decision</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-recent-gay-marriage-decision</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 20:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>As you likely already know, the US Supreme Court struck down prohibitions on gay marriage. The opinion (and its dissents) can be found here <a href="http://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/14pdf/14-556_3204.pdf" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.supremecourt.gov/<wbr></wbr>opinions/<wbr></wbr>14pdf/<wbr></wbr>14-556_3204.pdf</a> The ruling is a very good one and it will be good to see gay marriage become law across the nation. I have previously written about why I think gay marriage should be legal here <a href="https://www.theojones.name/if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage-5/" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage-5/<wbr></wbr></a> and here <a href="https://www.theojones.name/the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits/" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits/<wbr></wbr></a></p>

<p>Before I get in to the core of the opinion and the legal issues, I will give an overview of some of the reasons why I think it is good that gay marriage is now legal, as a policy issue. Anti-gay marriage advocates are often (if not usually) motivated by either severely misguided and false stereotypes and/or a desire to force everyone to conform to their conservative religious code of morality. There’s no justification for current bans on gay marriage and I can't think of a reasonable argument in their favor. The impact of this ruling on gay couples will certainly be strong.</p>

<p><a name="__DdeLink__0_472281813"></a> Marriage licenses provide many important legal benefits. A 2004 study by the United States General Accounting Office found that 1,138 federal laws use marital status as a factor in determining or receiving benefits, rights, and privileges. According to the Ontario Consultants on Religious Tolerance (OCRT), <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/aboutus.htm">a nonsectarian group that</a> "<em>that promotes the freedom of individuals to follow the religious path of their choosing, without discrimination or oppression</em>", <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/hom_marr.htm">these include benefits</a> to individuals that affect their "<em>Social Security, Medicare, medical leave, and other benefits; property inheritance; the right to visit their spouse in hospital, and make medical decisions if they are incapacitated; security of the couple and of their children</em>". This means gay couples lack the financial security of married couples and the right to have their partner involved in critical decisions if they become incapacitated.</p>

<p>Conservatives advocating bans on gay marriage cannot show they will be harmed in any way by gay marriages. Many conservatives argue that permitting gay marriage will be corrosive to families and society. However, there is a great body of evidence that contradicts this assertion. A <a href="http://www.aaanet.org/issues/policy-advocacy/Statement-on-Marriage-and-the-Family.cfm">statement issued by the American Anthropological Association</a> states that "<em>The results of more than a century of anthropological research on households, kinship relationships, and families, across cultures and through time, provide no support whatsoever for the view that either civilization or viable social orders depend upon marriage as an exclusively heterosexual institution …..a vast array of family types, including families built upon same-sex partnerships, can contribute to stable and humane societies</em>". I ask those conservatives who reject the vision of liberty for all including gay couples and those turning to religious dogma to consider is the Bible really a good guide for governance? Slavery, stoning, executing whole families for the crimes of one member, mass murder and genocide are <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/imm_bibl.htm">all found in the Bible</a>. Are religious ideologues asking the government to enforce a biblical version of Sharia law?</p>

<p>I am less impressed with the majority opinion (authored by Justice Kennedy) than with the ruling its self. It is strong on flowery language but quite weak on actual substance. It has the feel of being written much more towards a popular audience than the legally knowledgeable. Justice Kennedy will tell you about the "transcendent importance of marriage" but he provides little guidance towards courts in regard to future gay rights issues. He relies on arguments that are very narrowly focused on the issue of marriage -- instead of a more broad based recognition of gay rights. These might not be flaws that are that problematic (incrementalism, and comprehensibility to outsiders are not bad things) were it not for the it embraces arguments that are quite frankly weak, in order to obtain this.</p>

<p>As guidance to future courts, this opinion really falls down. It fails to set a scrutiny standard for evaluating future laws that affect gays. The courts tend to interpret the equal protection clause based on varying standards of scrutiny. The higher standards are only applied to certain protected classes. For a law that targets a group of people to pass the scrutiny of the courts, the law must meet standards that vary based on the scrutiny test applied.</p>
<ol><li>Strict Scrutiny. This standard is applied to laws that impact a fundamental right (i.e one in the Bill of Rights). More relevant to this case is the fact that this standard is used in regards to some protected classes, particularly race. To pass this standard the government must have a compelling governmental interest, the legislation must be narrowly tailored to fulfill the interest, and must be the least restrictive means of meeting the interest. This is the most stringent of the standards.</li>
    <li>Intermediate Scrutiny. This is the standard that applies on the basis of sex/gender discrimination, among other protected classes.To pass this standard a law must further an important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest</li>
    <li>The third standard is the rational basis test. It has two poorly defined sub-types. The cases where eachis used have not beenwell defined.
<ol><li>Regular rational basis -- this is the generic standard that applies to all laws. It is nearly all permissive. A law has to be rationally related to a legitimate government interest. This legitimate government interest does not need to be the actual reason for the law nor do the costs of the legislation have to be proportionate to the interest.</li>
    <li>Rational basis with teeth. This is a poorly defined heightened version of the rational basis test This adds to the regular rational basis standard by declaring that the interest must be strong enough that a reasonable and impartial legislature could come to the conclusion that the legislation is justified. The gay marriage related cases that have involved rational basis have used this standard.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p>Where does the court put this boundary? It didn't set it. It evaded the question. It hangs the case on the due process clause by treating marriage as a free-standing right. The first thing to note about this is that this results in a ruling that has little applicability to other areas of law. And frankly, I consider it to be a fairly weak argument in favor of gay marriage. Its clear to me that discrimination in regards to marriage licenses is a decidedly bad thing. But that is because discrimination is in regard to important areas of law is inherently bad and needs to be strongly justified (if it occurs at all), not because of an inherent value in marriage licenses. If one of the libertarian proposals to abolish marriage licenses all together were adopted would it be unconstitutional? (disregarding the degenerate case <a href="http://newsok.com/article/5400240">where in such a proposal were adopted with the direct intent to evade this ruling</a>) I would suggest not (although such a proposal would likely be wrong-headed on other grounds). If Justice Kennedy desired a narrow ruling for some reason, he would of been better to make an equal protection argument on the basis of the already established law regarding sex/gender discrimination.</p>

<p>If the majority opinion is weak, the dissenting opinions are worthless. Justice Scalia is not happy with the ruling "<em>The opinion is couched in a style that is as pretentious as its content is egotistic .... If, even as the price to be paid for a fifth vote, I ever joined an opinion for the Court that began: 'The Constitution promises liberty to all within its reach, a liberty that includes certain specific rights that allow persons, within a lawful realm, to define and express their identity,' I would hide my head in a bag. The Supreme Court of the United States has descended from the disciplined legal reasoning of John Marshall and Joseph Story to the mystical aphorisms of the fortune cookie</em> "</p>

<p>Aside from the bile, Scalia puts a huge emphasis on democracy. But this tends to be weak when laws that have a huge impact but little justification are in question. The court system in a strong way provides a roadblock to shortsightedness by the public. While the law does not prohibit a legislature from enacting a stupid law, it to some extent limits the damage. This is not to say I am prone to sloganeering about how rights shouldn't be brought to a vote. At some point such a thing is inevitable as the range of rights and their limits are in dispute. And some rights require more detailed policy making to enforce than could be provided through a court order. Democracy is the worst system of government except for all the others. But that does not mean that the only legitimate way to contest a law is through the ballot box. And that does not mean that it is consistently a bad idea to refer certain type of decision making to specialized bodies like courts. And the strong history of abuses of rights of gay people, and shortsightedness by policy makers in regards to equal protections, probably means that the courts have a role on this issue.</p>

<p>Justice Roberts is a bit more sensible. He emphasises the argument that a lot of the cases supporting a right to marriage cited by the majority come from the realm of procreation and child bearing. He does not dispute that gay marriage is good policy but he argues that it is not mandated by the constitution. At some point, this history is a good showcase of the weakness of the main argument fronted by the majority. But I do not think that such an argument is sufficient to over come all but the most weakest equal protection analysis. If discrimination against gays was subject to intermediate scrutiny, or a stronger standard, it is hard to think that such a historical analysis would further an important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest (and just the discrimination based on sex factor in gay marriage prohibitions suggests intermediate scrutiny).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
