<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Reactionaries on the left</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/reactionaries-on-the-left</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/reactionaries-on-the-left?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Reactionaries on the left</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/reactionaries-on-the-left</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/reactionaries-on-the-left</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>[caption id="attachment_2448" align="aligncenter" width="604"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/6261922023_049039a2d8_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-2448 size-full" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/6261922023_049039a2d8_o.jpg" alt="6261922023_049039a2d8_o" width="604" height="452"></a> 2010 Anti-GMO protest in San Diego[/caption]</p>

<p>I've noticed that the hard left has a large amount of opposition to modernism and a good dose of what could be described as reactionaryism (the belief in the return to a past state). Sure, this is commonly (and perhaps almost exclusively) associated with the right-wing, but it's a huge element of some newer left-wing points of view. It's common to view reactionaryism solely in terms of classic social issues, and on these points reactionaryism is an inherently right-wing point of view. But there are other elements of policy and on these it's the left that wants to resist/reverse social progress. Additionally, this is one of the reasons why liberalism is NOT equivalent to progressivism/leftism. It's only an oddity of US politics that has made it seem like this is true. The range of political possibilities in the United States has be limited in such a way as to leave both progressives and liberals in agreement on all major issues of politics. I think this is beginning to change, and there will become an increasingly strong distinction between these two ideologies in the future. I would commit that within the next 10 or so years this will become a very noticeable distinction -- similar to the one that splits conservatives and libertarians. The dispute is fundamentally over the three pillars of enlightenment liberalism 1) science as the arbitrator of knowledge,2) democracy and due process as the arbitrator of political outcomes, and 3) individual liberty. Here are a few of the reactionary tendencies in the left wing viewpoint</p>
<ol><li>A dislike of science. This can be seen in issues like the debate over GMO's and similar conflicts. This can also be seen in the broader world of ideology. The world of left-leaning academic theory is almost overwhelmingly skeptical of the view that human society can be studied scientifically using the (largely quantative) methods commonly associated with the natural sciences. At the very least, this involves an emphasis on "other ways of knowing", and on the self-reported and analyzed "lived experiences" of people. This comes under such names as "structuralism" in the literature. The most extreme form of this comes under such names as post-structuralism and postmodernism and outright disputes the primacy of science even in the realm of the natural sciences, like physics and biology. This is of, course a highly problematic position, but is not at all rare in the world of diversity studies, and other left-leaning elements of the humanities.</li>
<li><p>Persistent clashes with freedom of speech. A lot of members of the modern left don't recognize the liberal distinction between speech and action. They have resurrected the ancient view that offensive speech or an attack on personal honor is an equivalent to physical violence. They act as if the advocacy of a course of action, or the belief that a course of action is within one's rights, or the attempt to participate in the political process, is equivalent to actually doing the action in question. This treatment of disagreeable speech as an equivalent of a physical attack also materializes into things like "trigger warnings" and the "safe place" movement. This bodes poorly for the underlying conception of democracy. Democracy feeds on public contestability and public debate of possible options. The vast majority of policy proposals will prove to be wrongheaded, and will be rightly rejected. But the process of free discourse and debate is absolutely essential to this process. Enlightenment civic republicanism came into existence in about the same time as science, because the two are innately linked. Both rely on decentralized finding of knowledge. In the case of science, this is for finding facts, in the case of democracy this is for determining how to run society. An attack on free speech is a full scale attack on both.</p></li>
<li><p>A neo-luddite view of technology and industrialization. Widespread industrialization and deployment of technology has vastly improved the standard of living of the typical person. However, many elements of the hard left want to return to a "small is beautiful" way of running the economy. An emphasis is put on small businesses and cooperatives. Some want a small scale and decentralized economy that looks a lot like the pre-industrial world. Its states' rights for progressives. And equally absurd. Despite its flaws, major firms can put in place a large degree of economic planning and stability that smaller firms cannot. They can leverage economies of scale, and they have vast efficiency improvements over smaller firms when they produce a uniform product Small is not efficient.</p></li>
</ol><p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/axkZfP" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>axkZfP</a> Flickr user Alexis Baden-Mayer</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/us" class="p-category" rel="tag">#us</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#us</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
