<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Revisiting The UN Broadband Commission's "Cyberviolence" Report | Popehat</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/revisiting-the-un-broadband-commissions-cyberviolence-report-popehat</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/revisiting-the-un-broadband-commissions-cyberviolence-report-popehat?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting The UN Broadband Commission's "Cyberviolence" Report | Popehat</title>
      <link>https://popehat.com/2015/09/28/revisiting-the-un-broadband-commissions-cyberviolence-report</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/revisiting-the-un-broadband-commissions-cyberviolence-report-popehat</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 04:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"The UN and other multinational organizations are increasingly plagued by authoritarian regimes trying to set up ostensibly neutral rules that would allow them to suppress dissent. China, Russia, and Saudi Arabia recently pushed for a UN agency to have more authority over the internet, and in turn cede that control to member states. This would make it much easier for totalitarian regimes to stop online dissent and find dissenters. Also, I did not emphasize clearly enough that the global experience with blasphemy law shows that it is disproportionately used against ethnic and religious minorities in countries with authoritarian governments, and should be seen less as a sincere effort to protect the good name of Mohammed and more as a way to increase state power over those minorities. In short, when it comes to potential speech restrictions, working with the UN carries substantial risk that the rules you propose will be used abusively by the strong against the weak, and by totalitarian governments against dissenters. If you find that improbable, consider what use, say, Saudia Arabia could make of a very flexible international norm against online "harassment," given their brutal enforcement of narrow sexual norms."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
