<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Some Basic Assumptions of Mine about Philosophy</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Some Basic Assumptions of Mine about Philosophy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/some-basic-assumptions-of-mine-about-philosophy</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o.jpg" alt="486030422_bd28eb7e5e_o" width="769" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2463"></a>I am almost a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Positivism">positivist</a>/empiricist in my philosophical beliefs, I believe that about the only reliable source of knowledge is observation, the scientific method, and the repeated refinement of theories through science. This applies even for human society. My one difference from this view is the belief that just raw observation isn't sufficient. There is the need for bridge assumptions in order to translate mere observations into explanatory theories and moral judgements. Additionally, some basic metaphysical assumptions are needed. The list of such assumptions should be as short as possible, and as much of the heavy lifting should be loaded on to observation. But these bridge assumptions are needed as just pure observation is not enough. A pile of data is not a theory and is not an explanation of the world. Mere observation is not sufficient to produce knowledge. Results need to be merged into something greater than their parts. Correlations between different results need to be drawn together into a greater theory. All this requires interpretation, and there needs to be rules that to interpretation. Likewise there have to be a few basic assumptions about how the world works in order to make science workable. Ethics is another thing where mere data isn't enough. The is-ought gap needs to be bridged. Therefore a basic assumption about how to turn facts about how the world is to ethical judgments is needed. As follows in the rest of this blog post is a rough overview of what my basic assumptions about the world is like. Additionally, a positivist/empiricist worldview without bridge assumptions will be unavoidably self-contradictory. There is no way that empiricism itself can be confirmed through mere observation.</p>
<ol><li>Physicalism --- all objects that exist follow laws of physics that exist independently of the subjective views of observers. My preferred variant of this is the mathematical universe hypothesis, the idea that the universe is a mathematical structure.</li>
    <li>The basic rules of logic.</li>
    <li>The scientific method. For this I prefer something along the lines of Popperlian falseificationsim. This is the idea that science is the repeated refinement of falsifiable theories through observation.</li>
    <li>A rule regarding ethics. I prefer preference utilitarianism – the idea that the moral set of actions is the one that results in the longest long-run preference satisfaction when aggregated over all individuals.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: Flickr user Seth de l'Isle  <a href="https://flic.kr/p/JX2US" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>JX2US</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#philosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#philosophy</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
