<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Sortition as a way to remove bias in selecting for exclusive positions</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/sortition-as-a-way-to-remove-bias-in-selecting-for</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/sortition-as-a-way-to-remove-bias-in-selecting-for?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Sortition as a way to remove bias in selecting for exclusive positions</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/sortition-as-a-way-to-remove-bias-in-selecting-for</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/sortition-as-a-way-to-remove-bias-in-selecting-for</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 05:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/sorition.png"><img class="  wp-image-2494 alignright" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/sorition.png" alt="sorition" width="392" height="294"></a>Sortition -- the selection of people for positions of practical value by random lot --- can be used as a strong way to eliminate bias in the choice of people for positions of significance. In my opinion the source of a lot of implicit bias in the selection of people for employment, university admissions, and other highly selective positions comes from one clear source. The simple fact that there are almost no objective criteria to select from the very best. Subjective criteria are all there is when you get to the highest levels of candidates. And when subjective feelings are at work, a lot of times those feelings can come from ill places. Multiple studies have shown that a large part of society has a degree of implicit bias in regards to such criteria as race and gender.</p>

<p>The most selective universities in the country (for, instance, Ivy League schools) admit a very small portion of their applicants, often less than 5%. Many scarce job positions are similarly exclusive. It is extremely doubtful that the top 5% of applicants to a school are substantially different in any meaningful way than the top 10%. At that level of achievement merit is a totally subjective concept. And the current system of selecting people for such positions allow those in power to put a lot of their subjective biases into selecting people. It is doubtful that the result of applying those biases will be fair in any meaningful way.</p>

<p>That is where my preference for random choice comes in. Probability is fair, it is objective, and it perceives no bias It gives everyone an equal weight. And so, when there is no clear objective reason to differentiate between people, it is the only fair option. Chance is better than subjective views and bias. Adding an element of random selection to choosing people for exclusive positions could eliminate a lot of bias. My suggestion for doing so would change the role of human panels that handle things like college admissions and selection for employment positions, away from selecting the <strong>best</strong> applicant towards eliminating demonstrably unqualified ones. The process for eliminating unqualified applicants would rely as much as possible on objective criteria, and would definitely not be in the hands of a lone person (but would instead be referred to a committee). Once unqualified applicants are removed from the pool, a random set of them can be selected by chance.</p>

<p>Title image create with <a href="https://www.canva.com/">canva</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
