<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Systemic Causation and Anti-Science </title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Causation and Anti-Science </title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>In previous posts I have mentioned George Lakoff's ideas about how misunderstanding systemic causation contributes to science denialism. He describes <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">his ideas at HuffPo</a> and academically in <a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/17524030903529749">a 2010 paper </a>(as usual, full citation at end of post). Lakoff differentiates between two types of causation; systemic and direct. Direct causation is the type of non-probablistic causation that occurs when you shove a box. The box moves, and it will move pretty much every time you shove it. Systemic causation instead involves shifting the probability distribution of events. Climate change does not make a hurricane of a given strength at a given location an unvoidable occurance, in the same way that pushing the box make its movement unavoidable. However, it does make certan types of hurricanes more likely, and therefore can be said to cause hurricanes. A lot of science involves systemic causation. And the fields of science where the causation involved is the most systemic and probabilistic tend to be the biggest denialism magnets. Think climate change or evolution. Why does the role of systemic causation tend to correlate with tendiencies to deny the science? Lakoff seems to think the cause is political ideology.  In his opinion, conservative/libertarian political beliefs tend to have more difficulties with systemic causation. </p><p>However, I doubt this ideological explanation. It is wrong (and perhaps actively dangerous)  for roughly the reasons that <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1744-540X.2007.00466.x/abstract;jsessionid=EB663E5ADD49D613AFCC5CED88563015.f02t03">Steve Pinker points out</a>. Conservatives use arguements that reily on systemic causation all the time, particulary in regards to economic policy. And it is particulary dangerous to treat ideological framing as a goal of political discourse, instead of an all to common discription of it. Such a goal involves a brain-rotting mixing of normative goals and positive description of how the world works. Read Lakoff's writings on GMOs and nuclear energy to see the mind-rot in action.  </p><p>Instead I propose two other explinations of how systemic causation relates to denialism</p><ol><li>The fact that denialism relies on the asymmetry of difficulty in creating reasonable sounding, but incorrect arguements, and refuting them. </li>
<li>The fact that complex systems create emergent properties that often go aganist the intuitions and herististuics that underlie a lot of human reasoning.</li>
</ol><p>Lets start with point one.</p><p><img src="http://www.theojones.name/file/339c444f4e618040977c19a343fd4d1c" alt="The amount of energy necessary to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude bigger than to produce it width=" height="239"></p><p><em>Image via <a href="https://jasonapril.wordpress.com/2014/06/05/the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/"></a><a href="https://jasonapril.wordpress.com/2014/06/05/the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>jasonapril.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/<wbr></wbr></a></em></p><p> </p><p>The claims that climate change deniers and creationists and their ilk make reily on very subtle misconseptions. The misconceptions are pretty beleiveable to a non-expert, and a full explination of why the misconception is wrong can take a lot of effort. Go to SKS or a similar website that rebuts climate change deniers. Look at the section where they list their rebuttials to these arguements <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php"></a><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a> . Note that the rebuttal is usually at least a few times longer than the claim itself.  But it is only a certan type of science that follows the bullshit asymtery rule. Sciences that involve a lot of systemic causation. Complex systems can behave in some pretty subtle ways. Ways that are not ovious, and that take a lot of effort to understand and predict. Due to the Dunning-Kruger effect, and such, it can take quite a bit of knowledge to even be able tell good arguements from bad ones. Add bias, and the generally poor quality of human reasoning, and it becomes easy to talk from <a href="http://imgur.com/cNFqi">Mt. Stupid</a>. </p><p>But when was the last time you saw a math denialist? Not recently? The reason for that is the fact that math does not follow the bullshit asymmetry rule. Its hard to come up with a reasonable sounding, but wrong mathmatical arguement. And when you do come up with one the reason why it is wrong is usually pretty simple. It has actually  become a bit of a game in the math community to come up with invalid "proofs" that seem pleasing. Usually the "proof" is of a clearly absurd claim, like 1=2. Take the following example from Wikipedia. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero"></a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>en.wikipedia.org/<wbr></wbr>wiki/<wbr></wbr>Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero</a></p><p>Let a and b be be equal non-zero quantities.</p><p>$$a=b$$</p><p>Multiply  both sides of the above equation by a. This results in </p><p>$$a^2 = ab$$</p><p>Subtract </p><p>$$b^2$$</p><p>from both sides, resulting in </p><p>$$a^2 - b^2 = ab - b^2$$</p><p>Factor both sides</p><p>$$(a-b)(a+b) = b(a-b)$$ </p><p>Divide both sides by </p><p>$$(a-b) $$</p><p>Resulting in </p><p>$$a + b = b$$ </p><p>Because we know that a = b</p><p>$$ b + b = b $$ </p><p>$$2b = b$ </p><p>$$2 = 1$$ </p><p>The issue with this is simple, there was an implicit division by zero in the "proof" </p><p> </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialism</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lakoff" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lakoff</a> </p><p>Lakoff, George. "Why it matters how we frame the environment." Environmental Communication 4.1 (2010): 70-81.</p><p>Pinker, Steven, and George Lakoff. "Does language frame politics?." Public Policy Research 14.1 (2007): 59-71.</p><p> </p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Division</category>
      <category>#Division</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#denialism</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#lakoff</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
