<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>The employment trilemma</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-employment-trilemma</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-employment-trilemma?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The employment trilemma</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-employment-trilemma</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-employment-trilemma</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Employment-Trilemma.png"><img class="  wp-image-2484 alignright" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Employment-Trilemma.png" alt="Employment Trilemma" width="400" height="300"></a>In this post I will contend that macroeconomic policy faces a trilemma in regards to employment and that this trilemma makes alleviating poverty through full employment highly problematic (leaving transfer payments the only viable means of alleviating poverty on a large scale).  This is a large reason why I am a supporter of a basic income as the only viable way to eliminate poverty.   Namely, I will argue that the following three goals can not be satisfied simultaneously.</p>
<ul type="disc"><li>Full employment</li>
    <li>High wages --- the wages paid are living wages.</li>
    <li>No make-work, ie. the jobs being created are economically productive in way that is commiserate with the wages they pay. There are no useless jobs being produced just for the sake of increasing employment</li>
</ul>
<p>The core of this trilemma comes from the fact that the economically efficient wage level has very little to do with the needs of the people involved. In ideal circumstances, wages, like all other prices reflect the relative scarcity of the service or good in question. It is entirely possible, if not undoubtedly true, that the market equilibrium wage level for some workers would be far below any reasonable living wage, just as for some workers it is way higher.  At this point we get to the trilemma. If the government attempts to provide for a high wage level, say through a minimum wage increase, <a href="http://www.theojones.name/why-a-higher-minimum-wage-2/">there is a risk of increased unemployment</a> when the economy is out of recession. Thus we are at a case where there are high wages, and the work is useful, but there is unnecessary unemployment.</p>

<p>Now, the government could try to offset this in one of a few ways. The most obvious is a wage subsidy, such as the earned income tax credit. The government would pay a large portion of the wages, reducing the disemployment effect involved. Another proposal in this vein would be for the government to just outright hire the unemployed segment of the population. However, it seems probable that this would violate the third criteria. There would be high paying jobs, but the jobs being created have a good chance of not winding up economically productive in way that is commiserate with the wages they pay. In the case of a subsidy, employers would no longer feel the full cost of the labor they use. Their grounds for hiring someone would be based on the subsidized price of the wages, not the actual price. There would now be a solid range of circumstances when it would be viable for an employer to hire employees even when they produce less then their post-subsidy pay. Likewise, in the job guarantee case, the government would have to come up with the jobs to hire people under. If these are for services that are not desired by the public for reasons other than their employment production, then these services are probably of limited economic value. And thus we are at a case where you can have high wages, and full employment, but some of the employment would be useless.  There should be no useless jobs being produced just for the sake of increasing employment, as if you are paying people for nothing, you might as well enact a basic income.</p>

<p><strong>Title image produced with <a href="http://www.canva.com">canva</a>.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
