<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>The reddit crisis</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-reddit-crisis</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-reddit-crisis?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The reddit crisis</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-reddit-crisis</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-reddit-crisis</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2015 04:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>On reddit there is a crisis after the employee responsible for managing the site's famed Ask Me Anything <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/OutOfTheLoop/comments/3bxduw/why_was_riama_along_with_a_number_of_other_large/">discussions was fired</a>.<br />A "friend" on facebook linked to this image. I'm not sure its true, but its the most plausible theory I've heard. It claims that she was fired because she would no go along with reddit's plan to "monetize" AMAs <br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/CI9iYW7VAAAzzJN.png"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/CI9iYW7VAAAzzJN-263x300.png" alt="CI9iYW7VAAAzzJN" width="263" height="300" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-2581"></a></p>

<p>Reddit CEO Ellen Pao, denies this story. But due to recent actions, he credibility is trashed. I wouldn't say she is clearly lying, just that her past actions leave her with almost no credibility in my opinion. Her previous management decisions in reddit have been idiotic, she was caught in a number of lies during the discrimination trial (at Kliner Perkins), and she had finical ties to her husband's near-Ponzi scheme (and I would strongly suspect, but can't prove, knowledge of its workings. It <em>IS </em>her husband and one does not let one's spouse spend millions in joint accets without some knowledge of what is happening). I want external confirmation for pretty much every non-obvious statement she makes at this point.</p>

<p>A number of sub reddits (including many of the most popular ones on the site) have shut down.</p>

<p>Allegations have surfaced that a different employee was fired due to his lukimia. See that employee's statement (which was later taken down by reddit here  <a href="https://archive.is/gcT8X" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>archive.is/<wbr></wbr>gcT8X</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>It was only until recently, late 2014, that I was able to return to work (remotely). Unfortunately due to new practices at reddit, all of the working employees were mandated to work from San Francisco, so I wasn’t actually able to work until I was ready to move. In January of 2015, I was almost ready to move to reddit. I had even flown out to SF for a few days while all of the reddit employees met during a company-wide 3-day seminar. </p>

<p>During this time, I had sat down with Ellen Pao (current reddit CEO) to discuss my future at reddit and when I was able to move. I had told her that it would still be at least a month (but probably closer to 2 or 3) before I was finally able to move to SF, and she said she was 100% fine with that. We discussed my position, and ultimately determined that I would be returning to the Community Management team. I met some of the new members of the team, all was well, and then I flew home on day 3.</p>

<p>Less than a month later, in February of 2015, I received a call from Ellen stating that I was to be terminated in less than a week. When I asked what the specific reason was, she had roughly stated that “because of our discussion, you are too sick to properly fulfill your duties as Community Manager.” (At no point during our meeting was this stated - I had raised concerns about the stress levels of Community Management, but had ultimately decided that it was something I could easily manage.) </p>

<p>I pleaded with Ellen to let me stay, as I had been sick for over a full year now and the only thing that was on my mind was coming back to work - work I loved so very, very much. She finally stated that if I were to get permission from my doctor stating that it was okay for me to move to SF and begin work, that I would be able to come back.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If that is true, reddit is going to be in a world of legal hurt. The situation with the leukemia patient sounds like a blatant violation of the ADA. And it sounds like there is written documentation and witnesses. Veronica could probably front enough of a gender discrimination case to get through to discovery, and bring forth some fairly damaging stuff. And I wonder if some the attempts of reddit to suppress discussion of this will cause them trouble under the National Labor Relations Act (which protects employee discussion of working conditions)? There are some rumors that Reddit has used the NDA in their employment contract to dissuade former employees from going to the press.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
