<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Three Types of Troll</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/three-types-of-troll</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/three-types-of-troll?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Three Types of Troll</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/three-types-of-troll</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/three-types-of-troll</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 22:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A huge issue with a lot of discussions of how to handle trolling on the internet is that it is often not recognized that trolling refers to three distinct types of behavior. For one of these the usual no troll feeding logic applies, but for the others that is a much more dubious rule to follow. Here is my taxonomy of trolling</p>
<ul><li>The classic troll: This is the core thing that people think of when they think of trolling. This type of troll posts things on message boards to with the intent of getting the most lulzy response from that community. This is the type of troll that rants about how bad Micro$haft winblows is. But other than being mildly annoying and disruptive, the attention getting behavior of this troll type is pretty harmless. This is also the type of troll that the no feeding rule works the best for.  The other type of trolls are more toxic extensions of this variant. 
</li><li>The "flacker" – this type of troll is an ideologue that exhibits a lot of the same effect as the classic troll, but this effect and behavior is the result of extremism, not lulz seeking. Limited feeding/interaction with trolls of this kind is not useless, but you are usually dealing with a personality that is immune to logic.
</li><li>The grifer. This is the type of troll that does extremely destructive behavior like harassment, doxing, SWATing, script kiddy hacking, defacement of websites, mailbombing, and the like. This type of troll deserves a decisive response, and should not just be ignored.  This is the type that inhabits such places as 8chan /Baphomet/.</li></ul><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
