<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>University Runs Anti Vax Course</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/university-runs-anti-vax-course</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/university-runs-anti-vax-course?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>University Runs Anti Vax Course</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/university-runs-anti-vax-course</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/university-runs-anti-vax-course</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/2015/07/u-of-toronto-oks-anti-vaccine-homeopathy-course" rel="in-reply-to" class="u-in-reply-to">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>u-of-toronto-oks-anti-vaccine-homeopathy-course</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The syllabus for the course has been posted online, and it reads a bit like a bad blog post. "Quantum physics is a branch of physics that understands the interrelationship between matter and energy," It states. "This science offers clear explanations as to why homeopathic remedies with seemingly no chemical trace of the original substance are able to resolve chronic diseases, why acupuncture can offer patients enough pain relief to undergo surgery without anesthesia, why meditation alone can, in some instances, reduce the size of cancerous tumors."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is the type of crap I've seen a lot. There is Deepack Chopra and his ilk. Quantum gobbledygook is about the only justification for water memory I have heard other than total evasion of the issue. At the very least a lot of the homeopathic types also believe in quantum woo.</p>

<p>The really crappy thing with this is that is that it is under a natural sciences department. I've seen crap like this leak into social science classes. I've even had the misfortune of taking a class that somehow got into the Womens' studies department (taken for distribution requirements) with cross listing with other social science departments with a textbook that talked about how alternative medicine and homeopathy are perfectively good "ways of knowing" on par with "western medicine", and then went on to talk about the health risks of living near a power-line EMF field.</p>

<p>But this is the first I have seen from a department that should know better. At least its not from my university.</p>

<p>On a side note, I have a funny homeopathic story. I beekeep. One friend of mine heard this and insisted that a homeopathic dilution of bee alarm pheromone would work to calm bees in lue of smoke. All you have to do is spray the homeopathic remedy on the bees with a spray bottle. I am not making that up. It almost made me want to spray water on the bees to see what would happen, but I didn't do that because it is likely that the bees wouldn't be happy about it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/notweet" class="p-category" rel="tag">#notweet</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#notweet</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
