<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Water scarcity and water shortage</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/water-scarcity-and-water-shortage</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/water-scarcity-and-water-shortage?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Water scarcity and water shortage</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/water-scarcity-and-water-shortage</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/water-scarcity-and-water-shortage</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 22:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The ongoing drought in California has made it clear that water is now a scarce good  --- in many areas of the world there is not an effectively unlimited supply of it. Potential users of water just can't take as much of as they want without impacting other potential users negatively. However, scarcity of water does not mean shortage, scarcity is when there are practical limits to how much one can take, shortage is when even those who have a socially useful efficient use for the good cannot obtain it. What is happening in California is a shortage.  And this is unnecessary . In this post I will discuss a bit more about what I mean by this difference. In a future post, I will discuss what can be done to avoid having scarcity of water turn into shortage of water.</p>

<p>Scarcity is a fact of many economic goods. It is a simple truth that unconstrained demand will exceed possible production of goods and services. Wants and desires are effectively unlimited compared to what can actually be produced. Water will no longer be an exemption from this rule. When the system of water rights in the US was constructed, water was effectively non-scarce. Sure, there may have been a nominal amount of scarcity, but the even a fairly minimal set of limits on water draw could manage these. However, the actual sustainable output of waterways and ground water is limited. A river only has so much water flowing through it, and a ground water source only contains so much water. California is hitting up against those limit. Other states will be bound to hit extreme water scarcity in the near future.  And as the drought shows, climate change will make this worse.  Even if it were not for climate change, we would still encounter water scarcity eventually. The US (like most developed nations) uses a lot more water than the typical human. And these is simply not enough water on the planet to extend such a level of water use to the whole planet.  The system of water rights set up in the western United States was primarily designed to maximize the potential for migration to the west. Water rights in the east manage water as a commons -- a system inherited from British law. Neither setup is designed to handle true water scarcity and both systems were designed under much lower global population densities, and much lower levels of water consumption than exist today.</p>

<p>Despite this, there is no reason scarcity has to amount to shortage. Food is a scarce good, but it is rarely in shortage in western countries. One cannot take as much beef as one wants at only a minimal price because the possible desires for beef (and/or the resources required to produce it) are not available in an effectively unlimited amount.  However, there is not a shortage of it. Store shelves are not empty. This is because there is a price on beef. If beef were available at unlimited quantities at a very small price (such as is done with water) there would be a shortage of beef. Adding a price to a scarce good serves two purposes, 1) it limits how much of the good one can take, 2) it requires buyers to weigh  the relative utilities of different goods (is the benefit of consuming beef really better enough than the benefit of consuming chicken?), and 3) it discourages waste and inefficiency in the use of a good. The price charged for a good is fundamentally a reflection of its scarcity. Supply and demand are simply reflections of scarcity. Due to factor 1 a more plentiful good will be cheaper, while one with more demand will tend to be more expensive due to factor 2.</p>

<p>Now, it is worth noting that there is an intermediate case between shortage and non-shortage. Economic scarcity. particularly in developing nations with high poverty and high inequality, a price can poorly reflect the underlying utility provided by a good due to the ability to pay of most poor people. But this is fundamentally a reflection of poverty. And due to the very low costs of water infrastructure, this is a very limited problem in developed nations. The cost of water and water infrastructure is small compared to prevailing incomes in the United States.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
