<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Cakes, Gay Rights, and Religion</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/writing-on-cakes-gay-rights-and-religion</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/2015/writing-on-cakes-gay-rights-and-religion?_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Writing on Cakes, Gay Rights, and Religion</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/writing-on-cakes-gay-rights-and-religion</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/writing-on-cakes-gay-rights-and-religion</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 04:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There have been a number of cases recently where bakeries have been sued for refusing to provide cakes adjusted for gay weddings (i.e with two male figurines, or with appropriate phrasing of text).   Recently <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2015/01/21/denver-bakery-anti-gay-cake-_n_6516674.html">there also was a mirror image case</a> wherein a bakery refused to letter a cake with a religious anti-gay message. There is a bit of a point to those who object to this type of complaint, the service like a bakery or the like young something that is art are very close to art. Artists can express in their work, it does some pretty gnarly issues with freedom of speech and censorship. However, there is also a need for universal access to business services. Decision has been something quite a bit conflicted about since I've heard about it in previous incidents where this type of issue has come up. And really it comes down to how much of an artistic expression is in the final work. Closer things get to pure are the strong degree of creativity more there is to problems of freedom of expression and censorship. Pretty much what I think is the cutoff should be at where there's a substantial amount of creativity added. Think enough added actual creativity for a new work the baker or whatever creates to be eligible for copyright. And what I've come to realize is that just transcribing some text given to you by a customer doesn't really add much creativity. That makes it so it's really the same product is the same cake only with a different text. Businesses should generally be obligated to serve everyone in the community.It was something else like an artist, or a photographer, or such I would still feel different. Fact that they are concerns over freedom of expression thoroughly dismissed in this issue is more concerning a lot of the discrimination is trying to be combated. In fact, I would say that this might be symptomatic in general a retreat by the left from freedom of speech and civil liberties. Because it is close to undeniable that the closer attempts to eliminate discrimination to work of artists creative workers the more the severe issues with reductions in freedoms caused by the regulations become. Policymakers and commentators should not ignore those issues. Like many issues in politics there are trade-offs involved between different freedoms, and those trade-offs need to be weighed fairly, not completely dismissed.</p>

<p>    </p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#politics</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
