<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23old&amp;_t=rss&amp;offset=40" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Link Roundup: What I've Been Reading On the Web</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/link-roundup-what-ive-been-reading-on-the-web</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/link-roundup-what-ive-been-reading-on-the-web</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2014 12:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Here are some worthwhile articles that I've been reading.</p>

<p><strong>The Idea of Congressional Intent is Incoherent <br /></strong><a href="http://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2014/07/the-idea-of-congressional-intent-is-incoherent.html"></a><a href="http://marginalrevolution.com/marginalrevolution/2014/07/the-idea-of-congressional-intent-is-incoherent.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>marginalrevolution.com/<wbr></wbr>marginalrevolution/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>the-idea-of-congressional-intent-is-incoherent.html</a></p>

<p>Related to the above: <br /><strong>Congress is a “They,” not an “It”: Legislative intent as oxymoron <br /></strong><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/014481889290043Q"></a><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/014481889290043Q">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>014481889290043Q</a></p>

<p><strong>What did Congress mean by “established by the State”?</strong> <br /><a href="http://theincidentaleconomist.com/wordpress/what-did-congress-mean-by-established-by-the-state/"></a><a href="http://theincidentaleconomist.com/wordpress/what-did-congress-mean-by-established-by-the-state/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theincidentaleconomist.com/<wbr></wbr>wordpress/<wbr></wbr>what-did-congress-mean-by-established-by-the-state/<wbr></wbr></a></p>

<p><strong>What a Seattle PRT System Might Cost <br /></strong><a href="http://kinetic.seattle.wa.us/nxtlevel/prt/seattlecost.html"></a><a href="http://kinetic.seattle.wa.us/nxtlevel/prt/seattlecost.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>kinetic.seattle.wa.us/<wbr></wbr>nxtlevel/<wbr></wbr>prt/<wbr></wbr>seattlecost.html</a></p>

<p><strong>Renewable Energy Use Advantages of Maglev-Based Personal Rapid Transit <br /></strong> <br /><a href="http://trid.trb.org/view.aspx?id=909655"></a><a href="http://trid.trb.org/view.aspx?id=909655">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>trid.trb.org/<wbr></wbr>view.aspx?id=909655</a></p>

<p><strong>Paul Ryan's Anti-Poverty Plan Would Cost Billions to Implement. Will GOPers Go for That?</strong> <br /><a href="http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2014/07/paul-ryan-anti-poverty-plan-would-cost-billions"></a><a href="http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2014/07/paul-ryan-anti-poverty-plan-would-cost-billions">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.motherjones.com/<wbr></wbr>politics/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>paul-ryan-anti-poverty-plan-would-cost-billions</a></p>

<p><strong>The Middle East Friendship Chart</strong> <br /><a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/the">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.slate.com/<wbr></wbr>blogs/<wbr></wbr>the</a><em>world</em>/2014/07/17/the<em>middle</em>east<em>friendship</em>chart.html?wpsrc=sh<em>all</em>mob<em>tw</em>top</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Oil During World War 2</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/synthetic-oil-during-world-war-2</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/synthetic-oil-during-world-war-2</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 09:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <section class="post-content">
<p><i><a href="https://theojones.name/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">This is part of a blog post series on climate change.</a></i><i></i><i>In this post I am using a new way of doing citations that I will use in some of my longer posts. The citations can be found at the end notes/</i>During the interwar period and in World War 2 the German government placed heavy emphasis on fnding ways to synthesize fuel. Most of this research focused around the Fischer-Tropsch process [1, 26-29] and the Bergius process [2]. The Bergius process is able to hydrogenate coal, and other sources of carbon, and turn them into hydrocarbons. The Fischer-Tropsch process is able to synthesize hydrocarbons from carbon monoxide/carbon dioxide and hydrogen, with a input of energy. In the German program the CO2 and the energy came from coal. The Fischer-Tropsch process process was invented by Franz Fischer and Hans Tropsch in the 1920s at the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute for Coal Research. Germany' s frst commercial use of the process came in 1935.German company Ruhrchemie AG saw the process as a way to add value to surplus coal and in 1934 bought the patents for the process. Hitler saw an even more expansive use for the method, German energy independence, and commissioned large scale construction of such plants. By November of 1935 almost 800000 barrels of [1, 26-27]. This production didn't just include fuel, but also included non-fuel oil based products. These include rubber, alcohols, aldehydes, soft waxes and detergents. Coal hydrogenation was the preferred process for producing gasoline and aviation fuel, while the Fischer-Tropsch process was preferred for other fuels [3, 148]. However, the Fischer-Tropsch process is capable of producing either. The production of synthetic oil would turn out tobe critical to the war effort, as Germany has no supply of natural oil. This was part of a massive program to reconstruct German military power, and to promote a mircentilist trade policy. The World War One experience showed the dependence that Germany had of foreign goods. Furthermore, Germany had trouble obtaining the hard currency needed to import natural oil and the nation's government was concerned that global oil supplies could run out (both during the Weimar and Nazi periods). By 1938 of the war Germany was targeting a production of 38 million barrels of these fuels per year however there were some diffculties in actiuly meeting this production goal, and persistent labor shortages during the war. Actual 1938 production was about 10 million barrels, and 1943 production was 36 million barrels [5]. This prewar build-up received substantial investment from foreign firms, particularly American firms. Additionally, U.S firms (which were much more sophisticated at refinning oil) provided some needed technology. A report from the Commercial Attach of the U.S. Embassy in Berlin in 1933 stated "In two gears Germany will be manufacturing oil and gas enough out of soft coal for a long war. The Standard Oil of New York is furnishing millions of dollars to help." A memorandum from IG Farben, a major producter of fuels with the FT process, stated [6]<br />"The closing of an agreement with Standard was necessary for tech nical, commercial, and financial reasons,technically, because the specialized experience which was available only in a big oil company was necessary to the further development of our process, and no such industry existed in Germany; commercially, because in the absence of state economic control in Germany at that time, IG had to avoid a competitive struggle with the great oil powers, who always sold the best gasoline at the lowest price in contested markets; financially, because IG, which had already spent extraordinarily large sums for the development of the process, had to seek financial relief in order to be able to continue development in other new technical fields, such as buna. .... By reason of their decades of work on motor fuels, the Americans were ahead of us in their knowledge of the quality requirements that are called for by the different uses of motor fuels. In particular they had developed, at great expense, a large number of methods of testing gasoline for different uses. On the basis of their experiments they had recognized the good anti, knock quality of iso-octane long before they had any knowledge of our hydrogenation process. This is proved by the single fact that in America fuels are graded in octane numbers, and iso-octane was entered as the best fuel with the number 100. All this knowledge naturally became ours as a result of the agreement, which saved us much effort and protected us against many errors."  /blockquote&gt;<br />Why is the previous discussion in a history of German synthetic fuels during World War 2 relevant to a book on climate change? The Fischer-Tropsch process turns out to be one of the few ways known to produce sustainable fuels. It is a versatile process. The energy source it uses can be almost anything. Modern proposals based around the Fischer-Tropsch process often use nuclear energy or renewable sources  7 . Usually these modern proposals proposals argue for at first using the exhaust from coal plants as the CO2 source, and as these are decommissioned switching to sequestered atmospheric CO2  7 . This CO2 could be collected from an array of land based collecting stations  8  (spaced in a similar way as wind power generators  9 ), or could collect from the more concentrated CO2 in the ocean  10 .  11 . The cost of fuels produced in this fashion would up to $6 a gallon and possibly as low as $3 a gallon with modern techniques  10 .</p>

<p>References<br /> 1  A. Steynberg and M. Dry, Fischer-Tropsch Technology, ser. Studies in Surface Science and Catalysis. Elsevier Science, 2004.  Online . Available:<a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=gJfVfbd1Bd0C"></a><a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=gJfVfbd1Bd0C">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>books.google.com/<wbr></wbr>books?id=gJfVfbd1Bd0C</a><br /> 2  T. P. Hughes, Technological momentum in history: Hydrogenation in germany 1898-1933," Past and Present, pp. 106{132, 1969.  3  A. Stranges, Germanys synthetic fuel industry, 1927{1945," in The German Chemical Industry in the Twentieth Century. Springer, 2000, pp.147{216.  4  World crude oil consumption by year (thousand barrels per day). Online . Available: <a href="http://www.indexmundi.com/energy.aspx"></a><a href="http://www.indexmundi.com/energy.aspx">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.indexmundi.com/<wbr></wbr>energy.aspx</a>  5  P. Becker, The role of synthetic fuel in world war ii germany," Air University Review, 1981.  6  A. Sutton, Wall Street and the Rise of Hitler. Clairview Books, 2010. Online . Available: <a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=Q0amI9GmIe8C"></a><a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=Q0amI9GmIe8C">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>books.google.com/<wbr></wbr>books?id=Q0amI9GmIe8C</a>  7  D. Doty and S. Shevgoor, Windfuels{competitive transportation fuels from wind energy and waste co2," in paper 330c, AIChE Annual Meeting, Philadelphia, 2008.  8  E. A. Parson and D. W. Keith, Fossil fuels without co2 emissions," Science, vol. 282, no. 5391, pp. 1053{1054, 1998.  9  K. S. Lackner, P. Grimes, and H.-J. Ziock, Capturing carbon dioxide from air," 2001.  10  P. Daniel, Fueling the feet, navy looks to the seas."  Online . Available: <a href="http://www.nrl.navy.mil/media/news-releases/2012/fueling-the-fleet-navy-looks-to-the-seas"></a><a href="http://www.nrl.navy.mil/media/news-releases/2012/fueling-the-fleet-navy-looks-to-the-seas">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.nrl.navy.mil/<wbr></wbr>media/<wbr></wbr>news-releases/<wbr></wbr>2012/<wbr></wbr>fueling-the-fleet-navy-looks-to-the-seas</a>  11  By, Goodbye, oil: US navy cracks new renewable energy technology to turn seawater into fuel, allowing ships to stay at sea longer," Apr. 2014.  Online . Available: <a href="http://www.ibtimes.com/goodbye-oil-us-navy-cracks-new-renewable-energy-technology-turn-seawater-fuel-allowing-15684553">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.ibtimes.com/<wbr></wbr>goodbye-oil-us-navy-cracks-new-renewable-energy-technology-turn-seawater-fuel-allowing-15684553</a></p>
</section><footer class="post-footer"><section class="author"></section></footer><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/elsevierscience" class="p-category" rel="tag">#elsevierscience</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/germany" class="p-category" rel="tag">#germany</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ig" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ig</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worldwar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worldwar</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#elsevierscience</category>
      <category>#germany</category>
      <category>#ig</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#worldwar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Birth of Anti-environmentalism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-birth-of-anti-environmentalism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-birth-of-anti-environmentalism</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 07:50:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>The image to the top is an internet meme of "coal rolling", a trend that grew in popularity after the Obama administration attempted to increase regulations on greenhouse gasses. Coal rollers modify their trucks so that they can emit smoke on demand. Many do this to protest environmentalists and the regulations they advocate. This hobby is quite expensive and <a href="http://www.vocativ.com/culture/society/dicks-pick-trucks-meme-rollin-coal/">an article describes it as follows</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Today kids will spend anywhere from $1,000 to $5,000 modifying their pickups for this sole purpose; adding smoke stacks and smoke switches (which trick the engine into thinking it needs more gas), or even revamping the entire fuel system.  <br />Kids make a point of blowing smoke back at pedestrians, in addition to cop cars and rice burners (Japanese-made sedans), which can make it dangerously difficult to see out of the windshield. Diesel soot can also be a great road rage weapon should some wimpy looking Honda Civic ever piss you off. “If someone makes you mad, you can just roll coal, and it makes you feel better sometimes,” says Ryan, a high school senior who works at the diesel garage with Robbie. “The other day I did it to this kid who was driving a Mustang with his windows down, and it was awesome.” [...]</p>

<p>The ultimate highway enemy, however, are “nature nuffies,” or people who drive hybrid cars, because apparently, pro-earth sentiment is an offense to the diesel-trucking lifestyle. “The feeling around here is that everyone who drives a small car is a liberal,” says Ryan. “I rolled coal on a Prius once just because they were tailing me.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, this severe opposition to environmentalism did not come ex nihilo. This comes as part of a political movement.  As I noted in my last post, after the election of President Obama in 2008, the tone in the media changed from a reasonably pro environment one to a one where climate change denial was given strong credence. The Tea Party movement, formed out of a mix of populist New Right fiscal conservatives, libertarians and social conservatives, and this movement made opposition to climate change mitigation and other forms of environmental regulation a core goal. This movement started with the explosion of conservative ideology that came with the Reagan Administration.</p>

<p>However, at this time environmental regulation had wide political support and neither Congress nor the courts would accept a direct challenge to the increasing role of these regulations. However, the Reagan era did bring many important changes to the regulatory apparatus. Reagan was able to halt action on acid rain for almost a decade, and he placed conservative appointees in top places. His administration promoted the increased use of monetary based cost-benefit analysis and other procedural hurdles to new regulation. His budgets reduced the funding available to regulators and reduced the level of enforcement available -- turning many regulations into dead letters. Reagan was able to effectively use the bully pulpit to promote anti-regulatory sentiments, and due to his administration these sentiments began to gain credence among those with influence in politics. Even before the Reagan Administration, many economists, lawyers, and scholars criticized the system of environmental regulation as inefficient. These critics claimed that it came at a high cost, micromanaged business actions, was overly rigid, and is a highly complex system that buries businesses in paperwork. Some of this criticism was, and to some extent still is true. Regulators have tended to use a command and control (regulations that ) style of regulation, when a more market-based approach of subsidies, taxes, cap&trade programs, and property rights may have done better. A command and control based system limits choice available to businesses and consumers. However, there are still places for traditional regulation. In a future post I will discuss the role of command and control type regulation in abating climate change. In the 80s conservative thinktanks and advocacy groups began to attack the system of regulation. The Heritage Foundation published a 1000 page report titled <em>Mandate For Leadership</em> which declared that "regulation threatens to destroy the private competitive free market economy" and that "the extraordinary growth of government ... has brought mounting costs to society, which, in turn have added to inflationary pressures, reduced productivity, discouraged new investment, and increased bureaucrats' intrusion into everyday life". The report put forward a "conservative's dream of doing away with government controls and abolishing federal regulatory agencies". For his part Reagan stated that "if they [the EPA] had their way you and I would have to live in rabbit holes or bird's nests". To fight these regulations Reagan undertook a strategy of obstruction of the environmental laws instead of directly challenging them. He and his administration downplayed the risks of harms to the environment and up-played the harms of the regulations to prevent the damage. The Reagan Administration also played Democratic interest groups off each other, with unions often in opposition to environmental laws. Reagan also centralized the production of regulations. He mandated increased direct oversight of the production of regulations by the White House. He also interfered with the decision making of regulators, signing Executive Order 12291 which required all regulations to pass a cost-benefit analysis. He also increased the power of the Office of Budget Management to review regulations and directed that office to prepare lists of regulations that should be repealed or amended. When making selections of people to head regulatory agencies Reagan often appointed hard-line conservatives. While the courts often opposed the administration, the courts started to give great weight to the Administration's "interpretations" of environmental laws. In <em>Chevron U.S.A., Inc. v. Natural Resources Defense Council , Inc</em> (1984) the Supreme Court ruled that the interpretations of regulatory agencies should be given great deference. The Court declared "If the Court determines Congress has not directly addressed the precise question at issue, the court does not simply impose its own construction of the statute . . . If the statute is silent or ambiguous with respect to the specific question, the issue for the court is whether the agency's answer is based on a permissible construction of the statute." The Reagan administration also gave birth to the first conservative opposition to climate change. The Carter Administration decided to provide funding to the then nacient field of climate change research. Reagan's budgets slashed this funding. Reagan's administration was of course also opposed to doing anything about the climate change threat, or promoting sustainable energy. <br />     Reagan also <a href="http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/ws/index.php?pid=40982">acted deregulated the natural gas industry</a>, although this was a continuation  of policies enacted by the previous administration, <a href="http://www.eia.gov/oil_gas/natural_gas/analysis_publications/ngmajorleg/ngact1978.html">such as the The Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978</a>. The most impoprtant change was to lift price controls and restrictions that kept gas prices low at the expense of reduced supply and widespread shortages.  This action was probably the most beneficial of all of the environmental policy changes of this era. The increase in natural gas production allowed utilities to swap oil for gas as a electricity generating fuel source. <a href="http://moslereconomics.com/2008/07/25/nat-gas/">This broke the cycle of oil price increases that drove the high inflation</a> of the time.</p>

<p>George H. W. Bush however though that environmental regulation needed expansion. <a href="http://millercenter.org/president/bush/essays/biography/4">An article describes his policy on that subject as follows</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Bush took the lead with the other significant piece of domestic legislation he signed while in office: the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990. Ironically, an environmental disaster aided his efforts; in March 1989, the Exxon Valdez oil tanker ran aground, and more than 10 million gallons of oil spilled into Prince William Sound in Alaska. The Exxon Valdez disaster made the public more receptive to the need for environmental protection. Bush also showed his support for the environment by appointing the first professional environmentalist to lead the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) when he chose William Reilly as its head in 1989.  <br />The Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 built on the first bill passed in 1963 and subsequent bills in 1970 and 1977. The 1990 amendments focused on three aspects of clean air: reducing urban smog, curbing acid rain, and eliminating industrial emissions of toxic chemicals. Although critics were concerned about the cost of the act and its effect on an already weakened economy, President Bush was deeply committed to environmental issues and claimed that by working with the business community to find innovative ways to improve the environment, the economy and the American people could both benefit. Congress passed the bill with significant support, and on November 15, 1990, President Bush signed the act</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, Reagan's opposition to environmental regulation had a lasting impact and the Tea Party movement brought this ideology back into the mainstream. The growth of this movement gave birth to an anti-environmentalism that is the main road block to action on climate change.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/executiveorder" class="p-category" rel="tag">#executiveorder</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/presidentbush" class="p-category" rel="tag">#presidentbush</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/reaganadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#reaganadministration</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/williamreilly" class="p-category" rel="tag">#williamreilly</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#executiveorder</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#presidentbush</category>
      <category>#reaganadministration</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#williamreilly</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Politics, Media, and the Public Opinion on Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/politics-media-and-the-public-opinion-on-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/politics-media-and-the-public-opinion-on-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 11:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>In this post I will discuss the role of the media and the viewpoints of politicians in  forming the public opinion on climate change. Public opinion about climate change has generally been more closely related to the opinions presented in the news media by politicians than the opinions of professional scientists. In 2006, when both political parties were considering climate change action, public belief in the mainstream view of climate science was at its pinnacle. More than 85 percent of the American population believed that humans were causing climate change at that time. [1. <em>See Merchants of Doubt: How a Handful of Scientists Obscured the Truth on Issues from Tobacco Smoke to Global Warming </em> page 169] The most prominent media coverage of the issue was positive towards the mainstream view. The popular documentary, “An Inconvenient Truth,” featuring former vice president and presidential candidate, Al Gore, was released that year and received much positive media coverage. A scientifically implausible, but alarming fictional account of the effects of climate change was brought to the public eye in the 2004 disaster movie, “<em>The Day After Tomorrow.</em>” Then president George W. Bush accepted the existence of human-caused climate change, although he did oppose the Kyoto Protocol agreement and his policy proposals focused on voluntary industry action. After the election of President Obama in 2008, the tone in the media changed. [2. See the book <em>Open for Business: Conservatives’ Opposition to Environmental Regulation</em> for a discussion of the development of right-wing opposition to climate change, the information on the Bush Administration can be found on page 318]. After the election of President Obama in 2008, the tone in the media changed. The Tea Party movement, formed out of a mix of populist New Right fiscal conservatives, libertarians and social conservatives, and this movement made opposition to climate change mitigation and other forms of environmental regulation a core goal [3. Page 2 of <em>Open for Business: Conservatives’ Opposition to Environmental Regulation</em>]. Climate change became a partisan political issue and the media used its informational role in a way that cast public doubt on the fundamentals of the climate issue. It is true that some of this may have been due to the role of controversial political figures in the climate change issue, and the fact that some environmental activists have used the climate change issue to advocate for other weakly related topics. However, the role of a rising conservativism in the climate change issue is certain. The political and inherently controversial nature of solutions to climate change were interwoven and confused with the scientific and factual nature of the problem itself. Politicians not happy with proposed solutions cast doubt on climate change and sowed doubt with the help of the media. Journalists would often balance a climate change interview with a scientist with a politician denying there was a problem. Presenting two unequal sides as similar in merit is not objectivity and it misleads the audience. However, all too often the news media has not taken the time to figure out the scientific boundary of the climate change issue and to acknowledge the difference between fact and fiction.</p>

<p>The possibility that the media has failed to inform the public on the real scientific <br />boundaries of the climate change issue is backed up by data. A 2012 study by progressive advocacy group Media Matters found that between August and November of 2012 (approximately the election season), 72 percent of the people featured in print in climate change stories were politicians and only five percent were climate scientists. In television media, just 6 percent of the guests on climate change stories were scientists.Many publications did not interview any climate experts. The survey found that “<em>ABC, NBC, Fox News, USA Today, The Wall Street Journal, San Jose Mercury News, Las Vegas Review-Journal,Denver Post, Dallas Morning News , the St. Petersburg-Tampa Bay Times, and the Des Moines Register did not interview or quote a single scientist on climate change.</em>”</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/kyotoprotocol" class="p-category" rel="tag">#kyotoprotocol</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mediamatters" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mediamatters</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newright" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newright</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/presidentobama" class="p-category" rel="tag">#presidentobama</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#kyotoprotocol</category>
      <category>#mediamatters</category>
      <category>#newright</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#presidentobama</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Political Foundations of Denialism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-political-foundations-of-denialism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-political-foundations-of-denialism</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 08:44:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>Just being able to define denialism does not tell us why denialist theories gain public support. I will analyze three possible reasons that denialist theories gain popularity: psychological biases, political biases, and deliberate misinformation campaigns by businesses that could be harmed by environmental regulation. I will show that all three factors play a part in climate change denialism and the news media plays a role in all three sources of denialism.</p>

<p><a href="http://scienceblogs.com/denialism/about/">Mark Hoofnagle argues</a> that a primary cause of denialism of all types is psychological biases, in particular the Dunning-Kruger effect. The Dunning-Kruger effect shows that individuals who lack knowledge in a field have a tendency to both have an over-inflated sense of their own knowledge and, more importantly, are unable to recognize true skill in that field. Hoofnagle says this bias allows “cranks” to appear who are unable to judge sources of information and instead believe and spread incorrect information. In the climate change issue, the Dunning-Kruger effect can help explain why individuals and media personalities with no science background will believe and promote incorrect theories about climatology.</p>

<p>Just as the Dunning-Kruger effect explanation would suggest, climate change cranks often show great inability to notice general trends in climate research and to detect expertise in the field. For example well-known climate change denialist Anthony Watts <a href="http://www.donotlink.com/pYV">discussed the “global cooling alarmism” of the 1970s</a> and argues that the popularity of the now discredited global cooling theory was similar to the current popularity of global warming theories. Watts provides a list of articles that he believes shows this-- all but two of which are popular works from newspapers and magazines, such as <em>Time</em>. However, a quick review of the relevant climatology of the time shows that Watts' claim is clearly incorrect, and that belief in imminent global cooling was a clear minority position.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">Linguist and progressive political analyst George Lakoff argues </a>that ideological bias can reduce an individual's belief in scientific facts. According to Lakoff, there is an ideologically significant difference between two forms of causation: direct causation and systemic causation. According to Lakoff:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Any application of force to something or someone that always produces an immediate  <br />change to that thing or person is direct causation....Systemic causation, because it is less obvious, is more important to understand. A systemic cause may be one of a number of multiple causes. It may require some special conditions. It may be indirect, working through a network of more direct causes. It may be probabilistic, occurring with a significantly high probability.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many areas of science that face large denialist ideology, including climate change, are dominated by systemic causation. Systemic causation is generally emphasized by the left in the political discourse, while both progressives and conservatives emphasize direct causation. Differences about causation can explain much of the opposition to climate change regulation that comes from conservatives (See Lakoff's book “Whose Freedom?” pages 118-130).</p>

<p>A third possible cause of the prevalence of denialist theories is industry-funded campaigns. Climate scientist Michael Mann argues that climate change denialism is largely politically motivated and caused by business interests with a financial stake in pollution regulation. The largest of these interests are the oil, gas, and coal industries. Mann, who has published some of the most controversial work on climate change and has faced substantial criticism from the popular press for his work, uses his own experience as a case study in in his book <em>The Hockey Stick and the Climate Wars: Dispatches from the Front Lines</em>. He discusses the vitriolic attacks that he received after publishing a paper introducing the "hockey stick" graph, which showed the dramatic increase in global temperatures after the industrial revolution.</p>

<p>The news media generally has four major roles that relate to climate change coverage. <br />There is the obvious informational role where viewers of media are told about an issue. There are also three more subtle roles: the agenda setting role, the framing role, and the priming role. As discussed in the paper <em>The agenda-setting function of mass media</em>, by agenda setting the media has the power to change not only direct opinions on an issue, but also opinions on “how much importance to attach to that issue”. <a href="http://www.utwente.nl/cw/theorieenoverzicht/Theory%20Clusters/Mass%20Media/Framing.doc">By framing the media determines how viewers perceive the wider social context of an issue</a>. Framing tells the viewer how to think about an issue. <a href="http://www.utwente.nl/cw/theorieenoverzicht/Theory%20Clusters/Mass%20Media/Priming.doc/">In priming, the media tells the viewer what prior context should be used to interpret the issue.</a> The way that the media carries out all three of its roles amplifies climate change denialism.</p>

<p>There are two types of claims relating to climate change that journalists and the media cover: positive claims and normative claims. A positive claim discusses how the world is and/or what the physical state of the world is. A normative claim discusses what the world should be like, or in other words, what the ethical course of action is in a given situation [1. See <em>The Science and Politics of Global Climate <br /><br />Change:A Guide to the Debate</em> for a good discussion of this]. Positive claims are at their core the domain of science and often have definite or clear right or <br />wrong answers that most experts agree upon. Positive claims can be easily resolved by empirical testing of scientific theories and observation. They are often the domain of philosophy and politics. Scientific results can inform debates over ethics and politics, but will never by themselves resolve these debates. At best, science can remove some options from consideration, but cannot tell us how to create policy or what the ethical life should be. It is possible that a good explanation of a thing may lead to both a scientific and ethical theory. I don't believe in a strict is-ought barrier. But the two domains are different to a degree. A different way of putting this is that, a full theory of climate change, will need to explain both the direct effects of CO2 emissions, and what we should do about it in the political realm. Scientists know a lot about the first question, but we know less about the second one. Even in regards to the purely factual elements of climate change responce -- such as economics -- our knowledge has many limits.</p>

<p>Because of these differences, journalists should cover positive and normative claims differently.The objective way for a journalist to cover a normative claim about ethics or politics is through a balanced approach. Each side in a philosophical or political debate should be given equal weight. However, the objective way to cover a positive claim is to give weight to arguments in proportion to the evidence on each side of the issue. Fringe ideas with weak evidence should not be given equal weight to strong ideas backed by evidence. Guidance on how journalists should judge the merits of different scientific claims can be found in a field that has encountered similar issues in determining when a scientific theory is worthy of attention-- the legal system. In <em>Daubert v. Merrell Dow Pharmaceuticals</em> (1993), the U.S. Supreme Court found that five traits should be used to determine if a scientific result is worthy of being entered as evidence in a legal case. According to the court, good science should be: 1) empirically testable, 2) published and peer-reviewed, 3) free of an error rate that limits its applicability or usefulness, 4) held to standards and controls regarding collection of data, and 5) should be generally accepted by the relevant scientific community.</p>

<p>All three of the theoretical models of how denialism can occur relate to the functioning of the media. In the Dunning-Kruger effect model of denialism, the media is important as prominent media personalities are vectors for dubious theories. In this view, the role of the media is one of lack of knowledge – it takes a certain level of expertise in science to even be able to tell what a science expert sounds like. Denialism comes through the informational role of the media.Journalists, politicians, and media personalities who deal with science often lack the expertise to tell opinion or propaganda from real science. Prominent media personalities often become cranks in a field and promote dubious theories to an unsuspecting audience. Media personalities have high charisma and a large, loyal audience, but often have little ability to evaluate science, or who is even a credible source of information on a scientific issue. For example, Hoofnagle argues that TV host Oprah Winfrey has become a promoter of denialist theories in medicine that lack scientific merit due to this phenomenon. Oprah's guests discussing medical issues have been a mix of qualified medical experts and non-expert writers promoting long debunked theories, such as a link between childhood vaccinations and autism, and the host seems to be unable to tell which are which. The media affects the interplay between political ideology and denialism in two ways. First, the framing effect is critical in the weighing of different forms of causation and how individual freedom is viewed. Furthermore, the media and journalists are often hesitant to contradict the standard opinions of one of the major political parties-- even if the balance of scientific facts contradicts that conventional wisdom. Media actions are the path through which industry attempts to influence public opinion to gain currency. For the public to view these attempts at influence as significant, or credible, a source of information that is reliable to the public must promote them and that's where the news media comes in. The agenda setting role is used in a way that makes the reality of human-caused climate change appear to be something that is in doubt and unimportant. The media generally does not give environmental issues the coverage and importance that they deserve. Climate change coverage in the news media on the four major television networks dropped between 2011 and 2012, even though the effects of climate change are becoming more drastic.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/georgelakoff" class="p-category" rel="tag">#georgelakoff</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/michaelmann" class="p-category" rel="tag">#michaelmann</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/oprahwinfrey" class="p-category" rel="tag">#oprahwinfrey</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/whosefreedom" class="p-category" rel="tag">#whosefreedom</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#georgelakoff</category>
      <category>#michaelmann</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#oprahwinfrey</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#whosefreedom</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Anatomy of Climate Change Denialism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-anatomy-of-climate-change-denialism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-anatomy-of-climate-change-denialism</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 15:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em><a href="http://scienceblogs.com/denialism/about/">According to science blogger Mark Hoofnagle</a>, “Denialism is the employment of rhetorical <br />tactics to give the appearance of argument or legitimate debate, when in actuality there is none.” He argues that these techniques are primarily <strong>“conspiracy, selectivity (cherry-picking), fake experts, impossible expectations (also known as moving goalposts), and general fallacies of logic.</strong>” Emphasis as in original source.</p>

<p>Climate scientist Michael Mann states that climate change denialist arguments fall into “six stages of denial”, in his book <em>The Hockey Stick and the Climate Wars: Dispatches from the Front Lines</em>. Climate change denialists have shifted down the stages of denial as the evidence for the mainstream view on climate change has become stronger-- but all six claims are regularly made. I argue that popular works and political commentators are the most likely to be in the first stages of denial and academic works in the social sciences are the most likely to use the arguments in the higher stages. The first stage is claims that argue that “CO2 is not actually increasing”. However, the rise in CO2 claimed by mainstream researchers has been confirmed by study after study and can be predicted by basic chemistry and physics relations. So, denialists have gradually had to abandon this argument. They then switched to claiming, as Mann puts it, “The increase has no impact on the climate since there is no convincing evidence of warming”. The warming effect of CO2 increases is a bit harder to calculate and predict accurately, but decades of  research on climate change since the 1970s has created a scientific consensus that human produced CO2 is causing potentially harmful levels of warming, so this argument has been slowly abandoned.In the next two steps, denialists try to claim that most observed warming is natural: “3) Even if there is warming, it is due to natural causes 4) Even if the warming cannot be explained by natural causes, the human impact is small, and the impact of continued greenhouse gas emissions will be minor.” But humans have been shown to be the cause of almost all climate change. Scientists have been better able to predict the effects of CO 2 emissions and the effects that they will have on the climate. “5) ...the changes are generally going to be good for us 6) ...it's too late to do anything about it , and/or a technological fix is bound to come along...“ These are the most nuanced of the “stages of denial”. All six of the steps in the “stages of denial” have been shown to be incorrect and are considered to be false by the great majority of scientists. Therefore, an argument that makes any of these claims can be classified as climate change denialism. A viewpoint on climate change that disputes these claims of denialists can be interpreted as concurring with the mainstream scientific view.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/co" class="p-category" rel="tag">#co</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/markhoofnagle" class="p-category" rel="tag">#markhoofnagle</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/michaelmann" class="p-category" rel="tag">#michaelmann</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#co</category>
      <category>#markhoofnagle</category>
      <category>#michaelmann</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Science Now</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/climate-change-science-now</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/climate-change-science-now</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 13:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>In this post I will discuss the current state of climate science. I will also show that there is a broad consensus among climate scientists that global warming is happening, is human caused and is harmful. I will also show that there is wide agreement about this in both the natural sciences as a whole, and in the social sciences.</p>

<p>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) was created in 1988 to study the possibility of climate change and its impacts [1. See page 2 of Archer, David, and Rahmstorf. The Climate Crisis: An Introductory Guide to Climate Change]. The first IPCC report, published in 1990, found that a human-caused increase in global temperatures was likely, but not conclusive. The IPCC also found that the evidence should be conclusive within a decade. In their 2007 assessment on the physical science basis of climate change the IPCC found that levels of three greenhouse gasses, carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrous oxide, in the atmosphere had increased dramatically since the industrial revolution. According to the IPCC, these increases in greenhouse gasses have warmed and changed the climate and are human caused with a very high probability. Out of the three, the effect of carbon dioxide is the most significant. Most CO2 emissions come from the burning of fossil fuels. Changes to the climate, caused by these gasses, will affect sea ice levels, create extreme weather patterns, and increase sea levels. Global temperatures have increased to a level not exceeded for the last 125,000 years. Current changes to the climate will have effects that could last for hundreds of years. If measures are not taken to reduce current emissions levels, significant additional climate change will almost certainly happen. <a href="http://climatechange.worldbank.org/content/climate-change-report-warns-dramatically-%20warmer-world-century">A 2012 report by the World Bank</a> found that if no actions are taken to mitigate climate change, then the climate will warm by at least 4 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels (climate during the year 1500).This will be a roughly equivalent level of climatic change as the difference between the last ice age and late 19 th century levels. <a href="http://www.exploratorium.edu/climate/primer/index.html">The difference between the ice-age temperatures and late 19th century levels</a> is between 4.2 C and 4.6 C. A 2009 paper <em>(A Safe Operating Space for Humanity</em> by Rockström et. al.) found that maintaining a climate and global ecosystem that is fundamentally similar to the one that has existed over the last 10,000 years will require the change in radiative forcing to be limited to 1 watt per square meter-- roughly equivalent to limiting CO 2 levels to 350 parts per-million. This is compared to current levels of 1.5 watts per square meter and approximately 390 parts per million. The same paper also found that biodiversity loss has already increased to more than 10 times a sustainable/desirable level and found human-caused disruptions to the nitrogen cycle that exceeded what ecosystems can sustain without severe disruption. More than 84 percent of scientists in all fields (including ones unrelated to climate change) agree that climate change is happening and is human caused according to <a href="http://www.people-%20press.org/2009/07/09/public-praises-science-scientists-fault-public-media/">a survey by the Pew Research center</a>.There is a general consensus on climate change among researchers in the natural sciences and a similar consensus exists in three social sciences: psychology, anthropology and sociology. Economics appears to be the one major field of science with a climate change skeptic majority. There is also a general consensus among researchers in the fields of engineering and health. Economics appears to be the one major field of science with a climate change skeptic majority.</p>

<p>There are few researchers in the natural sciences that reject the mainstream view on climate change. A 2010 survey (published as the article <em>Expert Credibility in Climate Change</em> in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.) shows that between 97 and 98 percent of climate scientists agree that climate change is happening and is human caused.This shows that there is a consensus among experts about climate change, in contrast to the great doubt about climate change among the general public. It was also found that the expertise of the scientists who are climate change doubters-- as measured by the number of published papers in the field of climatology-- is substantially below that of the researchers who accept the mainstream view. The report by the Pew Research Center studied the views of both members of the American general public and of scientists (from both the natural and social sciences) on issues relating to science. It found that Americans have high opinions of scientists and their work, but still disagree with the typical views of scientists on many important issues-- including the reality of human-caused climate change. Eighty-four percent of the scientists that Pew polled, selected from professional members of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, believe that human-caused climate change is happening.</p>

<p>No major scientific body in the natural sciences or medicine disagrees <br />with the mainstream climate change view [2. See page 68 of DiMento, Joseph F., and Pamela Doughman Climate Change: What It Means for Us, Our Children, and Our Grandchildren ]. A 2004 review of all 928 abstracts on climate change, published between 1993 and 2003, and included in the Institute for Scientific Information database, found that no article disputed the mainstream view on human-caused climate change. However, approximately 25% of the articles took a neutral view on this issue. [3. See Oreskes, Naomi, and Erik M. Conway. Merchants of Doubt: How a Handful of Scientists Obscured the Truth on Issues from Tobacco Smoke to Global Warming. New York: Bloomsbury, 2010.]</p>

<p>Viewpoints in the social sciences are more divided. Researchers in public health,psychology, anthropology and sociology generally agree with the mainstream view on human-caused climate change. However, a substantial number of economists object to the mainstream view. Three major U.S-based associations in the social sciences, <a href="http://www.aaanet.org/cmtes/commissions/CCTF/gcctf.cfm">the American Anthropological Association</a> [4. See Fiske, Shirley J. “AAA Global Climate Change Task Force Takes Shape.” Anthropology News Nov. 2011: 46], the <a href="http://www.apa.org/science/about/publications/climate-change.aspx">American Psychological Association</a>, and the <a href="http://www.asanet.org/about/taskforces/sociology_and_global_climate_change.cfm">American Sociological Association</a> have released statements or reports concurring with the mainstream view on human-caused climate change. Economists show a more skeptical view towards the mainstream natural science view of climate change impacts. <a href="http://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/jep.23.2.29">A 2009 literature review of estimates of the total economic effects of climate change</a>, published in major economics journals and written by economists, found that all but one took a denialist view of climate change, finding little or positive impacts of climate change. According to the same review, papers focusing on the cost of each ton of CO2 emitted found a general opinion of low, but non-zero impacts. This economics literature generally suggests that current climate change mitigation efforts in the European Union are too aggressive and will likely cost more than the effects that they attempt to prevent. The review found that in economics “estimates of the economic effects of greenhouse gas emissions have become less pessimistic over time. For the studies listed here, the estimates become less negative by 0.23 percent of GDP per year in which the study was done...Projections of future emissions and future climate change have become less severe over time—even though the public discourse has become shriller”. A 2008 paper by Frank Ackerman (<em>Climate Economics in Four Easy Pieces</em> in the journal <em>Development</em>) argued that economists misuse discounting, an accounting technique whereby costs incurred in the future are weighted lower than more recently incurred costs, and therefore underestimate the costs of climate change. Additionally, most economic analyses of the effects of climate change use the most likely outcome of climate change. However, it may be better to use less likely, higher risk outcomes as the basis for policy making for the same reasons that a business would buy insurance against a low risk, but potentially very damaging outcome, such as a fire. The author also states that climate change impacts things that are socially valuable, but very difficult to price, such as endangered wildlife.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americanpsychologicalassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americanpsychologicalassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americansociologicalassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americansociologicalassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/pewresearchcenter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#pewresearchcenter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#americanpsychologicalassociation</category>
      <category>#americansociologicalassociation</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#pewresearchcenter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are only some political ideologies compatible with science?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/are-only-some-political-ideologies-compatible-with-science</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/are-only-some-political-ideologies-compatible-with-science</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 19:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>In this post I will discuss the question of the political neutrality of science --- not in the climate change sceptic meaning of "scientists with grant money worshipping Al Gore -- but in meaning of asking if all political ideologies are compatible with  science. I will conclude that there are in fact some political ideologies that are so incompatible and these ideologies are therefore inherently prone to denialism. These are ideologies that theorize that an at least roughly ideal way of structuring society is possible and known, and that the goal of politics is to bring this society into existence. I will further argue that such ideologies are common. I will also argue that ideologies that argue for the continuous contesting of government policies and social structures are the most compatible with science and that one example of such an ideology that fits that bill is liberalism (defined in a philosophical sense that i will discuss later, not in the commonly used political sense). I argue that there are broadly three common political philosophies in the  United States: conservativism (made up of three ideologies that I will call social conservativism, reactionary conservativism and axiomatic libertarianism), liberalism (with subdivisions that I will call individualist liberalism, right-liberalism/consequentialist libertarianism, civic republicanism, and populist liberalism), and leftism (with various varients that I will discuss later). As I will discuss later   I will now futher discuss what I mean by these ideologies:</p>

<p>I would define conservativism as the political theory that contends that the either current or past institutions, or a part of this structure, is the ideal way to run society. Conservatism contends that these institutions need to be fought for and preserved. I think that conservativism has three broad types. The first is social conservatism , which contends that the social institutions, ie religion and the like, are at the core of an ideal society. This ideology tends to emphasize a strong degree of social conventionalism and adherence to and preservation of conventions and social norms, including norms of social status.This ideology demands a strong degree of social conformity, and rejection of behaviors termed deviant. It endorses traditional authority and obedience to this authority. Reactionary conservatism is similar but advocates returning to an old version of these institutions and rolling back reforms of them. Axiomatic libertarianism are the variants of libertarianism that advocate that the free market and the business system are the ideal institution that should run society. These libertarians argue that this can be known apriori, without the need for factual questioning. This line of reasoning can be seen most directly in the libertarianism of Ayn Rand, and of the more hardline variants of Austrian School libertarianism (eg. Von Mises and other followers of praxology).</p>

<p>Next I will discuss the nature of liberalism. Now, I do not define liberalism in the sense commonly used in American politics as a different word for left wing politics, or do I use the commonly proposed alternate definition that defines it as synonymous with libertarianism. Instead I will define it as the ideologies that argue for the ability for systematic challenging and questioning of social institutions and political power. It contends that their is no known approximately ideal institution or set of laws (and there will never be), and that the best we can do is allow for a wide range of  individual freedom, and ability to change institutions as our knowledge improves. If this happens we will have the best ability to eliminate social ills through improvements in our knowledge of the world. In my opinion liberalism has four variants. The first is individualist liberalism which works through maximizing the range of human rights that can be exercised without interference and by maximizing the effective capacity to use these rights. Right-liberalism/consquentilist libertarianism, is similar to individualist liberalism, but denies that the effective capacity to use the rights is necessary, as long as there is no direct interference, or constraints on use of rights. Civic republicanism opposes arbitrary power, and opposes all forms of interference that does not follow the interests and values of those that are subjected to it. Under this view all power and institutional policies must be subjected to effective means of contestment and public debate. Structural inequality must be opposed and conditions where one person is subject to the arbitrary will of another must be minimized, freedom from this type of domination is at the core of liberty in this view. Populist liberalism contends that all institutions must be subject to democracy and should follow the will of the people as determined by a fair democratic process that allows all voices to be heard equally.</p>

<p>The third political category, what I call leftism, is less a single ideology but instead a grouping of somewhat related left-wing ideologies. The commonality of these is that they are the set of non-liberal, but left wing ideologies. These ideologies tend to believe that there is a form of perfect justice that can be implemented. The first ideology I put in this category is what I would call leftist-populism. To define this I will go with the following <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Populism">definition of populism as an ideology that</a> "pits a virtuous and homogeneous people against a set of elites and dangerous ‘others’ who were together depicted as depriving (or attempting to deprive) the sovereign people of their rights, values, prosperity, identity, and voice". Leftist-populism extends this by assuming a struggle between the oppressed populace and the oppressor group. The next type of leftist ideology that I will discuss is identity politics leftism. This ideology focus on the struggle between an oppressed social group and the oppressing society. There are also radical forms of environmentalism that fall into the leftist category.</p>

<p>What does this have to do with acceptance of science? Well, science is fundamentally about questioning knowledge. This often means questioning knowledge that also bares on the functioning of institutions in society.A political ideology that is compatible with science must also allow for questioning of the institutions in society, and for questioning of the actions of the political system. It is not possible to neatly divide questions into the scientific and into the political. Open debate of knowledge in one area must mean open debate in the other. An ideology that believes that there is a perfect way to organize a society and that any one who questions it must be evil or otherwise flawed, is one that is also fundamentally incompatible with the knowledge produced by science.</p>

<p>As I will discuss in a later post, there is a strong historical relation between a liberal political system, and the development of science. The relative liberalism of the Renaissance in Italy gave birth to science as we know it today. The development of science fostered the development of political liberalism during the Enlightenment. The Enlightenment created a culture of questioning that enveloped both science and politics and that greatly expanded the scope of human knowledge and prosperity. It is impossible to have the benefits of science without an open and liberal political culture. The history of the Soviet Union shows this. Its economy lagged in large part due to the USSR's inability to take the knowledge produced by science into running its economy. This eventually was a major contributor to the downfall of the Soviet Union.</p>

<p>With regards to social conservativism some of this questioning will involve knowledge that challenges traditional values and institutions. With regards to the axiomatic libertarian perspective on conservativism this means that scientific discoveries will sometimes challenge the legitimacy of the market. And as I will discuss in a later post in this series, conservative ideologies have a general inability to take into account what has been termed <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">systemic causation</a>. Due to these factors it is not difficult to see where conservative denialism of climate change originates from.</p>

<p>However, it is possible to see how a left wing form of denialism can emerge based on leftism. Those ideologies tend to identify politics in terms of a simple oppressor-oppressed system. When scientific knowledge challenges the assumptions then denialsim can emerge.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/austrianschool" class="p-category" rel="tag">#austrianschool</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aynrand" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aynrand</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sovietunion" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sovietunion</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vonmises" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vonmises</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#austrianschool</category>
      <category>#aynrand</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#sovietunion</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vonmises</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of Renewable Energy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/the-beginning-of-renewable-energy</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 07:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>The first energy sources in wide use by human civilization were of course renewable, but in the late 19th century the foundations of the renewable energy industry as we know it were built. While the direct use of energy from wind and water are ancient, solar was the first renewable energy source to be widely researched for electricity production. This early investment in solar was driven primarily by the concerns I <a title="Early Doubts about the Future of Fossil Fuel Energy Supply" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/early-doubts-about-the-future-of-fossil-fuel-energy-supply/">mentioned in the last post</a> that coal supplies could run out. French researcher Augustine Mouchot wrote the following</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The time will arrive when the industry of Europe will cease to find those natural resources, so necessary for it. Petroleum springs and coal mines are not inexhaustible but are rapidly diminishing in many places. Will man, then, return to the power of water and wind? Or will he emigrate where the most powerful source of heat sends its rays to all? History will show what will come.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://solarenergy.com/power-panels/history-solar-energy">In 1860 a patent was granted to Mouchot</a> for inventing a system that could generate steam though solar energy and use it to run a motor --- an early concentrated solar energy system. With funding from the French government Mouchot worked on scaling this invention up to an industrial scale. Mouchot created prototype water pumps and refrigration systems using solar energy and worked on deploying this in sunny Algeria. This system relied on a set of parabolic mirrors. However, parabolic mirrors are strongly limited in size and therefore can only have limited production. This doomed Mouchot designs. In 1881 the French Ministry of Public Works comissioned a report on the economics of solar energy produced by Mouchot's method and found the method to not be economically viable. William Adams, then the deputy registrar for the English Crown in Bombay further improved Mouchot's design. He came up with an innovation that underlies most modern concentrated solar energy systems. Adams realized that the limits of system production and mirror size would pretty much go away if instead of simple parabolic mirrors the system used series of mirrors in a flat shape. Flat mirrors can easily be chained together in to a large, connected system. Adams' conducted this chaining by placing the mirrors in a circular arrangement and focusing the mirrors towards central point. This exact setup is known today as a power tower, and is still in widespread use for electricity production.  Adams' system used 17-by-10-inch flat mirrors, and with 72 of these mirrors he could run a conventional  2.5  horsepower steam engine during all daytime hours. He penned a book titled <em>Solar heat: A substitute for fuel in tropical countries for heating steam boilers, and other purposes</em> on this subject. While impressive, this method was not good enough to compete with coal as an energy source with the technology available to Adams. Around this time American engineer John Ericsson came up with a third way to design a concentrated solar system --- a parabolic trough. Through each trough runs a pipe and through the pipe runs water that is boiled by the solar heat. This design has large benefits in terms of cost and is currently the most common method for large scale commercial use. Adams eventually became disenchanted with solar energy and stopped working on the technology due to failure to come up with a practical way to put it to use. Mouchot failed to come up with an improved design of his method. However other researchers persisted with concentrated solar technology. Engineer Charles Tellier created a solar refrigeration method based around an ammonia coolant. The core of this method can be found in modern electric refrigerators, but usually without solar energy. Aubrey Eneas founded the first solar energy company in 1900 and sold solar powered irrigation systems. These system were effective, but their parabolic collectors could easily be damaged by weather, and the company soon failed due to the problem of collectors being damaged beyond repair.  Henry E. Willsie also attempted to commercialize solar power --- focusing on electricity generation. He designed a thermal energy storage system that allowed energy to be produced all day. This system was cost competitive with coal and was marketed as "designed for furnishing power for electric light and power, refrigerating and ice making, for milling and pumping at mines, and for other purposes where large amounts of power are required." However, solar still had one big disadvantage compared to coal. With almost all sustainable energy technologies (even with today's technology) the main cost is up-front. Solar collectors are large and expensive, but they don't need any fuel, and the labor costs involved in their maintenance are small. With coal, building the furnace is cheap , but the coal itself is expensive. This means that solar (and all other sustainable energy technology, including nuclear) have costs that are almost all fixed. That is the cost of running the system at any output is about the same as running it at any output. This increases the risk of an investment in such a tech and as we will see in later posts in this series, it has economic implications for the wide deployment of sustainable energy and the commercial pricing of it.</p>

<p>In 1876 the photovoltaic effect was observed to occur in selenium by William Adams. This discovery enabled the creation of the first solar cells. In 1883 inventor <a href="http://inventors.about.com/od/timelines/a/Photovoltaics.htm">Charles Fritts used that discovery to create the first solar photovoltaic cell</a>. This cell was very expensive and was far from competitive with coal and other fossil fuels. It also was very inefficient at converting sunlight to electricity compared to modern technology. Throughout the early 20th century, researchers refined their knowledge of the theoretical basis of the photovoltaic effect. However, none of these early photovoltaic cells were nearly as efficient as modern ones. Additionally, all of these earily cells were extremely expensive. It wasn't until the development of modern semiconductor fabrication technology that solar PV cells came down to a reasonable price.</p>

<p>Biomass and biofuels energy also had a substantial growth during this period. In fact, the first liquid automotive fuels were not petroleum but biofuels. William K. Vanderbilt favored ethanol due to its higher performance -- particularly in racing. For this reason car racing sports widely use alcohol fuels even today (although this is usually methanol, which is far to dangerous for consumer use). However all commercially viable biofuels (even today) use feed stocks that compete with food production. Due to this issue petroleum soon became the dominant fuel source.This triggered the first research into cellulose based fuels. In 1925 Henry Ford stated that “The fuel of the future is going to come from fruit like that sumac out by the road, or from apples, weeds, sawdust — almost anything.” But celluloseic fuels have turned out to be the renewable energy equivalent to fusion power. Always 30 years away, and always facing key failings. However, fission power actually works, conventional biofuels do not. The modern attempts to implement conventional biofuels have been completely disastrous due to the food versus fuel issue. Furthermore, due to the inherent limits to crop production it is unclear that any method could solve  these issues. I would suggest that biofuel production should be halted and that the production or importation of these fuels should be illegal even for hobbyist uses or research. Heavy research should be put into alternative ways to make synthetic fuels, further discussion of these methods will be discussed in later posts. History shows that our best energy bets can be found in the atom (I will discuss nuclear energy more in a later post),and in solar power.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aubreyeneas" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aubreyeneas</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/charlesfritts" class="p-category" rel="tag">#charlesfritts</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/henryford" class="p-category" rel="tag">#henryford</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/williamadams" class="p-category" rel="tag">#williamadams</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aubreyeneas</category>
      <category>#charlesfritts</category>
      <category>#henryford</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#williamadams</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Core Opinions on Fiscal Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/my-core-opinions-on-fiscal-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/my-core-opinions-on-fiscal-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 09:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I consider my economic beliefs generally in the <a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Post-Keynesian_economics">Post-Keynesian camp</a> (same general category as MMT but I'm not fully convinced of a few of the oddities of MMT over similar approaches).</p><p>1) Money is pretty much a product of the government and the taxation system. Money and markets can't exist outside of the state and pre-state economies were non-monetary gift economies. <br />
2) Government Bonds and currency (including bank reserves) are for all intensive purposes equivalent when a government issues its own currency and floats its currency freely (without any peg or gold standard or the like) . <br />
3) The only role that the issue of bonds serves in the economy over currency is interest rate targeting, a role that could easily be taken over by paying interest on bank reserves and funding the deficit by currency issue. <br />
4) A government with its own and floating currency can not be forced into involuntary default (as long as its debts are in its currency). <br />
5) Government deficits (when the government has its own and floating currency) have no impact beyond changing aggregate demand. They should only be judged by their impacts on unemployment, inflation and the like. <br />
6) Because of the previous, taxes can effectively be taken as destroying money, and spending can be taken as effectively creating money because currency is another government debt that isn't terribly different than bonds. However, this is not the way that governments usually account for their spending. But for all practical purposes taxing money out of the economy is the same as destroying it. <br />
7) All money is credit and all financial assets are a liability of some actor in the economy. Currency is a government liability that can be redeemed on tax day. A buyer, seller, and bank are involved in all transactions. <br />
8) Government spending creates financial assets. It does not crowd out private demand for a finite source of them. However, producing too many financial assets may produce inflation. <br />
9) The money multiplier is a meaningless accounting formality. The money supply is set by the level of demand that prevails at the current government policy and interest rate. Banks have ways of getting funding regardless of their current reserves (such as borrowing from the Fed). <br />
10) Financial regulation is critical to limiting lending by banks. <br />
11) The interest rate is a product of the central bank, and there is no natural interest rate. <br />
12) There is no natural level of unemployment, and by the right mix of policies a government can create full employment at all times. <br />
13) Taxes should be kept as the lowest rate that does not produce excessive inflation, given the current level of spending. <br />
14) Governments should run deficits to fight high unemployment and surpluses to fight inflation.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/governmentbonds" class="p-category" rel="tag">#governmentbonds</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mmt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mmt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#governmentbonds</category>
      <category>#mmt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
