<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23tv</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23tv&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>On the Game of Thrones Rape Scene Issue</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-game-of-thrones-rape-scene-issue</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 23:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3245498261_093141423b_b.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3245498261_093141423b_b.jpg" alt="3245498261_093141423b_b" width="1024" height="683" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2458"></a> </p>

<p>I've been seeing this issue invade Twitter and Facebook. I don't really have enough knowledge to evaluate the substance of the claim that the rape in the GOT episode was too much (I'm not a GOT watcher). But I'll chime in on the issue with a few points</p>

<p><strong>Note: When I talk of things like "free speech", "censorship" and "rights" in this post I mean ethics, not law. A number of the ethical rules I suggest regarding free speech would be difficult to encode into law.<br /></strong></p>

<p>1) Everyone has the right to criticize the media they watch. Others retain the right to dismiss the criticism as wrong headed. Criticism is not censorship.</p>

<p>2) Consumers of media have to right to not watch a TV show if they don't like it, or think that part of it is beyond the pale, or if they think it downplays rape. Even if wrong headed and irrational, the exercise of this preference is not censorship.</p>

<p>3) Censorship happens when this criticism turns into outside pressure, with two types of pressure counting. Direct coercion -- ie. by law and indirect coercion by deprivation of a generally shared resource.</p>

<p>4) I don't consider a publisher that exercises direct editorial control (such as a TV station) to be a generally shared resource. I'm fine if consumers try to lobby TV stations and other such publishers to make media that they like.</p>

<p>5) Things like YouTube, Twitter, and such are generally shared resources. I would consider an attempt to pressure YouTube into dropping clips of the rape scene to be an attempt at censorship, and unethical.</p>

<p>6) It seems to me like a lot of activists are under the impression that the best way to "avoid downplaying" rape is to purge the media and the arts of all references to it. Its a very ostrich head in sand way of looking at the issue and one that probably serves to actually downplay the issue. Rape happens, and art should reflect that.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>:Flickr user Sarah Reid <a href="https://flic.kr/p/5WN2yz">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>5WN2yz</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#tv</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why 100+ Mile Range TV Antennas Do Not Exist</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-100-mile-range-tv-antennas-do-not-exist</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-100-mile-range-tv-antennas-do-not-exist</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 11:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I'm in the market for an over-the-air TV antenna to go with a TV tuner, and while searching I've noticed more than a few sellers advertising antennas that can get ranges as high as 150 miles.   [caption id="attachment_1440" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/1802424443_21761d4caa_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/1802424443_21761d4caa_o-300x213.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user  anomalous4 &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3KgTZv</a>" width="300" height="213" class="size-medium wp-image-1440" /&gt; Image via Flickr user  anomalous4<br /><a href="https://flic.kr/p/3KgTZv%5B/caption%5DSuch">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3KgTZv[/<wbr></wbr>caption]Such</a> a thing would be neat as it would allow me reach signals from other cities. But it is too good to be true. Such a device would violate the laws of physics considering the methods used to broadcast TV signals. You will be unlikely to find an antenna that gets more than 60 miles of range, and getting more than 50 miles will come at a high price premium. However, there are lots of people who seem to have fallen for this scam and brought these devices. There are two clear issues that prevent the creation of such a device, at least at a reasonable price. The first is the inverse-square law  of light. Even assuming a flat Earth, a radio signal declines in proportion to square of the distance. Because TV broadcasts are information rich, the antenna needs to catch a lot of information from the broadcast. But the strength of the signal rapidly declines as the broadcast gets farther away. And as there are three dimensions of space that the signal is spreading out in, this change isn't merely linear -- its quadratic.  When the distance doubles the signal (and the cost of picking it up) quadruples. When the distance doubles, the signal reduces nine-fold, when the distance quadruples the signal reduces 16 fold.   There is a second, even more restrictive limit on the creation of a long range antenna -- the fact that the earth is curved. This curvature enforces a line of sight on radio transmissions and therefore sets a maximum range for radio transmissions. Were the broadcasting station merely suspended in space the signal would go out evenly in all directions. However, in the real world, the Earth provides an obstruction. Therefore, the signal is directional, and as the recipient of the signal moves farther away the curvature of the Earth means that he is facing in a direction that is blocked by the Earth. Therefore the recipient is unable to receive the signal past the line of sight.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scienceandtech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scienceandtech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#scienceandtech</category>
      <category>#tv</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
