<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=280</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=280&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>One Quote that Showcases A Core Problem with Libertarianism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/one-quote-that-showcases-a-core-problem-with-libertarianism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/one-quote-that-showcases-a-core-problem-with-libertarianism</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I just discovered this quote from libertarian commentator Lew Rockwell's website in an article by Walter E. Block.Keep in mind</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_708" align="alignright" width="267"] Image via Wikipedia and Dedicated to the Public Domain[/caption]</p>

<p>that Block is actually trying to argue for libertarianism but ends up presenting a reductio ad absurdum of the philosophy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“<a href="http://www.lewrockwell.com/2003/02/walter-e-block/turning-their-coats-for-the-state/">First, you are standing on the balcony of a 25th story high-rise apartment when, much to your dismay, you lose your footing and fall out. Happily, in your downward descent, you manage to grab onto a flagpole protruding from the 15th floor of the balcony of another apartment, 10 floors below. Unhappily, the owner of this apartment comes out to her balcony, states that you are [trespassing] by holding on to her flag pole, and demands that you let go (e.g., drop another 15 floors to your death)… the only proper questions which can be addressed in [the libertarian] philosophy are of the sort, if the flagpole hanger attempts to come in to the apartment, and the occupant shoots him for trespassing, Would the forces of law and order punish the home owner?… When put in this way, the answer is clear. The owner is in the right, and the trespasser in the wrong</a>.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote proves two things about libertarianism</p>
<ol><li>The ideology has very little to do with actually preserving liberty, but instead tries to redefine liberty as the right to back up business and property by force</li>
    <li>Libertarianism is more a theory of legitimizing power then a theory of freedom.</li>
</ol>
<p><!--more-->That quote and the rest of Block's writing show libertarianism is about preserving property and business at all costs rather than what any normal person would call liberty. By any reasonable definition of liberty shooting someone definitely results in a strong reduction of their liberty and such an action should only be justified under very extreme circumstances. The shooting in Block's thought experiment was certainly not proportionate. However, property takes absolute priority in libertarian ideology.As Block put it "<em>libertarianism is a theory concerned with the justified use of aggression, or violence, <strong>based on property rights</strong>, not morality</em>" (emphisis added). The corollary of this analysis is that libertarianism is about legitimizing power, not freedom. The libertarian ideology would give individuals and groups absolute power over an area, regardless of the effects on others. By my definition people are free to the extend that they have the largest possible range of capabilities that are not subject to be limited by arbitrary power by others. The libertarian ideology would concentrate power and this power would give others the ability in interfere in the lives of others without substantive check. The government is not the only powerful entity on earth and given the right circumstances private actors can wield great power. But according to a libertarian this power inequality is AOK as long as the property rights check out.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aok" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aok</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lewrockwell" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lewrockwell</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aok</category>
      <category>#lewrockwell</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do Traffic Laws Restrict Freedom: Why Laws and Liberty go Together</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/do-traffic-laws-restrict-freedom-why-laws-and-liberty-go</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/do-traffic-laws-restrict-freedom-why-laws-and-liberty-go</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 14:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It is fashionable to believe that all laws and government regulations are a restriction on liberty.In-fact, the opposite is true, a society without any law is one that lacks liberty. A well structured system of laws when administered and drafted by a government that is accountable to the public can greatly expand freedom by expanding the range of actions that a typical person can do without being subject to the risk of arbitrary interference. To see why think about traffic laws. If these laws did not exist then the road would be useless to everyone. In a world without traffic regulations one could just blaze down the road at 100MPH, thereby impacting everyone else who uses the road. The range of actions the other road uses can take is reduced. Freedom is limited in this situation because the lack of regulation allows one to conduct dangerous actions that affect all other users of the road. The bad driver has the power to arbitrarily interfere with others. By passing laws these harms can be restricted. These laws expand freedom because allowing increased usage of the road expands the range of actions that the typical person can take without being subject to the risk of interference from another.  <br /><!--more--></p>
<p>Additionally,imagine a society with no government and no laws.In this world a wealthy/powerful person could just hire a hit-man to take out an opponent and no one could stop him. He would have almost absolute power over others.This power over potential targets would be almost as absolute as that possessed by a dictator who could have anyone eliminated at will and is fundamentally similar in nature. If fact a large part of the difference between dictators and the leaders of democratic nations comes from the fact that dictators are not bound by the law. </p><p>When do laws harm freedom? When the laws are not made and enforced by an authority bound to govern in the interests of the populace by rule of law, democracy and legally enforced human rights. Laws made otherwise can become tools to govern, not liberate the populace. But when these conditions are met government regulation expand liberty, instead of reducing it.  </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Census Bureau Publishes Summary of State and Local Tax Revenues</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/census-bureau-publishes-summary-of-state-and-local-tax-revenues</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/census-bureau-publishes-summary-of-state-and-local-tax-revenues</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 08:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The U.S Census Bureau has published a summary of state and local tax revenues. It appears that they have increased throughout the recession. In my opinion, the positive benefits of stimulus at the federal level have been largely neutralized by austerity at the state level.</p>

<p>The Census Bureau press release announcing this summary is as follows (below the read more).<br /><!--more--></p>
<div class="rpuEmbedCode"><div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-3347e33a42760db59e1b920142cd0478-top" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<p><script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1MbO1" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite"></a><a href="http://s.tt/1MbO1" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>Census Bureau News: Quarterly Summary of State and Local Government Tax Revenue for 2013: 2nd Quarter</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1MbO1" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">PR Newswire</a>)</p>
<p class="rpuSnip">  
Download image U.S. Census Bureau Logo. (PRNewsFoto/U.S. Census Bureau) WASHINGTON, Sept. 24, 2013 /PRNewswire-USNewswire/ -- Quarterly Summary of State and Local Government Tax Revenue for 2013: 2nd Quarter — This summary shows quarterly tax revenue…  
</p></div></div><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><!--more--><!--break--><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode"><div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-3347e33a42760db59e1b920142cd0478-bottom" style="display:none;"> </div><div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: <a href="http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/221ba0da9f62756fcf6008aaebe84177" >http:/<wbr />/<wbr />www.repost.us/<wbr />article-preview/<wbr />hash/<wbr />221ba0da9f62756fcf6008aaebe84177</a> --></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/censusbureaulogo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#censusbureaulogo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#censusbureaulogo</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melt of Glacier Shows Impact of Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/melt-of-glacier-shows-impact-of-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/melt-of-glacier-shows-impact-of-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 22:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The following video shows the impact of global warming through the melt of a glacier. Via Repost video news.</p>
<div class="rpuEmbedCode"><div class="rpuArticle rpuRepost-db23f284602d0120d13708e813cbdd6d-top" style="margin:0;padding:0;">
<p><script src="https://1.rp-api.com/rjs/repost-article.js?3" type="text/javascript" data-cfasync="false"></script><a href="http://s.tt/1LR7Y" class="rpuThumb" rel="norewrite"></a><a href="http://s.tt/1LR7Y" class="rpuTitle" rel="norewrite"><strong>Swiss glacier shows climate change in action</strong></a> (via <a href="http://s.tt/1LR7Y" class="rpuHost" rel="norewrite">Repost Video News</a>)</p>
<p class="rpuSnip">  
The walk from Morteratsch station in Switzerland to the glacier of the same name used to be covered in ice, but it has been steadily shrinking for decades providing one of the clearest examples of climate change in action. Duration: 01:28  
</p></div></div><!-- put the "tease", "jump" or "more" break here --><hr id="system-readmore" style="display: none;"><!--more--><!--break--><hr class="at-page-break" style="display: none;"><div class="rpuEmbedCode"><div class="rpuArticle rpuRepostMain rpuRepost-db23f284602d0120d13708e813cbdd6d-bottom" style="display:none;"> </div><div style="display: none;"><!-- How to customize this embed: <a href="http://www.repost.us/article-preview/hash/93cdfd02601f21ac602c6981f2f306c0" >http:/<wbr />/<wbr />www.repost.us/<wbr />article-preview/<wbr />hash/<wbr />93cdfd02601f21ac602c6981f2f306c0</a> --></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/switzerland" class="p-category" rel="tag">#switzerland</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/viarepost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#viarepost</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#switzerland</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#viarepost</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America's History of Immigration and of Immigration Restriction</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/americas-history-of-immigration-and-of-immigration-restriction</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/americas-history-of-immigration-and-of-immigration-restriction</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 22:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The history of United States immigration policy has been one of historical contradictions. The United States is in a way a nation of immigrants restricting immigration.Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. British Puritans and Pilgrims migrated to the New World for religious liberty and settled in New England and founded the colonies of Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Connecticut. However, nativism has also been constant throughout U.S. history and is often tied to racism and nationalism--even in this nation of immigrants. This is despite the fact that immigration to the United States has brought great benefits to both the United States and other nations. Quaker immigrants settled Pennsylvania looking for religious freedom. Pennsylvania after Quaker settlement was the first colony to provide religious freedom to all and soon became home to individuals of many religions. The Dutch founded what is now New York City, but this land was eventually absorbed into the British Empire. New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Delaware attracted many Irish, German and Scandinavian immigrants. By 1790,almost-one half of the American population was not of British ancestry .[1. Szucs, Loretto Dennis, and Sandra Hargreaves Luebking. 2006. The source: a guidebook to American genealogy. Provo, UT: Ancestry.]<br /><!--more--><br />Restrictions on immigration by the British were a significant cause of the American Revolution. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither. . .“ After independence, the United States immigration laws were extremely permissive. The Naturalization Act of 1790, which was the first U. S. immigration law, placed no restrictions on immigration and allowed free whites to obtain citizenship after two years of residency in the United States.However, nationalistic fervor soon resulted in increased immigration restrictions. The more restrictive Naturalization Act of 1795 was passed as a result of fears that European immigrants could hold views that were counter to views of American liberty. In 1798 Congress passed the Alien and Sedition Acts, which extended the residency requirement to 14 years, along with enacting severe censorship of the press. This law was enacted because of a fear that French immigrants were fomenting rebellion and anarchy in the United States</p>

<p>In the mid to late 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had an almost free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, as well as immigrants from Asia. This migration was at its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine and during this time period about 60 million immigrants migrated from Europe. In 1911, almost 15 percent of the United States population was foreign born. <a title="Immigration Helps the Economy" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140503011041/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>22/<wbr></wbr>immigration-helps-economy/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;This immigration had substantial benefits for both nations. It fueled much of United States industrial development in the period before World War I and immigration from 1840 to 1920 was a primary contributor to American urbanization. The migrants tended to be unskilled labor of the type best suited to employment in industry, compared to the highly skilled craftsmen who made up the bulk of native workers. This is because labor is a limiting factor to economic output in nations with high development of capital and technology. The result of migration, therefore, is an increase in industrial capacity triggered by the easing of that limiting factor. While the additional supply of labor may reduce wages to some degree, the increase in production enabled by immigration exceeded the change in wages, so overall economic output increased.[2. (Borjas, George J., and Valerie A. Ramey)].Additionally, the nations where the migrants emigrated from received great benefits from their migration flows. Nations with limited capital and technology development compared to the available labor are the most likely to produce emigrants. <a title="Immigration Helps the Economy" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140503011041/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>22/<wbr></wbr>immigration-helps-economy/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;This migration drives local wages up. . <br />However, despite the benefits of immigration to the United States, nationalism and racism prompted policy changes that greatly restricted this migration after World War I. All throughout the period of high immigration strong nativistic sentiment was always present. Irish Catholics were of particular concern. Often the Catholic Church and its Irish followers were viewed as a threat to freedom and promoters of tyrannical institutions. Ireland was the largest single source of immigrants, and in 1850, 47 percent of foreign-born Americans were Irish.</p>

<p>Showing a typical view of the anti-Irish sentiments of the time, inventor and artist Samuel Morse argued that while previous immigrants to the United States were “lovers of liberty,” the new immigrants were “selected for a service to their tyrants, and by their tyrants, not for their affinity for liberty, but for their mental servitude and their docility towards their priests ”. he opposition to immigration of Morse and others was despite the fact that the Irish immigrants showed no real opposition to core freedoms and Irish American Catholics were very strong defenders of religious freedom. In-fact, Irish-American Catholics were generally the most committed to separation of church and state of all Catholics during the mid to late 19th century and brought their liberal beliefs to the European church. In the late 1850s, the Know-Nothing party became the first anti-immigrant, xenophobic party to gain substantial electoral victories.</p>

<p>Mexico started to play an increasingly important role in United states immigration policy starting with World War I and continuing to current times. America's restrictions on immigration from Mexico have been influenced by the degree that we have needed Mexican workers. The labor shortages of World War I meant fewer restrictions on Mexican immigration. But as unemployment rose and many Americans began looking for jobs during the Great Depression, mass deportation of Mexican workers began. World War II again brought labor shortages and a guest-worker program was initiated, called the Bracero Program. By 1964, when the program ended, more than 4.5 million Mexicans had participated. In the era after Bracero, two issues came to dominate the American policy debate on immigration: protecting the United States borders from terrorists and illegal immigration, particularly from Mexico. The 1965 Immigration and Nationality Act was the first major immigration legislation after the repeal of the Bracero program and loosened many of the racily motivated immigration quotas. There was an increasing influx of illegal immigration into the United States at this point and this immigration was argued to be driving down the wages of American workers. The 1986 Immigration and Reform Act gave amnesty to 2.7 million immigrants who were in the United States without legal authorization.</p>

<p>The debate over U.S/Mexico immigration has been marred by nationalistic rhetoric, but there is strong evidence that this immigration flow is in general of benefit to both nations. <a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/2522570?uid=3739552&uid=2&uid=4&uid=3739256&sid=21102668867717">A study authored by economist George Johnson did not find an any unemployment effect from Mexican immigration – including illegal immigration.</a> It also found that this immigration increases GDP. Some inequality effect, particularly in the long run, was seen. However, this inequality effect could be mitigated by government spending, services, and tax policy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/irishcatholics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#irishcatholics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mexico" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mexico</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyorkcity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyorkcity</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#irishcatholics</category>
      <category>#mexico</category>
      <category>#newyorkcity</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigration Helps the Economy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A great body of research done by economists and other researchers shows that immigration has a potentially great potential to benefit the economy. The cost of immigration restrictions <a href="http://www.cgdev.org/publication/economics-and-emigration-trillion-dollar-bills-sidewalk-working-paper-264">is a large fraction of global GDP (around 25 percent)</a> and one of the most costly. This global cost of the current restrictions on immigrants from poor nations migrating to richer nations is trillions of dollars per year. Immigration restrictions can increase global economic inequality, particularly between nations, but also within nations.<br /><!--more--></p>

<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither. . .“</p>

<p>This immigration has been clearly beneficial to the nation. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.tcd.ie%2FEconomics%2FTEP%2F2003_papers%2FTEPNo15KOR23.pdf&ei=hZA-UvjGIYyayQH45ID4AQ&usg=AFQjCNH6zbsRZWrNg1bhyvSEUUZwrpIkxA&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc">Economist Kevin O'Rourke found that</a> immigration from Europe to the United States and Canada in the 19th and early 20th centuries narrowed the wage gaps between developed nations and then developing European nations, such as Ireland, Norway, and Italy.In the mid to late 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had an almost free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, as well as immigrants from Asia. This migration was at its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. In 1911, almost 15 percent of the United States population was foreign born. This immigration had substantial benefits for both nations. It fueled much of United States industrial development in the period before World War I and immigration from 1840 to 1920 was a primary contributor to American urbanization. <a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w12900">The migrants tended to be unskilled labor of the type best suited to employment in industry</a>, compared to the highly skilled craftsmen who made up the bulk of native workers. This is because labor is a limiting factor to economic output in nations with high development of capital and technology. The result of migration, therefore, is an increase in industrial capacity triggered by the easing of that limiting factor.Additionally, the nations where the migrants emigrated from received great benefits from their migration flows. Nations with limited capital and technology development compared to the available labor are the most likely to produce emigrants. This migration drives local wages up. While emigration between 1870 and 1910 lowered the Irish labor force by 45 percent, the Italian by 39 percent, and the Norwegian by 24 percent, wages increased dramatically in those nations. Irish wages rose by almost 25%.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/canada" class="p-category" rel="tag">#canada</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/irishpotatofamine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#irishpotatofamine</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#canada</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#irishpotatofamine</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Papers Show How Global Warming Harms Agriculture</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 23:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Three recent papers looked into the effect that global warming has on our agricultural system, and found many possibly harmful impacts. Food price instability can be expected to increase and households and farmers in developing nations will feel the pain of a changing climate. Hundreds of thousands will face risk of starvation. Farmers in developed nations will face reduced agricultural output and possibly increased exposure to plant diseases. The papers I will discuss provide case studies into this issue through looking at the impacts that can be expected in Yemen, Australia and the Netherlands.<br /><!--more--><br />[caption id="attachment_624" align="alignright" width="365"] Graph from Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change[/caption]</p>

<p>The paper<a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0306919213001139"> <em>Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change</em></a> published in the journal Food Policy discusses the effect that global warming will have on the people of the Middle Eastern nation Yemen. The paper found substantial harms. Agricultural productivity will be reduced in Yemen and the cost of imported food will increase. 32% percent of Yemen's population is unable to afford enough food to meet their calorie requirements. Unfortunately, global warming can be expected to increase this problem.  An additional 224,000 people can be expected to face hunger in Yemen in an average year between 2010 and 2050 because of climate change. Rural populations will be the most strongly affected. This study uses the climate change models by the Model for Interdisciplinary Research on Climate and the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation which are based on the IPCC's A1B projection<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ipcc.ch%2Fpdf%2Fassessment-report%2Far4%2Fwg1%2Far4-wg1-spm.pdf&ei=ODY9UqWtOYSwyQHpx4GQBQ&usg=AFQjCNH3kgAs4cAqOcmHrYLSRHIUIbkouw&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc"> which predicts 2.8 degrees Celsius warming by the end of the century</a>.The A1B scenario assumes that substantial attempts will be made to convert from fossil fuels to clean energy but that a complete conversion will not be attempted. The harsher A1FI projection assumes that no substantial changes to energy policy will be made and predicts 4.0C warming by the turn of the century.</p>

<p>The paper <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1467-8489.12021/abstract;jsessionid=986D3D8963DAA5D9F2A14937CB6BB8BE.d02t02?systemMessage=Wiley+Online+Library+will+be+unavailable+for+approximately+4+hours+between+09%3A00+EDT+and+14%3A00+EDT+on+Saturday%2C+28+September+2013+as+we+make+upgrades+to+improve+our+services+to+you.+There+will+also+be+some+delays+to+online+publishing+between+25+to+28+September+2013.+We+apologize+for+the+inconvenience+and+appreciate+your+patience.+Thank+you+for+using+Wiley+Online+Library%21&userIsAuthenticated=false&deniedAccessCustomisedMessage="><em>Economic impacts of climate change on the Australian dairy sector</em></a> published in the Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics looks at how global warming will affect dairy production in Australia. This study finds that production of dairy products will be substantially reduced by climate change. Additionally, production will be pushed to the areas of the country that are least affected by global warming. This effect will be so strong that some of these mildly affected areas will actually increase production because they will gain a competitive advantage over the areas with the most damaged productivity.<a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0073602#s4"><em>Impact of Climate Change Effects on Contamination of Cereal Grains with Deoxynivalenol</em></a> looks at how global warming (with intensity based on the A1B) will affect the spread of fungus infestations responsible for wheat and corn deoxynivalenol contamination in the Netherlands. The paper found no nationwide change in fungus growth but some regions may experience changes and increases after 2040.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/australia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#australia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/middleeastern" class="p-category" rel="tag">#middleeastern</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/yemenchallenges" class="p-category" rel="tag">#yemenchallenges</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#s4</category>
      <category>#australia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#middleeastern</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#yemenchallenges</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am not trading in my iPad for a MS Surface</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-not-trading-in-my-ipad-for-a</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-i-am-not-trading-in-my-ipad-for-a</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 22:29:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Microsoft has announced that they will give a <a href="http://www.geekwire.com/2013/microsoft-offering-350-gift-cards-nonmicrosoft-device/">350 dollar gift certificate</a> to anyone who trades in an Ipad. This effectively means a free Surface RT [1. See this refurb tablet on sale from Microsoft <a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Surface-RT-Refurbished/productID.275706600"></a><a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Surface-RT-Refurbished/productID.275706600">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.microsoftstore.com/<wbr></wbr>store/<wbr></wbr>msusa/<wbr></wbr>en_US/<wbr></wbr>pdp/<wbr></wbr>Surface-RT-Refurbished/<wbr></wbr>productID.275706600</a> ]. Needless to say, I will not be taking Microsoft up on this offer. The tablet that I currently use is an iPad. If I had to reccomend a new tablet it would probably be one running the Android OS. To convince me to switch, Microsoft does not just have to persuade me that they have a product that is as good as the competition. They must show me a reason why it is worth my effort to give up the apps I currently use and other investments in Apple's platform. They are nowhere near being able to do this.</p><!--more--><p>Microsoft has two distinct products under the surface banner. Their cheapest tablet, the Surface RT in in the same league as a iPad. The surface pro is pretty much a laptop. Neither products give much reason to recommend them. Microsoft's surface RT has failed to provide a reasonable alternative to their major competitors in the tablet market, namely Apple and Android. It it more expensive and has a weaker selection of software than Android tablets. Despite the RT's cost, Microsoft has not been able to create the community or support that make Apple products successful. The Surface Pro is underpowered and overpriced compared to other laptops in the market and Microsoft's Windows 8 operating system is a flop.</p><p>The surface RT <a href="http://www.microsoftstore.com/store/msusa/en_US/pdp/Surface-RT/productID.275275300">sells for </a>about 350 dollars (reduced from over $500), <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2013/09/nvidia-unveils-the-tegra-note-brought-to-you-by-evga/">compared to 200</a> for a similar Android. It looks like an RT user gets almost nothing for this extra 150 dollars. The RT's hardware is lackluster and similar to lower priced Android tablets. <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us/storage">It has just 36 GB of storage</a>, over half of which is hogged by the operating system.Its battery life is also comprible to other tablets. The selection of applications available for the RT is much more limited than other tablets. <a href="http://reviews.cnet.com/tablets/microsoft-surface-rt/4505-3126_7-35332494.html">The Windows 8 app store is sparse </a>and because the RT is based on an ARM chipset normal Windows 8 software will not run on the RT. Microsoft seems to be trying to avoid discussion of this situation as the word "apps" appears exactly twice in the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/surface/en-us">company's promotional website</a>.Apple's success in the tablet market to due to the company's ability to provide great customer support and present their products as the cool alternative. Microsoft can do nether.  </p><p>Microsoft's Surface Pro sells for $700. What does your money get you? 64 GB of hard drive space, 4 GB Ram and a 3rd generation Intel Core i5. There are much better laptops avaiable at that price range.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gb" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gb</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/intelcore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#intelcore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/microsoftsurfacepro" class="p-category" rel="tag">#microsoftsurfacepro</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gb</category>
      <category>#intelcore</category>
      <category>#microsoftsurfacepro</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#rt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nuclear Energy Is the Safest Energy Source</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/nuclear-energy-is-the-safest-energy-source</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/nuclear-energy-is-the-safest-energy-source</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 22:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Nuclear energy Is the safest energy source in existence.<a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/FAQ_on_radioactivity_and_nuclear_technology"> It produces a lower number of deaths per trillion kilowatt hours produced than any other power source in use</a>, even beating out renewable energy sources.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Energy source                              Deaths/Trillion KWH<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:HEUraniumC.jpg"></a> <br />Coal (world, all uses)                         100,000 <br />Coal (world, electricity only)                60,000 <br />Coal (China, all uses)                        170,000 <br />Coal (USA, all uses)                          15,000 <br />Oil                                                    36,000 <br />Natural gas                                       4,000 <br />Biomass                                          12,000 <br />Peat                                                12,000 <br />Solar PV (rooftop)                             440 <br />Wind                                               150 <br />Hydro (world)                                    1,400 <br />Hydro (Europe)                                 100 <br />Nuclear                                            40</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/coalchina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#coalchina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hydroeurope" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hydroeurope</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#coalchina</category>
      <category>#hydroeurope</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Eliminate Poverty in the United States</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-best-way-to-eliminate-poverty-in-the-united-states</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-best-way-to-eliminate-poverty-in-the-united-states</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 21:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america/" title="Poverty: A Economic and Moral Crisis in America">As I have previously discussed</a>, poverty is a great problem in America.</p>
<p dir="ltr">To replace many of the current welfare programs that we have in the United States, I would recommend a basic income program along the lines of the negative income tax proposal created by the Nobel Prize winning economist Milton Friedman.</p><p dir="ltr">Every family would receive a sum of money from the federal government to make their income above the poverty line level. All income earned separately, apart from the federal government grant would be taxed at a flat rate to help pay for the program. This proposal would simplify the current welfare programs by replacing many of them with a single program. Because everyone would get to keep the income they earned by working, without effecting the lump sum paid to them, someone is always better off working. Also an income level just barely above the poverty line isn't enough to take away someone's motivation to work, since isn't very much money and wouldn't provide for many or any extras or luxuries.</p><p dir="ltr">This sum of money would be distributed through the federal income tax system as a refundable tax credit.  If you owed no taxes, instead of a tax credit, you would receive a grant check from the federal government.</p><!--more--><p dir="ltr">A negative income tax isn't just some idea that some economist came up with, during the 1960s and 70s this idea was seriously considered by the federal government. In 1969 Richard Nixon proposed a bill that would have created a basic income through a negative income tax system. The bill failed in the Senate.  The Johnson administration studied the possibility of a negative income tax and George McGovern proposed it during his failed 1972 presidential campaign.</p>
<p>This system would give the working poor a living wage that would not take away their motivation to work. To help the unemployed, I would recommend that we create a jobs program to help them. This could provide work and help the United States by improving its infrastructure and creating alternative energy projects. This would work like the Works Progress Administration, which was created during the Great Depression to reduce unemployment.  It constructed roads streets, parks and other public buildings.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/greatdepression" class="p-category" rel="tag">#greatdepression</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/richardnixon" class="p-category" rel="tag">#richardnixon</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worksprogressadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worksprogressadministration</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#greatdepression</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#richardnixon</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#worksprogressadministration</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
