<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23IPCC</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23IPCC&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change Science Now</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/climate-change-science-now</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/climate-change-science-now</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 13:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><em>This post is part of a series <a title="Blog Post Series on the History of Sustainable Energy and Climate Change Politics" href="https://theojones.name/index.php/blog-post-series-on-the-history-of-sustainable-energy-and-climate-change-politics/">on the history of the politics of sustainable energy</a> <br /></em>In this post I will discuss the current state of climate science. I will also show that there is a broad consensus among climate scientists that global warming is happening, is human caused and is harmful. I will also show that there is wide agreement about this in both the natural sciences as a whole, and in the social sciences.</p>

<p>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) was created in 1988 to study the possibility of climate change and its impacts [1. See page 2 of Archer, David, and Rahmstorf. The Climate Crisis: An Introductory Guide to Climate Change]. The first IPCC report, published in 1990, found that a human-caused increase in global temperatures was likely, but not conclusive. The IPCC also found that the evidence should be conclusive within a decade. In their 2007 assessment on the physical science basis of climate change the IPCC found that levels of three greenhouse gasses, carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrous oxide, in the atmosphere had increased dramatically since the industrial revolution. According to the IPCC, these increases in greenhouse gasses have warmed and changed the climate and are human caused with a very high probability. Out of the three, the effect of carbon dioxide is the most significant. Most CO2 emissions come from the burning of fossil fuels. Changes to the climate, caused by these gasses, will affect sea ice levels, create extreme weather patterns, and increase sea levels. Global temperatures have increased to a level not exceeded for the last 125,000 years. Current changes to the climate will have effects that could last for hundreds of years. If measures are not taken to reduce current emissions levels, significant additional climate change will almost certainly happen. <a href="http://climatechange.worldbank.org/content/climate-change-report-warns-dramatically-%20warmer-world-century">A 2012 report by the World Bank</a> found that if no actions are taken to mitigate climate change, then the climate will warm by at least 4 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels (climate during the year 1500).This will be a roughly equivalent level of climatic change as the difference between the last ice age and late 19 th century levels. <a href="http://www.exploratorium.edu/climate/primer/index.html">The difference between the ice-age temperatures and late 19th century levels</a> is between 4.2 C and 4.6 C. A 2009 paper <em>(A Safe Operating Space for Humanity</em> by Rockström et. al.) found that maintaining a climate and global ecosystem that is fundamentally similar to the one that has existed over the last 10,000 years will require the change in radiative forcing to be limited to 1 watt per square meter-- roughly equivalent to limiting CO 2 levels to 350 parts per-million. This is compared to current levels of 1.5 watts per square meter and approximately 390 parts per million. The same paper also found that biodiversity loss has already increased to more than 10 times a sustainable/desirable level and found human-caused disruptions to the nitrogen cycle that exceeded what ecosystems can sustain without severe disruption. More than 84 percent of scientists in all fields (including ones unrelated to climate change) agree that climate change is happening and is human caused according to <a href="http://www.people-%20press.org/2009/07/09/public-praises-science-scientists-fault-public-media/">a survey by the Pew Research center</a>.There is a general consensus on climate change among researchers in the natural sciences and a similar consensus exists in three social sciences: psychology, anthropology and sociology. Economics appears to be the one major field of science with a climate change skeptic majority. There is also a general consensus among researchers in the fields of engineering and health. Economics appears to be the one major field of science with a climate change skeptic majority.</p>

<p>There are few researchers in the natural sciences that reject the mainstream view on climate change. A 2010 survey (published as the article <em>Expert Credibility in Climate Change</em> in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences.) shows that between 97 and 98 percent of climate scientists agree that climate change is happening and is human caused.This shows that there is a consensus among experts about climate change, in contrast to the great doubt about climate change among the general public. It was also found that the expertise of the scientists who are climate change doubters-- as measured by the number of published papers in the field of climatology-- is substantially below that of the researchers who accept the mainstream view. The report by the Pew Research Center studied the views of both members of the American general public and of scientists (from both the natural and social sciences) on issues relating to science. It found that Americans have high opinions of scientists and their work, but still disagree with the typical views of scientists on many important issues-- including the reality of human-caused climate change. Eighty-four percent of the scientists that Pew polled, selected from professional members of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, believe that human-caused climate change is happening.</p>

<p>No major scientific body in the natural sciences or medicine disagrees <br />with the mainstream climate change view [2. See page 68 of DiMento, Joseph F., and Pamela Doughman Climate Change: What It Means for Us, Our Children, and Our Grandchildren ]. A 2004 review of all 928 abstracts on climate change, published between 1993 and 2003, and included in the Institute for Scientific Information database, found that no article disputed the mainstream view on human-caused climate change. However, approximately 25% of the articles took a neutral view on this issue. [3. See Oreskes, Naomi, and Erik M. Conway. Merchants of Doubt: How a Handful of Scientists Obscured the Truth on Issues from Tobacco Smoke to Global Warming. New York: Bloomsbury, 2010.]</p>

<p>Viewpoints in the social sciences are more divided. Researchers in public health,psychology, anthropology and sociology generally agree with the mainstream view on human-caused climate change. However, a substantial number of economists object to the mainstream view. Three major U.S-based associations in the social sciences, <a href="http://www.aaanet.org/cmtes/commissions/CCTF/gcctf.cfm">the American Anthropological Association</a> [4. See Fiske, Shirley J. “AAA Global Climate Change Task Force Takes Shape.” Anthropology News Nov. 2011: 46], the <a href="http://www.apa.org/science/about/publications/climate-change.aspx">American Psychological Association</a>, and the <a href="http://www.asanet.org/about/taskforces/sociology_and_global_climate_change.cfm">American Sociological Association</a> have released statements or reports concurring with the mainstream view on human-caused climate change. Economists show a more skeptical view towards the mainstream natural science view of climate change impacts. <a href="http://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/jep.23.2.29">A 2009 literature review of estimates of the total economic effects of climate change</a>, published in major economics journals and written by economists, found that all but one took a denialist view of climate change, finding little or positive impacts of climate change. According to the same review, papers focusing on the cost of each ton of CO2 emitted found a general opinion of low, but non-zero impacts. This economics literature generally suggests that current climate change mitigation efforts in the European Union are too aggressive and will likely cost more than the effects that they attempt to prevent. The review found that in economics “estimates of the economic effects of greenhouse gas emissions have become less pessimistic over time. For the studies listed here, the estimates become less negative by 0.23 percent of GDP per year in which the study was done...Projections of future emissions and future climate change have become less severe over time—even though the public discourse has become shriller”. A 2008 paper by Frank Ackerman (<em>Climate Economics in Four Easy Pieces</em> in the journal <em>Development</em>) argued that economists misuse discounting, an accounting technique whereby costs incurred in the future are weighted lower than more recently incurred costs, and therefore underestimate the costs of climate change. Additionally, most economic analyses of the effects of climate change use the most likely outcome of climate change. However, it may be better to use less likely, higher risk outcomes as the basis for policy making for the same reasons that a business would buy insurance against a low risk, but potentially very damaging outcome, such as a fire. The author also states that climate change impacts things that are socially valuable, but very difficult to price, such as endangered wildlife.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americanpsychologicalassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americanpsychologicalassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americansociologicalassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americansociologicalassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/pewresearchcenter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#pewresearchcenter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#americanpsychologicalassociation</category>
      <category>#americansociologicalassociation</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#pewresearchcenter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Study: Twitter Discussions Reflect Political Polarization on Climate Change</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-study-twitter-discussions-reflect-political-polarization-on-climate-change</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-study-twitter-discussions-reflect-political-polarization-on-climate-change</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 15:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A <a href="http://eprints.nottingham.ac.uk/2236/">study published this month</a> ,<em>Climate change on Twitter: topics, communities and conversations about the 2013 IPCC report</em>, looked into the debate about climate change on Twitter around the release of the latest Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change assessment.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_843" align="alignright" width="238"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:GRES-2.jpg"></a> Image Via Wikipedia.Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by the Free Software Foundation; with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.[/caption]</p>

<p>They analysed the content of  tweets that mentioned the IPCC. Most Twitter posts on climate change  Among their findings is the discovery of a clear political polarization in online discussions of this issue. The discussions largely fit into four topics, "relation to science, political campaigns, geography, and social meanings of climate change". Of particular frequency in this discussion is the debate over the carbon tax bill in Australia. The debate over the accuracy of the science strongly follows these political lines. The following two example tweets given in the paper illustrate this.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Australian" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Australian</a> PM thinks that if he doesn't read the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/IPCC" class="p-category" rel="tag">#IPCC</a> report then <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> is still crap. That's the way this government works.</p>
</blockquote><blockquote>
<p>Global Warming Scam unravelling by the day. IPCC exposed as corrupt liars. <a href="http://t.co/rotD07eIEX"></a><a href="http://t.co/rotD07eIEX">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>t.co/<wbr></wbr>rotD07eIEX</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/auspol" class="p-category" rel="tag">#auspol</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ausvotes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ausvotes</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the United States tweets followed liberal and conservative lines with conservative tweets outnumbering liberal ones two to one. The authors state that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The dominance of conservative-leaning hashtags in the US provide support for the theory that the country’s climate debate is in danger of becoming so polarized as to be described as a “logic schism”, in a similar manner to struggles over President Obama’s healthcare program.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/globalwarmingscam" class="p-category" rel="tag">#globalwarmingscam</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviawikipedia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviawikipedia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/us" class="p-category" rel="tag">#us</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Australian</category>
      <category>#IPCC</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#auspol</category>
      <category>#ausvotes</category>
      <category>#globalwarmingscam</category>
      <category>#imageviawikipedia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#us</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Papers Show How Global Warming Harms Agriculture</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 23:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Three recent papers looked into the effect that global warming has on our agricultural system, and found many possibly harmful impacts. Food price instability can be expected to increase and households and farmers in developing nations will feel the pain of a changing climate. Hundreds of thousands will face risk of starvation. Farmers in developed nations will face reduced agricultural output and possibly increased exposure to plant diseases. The papers I will discuss provide case studies into this issue through looking at the impacts that can be expected in Yemen, Australia and the Netherlands.<br /><!--more--><br />[caption id="attachment_624" align="alignright" width="365"] Graph from Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change[/caption]</p>

<p>The paper<a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0306919213001139"> <em>Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change</em></a> published in the journal Food Policy discusses the effect that global warming will have on the people of the Middle Eastern nation Yemen. The paper found substantial harms. Agricultural productivity will be reduced in Yemen and the cost of imported food will increase. 32% percent of Yemen's population is unable to afford enough food to meet their calorie requirements. Unfortunately, global warming can be expected to increase this problem.  An additional 224,000 people can be expected to face hunger in Yemen in an average year between 2010 and 2050 because of climate change. Rural populations will be the most strongly affected. This study uses the climate change models by the Model for Interdisciplinary Research on Climate and the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation which are based on the IPCC's A1B projection<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ipcc.ch%2Fpdf%2Fassessment-report%2Far4%2Fwg1%2Far4-wg1-spm.pdf&ei=ODY9UqWtOYSwyQHpx4GQBQ&usg=AFQjCNH3kgAs4cAqOcmHrYLSRHIUIbkouw&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc"> which predicts 2.8 degrees Celsius warming by the end of the century</a>.The A1B scenario assumes that substantial attempts will be made to convert from fossil fuels to clean energy but that a complete conversion will not be attempted. The harsher A1FI projection assumes that no substantial changes to energy policy will be made and predicts 4.0C warming by the turn of the century.</p>

<p>The paper <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1467-8489.12021/abstract;jsessionid=986D3D8963DAA5D9F2A14937CB6BB8BE.d02t02?systemMessage=Wiley+Online+Library+will+be+unavailable+for+approximately+4+hours+between+09%3A00+EDT+and+14%3A00+EDT+on+Saturday%2C+28+September+2013+as+we+make+upgrades+to+improve+our+services+to+you.+There+will+also+be+some+delays+to+online+publishing+between+25+to+28+September+2013.+We+apologize+for+the+inconvenience+and+appreciate+your+patience.+Thank+you+for+using+Wiley+Online+Library%21&userIsAuthenticated=false&deniedAccessCustomisedMessage="><em>Economic impacts of climate change on the Australian dairy sector</em></a> published in the Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics looks at how global warming will affect dairy production in Australia. This study finds that production of dairy products will be substantially reduced by climate change. Additionally, production will be pushed to the areas of the country that are least affected by global warming. This effect will be so strong that some of these mildly affected areas will actually increase production because they will gain a competitive advantage over the areas with the most damaged productivity.<a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0073602#s4"><em>Impact of Climate Change Effects on Contamination of Cereal Grains with Deoxynivalenol</em></a> looks at how global warming (with intensity based on the A1B) will affect the spread of fungus infestations responsible for wheat and corn deoxynivalenol contamination in the Netherlands. The paper found no nationwide change in fungus growth but some regions may experience changes and increases after 2040.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/australia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#australia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/middleeastern" class="p-category" rel="tag">#middleeastern</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/yemenchallenges" class="p-category" rel="tag">#yemenchallenges</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#s4</category>
      <category>#australia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#middleeastern</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#yemenchallenges</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Response to an Article from the Cato Institute on Global Warming</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-response-to-an-article-from-the-cato-institute-on</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/a-response-to-an-article-from-the-cato-institute-on</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 00:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Cato institute recently published an article titled <em><a href="http://www.cato.org/publications/commentary/carbon-tax-would-make-no-sense">A Carbon Tax Would Make No Sense</a></em> that represents many of the most common arguments made by climate change denialists. In this post I will do a analysis of why these arguments are wrong.</p>
<!--more--><blockquote>
<p>Do you know how much carbon dioxide is in the atmosphere? It is a little less than 400 parts per million. Do you know what the optimum level of carbon dioxide is? No one does, even though some have the extreme conceit to think they do.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What is the optimal level of CO2. Any level between 250-350 parts per million.Climate change is harmful because of the rapid rate of temperature change it has caused, not the absolute level of temperature created. Ecosystems and human civilization have developed around a relitively stable climate since the last ice age. The current rate of change to this climate is almost unprecedented in the Earth's geologic history and every time a similarly rapid change has happened, the result has been a mass extinction and a widespread disruption of ecosystems. <a href="http://www.ecologyandsociety.org/vol14/iss2/art32/main.html">A CO2 concentration at this level would stabilize</a> the climate at a level that is consistent with what ecosystems have evolved to handle and what human infrastructure is adapted to handle. The human economy is extremely dependent on this stable ecosystem. In fact it could be said that the economy is a wholly-owned subsidiary of the global ecosystem.These impacts will be disastrous for human health, agriculture and the economy. The 2007 IPCC assessment contains a excellent diagram that summarizes these impacts. <br /><a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg2/en/figure-spm-2.html"></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earth’s atmosphere is 78 percent nitrogen, about 21 percent oxygen, less than 1 percent argon, and only 0.038 percent carbon dioxide — plus a variable amount of water vapor. The gas is necessary for life. Plants cannot grow without it. .... There is evidence that as carbon-dioxide levels have risen, plants are growing faster, which means cheaper food.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A small amount of CO2 can do a lot as this video via <a href="http://climateplace.org">climateplace.org</a> shows</p>

<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/81FHVrXgzuA" height="360" width="480" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>

<p>First of all the claim <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-plant-food-advanced.htm">that increased CO2 in the atmosphere will increase agricultural productivity is false</a>. Second, plants are also sensitive to temperature which means more expenive food. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>When fossil fuels are burned, they produce small amounts of carbon dioxide but large amounts of water vapor. Increases in water vapor show up as more cloud cover. Clouds both trap heat (which increases warming) and reflect sunlight (which reduces warming), but there is no consensus about which effect is greater.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Want to hear something that will rock your world? Climatologists know clouds exist and have taken them into account in their models.In fact, the IPCC report devotes <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg1/en/ch1s1-5-2.html">a whole section</a> to the effect of clouds on the climate system. Oh wait not just one section <a href="http://www.ipcc.ch/publications_and_data/ar4/wg1/en/ch8s8-6-3-2.html">but two sections</a>. The result of this research into the clould feedback is that clouds can have a significant effect of the climate system but don't even come close to being able to neutralize the effect of a CO2 increase.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is known with a high degree of certainty is that at times in the past, the Earth has been both warmer and cooler at current levels of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/co2-higher-in-past-intermediate.htm">Compare CO2 levels for the past 500 million years to temperature. <br /></a> </p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is also known is the current climate models have a dreadful record of prediction.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Climate models have actually been very accurate. <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/Hansen-1988-prediction-advanced.htm">Compare Hansen's 1988 predictions</a></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_575" align="alignnone" width="433"]<a href="https://theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Hansen88Temps.jpg"></a> Note scenario B.[/caption]</p>

<p><a title="What is the Evidence of Global Warming? Part one: How we know that the temperature is increasing." href="https://theojones.name/index.php/what-is-the-evidence-of-global-warming-part-one-how-we-know-that-the-temperature-is-increasing/">to what actually happened. <br /></a></p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_159" align="alignnone" width="410"] Image Description from NASA:Graph of global annual surface temperatures relative to 1951-1980 mean temperature. Air and ocean data from weather stations, ships and satellites. The 2007 point is the 11-month anomaly.[/caption]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Twenty years ago, we were told that the Earth’s temperatures would steadily rise from then on, yet there has been no average warming for the past 16 years — oops.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/graphics.php?g=47">Bzzzt</a>! Looks like you still haven't had any luck at understanding climate science.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_569" align="alignright" width="1024"] One of the most common misunderstandings amongst climate change "skeptics" is the difference between short-term noise and long-term signal. This animation shows how the same temperature data (green) that is used to determine the long-term global surface air warming trend of 0.16°C per decade (red) can be used inappropriately to "cherrypick" short time periods that show a cooling trend simply because the endpoints are carefully chosen and the trend is dominated by short-term noise in the data (blue steps). Isn't it strange how five periods of cooling can add up to a clear warming trend over the last 4 decades? Several factors can have a large impact on short-term temperatures, such as oceanic cycles like the El Niño Southern Oscillation (ENSO) or the 11-year solar cycle. These short-term cycles don't have long-term effects on the Earth's temperature, unlike the continuing upward trend caused by global warming from human greenhouse gas emissions. Image and caption via Skeptical Science Graphics by Skeptical Science is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.[/caption]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A carbon tax has real costs to the American economy. Energy prices and food prices would be higher, and virtually everything else that people consume would cost more. The results of higher prices are a lower standard of living, less economic opportunity, lower real wages and fewer jobs. All for what?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is of course why the Cato Institute thinks <a href="http://www.cato.org/blog/unfair-criticism-fair-tax">replacing the current tax system with a sales tax is a "pro-growth"</a> option.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an economist, I make no pretense to knowing what the optimum temperature of the earth ought to be and what the optimal level of carbon dioxide should be.....</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then why tell policymakers to ignore the advice of an overwhelming majority of researchers in the natural sciences on the subject?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an economist, though, I am prepared to make judgments as to whether a proposed tax is likely to have more benefits than costs.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You seem to be doing this by assuming away the costs of climate change. <a href="http://economics.about.com/od/termsbeginningwith1/g/assume_a_can_opener.htm">Ever hear of the joke about when an economist, a chemist and a physicist got struck on an island</a>?" <em>A physicist, a chemist and an economist are stranded on an island, with nothing to eat. A can of soup washes ashore. The physicist says, "Let's smash the can open with a rock." The chemist says, "Let's build a fire and heat the can first." The economist says, "Let's assume that we have a can-opener..."</em> "</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/bzzztlooks" class="p-category" rel="tag">#bzzztlooks</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/creativecommonsattribution" class="p-category" rel="tag">#creativecommonsattribution</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/elni" class="p-category" rel="tag">#elni</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#bzzztlooks</category>
      <category>#creativecommonsattribution</category>
      <category>#elni</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Climate Change Science New?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/is-climate-change-science-new</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/is-climate-change-science-new</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 13:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Is the idea of global warming a new concept--just a fad-- something dreamed up by tree huggers and Al Gore with scientists jumping on the propaganda bandwagon? Climate change denialists, like <a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/">Anthony Watts</a> [1. See for instance this article <a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2011/06/25/the-end-is-near-for-faith-in-agw/"></a><a href="http://wattsupwiththat.com/2011/06/25/the-end-is-near-for-faith-in-agw/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>wattsupwiththat.com/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>25/<wbr></wbr>the-end-is-near-for-faith-in-agw/<wbr></wbr></a>], would have you believe that. But the truth is scientists have been studying it for more than 100 years.</p>

<p>The first scientist that theorized the possibility that the combustion of coal fuels could result in a global increase in temperature was chemist Svante Arrhenius,</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_105" align="alignright" width="239"] Svante Arrhenius (<a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Arrhenius2.jpg">Image from Wikimedia Commons</a>)[/caption]</p>

<p><a href="http://www.aip.org/history/climate/co2.htm">who in 1896 theorized that coal burning could warm the climate at a scale similar to the effect caused by geologic sources</a>, such as volcanoes. He first estimated that a carbon dioxide increase sufficient to double CO2, and thereby increase global temperatures by 5 degrees Celsius, would take a few thousand years. By 1908, he had reduced this estimate to a few hundred years. However, Arrhenius' model of the climate was simplistic and the possibility that human activity and changes in CO2 level could increase global temperature was disregarded until the 1950s.</p>

<p>During that decade, new models were created that added support to this theory, but the evidence was still not conclusive. In the late 1970s, this began to change. Computers allowed the creation of accurate and detailed estimates of the possibility of human-caused climate change, and these estimates were calculated and widely accepted. In 1979, the United States National Academy of Sciences released a report warning of human-caused climate change [2. Archer, David, and Stefan Rahmstorf. The climate crisis: an introductory guide to climate change. New York: Cambridge University Press, 2010. Page x.], marking the first general acceptance of this theory.</p>

<p>The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) was created in 1988 to study the possibility of climate change and its impacts. The first IPCC report, published in 1990, found that a human-caused increase in global temperatures was likely, but not conclusive. The IPCC also found that the evidence should be conclusive within a decade. In their 2007 assessment on the physical science basis of climate change, the fourth and most recent assessment available at this time, the IPCC found that levels of three greenhouse gasses, carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrous oxide, in the atmosphere had increased dramatically since the Industrial Revolution. According to the IPCC, these increases in greenhouse gasses have warmed and changed the climate and are human caused with a very high probability. Out of the three, the effect of carbon dioxide is the most significant.</p>

<p>Over 97 percent of climate scientists agree that human-caused climate change is happening and has the potential to cause severe harm. Some might say that this means nothing. But I believe that when 97 percent of scientists believe something, we should listen, especially when there is a whole century of evidence to back them up.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/algore" class="p-category" rel="tag">#algore</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/industrialrevolution" class="p-category" rel="tag">#industrialrevolution</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/svantearrhenius" class="p-category" rel="tag">#svantearrhenius</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#algore</category>
      <category>#industrialrevolution</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#svantearrhenius</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
