<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23mmt</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23mmt&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>My Core Opinions on Fiscal Policy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/my-core-opinions-on-fiscal-policy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/my-core-opinions-on-fiscal-policy</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 09:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>I consider my economic beliefs generally in the <a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Post-Keynesian_economics">Post-Keynesian camp</a> (same general category as MMT but I'm not fully convinced of a few of the oddities of MMT over similar approaches).</p><p>1) Money is pretty much a product of the government and the taxation system. Money and markets can't exist outside of the state and pre-state economies were non-monetary gift economies. <br />
2) Government Bonds and currency (including bank reserves) are for all intensive purposes equivalent when a government issues its own currency and floats its currency freely (without any peg or gold standard or the like) . <br />
3) The only role that the issue of bonds serves in the economy over currency is interest rate targeting, a role that could easily be taken over by paying interest on bank reserves and funding the deficit by currency issue. <br />
4) A government with its own and floating currency can not be forced into involuntary default (as long as its debts are in its currency). <br />
5) Government deficits (when the government has its own and floating currency) have no impact beyond changing aggregate demand. They should only be judged by their impacts on unemployment, inflation and the like. <br />
6) Because of the previous, taxes can effectively be taken as destroying money, and spending can be taken as effectively creating money because currency is another government debt that isn't terribly different than bonds. However, this is not the way that governments usually account for their spending. But for all practical purposes taxing money out of the economy is the same as destroying it. <br />
7) All money is credit and all financial assets are a liability of some actor in the economy. Currency is a government liability that can be redeemed on tax day. A buyer, seller, and bank are involved in all transactions. <br />
8) Government spending creates financial assets. It does not crowd out private demand for a finite source of them. However, producing too many financial assets may produce inflation. <br />
9) The money multiplier is a meaningless accounting formality. The money supply is set by the level of demand that prevails at the current government policy and interest rate. Banks have ways of getting funding regardless of their current reserves (such as borrowing from the Fed). <br />
10) Financial regulation is critical to limiting lending by banks. <br />
11) The interest rate is a product of the central bank, and there is no natural interest rate. <br />
12) There is no natural level of unemployment, and by the right mix of policies a government can create full employment at all times. <br />
13) Taxes should be kept as the lowest rate that does not produce excessive inflation, given the current level of spending. <br />
14) Governments should run deficits to fight high unemployment and surpluses to fight inflation.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/governmentbonds" class="p-category" rel="tag">#governmentbonds</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mmt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mmt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#governmentbonds</category>
      <category>#mmt</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
