<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23gamergate&amp;_t=rss&amp;offset=0" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The dangers and ramifications of doxxing and swatting</title>
      <link>http://www.gamezone.com/originals/the-dangers-and-ramifications-of-doxxing-and-swatting</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-dangers-and-ramifications-of-doxxing-and-swatting</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 23:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"If there’s one thing we’ve learned from the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> debate, it’s that people -- on both sides -- are being harassed. I’m not just referring to tweets and emails saying rotten things, but the leaking of personal information for everyone to see, also referred to as doxxing. Even before Gamergate, doxxing and swatting (filing a false report of a critical incident in which response units, including SWAT and bomb squads, are deployed) have been tactics used to harass people in the gaming community -- mostly pro gamers."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I've deployed twitter blocklists like GG autoblocker and...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-deployed-twitter-blocklists-like-gg-autoblocker-and</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-deployed-twitter-blocklists-like-gg-autoblocker-and</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 22:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I've deployed twitter blocklists (like GG autoblocker, and the A+ blocklist) because I've gotten a bit of trolling because of tweeting about controversial topics (like gamergate). And I'm a man with ~4000 followers. But even despite a smallish audience and my gender, the trolling was annoying enough. And the blocklists shut the trolls up. I'm not totally a fan of them -- the method of adding accounts to the lists seems more aggressive than a Klingon with an anger management problem -- but its better than nothing. Really, these twitter blocklists are like some of the first spam blocklists. Problematic in how they decided to add ip addresses to the killfile, but good enough at killing spammers to make it worth it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/twitter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#twitter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#twitter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do you tell the difference between Twitter's...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-do-you-tell-the-difference-between-twitters</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-do-you-tell-the-difference-between-twitters</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 03:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>How do you tell the difference between Twitter's new killfile options and McCarthyist censorship?  In one Commie McRed was prevented from talking to people who what to hear what he has to say. In the other, Gater McAsshole is being stopped from spewing to a captive audience who doesn't want to listen to him. Freedom of speech doesn't guarantee an audience. There will be people who don't want to hear what you have to say, and its their right to tune you out (as long as they don't try to stop you from reaching those who do want to hear you). McCarthyism was firing people for being part of the communist party. This twitter feature is more like telling your secretary you want all mailings from the communist party thrown away.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/censorship" class="p-category" rel="tag">#censorship</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/twitter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#twitter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#censorship</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#twitter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When does censorship occur?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/when-does-censorship-occur</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/when-does-censorship-occur</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 15:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A lot of people try to pretend that censorship is something that can only exist when done by governments, that private actors cannot affect free speech in any meaningful way. This is absurd in my point of view. A right does not meaningfully exist if it cannot be effectively exercised. And private actors can easily put restraints on speakers that can make it very difficult to effectively participate<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3992988737_bebac07fb4_b.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2451" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3992988737_bebac07fb4_b-300x189.jpg" alt="3992988737_bebac07fb4_b" width="300" height="189"></a> in politics or partake in free speech. The "freedom of speech isn't freedom of consequences" rejoinder that is commonly heard on internet debates isn't much better either. All censorship works by imposing consequences. The question on free speech is simply, what consequences are acceptable. On the other extreme, there are a lot of people who seem to act like that all criticism of a work they like is an attempt at censorship. This is at the very least a self-contradictory (although there is the easy to over-apply aside that an overly toxic social attitude towards a set of idea can make it very difficult to express them). A much better boundary for free speech versus censorship would be external versus internal consequences. An external consequence on speech is one that occurs through a factor other than the direct market for a work. An internal one comes from the market for the work, and the response from consumers to it. External consequences are often censorship, while internal ones are very rarely censorship. Examples of external consequences would include classic government censorship, threats to unrelated employment, harassment (i.e. SWATing, doxxing, etc.), deprivation of a resource that is generally available to all comers, attempts to pressure a publisher to drop a work by targeting unrelated ones, and so on. The problem with such external consequences comes from my belief that it is fundamentally problematic to use power gained in unrelated markets to muscle one's way into an advantageous position in the marketplace of ideas. Idea and art should rise and fall on their own terms, not the terms of who has the most power in society. It's a similar issue to anti-trust efforts. It is unjust for a company to use its power in one sector of the economy to blast out otherwise viable competitors in other sectors. A focus on external consequences as the demarcating like explains clearly why a lot of things are extremely problematic. Campaigns to target the employment of those with disfavored views (like what occurred in the Brendan Eich controversy) are unethical. <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> style harassment campaigns against people speaking disfavored views are unethical. Campaigns to get stores to drop disfavored works by boycotting unrelated products are problematic (like the one that recently hit Target over the Grand Theft Auto video game). Attempts to pressure providers of generally available services like Facebook and Twitter to drop unpopular speakers are cases of censorship, Internal consequences would include the loss of market for a work due to consumer distaste, and regular editorial discretion by publishers. They are unavoidable and not necessarily unethical.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit: Flickr User Carolyn Tiry <a href="https://flic.kr/p/75R7rp">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>75R7rp</a> </strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/brendaneich" class="p-category" rel="tag">#brendaneich</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#brendaneich</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamergate is trashing the reputation of the tech community</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-is-trashing-the-reputation-of-the-tech-community</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-is-trashing-the-reputation-of-the-tech-community</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7439512656_04f88d7461_z.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7439512656_04f88d7461_z.jpg" alt="7439512656_04f88d7461_z" width="640" height="426" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2454"></a>There is another reason to dislike the toxic cloud of sexism that is <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a>. It's totally trashing the reputation of every community it touches. The gaters have reinforced pretty much every negative stereotype about gamers. They have made every gamer look like a doxing and SWATTing idiot. They have created a massive harassment campaign in the name of "protecting" gaming. And all they have done is to damage the reputation of the tech community. Look at anything in the popular press on this issue. Look at this article, for instance <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/culture/2015/06/05/3661042/women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/"></a><a href="http://thinkprogress.org/culture/2015/06/05/3661042/women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>thinkprogress.org/<wbr></wbr>culture/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>3661042/<wbr></wbr>women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/<wbr></wbr></a>   What is its first example of sexism in tech? <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> . Incidents like <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> have made it look like everyone in tech is like the gaters.  It makes us all look like a pack of Neanderthals that was dredged up from the Pleistocene.  The gaters may screech and holler about the so-called "gamers are dead" articles what were published earily in this controversy. But all they have done is prove that gaming will be dead in its current form if it doesn't clean up its toxic community. And gaters and their ilk are at the forefront of the toxic elements of the gamer community. And that's the saddest thing about GG, they have failed by even their own objectives. They have made every issue they claim to care about worse. They have proven to the world that, even their fiercest critics, and the fiercest critics of the gaming community have a point. Its time fight back against GG and its toxic sexism, lest the gaters burn the community to the ground.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: Flickr user JD Hancock <a href="https://flic.kr/p/ckprVA">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>ckprVA</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest from the gaters http www vocativ...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-latest-from-the-gaters-http-www-vocativ</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-latest-from-the-gaters-http-www-vocativ</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The latest from the gaters<br /><a href="http://www.vocativ.com/tech/internet/gamergate-newest-nemesis-phd-student-natalie-zed/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.vocativ.com/<wbr></wbr>tech/<wbr></wbr>internet/<wbr></wbr>gamergate-newest-nemesis-phd-student-natalie-zed/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Gamergate’s zombie horde of trolls have struck again. This time, the target was Canadian journalist, author and PhD candidate Natalie Zed, slammed for trying to discuss gamergate for an entire conference without publicly saying the word: gamergate.</p>

<p>Last week, Zed attended the Canadian Game Studies Association’s 2015 conference as a panelist. In the opening comments, the organizers asked attendees to refrain from using the Gamergate hashtag, even though many of the panels were focused on the Gamergate phenomenon (depending on your perspective, either a debate about ethics in gaming, mostly focused on the sexism in games and gaming culture, or a vitriolic campaign of hatred directed at women who dare venture into the gaming industry).</p>

<p>The imposed twitter silence was an effort both to protect attendees from Gamergate troll hostility and to prevent Gamergaters from hijacking the online conversation about the conference, rendering Twitter useless for attendees.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#Gamergate link roundup http www motherjones com mojo...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-link-roundup-http-www-motherjones-com-mojo</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-link-roundup-http-www-motherjones-com-mojo</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 06:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a>link roundup<br /><a href="http://www.motherjones.com/mojo/2015/06/anti-gamergate-bill">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.motherjones.com/<wbr></wbr>mojo/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>anti-gamergate-bill</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Could This Bill Prevent Another "Gamergate"?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://southborough.wickedlocal.com/article/20150604/NEWS/150608123">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>southborough.wickedlocal.com/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>20150604/<wbr></wbr>NEWS/<wbr></wbr>150608123</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>U.S. Rep. Katherine Clark unveiled legislation Wednesday that would require the Department of Justice to put more resources into prosecuting individuals who go online to stalk, harass or threaten others – particularly women.<br />Her bill would provide $4 million annually to hire and train more FBI agents to investigate and prosecute such cybercrimes. It would also require the Attorney General, FBI and U.S. Attorneys to make cybercrimes a priority.<br /> “Imagine while you are in our office people threaten to sexually assault you,” said Clark, D-Melrose. “We would never tolerate this in our offices, but this is a daily reality for women online.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Cracked series on GG<br /><a href="http://www.cracked.com/blog/7-ways-gamergate-debate-has-made-world-worse/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cracked.com/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>7-ways-gamergate-debate-has-made-world-worse/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>7 Reasons "Gamergate" Proves Humanity is Doomed</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.cracked.com/quick-fixes/a-90-second-guide-to-determine-if-your-internet-cause-bs/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cracked.com/<wbr></wbr>quick-fixes/<wbr></wbr>a-90-second-guide-to-determine-if-your-internet-cause-bs/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A 90-Second Guide to Determine if Your Internet Cause Is BS</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://www.cracked.com/blog/4-ways-gamers-still-suck-at-dealing-with-women/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.cracked.com/<wbr></wbr>blog/<wbr></wbr>4-ways-gamers-still-suck-at-dealing-with-women/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>4 Ways Gamers Still Suck at Dealing With Women</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://storify.com/a_man_in_black/how-chan-style-anonymous-culture-shapes-gamergate">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>storify.com/<wbr></wbr>a_man_in_black/<wbr></wbr>how-chan-style-anonymous-culture-shapes-gamergate</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>How Chan-Style Anonymous Culture Shapes <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a></p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Via https storify com a man in black...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/via-https-storify-com-a-man-in-black</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/via-https-storify-com-a-man-in-black</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 06:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Via <a href="https://storify.com/a_man_in_black/patreon-and-common-carrier-sociopathy">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>storify.com/<wbr></wbr>a_man_in_black/<wbr></wbr>patreon-and-common-carrier-sociopathy</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/resize.png"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/resize.png" alt="resize" width="429" height="401" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2326"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamergaters and Protectionists</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergaters-and-protectionists</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergaters-and-protectionists</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 09:08:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The closest thing to a Gamergater/MRA/Redpiller that I know of is a protectionist/nationalist. Protectionists think immigrants/foreigners will kill their jobs if given the chance to compete in "their" market and that immigrants will wreck their culture. Therefore, they want to close off markets and keep the foreigners out. In effect they believe that there is a constant amount of income available in the economy and any new competitors will automatically mean less for them. Gaters/MRAs imported (ha) these protectionist arguments and aimed them at women. They believe that allowing women in to the tech market will destroy their share of that pie that it will make them unemployed, and that creating new markets for products that women like will destroy the availability of the products that men want. Its why <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> started as an attack on Zoe Quinn – the author of a video game on depression. The gaters took this as a pretty direct threat against the continued existence of the games they like. Its why they are in general opposed to any game that isn't the latest "<em>Call of Murder XIIV: Personal Revenge".</em>  Its why gaters are paranoid about SJWs. They are convinced that the two communities cannot coexist in any way.   To counteract this threat they act like a corrupt union official who harasses migrant workers, in-order to protect his workers. It also means that the arguments against protectionism will work almost unmodified against MRAs. Apply your good old friend comparative advantage, and you can show and allowing women to compete in the market under equal conditions will make both men and women better off. The Gamergater/MRA fallacy that its a zero sum game is just wrong. But it's a werid newish type of sexism.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/zoequinn" class="p-category" rel="tag">#zoequinn</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#zoequinn</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The #Gamergate mascot comes from the 4chan ...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gamergate-mascot-comes-from-the-4chan-</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gamergate-mascot-comes-from-the-4chan-</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 06:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> mascot comes from the 4chan "picclo dick" rape joke.<br /><a href="https://www.fastcodesign.com/3037941/the-secret-meaning-behind-gamergates-branding#3">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.fastcodesign.com/<wbr></wbr>3037941/<wbr></wbr>the-secret-meaning-behind-gamergates-branding#3</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The meme is based around an animated GIF called “Piccolo Dick,” which shows the Dragon Ball anime character Piccolo sodomizing Vegeta, another character from the series. Banned by many internet forums, posters began to abstract the image to the point that the colors alone were easily associated with the meme.....The image first appeared on 4chan in the 2000s and was frequently reposted by forum trolls, who spoke of giving a "daily dose" of the graphic to forum members, who’d then reply with the catchphrase "Thanks, doc," according to the meme encyclopedia Know Your Meme. Soon, the image was banned, and users began to post other purple-and-green images understood to be a reference to the forbidden GIF...... in the initial forum discussion that led to the Vivian James design, a draft of the Vivian character with her distinctive color palette got plenty of "thanks, doc" replies, as did an anonymous illustrator who a few days later posted a first draft of the now standard GamerGate logo, showing a stylized video game controller with purple and green G’s.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#3</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
