<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23westafrica</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23westafrica&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why you should not be concerned about the Ebola Case in the U.K</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-you-should-not-be-concerned-about-the-ebola-case</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-you-should-not-be-concerned-about-the-ebola-case</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 04:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-scotland-30628349">According to the BBC</a>, a woman living in Glasgow, U.K has contracted Ebola. It is probably clear at this point that substantial public alarm will occur as a result of this as has happened in the United States and elsewhere that Ebola has spread to. However, individuals in developed have little to fear from the virus for various reasons.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1314" align="alignright" width="384"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/15653404835_7999f5f384_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1314" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/15653404835_7999f5f384_o-1024x683.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr (user Army Medicine) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>pReMUg</a> "Kristie Yeakle, right, bio safety officer,, evaluates two students as they sanitize their personal protective equipment during training at the San Antonio Military Medical Center in San Antonio, Texas, Oct. 24, 2014."" width="384" height="256" /&gt; Image via Flickr (user Army Medicine) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/pReMUg">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>pReMUg</a> "Kristie Yeakle, right, bio safety officer,, evaluates two students as they sanitize their personal protective equipment during training at the San Antonio Military Medical Center in San Antonio, Texas, Oct. 24, 2014."[/caption]</p>

<p>In this post I will list five reasons why Ebola should be low on the list of threats to your safety.<br />1. Ebola has a low infectivity. It <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/health/2014/10/02/352983774/no-seriously-how-contagious-is-ebola">is estimated</a> that, even in the favorable conditions the disease experiences in West Africa, a typical Ebola victim infects just two other individuals. This is much lower than other major diseases, and this means that aggressive actions by public health officials can easily contain the disease. Interestingly, the main factor that makes Ebola notable is also the factor that suppresses the disease's ability to infect. Contrary to most depictions in science fiction, extreme leathality reduces the ability for a disease to spread. If the host of a virus is dead or incapacitated, then the host isn't spreading the virus.<br />2. Compared to other major diseases, there have been relatively few deaths and infections caused by Ebola. The number of individuals throughout the world who have been infected by Ebola is around 20,000. About 70 percent of them have died. However, this number of infections and deaths is dwarfed by more mundane diseases such as AIDS, Influenza, Malaria, and many others. A lot of the Ebola panic can be accounted for by peoples' inability to prioritize the risk of infrequent but dramatic events.<br />3. Reasonably effective health care systems have had a solid history of controlling Ebola outbreaks. Every developed nation to have had an Ebola case has controlled it with only a few additional infections occurring. Even nations with relatively weak healthcare systems, such as Nigeria, have contained Ebola outbreaks.<br />4. The main contributor to the spread of Ebola in developing nations is a lack of basic resources and a public that is ill informed about the basic nature of disease spread. The medical and sanitation systems of the nations most effected by Ebola are strongly lacking and these systems face a widespread lack of basic equipment and personnel. In many of the most severely affected locations there is widespread Ebola denialism.<br />5. Ebola is poorly adapted to spread in human hosts. The native host of the disease is the fruit bat, and its symptoms are not optimized for optimal spread in humans.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aids" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aids</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/armymedicine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#armymedicine</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ebolacase" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ebolacase</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westafrica" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westafrica</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aids</category>
      <category>#armymedicine</category>
      <category>#ebolacase</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westafrica</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
