<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23battery</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23battery&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The Tesla home battery has been getting a...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-tesla-home-battery-has-been-getting-a</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-tesla-home-battery-has-been-getting-a</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 06:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Tesla home battery has been getting a lot of attention. Will it resolve the intermittentcy problem for solar? Probably not. Its too expensive.<br /><a href="http://ideas.4brad.com/does-tesla-new-home-storage-battery-suggest-amazing-breakthrough">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ideas.4brad.com/<wbr></wbr>does-tesla-new-home-storage-battery-suggest-amazing-breakthrough</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is very interesting because, at present, battery grid storage is not generally economical. The problem is the cost of the batteries. While batteries can be as much as 90% efficient, they wear out the more you use and recharge them. Batteries vary a lot in how many cycles they will deliver, and this varies according to how you use the battery (ie. do you drain it all the way, or use only the middle of the range, etc.) If your battery will deliver 1,000 cycles using 60% of its range (from 20% to 80%) and costs $400/kwh, then you will get 600kwh over the lifetime of a kwh unit, or 66 cents per kwh (presuming no residual value.) That’s not an economical cost for energy anywhere, except perhaps off-grid. (You also lose a cent or two from losses in the system.) If you can get down to 9 cents/kwh, plus 1 cent for losses, you get parity with the typical grid. However, this is modified by some important caveats:</p>

<p>If you have a grid with very different prices during the day, you can charge your batteries at the night price and use them during the daytime peak. You might pay 7 cents at night and avoid 21 cent prices in the day, so a battery cost of 14 cents/kwh is break-even.<br />You get a backup power system for times when the grid is off. How valuable that is varies on who you are. For many it’s worth several hundred dollars. (But not too many as you can get a generator as backup and most people don’t.)<br />Because battery prices are dropping fast, a battery pack today will lose value quickly, even before it physically degrades. And yes, in spite of what you might imagine in terms of “who cares, as long as it’s working,” that matters.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/battery" class="p-category" rel="tag">#battery</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/renewable" class="p-category" rel="tag">#renewable</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/solar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#solar</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#battery</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#renewable</category>
      <category>#solar</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
