<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23norway</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23norway&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why We Need to Provide Health Care to All.</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-we-need-to-provide-health-care-to-all</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/why-we-need-to-provide-health-care-to-all</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 18:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>As a follow up to <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140326141811/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>01/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>done-u-s-health-care-system/<wbr></wbr></a>" title="What should be done with the U.S health care system?"&gt;yesterday's blog post, I will discuss why we need a health care system which provides universal coverage. <br />What would you do if one day while you were driving on the highway and you saw a car accident victim lieing on the road injured bleeding to death? Most people would try to help the injured person. Some states even require you to do so. When that person is taken to the hospital the hospital is required to provide treatment regardless of the victim's ability to pay.  However, our current healthcare system is not as compassionate to a cancer patient who can not afford the treatment he needs to live. There are millions of uninsured in this country that might face the same fate as that hypothetical cancer patient. <br />Many of you might be worried about the involvement in the healthcare system by government that guaranteeing healthcare as a human right might entail. While this debate is just about whether healthcare is a human right I will address this issue. Are private insurance companies that are accountable to nothing but their profit margins really any better then an accountable elected government? Under our current system you have life and death decisions being made to maximize profit instead of providing healthcare to all.  </p>

<p><!--more--><br />I will argue that healthcare is a human right. Something can become a human right if it is needed to sustain human freedom and dignity. That is the very definition of a right. Protecting human rights keep society livable for all citizens.   I will argue that in the 21st century healthcare is needed for the the rights of "life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness" that are detailed in the United States Deceleration of Independence  to truly take effect.  <br />Very few of will dispute commonly recognized human rights such as freedom of speech, privacy and the ability to participate in the political system. Why should health care also be in this list? One reason is that it's a right that is necessary to fully utilize the political rights. All the rights that exist on paper mean nothing to a dead person. Having the ability to be alive and healthy is a necessary predecessor to being able to enjoy civil and political rights. <br />  <br />The rationale for healthcare being a human right really all goes back to what's in our Declaration of Independence. The Declaration of Independence guarantees everyone "life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness" In our modern society healthcare is life. No one can easily have equal opportunity in pursuing happiness when they have to worry about how they'll pay for their child's cancer treatment. Human rights are special because of the fact that human rights directly relate to fundamental human needs.</p>

<p> Health care  qualifies as a fundamental human need in the 21st century. If you don't have healthcare you get sick and die. Having a functional body that is not collapsing around you is the first and foremost need of humans. It is the need that we are the most concerned about and it is the need that we seek to fulfill for our selves before we become concerned about such issues as participating in society to make the world a better place.   People without healthcare can not fully participate in the society. The level of poverty that allows people to go without something as fundamental as adequate healthcare undermines human dignity. The suffering of someone who can not get the cancer treatment they need is real and it is an avoidable side effect of our current economic system. <br />Even in a industrialized economy like the U.S many people still die from lack of health care. According to a study by Harvard University that was cited by a 2009 article in Reuters over 45,000 Americans die from lack of health care.the study found that the uninsured aged between 17 an 64 have a 40% higher chance of dyeing then those that have health insurance.  According to the U.S Department of Health and Human Services there are almost 46 million uninsured. There are 46 million people in the wealthiest nation in the world that might die of a preventable cause because we have chosen not to provide healthcare to them. <br />Even children and babies are not immune the the effects of lack of healthcare. According to the United Nations Population Division the United States has a infant mortality rate of 6.3 deaths per 1000 births. Nations with universal healthcare tend to have lower infant mortality rates. For example Norway has a infant mortality rate of 3.3 deaths per 1000 births and Sweden has a infant mortality rate of 3.2 deaths per 1000 births <br />The lack of health care in the United States is an issue that causes millions throughout this country to worry and suffer This problem even causes some people to lose their lives. This is one of the strongest arguments that health care is a human right. In the 21st century with all of the inventions of modern medicine that can extend the average person's life by decades healthcare means life. <br />The role of our government is to provide for the safety and protection of its population and to provide a framework for a system  truly allow everyone to pursue happiness.The preamble to the U.S Constitution gives a good summary of this role of government. It reads </p>
<blockquote>
<p>We the People of the United States, in Order to form a more perfect Union, establish Justice, insure domestic Tranquility, provide for the common defense, promote the general Welfare, and secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity, do ordain and establish this Constitution for the United States of America.</p>
</blockquote>
<p> Healthcare isn't all that distinct from other human rights. All human rights require some degree of legal enforcement to be set up so they can be fully realized by the population. One can not invision a workable system where property rights self enforce but they are still internationality reconised as a right that deserves enforcement. Even the political rights require an independent judiciary to validate that they are indeed being enforced.</p>

<p>The argument that healthcare is a human right is bolstered by such treaties as the universal declaration of human rights , which includes the following:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Everyone has the right to a standard of living adequate for the health and  <br />well-being of himself and of his family, including food, clothing, housing  <br />and medical care and necessary social services, and the right to security in  <br />the event of unemployment, sickness, disability, widowhood, old age or other  <br />lack of livelihood in circumstances beyond his control."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The Universal Declaration of Human Rights was written by the United Nations in 1948 and just eight of the U.N member states chose not to approve the treaty.</p>

<p>In the 21st century healthcare is needed for the the rights of "life, liberty and the pursuit of happiness" to truly take effect. In our world with the wonders of modern science and medicine healthcare is life. Thousands in this country die each year because of lack of healthcare. The U.S has an obligation help the right to healthcare be realised at home and abroad. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/harvarduniversity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#harvarduniversity</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/norway" class="p-category" rel="tag">#norway</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitednations" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitednations</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#harvarduniversity</category>
      <category>#norway</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitednations</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
