<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link/>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23unitedstates&amp;_t=rss&amp;offset=10" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>America's History of Immigration and of Immigration Restriction</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/americas-history-of-immigration-and-of-immigration-restriction</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/americas-history-of-immigration-and-of-immigration-restriction</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 22:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The history of United States immigration policy has been one of historical contradictions. The United States is in a way a nation of immigrants restricting immigration.Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. British Puritans and Pilgrims migrated to the New World for religious liberty and settled in New England and founded the colonies of Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Connecticut. However, nativism has also been constant throughout U.S. history and is often tied to racism and nationalism--even in this nation of immigrants. This is despite the fact that immigration to the United States has brought great benefits to both the United States and other nations. Quaker immigrants settled Pennsylvania looking for religious freedom. Pennsylvania after Quaker settlement was the first colony to provide religious freedom to all and soon became home to individuals of many religions. The Dutch founded what is now New York City, but this land was eventually absorbed into the British Empire. New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Delaware attracted many Irish, German and Scandinavian immigrants. By 1790,almost-one half of the American population was not of British ancestry .[1. Szucs, Loretto Dennis, and Sandra Hargreaves Luebking. 2006. The source: a guidebook to American genealogy. Provo, UT: Ancestry.]<br /><!--more--><br />Restrictions on immigration by the British were a significant cause of the American Revolution. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither. . .“ After independence, the United States immigration laws were extremely permissive. The Naturalization Act of 1790, which was the first U. S. immigration law, placed no restrictions on immigration and allowed free whites to obtain citizenship after two years of residency in the United States.However, nationalistic fervor soon resulted in increased immigration restrictions. The more restrictive Naturalization Act of 1795 was passed as a result of fears that European immigrants could hold views that were counter to views of American liberty. In 1798 Congress passed the Alien and Sedition Acts, which extended the residency requirement to 14 years, along with enacting severe censorship of the press. This law was enacted because of a fear that French immigrants were fomenting rebellion and anarchy in the United States</p>

<p>In the mid to late 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had an almost free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, as well as immigrants from Asia. This migration was at its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine and during this time period about 60 million immigrants migrated from Europe. In 1911, almost 15 percent of the United States population was foreign born. <a title="Immigration Helps the Economy" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140503011041/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>22/<wbr></wbr>immigration-helps-economy/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;This immigration had substantial benefits for both nations. It fueled much of United States industrial development in the period before World War I and immigration from 1840 to 1920 was a primary contributor to American urbanization. The migrants tended to be unskilled labor of the type best suited to employment in industry, compared to the highly skilled craftsmen who made up the bulk of native workers. This is because labor is a limiting factor to economic output in nations with high development of capital and technology. The result of migration, therefore, is an increase in industrial capacity triggered by the easing of that limiting factor. While the additional supply of labor may reduce wages to some degree, the increase in production enabled by immigration exceeded the change in wages, so overall economic output increased.[2. (Borjas, George J., and Valerie A. Ramey)].Additionally, the nations where the migrants emigrated from received great benefits from their migration flows. Nations with limited capital and technology development compared to the available labor are the most likely to produce emigrants. <a title="Immigration Helps the Economy" href="http://web.archive.org/web/20140503011041/&lt;a%20href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>index.php/<wbr></wbr>2013/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>22/<wbr></wbr>immigration-helps-economy/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;This migration drives local wages up. . <br />However, despite the benefits of immigration to the United States, nationalism and racism prompted policy changes that greatly restricted this migration after World War I. All throughout the period of high immigration strong nativistic sentiment was always present. Irish Catholics were of particular concern. Often the Catholic Church and its Irish followers were viewed as a threat to freedom and promoters of tyrannical institutions. Ireland was the largest single source of immigrants, and in 1850, 47 percent of foreign-born Americans were Irish.</p>

<p>Showing a typical view of the anti-Irish sentiments of the time, inventor and artist Samuel Morse argued that while previous immigrants to the United States were “lovers of liberty,” the new immigrants were “selected for a service to their tyrants, and by their tyrants, not for their affinity for liberty, but for their mental servitude and their docility towards their priests ”. he opposition to immigration of Morse and others was despite the fact that the Irish immigrants showed no real opposition to core freedoms and Irish American Catholics were very strong defenders of religious freedom. In-fact, Irish-American Catholics were generally the most committed to separation of church and state of all Catholics during the mid to late 19th century and brought their liberal beliefs to the European church. In the late 1850s, the Know-Nothing party became the first anti-immigrant, xenophobic party to gain substantial electoral victories.</p>

<p>Mexico started to play an increasingly important role in United states immigration policy starting with World War I and continuing to current times. America's restrictions on immigration from Mexico have been influenced by the degree that we have needed Mexican workers. The labor shortages of World War I meant fewer restrictions on Mexican immigration. But as unemployment rose and many Americans began looking for jobs during the Great Depression, mass deportation of Mexican workers began. World War II again brought labor shortages and a guest-worker program was initiated, called the Bracero Program. By 1964, when the program ended, more than 4.5 million Mexicans had participated. In the era after Bracero, two issues came to dominate the American policy debate on immigration: protecting the United States borders from terrorists and illegal immigration, particularly from Mexico. The 1965 Immigration and Nationality Act was the first major immigration legislation after the repeal of the Bracero program and loosened many of the racily motivated immigration quotas. There was an increasing influx of illegal immigration into the United States at this point and this immigration was argued to be driving down the wages of American workers. The 1986 Immigration and Reform Act gave amnesty to 2.7 million immigrants who were in the United States without legal authorization.</p>

<p>The debate over U.S/Mexico immigration has been marred by nationalistic rhetoric, but there is strong evidence that this immigration flow is in general of benefit to both nations. <a href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.2307/2522570?uid=3739552&uid=2&uid=4&uid=3739256&sid=21102668867717">A study authored by economist George Johnson did not find an any unemployment effect from Mexican immigration – including illegal immigration.</a> It also found that this immigration increases GDP. Some inequality effect, particularly in the long run, was seen. However, this inequality effect could be mitigated by government spending, services, and tax policy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/irishcatholics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#irishcatholics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mexico" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mexico</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newyorkcity" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newyorkcity</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#irishcatholics</category>
      <category>#mexico</category>
      <category>#newyorkcity</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immigration Helps the Economy</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/immigration-helps-the-economy</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 00:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A great body of research done by economists and other researchers shows that immigration has a potentially great potential to benefit the economy. The cost of immigration restrictions <a href="http://www.cgdev.org/publication/economics-and-emigration-trillion-dollar-bills-sidewalk-working-paper-264">is a large fraction of global GDP (around 25 percent)</a> and one of the most costly. This global cost of the current restrictions on immigrants from poor nations migrating to richer nations is trillions of dollars per year. Immigration restrictions can increase global economic inequality, particularly between nations, but also within nations.<br /><!--more--></p>

<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither. . .“</p>

<p>This immigration has been clearly beneficial to the nation. <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.tcd.ie%2FEconomics%2FTEP%2F2003_papers%2FTEPNo15KOR23.pdf&ei=hZA-UvjGIYyayQH45ID4AQ&usg=AFQjCNH6zbsRZWrNg1bhyvSEUUZwrpIkxA&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc">Economist Kevin O'Rourke found that</a> immigration from Europe to the United States and Canada in the 19th and early 20th centuries narrowed the wage gaps between developed nations and then developing European nations, such as Ireland, Norway, and Italy.In the mid to late 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had an almost free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, as well as immigrants from Asia. This migration was at its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. In 1911, almost 15 percent of the United States population was foreign born. This immigration had substantial benefits for both nations. It fueled much of United States industrial development in the period before World War I and immigration from 1840 to 1920 was a primary contributor to American urbanization. <a href="http://www.nber.org/papers/w12900">The migrants tended to be unskilled labor of the type best suited to employment in industry</a>, compared to the highly skilled craftsmen who made up the bulk of native workers. This is because labor is a limiting factor to economic output in nations with high development of capital and technology. The result of migration, therefore, is an increase in industrial capacity triggered by the easing of that limiting factor.Additionally, the nations where the migrants emigrated from received great benefits from their migration flows. Nations with limited capital and technology development compared to the available labor are the most likely to produce emigrants. This migration drives local wages up. While emigration between 1870 and 1910 lowered the Irish labor force by 45 percent, the Italian by 39 percent, and the Norwegian by 24 percent, wages increased dramatically in those nations. Irish wages rose by almost 25%.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/canada" class="p-category" rel="tag">#canada</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/irishpotatofamine" class="p-category" rel="tag">#irishpotatofamine</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#canada</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#irishpotatofamine</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Eliminate Poverty in the United States</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-best-way-to-eliminate-poverty-in-the-united-states</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-best-way-to-eliminate-poverty-in-the-united-states</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 21:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america/" title="Poverty: A Economic and Moral Crisis in America">As I have previously discussed</a>, poverty is a great problem in America.</p>
<p dir="ltr">To replace many of the current welfare programs that we have in the United States, I would recommend a basic income program along the lines of the negative income tax proposal created by the Nobel Prize winning economist Milton Friedman.</p><p dir="ltr">Every family would receive a sum of money from the federal government to make their income above the poverty line level. All income earned separately, apart from the federal government grant would be taxed at a flat rate to help pay for the program. This proposal would simplify the current welfare programs by replacing many of them with a single program. Because everyone would get to keep the income they earned by working, without effecting the lump sum paid to them, someone is always better off working. Also an income level just barely above the poverty line isn't enough to take away someone's motivation to work, since isn't very much money and wouldn't provide for many or any extras or luxuries.</p><p dir="ltr">This sum of money would be distributed through the federal income tax system as a refundable tax credit.  If you owed no taxes, instead of a tax credit, you would receive a grant check from the federal government.</p><!--more--><p dir="ltr">A negative income tax isn't just some idea that some economist came up with, during the 1960s and 70s this idea was seriously considered by the federal government. In 1969 Richard Nixon proposed a bill that would have created a basic income through a negative income tax system. The bill failed in the Senate.  The Johnson administration studied the possibility of a negative income tax and George McGovern proposed it during his failed 1972 presidential campaign.</p>
<p>This system would give the working poor a living wage that would not take away their motivation to work. To help the unemployed, I would recommend that we create a jobs program to help them. This could provide work and help the United States by improving its infrastructure and creating alternative energy projects. This would work like the Works Progress Administration, which was created during the Great Depression to reduce unemployment.  It constructed roads streets, parks and other public buildings.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/greatdepression" class="p-category" rel="tag">#greatdepression</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/richardnixon" class="p-category" rel="tag">#richardnixon</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worksprogressadministration" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worksprogressadministration</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#greatdepression</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#richardnixon</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#worksprogressadministration</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Connects Media Coverage of Global Warming to Lack of Images</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/study-connects-media-coverage-of-global-warming-to-lack-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/study-connects-media-coverage-of-global-warming-to-lack-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 22:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://pus.sagepub.com/content/early/2013/09/04/0963662513500196.abstract">A study published this month </a>in the journal Public Understanding of Science [1. León, Bienvenido, and Mª Carmen Erviti. "Science in pictures: Visual representation of climate change in Spain’s television news." Public Understanding of Science (2013): 0963662513500196.] looked at the relation of visual images to coverage of the global warming issue in Spain's television media.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_533" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://earthobservatory.nasa.gov/Features/WorldOfChange/decadaltemp.php"></a> This images represents the causes of climate change. Image via NASA Earth Observatory[/caption]</p>

<p>The study found that "<em>the low rate of coverage of CC[Climate Change] can be related to the scarcity of attractive images available to the channels</em>".<!--more--> The authors looked at three issues; the extent to which the lack of images to illustrate global warming, the extent to which images used showcase the impacts of climate change rather than its causes and the extent to which images used represent climate change as a remote process. The research was done through a mix of analysis of television shows aired by Spain's major networks and interviews with journalists. The authors found that climate change is generally considered a niche topic and that scarcity of images is one core reason this is true. Of particular importance is the amount of original images available to networks. Furthermore the visual representation of impacts of climate change looms large in media coverage and can produce spectacular images. Images of climate change impacts are almost always focused on international matters such as the effects of global warming on polar bears. Images of local impacts are rare. The most common way to visually represent the causes of climate change is by showing an image of a smokestack. These representations have a tendency to make the climate change issue seem distant, remote, mundane and insignificant.</p>

<p>I think that the results of this study are related to the current state of climate change denialism. Those who try to ignore the human role in global warming have switched their focus away from arguing that it isn't happening to arguing that it isn't important. Conservative groups in the United States have tried to make it seem like climate change activists are just a bunch of tree huggers trying to save the polar bears at the expense of the economy. Portrayal in the media can bolster this impression when climate change gets portrayed as unimportant.</p>

<p><strong>Published Work Cited </strong></p>

<p>León, Bienvenido, and Mª Carmen Erviti. "Science in pictures: Visual representation of climate change in Spain’s television news." Public Understanding of Science (2013): 0963662513500196</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/spain" class="p-category" rel="tag">#spain</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#spain</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Our Drug Laws Need Reform and How to Carry Out the Reform</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-our-drug-laws-need-reform-and-how-to-carry</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/why-our-drug-laws-need-reform-and-how-to-carry</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 16:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><!--StartFragment--><a href="http://www.countthecosts.org/seven-costs/wasting-billions-drug-law-enforcement#%281%29">Current drug laws cost the global economy at least 100 billion dollars per year.</a> Imagine what we could do with that money if it were instead spent on something like healthcare, education, reducing non-drug crimes or alleviating poverty. Instead of spending this money on something that is useful to the nation we chose to spend it on an ineffective policy that increases crime and jams our courts and spreads disease. There is an alternative</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_454" align="alignright" width="300"] A view of a neon sign of a cannabis coffee shop in Arnhem, The Netherlands .Image via Wikipedia and licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license[/caption]</p>

<p>to this policy. I advocate the legalization of mild drugs such as marijuana and the decriminalization of hard drugs. This policy will treat marijuana like alcohol and tobacco and will treat the hard drugs such as cocaine as a public health issue instead of a criminal problem. If we decriminalize drug use the government will not continue to try to tell millions of people throughout this country what chemicals they can or can not voluntarily put into their bodies. Decriminalizing drugs will reduce non drug crimes and will free up law enforcement resources to prosecute other more important crimes. Legalizing drugs is a good policy.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>Despite all of the money that we spend on keeping drugs illegal this policy is not working. Millions throughout this country still use illegal drugs.<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adult_lifetime_cannabis_use_by_country"> Over 100 million Americans over the age of 12 have used marijuana at least once during their lives.</a> According a survey by the<a href="http://oas.samhsa.gov/NSDUH/2k10NSDUH/2k10Results.htm"> Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration 7.8% of high school seniors surveyed said that they have used cocaine,</a> 16.8% have used amphetamines (speed) , 12% have used hallucinogenic drugs and 47.8 have used marijuana. Is this what we are paying tens of billions of dollars for? Why as a country are we paying billions of dollars to enforce laws that tens of millions people regularly violate? What does trying to enforce an unenforceable law do to the public’s respect of our government and the laws it makes?</p>

<p>I believe that we should adopt the marijuana policy that the Netherlands currently uses. In the Netherlands highly regulated “coffee shops” can sell marijuana to adults. Unlike drug dealers in the U.S “coffee shop” owners in the Netherlands are subject to strict regulation over the quality and safety of their products. A “coffee shop” is prevented from advertising , selling hard drugs or alcohol , selling more than five grams of marijuana during any single transaction or operating within 250 meters of a school.</p>

<p>If our government adopted the same policy as Netherlands of allowing highly regulated stores to legally sell marijuana it would take the crime and violence out of the trade of this drug. Doing this would make it harder for minors to obtain marijuana because the legal stores would have no incentive to risk getting shut down by breaking the law by selling to minors. Legalizing marijuana would also generate tax revenue because unlike the drug dealers the legal sellers of marijuana would pay sales and excise taxes.</p>

<p>I would recommend I policy of drug decriminalization to deal with the “hard” drugs such as cocaine. This policy would be along the lines of the one that currently exists for heroin addicts in Switzerland. Swiss heroin addicts can go to one of 22 government operated clinics to receive a safe,clean and free shot of heroin. While they are at the clinic the addicts will be informed about treatment they can receive to end their addiction. Social workers at the clinics will encourage addicts to seek rehab. The clinics are the only entity that may legally distribute the drugs. Possession of drugs is not prosecuted but drug dealers are. If the U.S adopted this system the illegal drug dealers would soon be out of business as there is no way that they can compete with the clinics that distribute the drugs for free. There will no longer be drug dealers shooting each other in the streets. The drugs distributed by the clinic will be at a constant and safe dosage so there will be a much lower risk of addicts dieing of drug overdose. The drugs will be administered through safe needles, so diseases will no longer be spread through unsafe injections . There will no longer be any more drug dealers to encourage children to take up drugs . The only legal distributor of drugs will be encouraging its clients to kick their drug habit instead of trying to find new clients.</p>

<p>Drug use in the U.S causes many public health issues. These issues can be resolved by drug use decriminalization. In 2001 Portugal decriminalized drug use. <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=portugal-drug-decriminalization">According to an article published in Scientific American the number of new cases of HIV caused by unsafe injections of drugs went from almost 1400 in 2001 to 400 in 2006</a>. Imagine how many lives could be saved if a policy of drug decriminalization was adopted in the U.S and that policy had a similar effect. According to a 2002 fact sheet published by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, a Federal Government agency unsafe injections of illegal drugs account for over one third of all cases of HIV. An estimated 11,635 people per year in the United States get HIV through unsafe injections of illegal drugs. Other countries that have taken the path of drug decriminalization have had similar reductions in HIV rates. According to the World Health Organization the percentage of users of injected drugs that have HIV declined from 5% in 1991 to 1% in 2006 . It is clear that our current drug policy is a public health disaster and that it will make for a healthier population if we decriminalize drugs</p>

<p>We have already done something similar to our current drug policy. In 1920 the 18th amendment to the constitution was ratified. Section one of it read:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After one year from the ratification of this article the manufacture, sale, or transportation of intoxicating liquors within, the importation thereof into, or the exportation thereof from the United States and all territory subject to the jurisdiction thereof for beverage purposes is hereby prohibited.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The ratification of the 18th amendment brought prohibition into existence. Prohibition turned out in a similar way to our current drug policy. Millions of people throughout the country illegally consumed alcoholic beverages. The prohibition policy increased crime because the mafia became involved in the illegal distribution of alcoholic beverages. Just as thousands of people today are getting sick from unsafe injections of illegal drugs thousands died during prohibition because the illegal producers of alcoholic beverages would mix industrial (denatured) alcohol with their brews to create a stronger beverage. industrial alcohol sometimes contains the toxic methyl alcohol and this ended up killing people. When prohibition was replied legal breweries replaced the illegal ones, safe regulated producers of alcoholic beverages replaced the mafia and a law that millions violated went away .</p>

<p>To those who think that drugs are dangerous because they cause violent crimes I have a response. Much of the crime involved with drugs is because of our current drug policy. Drug dealers shoot each other on the streets over turf to sell their products. Terrorist organizations are funded by the illegal drug trade. A study published by the United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime found that the Taliban received between 50 to 70 million dollars in revenue through the opium trade. These problems would go away after regulated, legal producers of drugs out competed the drug smugglers.</p>

<p>There is also a moral issue involved here. Why should the government prevent someone from putting a chemical into his or her body if that person willingly does so with full knowledge of the damage possible. This is what the government is doing with it's current drug policies. A person that takes drugs is not harming anyone else. If a addict happens to commit another crime while on drugs then that is a separate issue and that person should be prosecuted for the non-drug crime. However, prosecuting someone because they just put a certain chemical into their bodies takes away part of their right to privacy and their right to control what happens to their own body.</p>

<p>Legalizing drugs will benefit public health, reduce violence and eliminate a law that millions violate each day. We are repeating what happened with Prohibition but just with another substance. Repealing our drug laws will remove a funding source from criminal organizations and will stop drug violence. Replacing our drug laws will reduce infections from unsafe injections and will replace the unregulated drug dealers with a system of regulated manufacturers. It is past time to repeal our drug laws and replace them with something more reasonable.   <!--EndFragment--></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hiv" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hiv</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/netherlands" class="p-category" rel="tag">#netherlands</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worldhealthorganization" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worldhealthorganization</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#hiv</category>
      <category>#netherlands</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#worldhealthorganization</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health Care Monopoly: Why the Hospital Market is not Competitive and How Patients Get Ripped Off or Worse</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/health-care-monopoly-why-the-hospital-market-is-not-competitive</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/health-care-monopoly-why-the-hospital-market-is-not-competitive</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 23:58:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB121986172394776997.html?mod=hps_us_pageone&cb=logged0.4228730972390622">After a 1989 merger the Roanoke, Va hospital market became concentrated in the hands of one company</a>, Carilion Health Systems. By the most recent accounts profits of the company reached 107 million dollars and the pay of its CEO reached $2.07 million. However, things are not going as well for Carilion's patients. Carilion's colonoscopy fees are 4 to 10 times those of nearby health-care providers and their CT scan fees are almost three times those of other providers.  After the formation of the monopoly, insurance premiums soared in Roanoke. This change was largely driven by Carilion's high fees. Before the merger premiums were 20% lower than those of nearby Richmond. Now premiums in Roanoke are the highest in Virginia.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, such monopolies are all too common in the American health care system. Hospital owners and management get rich while patients get shafted with high fees. Or in many cases bodies that control the care provided at many hospitals pull their weight to ensure that needed care is not provided at all.</p>

<p><a href="http://content.healthaffairs.org/content/suppl/2003/12/12/hlthaff.w3.472v1.DC1">A study published in the journal <em>Health Affairs </em>f</a>ound substantial market concentration in the health care market that is sufficient to allow hospitals to charge public insurance providers (such as Medicare and Medicaid) different prices than those demanded of private insurance providers and individuals. In particular, hospitals can shift costs onto private insurance providers. The evidence suggests that for-profit providers are more likely to abuse their market power then non-profit providers. This differential pricing would be unlikely to occur in a competitive market because competition, and the risk of being undercut by other hospitals, would tend to push the maximum price down to a level near the cost of production.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/05/08/hospital-prices-cost-differences_n_3232678.html?1367985666">A review of prices charged by hospitals in the greater New York City metropolitan area</a> found vast differences in prices charged for equivalent COPD treatments. The most expensive hospital charged $99,690. The cheapest hospital charged $7,044.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21756018">A 2011 study concluded that</a> "Hospital markets in the United States now mostly fall within the definitions adopted by the DOJ [Department of Justice] and FTC [Federal Trade Commission] as moderately to highly concentrated" and that "Hospitals in concentrated markets charge significantly higher prices and earn significantly higher margins from private insurers than do hospitals in competitive markets."</p>

<p><a href="http://ncronline.org/news/catholic-hospitals-serve-one-six-patients-united-states">One in every 6</a> hospital patients in America is served at a Catholic hospital. <a href="http://rhrealitycheck.org/article/2013/03/25/dont-take-her-to-catholic-hospital/">Almost 10%</a> of the religious hospitals in the United States are the sole provider of hospital care in their area. However, this vast patient body gives the Church substantial power to set the range of health care provided in the United States.  Many more are in highly concentrated markets and face only limited competition.  The Catholic Church requires the hospitals under its control to follow “<a title="(Open in new tab) " href="http://www.usccb.org/about/doctrine/ethical-and-religious-directives/" rel="external">Ethical and Religious Directives</a>” which often<a href="http://rhrealitycheck.org/article/2013/06/06/do-religious-restrictions-force-doctors-to-commit-malpractice/"> contradict generally accepted medical practices</a>.</p>

<p>What should be done to increase competition in the health care market? First of all increased anti-trust enforcement should be applied to the health care market and hospital chains in concentrated markets should be broken up. In areas where there is not sufficient demand for hospital services to support a competitive market a publicly owned hospital monopoly is preferable to a private one.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/carilionhealthsystems" class="p-category" rel="tag">#carilionhealthsystems</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ftc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ftc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/healthaffairs" class="p-category" rel="tag">#healthaffairs</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#carilionhealthsystems</category>
      <category>#ftc</category>
      <category>#healthaffairs</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ideal of America</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-ideal-of-america</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/the-ideal-of-america</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2013 22:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <div title="Page 1">
<p>[caption id="attachment_317" align="alignright" width="203"] Unveiling of the Statue of Liberty Enlightening the World (1886) by Edward Moran[/caption]</p>

<p>What are the values that have made America and Americans different? An American can be of any race, creed, religion, philosophy, or ethnicity. The United States has never been a country of one religious or ethnic group, and Americans have many diverse political philosophies. The ideal of America has been that of a country where immigrants from throughout the world could come and make a good life and where Americans from all socioeconomic backgrounds could move up the economic ladder, or at the least attain a good education and provide for themselves and their families if they work hard. America has always been a melting pot and a nation of diversity. America is a home for persons of all types­­ there is no one stereotypical real American.</p>

<p>Americans enjoy freedom of speech and religion and live under a legal system that protects these basic individual rights. What makes a real American is the strong belief in these values and the freedoms that come with being a citizen of the United States, as well as respect for those values and freedoms. The United States was founded to be a country where the most famous lines of the Declaration of Independence -- a document ratified 237 years ago today -- ring true, where “<em>We hold these truths to be self­ evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>America was founded to be a nation of laws, not men, where there would never be a European­style aristocracy and where all were equal in rights and opportunity. These values are inherently both communal and individual as both liberty and equality involve the relations between individuals to other individuals in society. Because of this, the power of community has been at the heart of what makes America great. While these values and hopes have never been fully implemented, and there are still great inequities in American society, these values form the heart and soul of America and its people.</p>
<div title="Page 1">
<p>The fact that America is a nation of diversity can be seen in where Americans have come from. There have been Americans that have come from almost all cultural groups in the world.</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>Starting even before independence, America has been a melting pot of immigrants of different cultures and religions. British Puritans and Pilgrims migrated to the New World for religious liberty and settled in New England and founded the colonies of Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island and Connecticut. Quaker immigrants settled Pennsylvania looking for religious freedom. Pennsylvania after Quaker settlement was the first colony to provide religious freedom to all and soon became home to individuals of many religions. The Dutch founded what is now New York City, but this land was eventually absorbed into the British Empire. New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Delaware attracted many Irish, German and Scandinavian immigrants. By 1790 almost one half of the American population was not of British ancestry. Restrictions on immigration and importation of goods imposed by the British were a significant cause of the American Revolution. One of the grievances against the British monarch stated in the Declaration of Independence is that “<em>He has endeavored to prevent the population of these States; for that purpose obstructing the Laws for Naturalization of Foreigners; refusing to pass others to encourage their migrations hither</em>... “</p>
<div title="Page 2">
<p>After independence, the United States immigration laws were extremely permissive. The Naturalization Act of 1790, which was the first U. S. immigration law, placed no restrictions on immigration and allowed free whites to obtain citizenship after two years of residency in the United States. In the 19th and early 20th centuries, the United States had a free migration policy and had massive flows of immigrants from European nations, such as Ireland, and immigrants from Asia. This migration was its strongest around the time of the Irish Potato Famine. The inscription on the Statue of Liberty greeted the immigrants entering the country through Ellis Island with the following poem written by Emma Lazarus and titled The New Colossus. It summed up America's values toward immigrants,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Not like the brazen giant of Greek fame, With conquering limbs astride from land to land; Here at our sea­washed, sunset gates shall stand A mighty woman with a torch, whose flame Is the imprisoned lightning, and her name Mother of Exiles. From her beacon­ hand Glows world­ wide welcome; her mild eyes command The air-­bridged harbor that twin cities frame. 'Keep, ancient lands, your storied pomp!' cries she With silent lips. 'Give me your tired, your poor, Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free, The wretched refuse of your teeming shore. Send these, the homeless, tempest ­tossed to me, I lift my lamp beside the golden door!'”</p>
</blockquote><div title="Page 3">
<p>America was open to immigrants throughout the world and was a nation of opportunities. It is clear that this history has made the United States a nation of diversity created by immigrants from all over the world. This American history of immigration is what makes being American not about what religious or ethnic group you are part of, but about the American values of liberty and equality that are so eloquently summed up by The New Colossus. American values have always been to create a nation where people from throughout the world could come to experience liberty and opportunity. What makes an American is therefore belief in these values, the values that have attracted and brought so many immigrants to the United States.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The core values of America that shape and created the nation are liberty and equality. These values have drawn immigrants to the nation since the Puritans, Pilgrims and Quakers first set foot in the New World looking for religious liberty. It is these values that define what being an American is and form the basis of the American community. America was founded to be a place where no king could arbitrarily interfere with basic liberties. Freedom and equality come hand in hand and cannot exist without each other.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>Freedom in the American community means not being dominated over, and living in a community with other citizens that are equal in rights and opportunities. American poet and author Walt Whitman defined freedom as follows, “<em>Freedom --­ to walk free and own no superior.</em>“ and said this of being a citizen of America, “<em>Neither a servant nor a master am I</em>.” These values have motivated American activists throughout the nation's history to fight for what is right and to fight to bring liberty and equal opportunity to all.</p>
<div title="Page 3">
<p>The founders of the United States saw freedom and equality as inherently linked. Excessive inequality could result in aristocracy and would be corrosive to society and freedom. But freedom was inherently linked with accepting that all men are created equal. Alexis de Tocqueville, a famous French author who wrote about the early United States, said, “<em>Grant me thirty years of equal division of inheritances and a free press, and I will provide you with a republic.</em>” In the Federalist #10, James Madison stated that “<em>the most common and durable source of factions has been the various and unequal distribution of property. Those who hold and those who are without property have ever formed distinct interests in society.</em>”</p>
<div title="Page 4">
<p>The struggle for freedom and equality for all has defined the United States throughout its history and defines what it means to be an American. The biggest questions in American history have been “what is liberty?” and “what is the proper relation between liberty and order?” and the biggest struggles in American history have involved expanding freedom and equality. The greatest victories in these struggles have come in four waves. The first wave of this struggle came with the Revolutionary War and the formation of the new United States government. The second wave of the American struggle for freedom for all came with the U.S Civil War and its aftermath. The third wave of this struggle came with the Great Depression, the New Deal and the Second World War and its aftermath. The fourth wave was the Civil Rights Movement. The Declaration of Independence was the statement of the core values of America and its people. However, the realization that “<em>all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights</em>” came throughout the history of the United States and is still not entirely complete. The Declaration of Independence stated that the role of government ought to be to protect these rights and that a just government is based around the consent of the governed. After independence, American society became the closest in existence to a society without an aristocracy. A government was created that was the closest thing to a republic of laws, not men, that existed in the world. About a decade after the end of the revolution, a constitution was ratified that created a new national government for the United States. In its Preamble the Constitution stated its purpose as follows, “<em>to form a more perfect Union, establish Justice, insure domestic Tranquility, provide for the common defense, promote the general Welfare, and secure the Blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our Posterity.</em>” Shortly thereafter, a second great American document was created, the Bill of Rights. This document protected many fundamental rights from government violation. Through many years of existence and legal interpretation, the Bill of Rights became a great American document that has played a large role in determining the nature of American freedom and liberty and has been at the heart of the shared American historical and cultural heritage. These documents are part of what makes America what it is and Americans who they are.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The history of the Civil War and reconstruction resulted in a great expansion of liberty, the end of slavery, and the expansion of the rights of citizenship to many Americans who did not receive those liberties before. The legal changes that happened during this period are most dramatically reflected in the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, which reads in part, “<em>No State shall make or enforce any law which shall abridge the privileges or immunities of citizens of the United States; nor shall any State deprive any person of life, liberty, or property, without due process of law; nor deny to any person within its jurisdiction the equal protection of the laws.</em>” The 14th Amendment's declaration that all are equal before the law put the Declaration of Independence's most famous value into the constitution. It stated that all Americans have rights that must be protected by law. Furthermore, the Civil War and its aftermath helped define what it means to be American by creating an American national identity. Americans were Americans first and foremost instead of residents of their states first and foremost.</p>
<div title="Page 5">
<p>The New Deal era and the aftermath of World War II brought a new era in the expansion of rights in the United States. During the New Deal, it was realized that liberty included certain economic rights and that protecting the liberty of the population included giving everyone economic opportunities. In a tradition that went back to the nation's founding, it was realized that excessive concentrations of wealth were harmful and made it difficult to maintain the conditions needed for freedom to continue. The Second World War and its aftermath saw the exportation of the American values of freedom for all to the rest of the world. During the war, President Franklin D. Roosevelt made his Four Freedoms speech in which he stated that freedom of speech, freedom of religion, freedom from fear, and freedom from want were human rights that ought to be protected for all persons everywhere in the world. This speech served to be an inspiration for the development of the United Nations after the war, and the expansion of human rights to everyone throughout the world. The civil rights movement that started in the 1950s expanded the horizons of American liberty and freedom. The formal racial segregation and discrimination of the Jim Crow era was ended and economic discrimination was reduced. Courts made important civil rights and civil liberties decisions that expanded liberty and equality for all. Economic programs such Lyndon Johnson's Great Society expanded opportunity and alleviated poverty. During the 1970s and 80s women's rights were established and expanded., in a large part due to court victories won by activists.</p>
<div title="Page 6"><div title="Page 6">America is a nation of diversity created by a history of immigration, a nation not made of any one cultural or religious group. This nation has been a place where people of all kinds came for a better life throughout its entire history. This has been true since even before U.S independence. From Quaker and Puritan immigrants looking for religious freedom, to the immigrants of Ellis Island to modern immigrants, people have come to America looking for freedom. America has been a nation of ideals and laws, not of men or aristocracy, throughout its history. These values of freedom and equality have inspired struggle for all of America's history. While these struggles have never created a perfect union, America has become more perfect and a greater home to the blessings of liberty over its history. What makes a real American is not simply who you are, but it is our shared values and the belief that you have the freedom and opportunity to become all that you want to be, as long as you don't violate the freedoms and liberties of others. It is this belief in liberty and equality for all that makes America great and makes being an American great. The constitution gives Americans certain rights and our freedom and liberty are guaranteed. But what makes an American a real American is the respect for these values and the respect for the struggle that secured these freedoms, as well as a determination to continue to protect and fight for these values.</div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ellisisland" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ellisisland</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newdeal" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newdeal</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newworld" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newworld</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#10</category>
      <category>#ellisisland</category>
      <category>#newdeal</category>
      <category>#newworld</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Warming Is Lethal</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2012/global-warming-is-lethal</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2012/global-warming-is-lethal</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 14:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>300,000, 13,000, and 893. These three numbers will help you understand why global warming and our nation's fossil fuel dependency are grave issues that merit immediate attention.</p>

<p>300,000 represents the number of people who die each year due to the effects of global warming,<a href="http://edition.cnn.com/2009/WORLD/europe/05/29/annan.climate.change.human/"> according to a study by the Global Humanitarian Forum</a>, a think tank headed by former United Nations Secretary General Kofi Annan. Of those 300,000 deaths, 90 percent were due to malnutrition and disease caused by environmental degradation in developing nations. Additional deaths were caused by weather-related disasters.</p>

<p>300,000 is the number of Americans who die each year due to particle pollution from power plants, according to <a href="http://www.lung.org/about-us/our-impact/top-stories/toxic-air-coal-fired-power-plants.html"> a study by the American Lung Association.</a> That same study also found that "Coal-fired power plants that sell electricity to the grid produce more hazardous air pollution in the U.S. than any other industrial pollution sources".</p>

<p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20120718072711/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>mediakit.motherjones.com:80/<wbr></wbr>blue-marble/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>carbon-dioxide-emissions-cost-economy-underestimated</a>"&gt;$893 is the economic damage that each ton of emitted carbon dioxide causes.The total cost of the damage done by all CO2 pollution that the average American produces in a year is almost $15,000 (the per capita CO2 emissions of the United States is 17.5 tons).</p>

<p>Polluting industries, such coal, oil and gas, make their profits by not cleaning up the messes they make. They are profitable only because they are not paying the full costs of doing business and instead are placing those costs on the public.Natural resources are never free and they are not limitless. By destroying them now we are depriving future generations of their use and placing the costs of their depletion elsewhere.</p>

<p>Global warming is real and the damage it causes is already devastating to people throughout the world and to the world economy. We have an ethical obligation to rapidly reduce CO2 emissions now and move our economy towards sustainability and alternative energy sources.A full presentation of the scientific evidence for global warming is out of the scope of this blog post, but if you're interested, see this article for a basic overview <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150325153156/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>physics.ucsd.edu/<wbr></wbr>do-the-math/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>recipe-for-climate-change/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;<a href="http://physics.ucsd.edu/do-the-math/2011/08/recipe-for-climate-change/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>physics.ucsd.edu/<wbr></wbr>do-the-math/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>recipe-for-climate-change/<wbr></wbr></a> and this website for rebuttals for common denialist arguments <a href="&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a>"&gt;<a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a> Even if you are a global warming denialist, the fact is we are starting to run out of oil and high-grade deposits of coal and natural gas.<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20150630144808/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>physics.ucsd.edu/<wbr></wbr>do-the-math/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>10/<wbr></wbr>the-energy-trap/<wbr></wbr></a>"&gt;If we wait until there are dire shortages of energy resources, it will be more difficult to make the switch to alternative energy sources.</p>

<p>Unaddressed global warming will amount to to the mass violation of the human rights of tens of millions of people.Through no fault of their own whole populations will be exposed to health risks, food shortages, increased poverty and damage to their property. Coastal communities will be threatened with destruction as water levels rise. As Penn State professor Donald A. Brown stated "inadequate climate change policies must be understood to trigger human rights violations because climate change will not only make human dignity impossible for tens of millions of people around the world, including countless members of future generations, but directly threaten life itself and resources necessary to sustain life. That is, inadequate climate change policies qualify as human rights violations because of the enormity of harm to life, health, food, property, and inviolability of the right to enjoy the places where people live."(<a href="http://rockblogs.psu.edu/climate/2010/09/ethical-problems-with-cost-arguments-against-climate-change-policies-increased-costs-may-not-justify.html"></a><a href="http://rockblogs.psu.edu/climate/2010/09/ethical-problems-with-cost-arguments-against-climate-change-policies-increased-costs-may-not-justify.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>rockblogs.psu.edu/<wbr></wbr>climate/<wbr></wbr>2010/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>ethical-problems-with-cost-arguments-against-climate-change-policies-increased-costs-may-not-justify.html</a>) If the United States government did not take appropriate and rapid actions to reduce greenhouse gas pollution it would be a default on the principles set out under treaties including the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</p>

<p>High CO2 fuels also come with high costs to national security. According to <a href="http://www.iags.org/costofoil.html"> a report published by the Institute for the Analysis of Global Security “the economic penalties of America's oil dependence total $297.2 to $304.9 billion annually”</a><a>. Most of those costs of importing oil come from the military and political instability the oil trade creates and exposes the United States to. Our oil dependence also exposes the United States to price manipulation by the few major oil producers. An example of this risk came in</a><a href="http://www.setamericafree.org/index.php?option=com_content&task=view&id=20&Itemid=2#1"> "1973 when, in response to the Yom Kippur War, OPEC slashed production by 4.3 million barrels a day and caused a four-fold increase in oil prices"</a><a>.</a><a href="https://theojones.name/index.php/global-warming-is-leathal" rel="attachment wp-att-30"> That oil price shock was a primary trigger of the stagflation of the 1970s.</a></p>

<p>Phasing out fossil fuels will have minimal costs. A <a href="http://www.google.org/energyinnovation/growth.html"> study funded by Google found </a> that in their model investment in low CO2 energy sources "added $155 billion per year in GDP, creating 1.1 million net jobs, while reducing household energy costs by $942 per year". That study also found that "a mere five year delay in starting aggressive cost curves could cost the economy an aggregate $2.3-3.2 trillion in unrealized GDP gains, 1.2-1.4 million net jobs, and 8-28 gigatons in avoided greenhouse gas emissions by 2050".</p>

<p>Global warming will become a severe economic and human rights issue if rapid attempts to reduce fossil fuel use are not made. We have a ethical obligation to reduce CO2.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/globalhumanitarianforum" class="p-category" rel="tag">#globalhumanitarianforum</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/yomkippurwar" class="p-category" rel="tag">#yomkippurwar</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#1</category>
      <category>#gdp</category>
      <category>#globalhumanitarianforum</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#yomkippurwar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poverty: A Economic and Moral Crisis in America</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2012/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2012/poverty-a-economic-and-moral-crisis-in-america</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 23:45:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Today, many people in our nation face decisions like these:"<em>Should I pay for my children to go to the doctor or should I pay the rent?</em>" "<em>Should I put food on the table or pay my mortgage?</em>" Poverty shouldn't be an issue in our country. Nobody should have to face these decisions. We are better than that. We are the richest nation in the world. There is sufficient wealth in the United States to eliminate poverty. We have taken the path of inaction when all Western European and Scandinavian nations have for decades tried to eliminate and alleviate the suffering of the poor. They have made great strides in doing so, while still keeping strong economies. But the U.S. has stood still, letting poverty deprive millions of access to basic rights such as food, shelter, health care, and a chance for a productive life. The United States must take action.In this post I will explain why we have a obligation to help the poor and why current government programs are not up to the task of alleviating poverty.When you think of someone that is in poverty you might think of someone that is lazy and never does any work . But this is not true. Millions of those in poverty are the working poor that currently have a job. Many others are unemployed while they try to find a job. According to <a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/content/04_22/b3885001_mz001.htm">an article in Business Week magazine</a>, 24 percent of the workforce is in poverty.A <a href="http://www.urban.org/publications/310291.html">study by the Urban Institute</a> found that over 44 percent of homeless persons surveyed said they have worked at a job during the week that they were polled. A study by the Department of Health and Human Services <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20070510103756/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.nrchmi.samhsa.gov/<wbr></wbr>facts/<wbr></wbr>facts_question_2.asp</a>"&gt;found that 23 percent of the homeless are veterans. According to the National Coalition for the Homeless, <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20141229123239/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.nationalhomeless.org/<wbr></wbr>factsheets/<wbr></wbr>who.html</a>"&gt;39 percent of those that are currently homeless are in families with children.rnrnPoverty prevents many people from becoming the productive citizens that they would otherwise become. Someone will not pursue their higher goals, like getting an education or other job training, if their basic needs are not met.Our Declaration of Independence states that. We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal, that they are endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.But to realize these rights we must guarantee that people have a degree of equality of opportunity and their basic needs for food and shelter are met. This is especially true for children who are just starting out and who must rely on their parents.If we want to realize the principles of the Declaration of Independence, we must try our best to give everyone the same chance at a successful life. We must try our best to eliminate the cycle of poverty. We must try our best to allow everyone to get a good education, to receive health care, to get a decent job, to enjoy the same opportunities that all others enjoy. Poverty in childhood comes close to setting how far someone will go in their life. Poverty is the ultimate source of inequality in a modern democracy like the U.S.Alleviating poverty will not hurt the economy. Instead it will improve the economy. To see this, just look at the economies of the social democracies such as Sweden, Finland, Norway and Denmark. These countries tend to have even greater economic prosperity then the United States, without much of the poverty seen all too often in the U.S.Norway , Iceland, Canada, Sweden, and France, all countries with larger welfare systems then the United States, have higher Human Development Index scores then the U.S., according to the United Nations Development Program. The Human Development Index is a measure of the well-being of the population based on per capita GDP, life expectancy and education level.We are country that prides itself on the American Dream. But, the U.S has the second lowest income mobility of any developed nation (only the income mobility of the United Kingdom is worse). In other words "<a href="http://www.freakonomics.com/2012/01/19/is-higher-income-inequality-associated-with-lower-intergenerational-mobility/">rich parents have rich kids and poor parents have poor kids</a>".rnrnAccording to an ABC News report, which cited a study released in November 2009 in the Archives of Pediatrics and Adolescent Medicine, <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/Health/wireStory?id=8977934">almost half of the children in the United States will be on food stamps at some point during their childhood</a>. The cost of a home continues to decrease with our current economic depression. Yet many people still can't afford a home. We have almost 500,000 homeless in the U.S. at any given time and <a href="http://www.nationalhomeless.org/factsheets/How_Many.html">at some point in a typical year there will be 3.5 million people</a> that experience homelessness according to the National Coalition for the Homeless .rnrnEvery welfare program that we currently have leaves many behind. For example, look at Medicaid. It has done much to provide healthcare to the poor but does nothing for the 17% percent of the population that a Gallup survey published in 2012 found is uninsured. These people earn too little to buy insurance, but earn too much to qualify for our current welfare programs.The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program, which is commonly known as the food stamp program, has a similar problem. This program helps many people, but still millions of people have to worry about putting food on the table.According to the Food Research and Action Center, 49.1 million people in the United States live in food insecure households.Public housing programs, such as the Housing Choice Voucher program, that provide aid to families to help them rent a house, haven't eliminated homelessness.Our welfare programs leave millions behind. We need new programs that will help those that fall through the current welfare safety net, particularly the working poor. We have an ethical obligation to help those who are currently in poverty. Everyone deserves a basic standard of living and everyone should have equality of opportunity. We need to make sure everyone has the human rights outlined by our Declaration of Independence. Millions of the poor have been denied equality of opportunity by being born to impoverished parents. They have been denied the basic right to food, shelter, health care and a chance for a productive life.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/housingchoicevoucher" class="p-category" rel="tag">#housingchoicevoucher</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sweden" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sweden</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/urbaninstitute" class="p-category" rel="tag">#urbaninstitute</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#housingchoicevoucher</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#sweden</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
      <category>#urbaninstitute</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
