<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=110</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=110&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Black and white plant More at https www...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/black-and-white-plant-more-at-https-www</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/black-and-white-plant-more-at-https-www</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 02:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Black and white plant<br />More at <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157654065211549">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157654065211549</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0701web.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0701web.jpg" alt="DSCN0701web" width="1031" height="773" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2362"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactionaries on the left</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/reactionaries-on-the-left</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/reactionaries-on-the-left</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 21:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>[caption id="attachment_2448" align="aligncenter" width="604"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/6261922023_049039a2d8_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-2448 size-full" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/6261922023_049039a2d8_o.jpg" alt="6261922023_049039a2d8_o" width="604" height="452"></a> 2010 Anti-GMO protest in San Diego[/caption]</p>

<p>I've noticed that the hard left has a large amount of opposition to modernism and a good dose of what could be described as reactionaryism (the belief in the return to a past state). Sure, this is commonly (and perhaps almost exclusively) associated with the right-wing, but it's a huge element of some newer left-wing points of view. It's common to view reactionaryism solely in terms of classic social issues, and on these points reactionaryism is an inherently right-wing point of view. But there are other elements of policy and on these it's the left that wants to resist/reverse social progress. Additionally, this is one of the reasons why liberalism is NOT equivalent to progressivism/leftism. It's only an oddity of US politics that has made it seem like this is true. The range of political possibilities in the United States has be limited in such a way as to leave both progressives and liberals in agreement on all major issues of politics. I think this is beginning to change, and there will become an increasingly strong distinction between these two ideologies in the future. I would commit that within the next 10 or so years this will become a very noticeable distinction -- similar to the one that splits conservatives and libertarians. The dispute is fundamentally over the three pillars of enlightenment liberalism 1) science as the arbitrator of knowledge,2) democracy and due process as the arbitrator of political outcomes, and 3) individual liberty. Here are a few of the reactionary tendencies in the left wing viewpoint</p>
<ol><li>A dislike of science. This can be seen in issues like the debate over GMO's and similar conflicts. This can also be seen in the broader world of ideology. The world of left-leaning academic theory is almost overwhelmingly skeptical of the view that human society can be studied scientifically using the (largely quantative) methods commonly associated with the natural sciences. At the very least, this involves an emphasis on "other ways of knowing", and on the self-reported and analyzed "lived experiences" of people. This comes under such names as "structuralism" in the literature. The most extreme form of this comes under such names as post-structuralism and postmodernism and outright disputes the primacy of science even in the realm of the natural sciences, like physics and biology. This is of, course a highly problematic position, but is not at all rare in the world of diversity studies, and other left-leaning elements of the humanities.</li>
<li><p>Persistent clashes with freedom of speech. A lot of members of the modern left don't recognize the liberal distinction between speech and action. They have resurrected the ancient view that offensive speech or an attack on personal honor is an equivalent to physical violence. They act as if the advocacy of a course of action, or the belief that a course of action is within one's rights, or the attempt to participate in the political process, is equivalent to actually doing the action in question. This treatment of disagreeable speech as an equivalent of a physical attack also materializes into things like "trigger warnings" and the "safe place" movement. This bodes poorly for the underlying conception of democracy. Democracy feeds on public contestability and public debate of possible options. The vast majority of policy proposals will prove to be wrongheaded, and will be rightly rejected. But the process of free discourse and debate is absolutely essential to this process. Enlightenment civic republicanism came into existence in about the same time as science, because the two are innately linked. Both rely on decentralized finding of knowledge. In the case of science, this is for finding facts, in the case of democracy this is for determining how to run society. An attack on free speech is a full scale attack on both.</p></li>
<li><p>A neo-luddite view of technology and industrialization. Widespread industrialization and deployment of technology has vastly improved the standard of living of the typical person. However, many elements of the hard left want to return to a "small is beautiful" way of running the economy. An emphasis is put on small businesses and cooperatives. Some want a small scale and decentralized economy that looks a lot like the pre-industrial world. Its states' rights for progressives. And equally absurd. Despite its flaws, major firms can put in place a large degree of economic planning and stability that smaller firms cannot. They can leverage economies of scale, and they have vast efficiency improvements over smaller firms when they produce a uniform product Small is not efficient.</p></li>
</ol><p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/axkZfP">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>axkZfP</a> Flickr user Alexis Baden-Mayer</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/us" class="p-category" rel="tag">#us</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#us</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>http news yahoo com twitter adds sharing block...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/http-news-yahoo-com-twitter-adds-sharing-block</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/http-news-yahoo-com-twitter-adds-sharing-block</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 03:56:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://news.yahoo.com/twitter-adds-sharing-block-lists-224203264.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>news.yahoo.com/<wbr></wbr>twitter-adds-sharing-block-lists-224203264.html</a>Twitter's new block list feature is very good. Its the perfect fix to idiots on twitter with little potential for abuse. These blocklists are voluntary. In fact, voluntary, user directed filtering is much less abuse prone than its alternative -- the banhammer. If a killfile you got from somewhere is nuking stuff you want to see, just drop it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/twitter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#twitter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#twitter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do you tell the difference between Twitter's...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-do-you-tell-the-difference-between-twitters</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/how-do-you-tell-the-difference-between-twitters</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 03:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>How do you tell the difference between Twitter's new killfile options and McCarthyist censorship?  In one Commie McRed was prevented from talking to people who what to hear what he has to say. In the other, Gater McAsshole is being stopped from spewing to a captive audience who doesn't want to listen to him. Freedom of speech doesn't guarantee an audience. There will be people who don't want to hear what you have to say, and its their right to tune you out (as long as they don't try to stop you from reaching those who do want to hear you). McCarthyism was firing people for being part of the communist party. This twitter feature is more like telling your secretary you want all mailings from the communist party thrown away.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/censorship" class="p-category" rel="tag">#censorship</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/twitter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#twitter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#censorship</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#twitter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today's photos of mine https www flickr com...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/todays-photos-of-mine-https-www-flickr-com</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/todays-photos-of-mine-https-www-flickr-com</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 03:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Today's photos of mine<br /><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157653969806690">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157653969806690</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0605web.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0605web.jpg" alt="DSCN0605web" width="1031" height="773" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2353"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When does censorship occur?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/when-does-censorship-occur</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/when-does-censorship-occur</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 15:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>A lot of people try to pretend that censorship is something that can only exist when done by governments, that private actors cannot affect free speech in any meaningful way. This is absurd in my point of view. A right does not meaningfully exist if it cannot be effectively exercised. And private actors can easily put restraints on speakers that can make it very difficult to effectively participate<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3992988737_bebac07fb4_b.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2451" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/3992988737_bebac07fb4_b-300x189.jpg" alt="3992988737_bebac07fb4_b" width="300" height="189"></a> in politics or partake in free speech. The "freedom of speech isn't freedom of consequences" rejoinder that is commonly heard on internet debates isn't much better either. All censorship works by imposing consequences. The question on free speech is simply, what consequences are acceptable. On the other extreme, there are a lot of people who seem to act like that all criticism of a work they like is an attempt at censorship. This is at the very least a self-contradictory (although there is the easy to over-apply aside that an overly toxic social attitude towards a set of idea can make it very difficult to express them). A much better boundary for free speech versus censorship would be external versus internal consequences. An external consequence on speech is one that occurs through a factor other than the direct market for a work. An internal one comes from the market for the work, and the response from consumers to it. External consequences are often censorship, while internal ones are very rarely censorship. Examples of external consequences would include classic government censorship, threats to unrelated employment, harassment (i.e. SWATing, doxxing, etc.), deprivation of a resource that is generally available to all comers, attempts to pressure a publisher to drop a work by targeting unrelated ones, and so on. The problem with such external consequences comes from my belief that it is fundamentally problematic to use power gained in unrelated markets to muscle one's way into an advantageous position in the marketplace of ideas. Idea and art should rise and fall on their own terms, not the terms of who has the most power in society. It's a similar issue to anti-trust efforts. It is unjust for a company to use its power in one sector of the economy to blast out otherwise viable competitors in other sectors. A focus on external consequences as the demarcating like explains clearly why a lot of things are extremely problematic. Campaigns to target the employment of those with disfavored views (like what occurred in the Brendan Eich controversy) are unethical. <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> style harassment campaigns against people speaking disfavored views are unethical. Campaigns to get stores to drop disfavored works by boycotting unrelated products are problematic (like the one that recently hit Target over the Grand Theft Auto video game). Attempts to pressure providers of generally available services like Facebook and Twitter to drop unpopular speakers are cases of censorship, Internal consequences would include the loss of market for a work due to consumer distaste, and regular editorial discretion by publishers. They are unavoidable and not necessarily unethical.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit: Flickr User Carolyn Tiry <a href="https://flic.kr/p/75R7rp">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>75R7rp</a> </strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/brendaneich" class="p-category" rel="tag">#brendaneich</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#brendaneich</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is a interesting blog on philosophy https...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-is-a-interesting-blog-on-philosophy-https</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/this-is-a-interesting-blog-on-philosophy-https</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 05:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>This is a interesting blog on philosophy <br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com</a></p>

<p>Some of the more interesting articles:<br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/2010/07/01/the-normative-web-an-argument-for-moral-realism-by-terance-cuneo/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2010/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>01/<wbr></wbr>the-normative-web-an-argument-for-moral-realism-by-terance-cuneo/<wbr></wbr></a><br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/2011/05/20/the-debate-over-moral-realism/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>20/<wbr></wbr>the-debate-over-moral-realism/<wbr></wbr></a><br /><a href="https://ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/2011/07/19/the-isought-gap-how-do-we-get-ought-from-is/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ethicalrealism.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2011/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>19/<wbr></wbr>the-isought-gap-how-do-we-get-ought-from-is/<wbr></wbr></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/philosophy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#philosophy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#philosophy</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New photos https www flickr com photos 132940671@N06...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-https-www-flickr-com-photos-132940671n06-1</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/new-photos-https-www-flickr-com-photos-132940671n06-1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 05:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>New photos <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157652000470244">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157652000470244</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0578web.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0578web.jpg" alt="DSCN0578web" width="773" height="580" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2346"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Progress used to be one of the...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/climate-progress-used-to-be-one-of-the</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/climate-progress-used-to-be-one-of-the</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Climate Progress used to be one of the better blogs on the climate change issue, particulary when it was pretty much Joe Rohm's site. But then the Center for American Progress (its host) decided to shake things up a little bit, and its quality tanked. To see what I mean, look at this claptrap <br /><a href="http://thinkprogress.org/climate/2015/06/09/3667260/oregon-gmo-ban/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>thinkprogress.org/<wbr></wbr>climate/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>09/<wbr></wbr>3667260/<wbr></wbr>oregon-gmo-ban/<wbr></wbr></a><br />"This County In Oregon Completely Banned GMO Crops. Here’s Why That Matters For The Environment."</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gmo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gmo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#gmo</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamergate is trashing the reputation of the tech community</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-is-trashing-the-reputation-of-the-tech-community</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/gamergate-is-trashing-the-reputation-of-the-tech-community</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7439512656_04f88d7461_z.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7439512656_04f88d7461_z.jpg" alt="7439512656_04f88d7461_z" width="640" height="426" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2454"></a>There is another reason to dislike the toxic cloud of sexism that is <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a>. It's totally trashing the reputation of every community it touches. The gaters have reinforced pretty much every negative stereotype about gamers. They have made every gamer look like a doxing and SWATTing idiot. They have created a massive harassment campaign in the name of "protecting" gaming. And all they have done is to damage the reputation of the tech community. Look at anything in the popular press on this issue. Look at this article, for instance <a href="http://thinkprogress.org/culture/2015/06/05/3661042/women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/"></a><a href="http://thinkprogress.org/culture/2015/06/05/3661042/women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>thinkprogress.org/<wbr></wbr>culture/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>3661042/<wbr></wbr>women-using-gamergate-industry-discrimination-change-tech/<wbr></wbr></a>   What is its first example of sexism in tech? <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> . Incidents like <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> have made it look like everyone in tech is like the gaters.  It makes us all look like a pack of Neanderthals that was dredged up from the Pleistocene.  The gaters may screech and holler about the so-called "gamers are dead" articles what were published earily in this controversy. But all they have done is prove that gaming will be dead in its current form if it doesn't clean up its toxic community. And gaters and their ilk are at the forefront of the toxic elements of the gamer community. And that's the saddest thing about GG, they have failed by even their own objectives. They have made every issue they claim to care about worse. They have proven to the world that, even their fiercest critics, and the fiercest critics of the gaming community have a point. Its time fight back against GG and its toxic sexism, lest the gaters burn the community to the ground.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: Flickr user JD Hancock <a href="https://flic.kr/p/ckprVA">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>ckprVA</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
