<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23newzealand</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23newzealand&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Riders : Thoughts on the Trans-Pacific Partnership</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/riders-thoughts-on-the-trans-pacific-partnership</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/riders-thoughts-on-the-trans-pacific-partnership</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The Trans-Pacific Partnership is a proposed trade agreement involving multiple countries bordering the Pacific Ocean. These countries include the United States, Australia, New Zealand, and Singapore.  However, this agreement is not just about trade. It contains multiple riders relating to copyright, trademark, patent, and anti-trust law. Some of these riders will also serve to censor journalists and researchers, particulary those who study computer security. I believe that these riders will have effects that are harmful enough to erase the benefits of the increased trade that the treaty may bring. The trade parts of the treaty are good, the riders are not. In this post I will briefly discuss the reasons why I generally support free trade. I will then discuss some of the problematic parts of this agreement.  <br /><!--more--></p>
<h3>My General Opinions On Trade</h3><p>I believe that in general <a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/report-on-business/economy/economy-lab/imports-are-a-benefit-exports-are-a-cost-is-it-clear-now/article614908/">imports are a benefit to the economy and exports are not a benefit, but instead the cost of imports</a>. Trade provides the economy tangible goods that can only be produced in the domestic economy at a high cost if at all. I believe that a majority of the trade barriers which remain in the economy primarily "protect" skilled industries.Protectionism harms the economy. It causes consumers to pay more, and because protectionism harms domestic industries that rely on imported materials it can serve as more of a job swap than job protection. An economy in free trade will tend to focus on its most productive industries, and thereby maximize its productivity.</p><p>There are only a handful of cases where I believe that trade restrictions may be justified and none of these cases are protectionist.For example, a government may enact a humanitarian trade restriction, such as a trade sanction designed to deter a human rights violation. Some trade and immigration restrictions may be necessary to give nations policy space to enact needed programs or to protect global economic stability. These may include capital controls designed to restrict speculative transactions that destabilize markets, or possibly some restrictions on immigration designed to limit migrant inflows to a level that an economy has the ability to sustain itself without excessive disruption. Some trade restrictions may also be necessary to develop domestic industry, to allocate limited foreign capital resources in an optimal way, or to phase out a trade policy that cannot be sustained in the long run. Restrictions of this form may be more necessary in developing nations or small nations with limited economic resources.</p><p> </p><h3>The TTP and Free Speech</h3><p>Article 4 of the latest draft of the TTP prohibits the development or publication of technology or methods that serve to "enable or facilitate" the circumvention of a computer security system. This could have a severe chilling effect on discussion and education about computer security. Even though there is a narrow exemption for research this provision could be used to intimidate scholars looking into computer security issues. Even worse would be the effect  on journalists, as there is no exemption for their work. Journalists would be restricted in their ability to discuss computer security issues and would need the approval of the software developer before they could publish information about security  vulnerability in a computer program. J<a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2007/05/09-f9-legal-primer">udicial interpretation of similar</a>, but more narrow, laws already on the books in the United States suggests that the TPP could make it illegal for bloggers or journalists to even link to websites that publish software that can be used to disable copy protection.</p><p>This provision would also restrict the ability of librarians to archive books and other works which are protected by copy protection. The provision of the treaty which applies penalties to anyone who “distributes, imports for distribution, broadcasts, communicates or makes available to the public copies of works [protected by DRM when the DRM has been disabled]” would completely prohibit librarians from making these archives open to the public.</p><p><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2012/08/new-leaked-tpp-puts-fair-use-risk">The TPP would reduce the fair use restrictions that allow excerpts of copyrighted works to be used for "criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship and research".  </a>  </p><h3 style="text-align: center;">Copyright, Patent, and Trademarks</h3><p><a href="https://www.eff.org/issues/tpp">The treaty would have other effects on copyright law</a>. It would  </p><ol><li>Enhance the liability put on ISPs for the actions of their users, and would make it easier for people who claim a copyright to force ISPs to remove their users' data. This takedown procedure would have little to no independent oversight and would have few protections against false claims.</li>
    <li>It would expand copyright terms  to the life of the author plus 70 years.</li>
    <li>It would <em>prohibit</em> the resale of copyrighted works between countries without the permission of the copyright holder, even when the copies were legally purchased.</li>
</ol><p>The treaty would also expand the scope of patent law by  </p><ol><li>Lowering the standards needed for an invention to receive a patent. The TPP declares that “patents shall be available for any new forms, uses, or methods of <strong>using a known product</strong>; and may satisfy the criteria for patentability, <strong>even if such invention does not result in the enhancement of the known efficacy of the product</strong>.” (emphasis added)</li>
    <li>The treaty also expands the scope of genetic patents. It declares that patents may be granted on “plants and animals”.</li>
    <li>It also expands the scope of medical patents and allows patents on “diagnostic, therapeutic, and <strong>surgical methods</strong> for the treatment of humans or animals.” Emphasis added.</li>
</ol><p>Trademarks are also expanded.“No Party may require, as a condition of registration, <strong>that a sign be visually perceptible</strong>, nor may a Party deny registration of a trademark solely on the grounds that the sign of which it is composed is a sound or a scent.” Emphasis added.</p><p> </p><p>I will discuss the anti-trust and regulatory implications of the treaty in a later post.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/freespeech" class="p-category" rel="tag">#freespeech</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/newzealand" class="p-category" rel="tag">#newzealand</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tpp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tpp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/unitedstates" class="p-category" rel="tag">#unitedstates</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#freespeech</category>
      <category>#newzealand</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#tpp</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#unitedstates</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
