<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=30</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=30&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>You Can&#x2019;t &#x2018;Steal&#x2019; a Culture: In Defense of Cultural Appropriation - The Daily Beast</title>
      <link>http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2014/07/15/you-can-t-steal-a-culture-in-defense-of-cultural-appropriation.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/you-cant-steal-a-culture-in-defense-of-cultural-appropriation</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 05:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"<span style="font-family: Georgia, Times, serif; font-size: 1.1875em; line-height: 1.6;">But</span><a style="font-family: Georgia, Times, serif; font-size: 1.1875em; line-height: 1.6; box-sizing: border-box; outline: 0px; cursor: pointer; color: #6c899d; transition: color 0.2s ease-in-out initial; -webkit-transition: color 0.2s ease-in-out initial; display: inline;" name="_GoBack"></a><span style="font-family: Georgia, Times, serif; font-size: 1.1875em; line-height: 1.6;"> </span><span style="font-family: Georgia, Times, serif; font-size: 1.1875em; line-height: 1.6;">what does it mean to 'steal' someone’s culture when we’re not talking about money? With gay white men and black women, for example, it’s not as if the black women are being left without their culture after the 'theft,' or as if gay white men are somehow out there 'out-blacking' the women they 'stole' from."</span></p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
      <category>#6c899d</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxford University Student Union bans free speech magazine because it is 'offensive' - Telegraph</title>
      <link>http://www.telegraph.co.uk/education/universityeducation/11904376/Oxford-University-Student-Union-bans-free-speech-magazine-because-it-is-offensive.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/oxford-university-student-union-bans-free-speech-magazine-because-it</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 05:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    </div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Songbun and the five castes of North Korea</title>
      <link>http://www.nknews.org/2015/02/songbun-and-the-five-castes-of-north-korea/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/songbun-and-the-five-castes-of-north-korea</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 05:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    
<p>"The most important element in the social structure of Kim Il Sung’s North Korea was the infamous songbun system. This system was established in the late 1950s and came into full power somewhere around 1967. It divides the population into groups, according to the actions and status of their paternal ancestor (and themselves, depending on their age) during the Japanese colonial period and the Korean War. Songbun determined, among other things, whether one was allowed to live in the capital or in special cities like Kaesong and later Rason, the workplace one is allocated and what kind of education one can receive."</p>
</div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jon Ronson&#x2019;s So You&#x2019;ve Been Publicly Shamed, reviewed.</title>
      <link>http://www.slate.com/articles/arts/books/2015/04/jon_ronson_s_so_you_ve_been_publicly_shamed_reviewed.2.html</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/jon-ronsons-so-youve-been-publicly-shamed-reviewed</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 05:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    
<p>"I wish that Ronson had also considered why demanding that someone is fired from his or her job has become so central to the public shaming ritual. This demand, I think, reveals several things. First, it reflects how we are all public figures now and all have brands or reputations to protect, and so do our erstwhile employers. We have ported the logic of the celebrity shame cycle—in which corporate sponsors are expected to drop the offender posthaste—to the workaday world. It’s a strange conflation of the public and private, of believing that individuals are always-on representatives of their employers and that an incensed public is in a position to decide when this association should end."</p>
</div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Francis and Kim Davis</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/pope-francis-and-kim-davis</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/pope-francis-and-kim-davis</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Pope Francis met with Kim Davis, and in the process killed some <a href="https://twitter.com/VincentHarris/status/649291050067099648">endangered social media feels</a>. I'm with Washington Post <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2015/09/30/why-no-one-should-be-surprised-that-pope-francis-met-with-kim-davis/?tid=sm_fb">editorial writer Chris Cillizza on this, why is anyone surprised</a>? </p><p>Its not like the pope kept his opinions on gay marriage a secret. And on a similar note, why do people think that Pope Francis is such a change from previous popes? Other than changing the presentation, he has made minimal changes to catholic doctrine. His opinions on economic issues are the same as most other recent popes, and skepticism about capitalism has been part of the religion for quite a while. And the catholic church is as opposed to gay marriage, and abortion as ever. It is still the same religion as before, only with different packaging. </p><p>And do Davis' opinions and those  of the Pope actually vary that radically? Other than the fact that Davis is a million times more of an asshole about them?</p><p>Consider the following:</p><ul><li>Pope Francis is the monarch of a country that is decidedly not issuing marriage licenses to gay people.</li>
<li>Until a week ago, Davis was a member of the democratic party, so we can at least assume her opinions are at least somewhat moderate on economic issues.</li>
</ul><p>A lot of the sympathy going around towards both individuals is just political signaling. Davis  sends out the conservative political signals, while Francis is associated with liberal ones. Supporters of both follow these signals.</p></div>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Virtual Violence | Simple Justice</title>
      <link>http://blog.simplejustice.us/2015/09/26/the-new-virtual-violence/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-new-virtual-violence-simple-justice</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:04:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p><span style="color: #444444; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 15px; line-height: 20px;">"now is exactly the time to stop the use of the word 'violence' in connection with online communications. Speech on the internet can be patently offensive and monumentally stupid (and those of you doing so really need to STFU), but this isn’t violence."</span></p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
      <category>#444444</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Safe Spaces" And The Mote In America's Eye | Popehat</title>
      <link>https://popehat.com/2015/04/19/safe-spaces-and-the-mote-in-americas-eye/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/safe-spaces-and-the-mote-in-americas-eye-popehat</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 23:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"Today's college students came of age in the years after 9/11. What did we teach them about the balance between liberty and safety in that time? We should have taught them not to give up essential liberty for a little safety. Instead, we taught them that the government needs the power to send flying robots to kill anyone on the face of the earth without review and without telling us why. The government, we're told, needs to do that for our safety. We also taught them that the government also needs the power to detain people indefinitely without judicial review, again in the name of safety. We taught them that to ensure our safety the government needs the records of what books we read and who we talk to. With that as a model, it seems like small potatoes to say that safety requires disinviting Bill Maher from a university commencement, because he's something of a dick."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Safe Spaces For Bad Scholarship | Simple Justice</title>
      <link>http://blog.simplejustice.us/2015/09/24/safe-spaces-for-bad-scholarship/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/safe-spaces-for-bad-scholarship-simple-justice</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"The “solutions” to drug violence permeate the law, and attitudes toward drugs, that grew out of the crack days, from the drug kingpin sentences reflected in the sentencing guidelines to in rem forfeiture, sold as “taking the profit out of crime.” These are monumentally serious issues, given that the number of murders in New York City in 2014 was 328. Clearly, something has changed, given that recent drug crime hasn’t produce a fraction of the violence. Does this matter? You bet it does. It’s critical that judges recognize that the perceived connection between drugs and violence from the bad old days is no longer true, and that defendants sentenced for drug offenses not be viewed through the prism of violence as well. But when the “scholarship” relies on such a mistaken premise, that violence never happened, it’s immediately dismissed."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cowardly Silence (Update) | Simple Justice</title>
      <link>http://blog.simplejustice.us/2015/09/22/cowardly-silence/</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/cowardly-silence-update-simple-justice</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 23:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <p>"This is the Teacup’s Veto, the twisted logic that speech that causes the most fragile to make the choice of remaining silent lest their feelings be hurt by unpleasant words must be silenced. "</p></div>
]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dangers and ramifications of doxxing and swatting</title>
      <link>http://www.gamezone.com/originals/the-dangers-and-ramifications-of-doxxing-and-swatting</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-dangers-and-ramifications-of-doxxing-and-swatting</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 23:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div class="known-bookmark">
    <blockquote><p>"If there’s one thing we’ve learned from the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> debate, it’s that people -- on both sides -- are being harassed. I’m not just referring to tweets and emails saying rotten things, but the leaking of personal information for everyone to see, also referred to as doxxing. Even before Gamergate, doxxing and swatting (filing a false report of a critical incident in which response units, including SWAT and bomb squads, are deployed) have been tactics used to harass people in the gaming community -- mostly pro gamers."</p></blockquote></div>
]]></description>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
