<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=100</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=100&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why avoid online SEO services: a personal experience.</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-avoid-online-seo-services-a-personal-experience</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-avoid-online-seo-services-a-personal-experience</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 15:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/SEO.png"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/SEO.png" alt="SEO" width="1000" height="496" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2435"></a>A while ago, I was an idiot and decided to try one of those SEO services on Fivver. The "SEO" person sent me an analytics link for the url shortener used, it was reporting thousands of views a day from the campaign. The analytics on my blog reported less but still over 1000 a day. And, of course, it was fake traffic city.<br />The traffic delivered was obvious bot traffic with spoofed referral headers, instead of the genuine traffic promised in the offer. On both the analytics link the seller provided, and in the internal analytics of my website, there was a large amount of Google traffic. That traffic was almost certainly spoofed for four reasons 1) the Google webmaster tools for my website does not record anywhere near the amount of google search traffic as reported, meaning that the traffic did not go through Google, 2) it is hard to fathom any legitimate way that thousands of Google hits could be produced in a few days when my site usually has around 20 google hits, 3) the IP addresses of this traffic (on the logs of my analytics) come from data centers, and 4) there is no additional traffic from other search engines like Bing (any legitimate way of providing Google hits would of also affected other search engines). Furthermore, the retweets on the promised tweet are also almost certainly fake. These accounts have little activity. The fake tweets and the spoofed search both could have had the strong potential to harm the google ranking of my site.<br />Now, it didn’t take long for me to realize what was going on. So I requested a cancelation on Fivver with text that was effectively the same as the paragraph above. And weirdly, the “seller” accepted – pretty much just conceded and gave my money back in a few hours. I actually expected that I would have had to of gone to support for that one. But, the conclusion remains. Most such online SEO programs are blatant scams. Don’t buy them.</p>

<p><strong>Image credit:</strong> India7 Network <a href="https://flic.kr/p/qYSLjm">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>qYSLjm</a> www.seolinkbuilding.org/seo-tools/</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/seo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#seo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#seo</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More at https www flickr com photos 132940671@N06...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-at-https-www-flickr-com-photos-132940671n06</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/more-at-https-www-flickr-com-photos-132940671n06</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 04:58:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>More at <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/132940671@N06/sets/72157652336763754">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.flickr.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>132940671@N06/<wbr></wbr>sets/<wbr></wbr>72157652336763754</a><br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0736web.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/DSCN0736web.jpg" alt="DSCN0736web" width="836" height="627" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2378"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/photos" class="p-category" rel="tag">#photos</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#photos</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GOP has a catch 22 on issues...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gop-has-a-catch-22-on-issues</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-gop-has-a-catch-22-on-issues</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 04:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The GOP has a catch 22 on issues like abortion. Abortion talk is good base feed, but it summons the idots who talk about legitimate rape.  GOPers need to get past the primaries, but they can't nuckledrag too much lest they lose out at the general election.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gop" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gop</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gop</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A New Uber Service (satire)</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/a-new-uber-service-satire</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/a-new-uber-service-satire</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 05:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/uberseminar.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2431" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/uberseminar.jpg" alt="uberseminar" width="1000" height="361"></a>[podcast]<a href="https://objects.dreamhost.com:443/theopodcasts/uber_01_01.mp3%5B/podcast%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>objects.dreamhost.com:443/<wbr></wbr>theopodcasts/<wbr></wbr>uber_01_01.mp3[/<wbr></wbr>podcast]</a></p>

<p>Interested in forming your own <strong><em><u>disruptive</u></em></strong> startup? Well, the Uber business seminar is for you. Learn how to <strong><em><u>disrupt</u></em></strong> competitors, consumers and regulators from the founders of Uber --- <em>Ayn Rand’s Favorite Taxi</em>.</p>
<ul><li>Learn how to turn a service that has existed for over a century into a <strong><em><u>disruptive</u></em></strong> Silicon Valley wonder, by doing the same thing, only with a computer. Learn the core of the Uber business model from someone who has practiced it for 20 years – John Smith the taxi driver.</li>
    <li>Learn how to <strong><em><u>disrupt</u></em></strong> regulations regarding your service by pretending that adding a computer means you are doing something different. Learn about the intellectual property applications of this technique from Jack Cheatem, lawyer for many IP litigation companies including Prenda Law, and Intellectual Ventures.</li>
    <li>Learn from the Uber IT team just how little you can spend on computer security without immediate impact. If you follow our method, by the time you get customer data hacked from your insecure servers, you will be a multibillion dollar company that just doesn’t need to care.</li>
    <li>Learn how to <strong><em><u>disrupt</u></em></strong> consumer behavior. Are your users attune to your high prices? Our surge pricing method will fix that. They won’t even realize how much you are charging them.</li>
    <li>Learn how to become a platform not a service. Platforms sound nice and <strong><em><u>disruptive</u></em></strong> and even better, the <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">dolts</span> service providers on your platform aren’t your employees, so you don’t have to follow labor law, disability law, anti-discrimination law, or other big government red tape. And even better, the <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">dolts</span> service providers on your platform won’t realize how many of your costs you outsourced to them.</li>
    <li>Discuss the books that every business man should read, including, <em>Atlas Shrugged, The Fountainhead,</em> and <em>The Virtue of Selfishness</em>.</li>
    <li>Learn how to apply the Ferengi Rules of Acquisition to your startup.</li>
</ul>
<p>Image credit:<a href="https://flic.kr/p/s6895ev">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>s6895ev</a><br /><em>See <a href="https://objects.dreamhost.com:443/theopodcasts/uber_01.flac">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>objects.dreamhost.com:443/<wbr></wbr>theopodcasts/<wbr></wbr>uber_01.flac</a> for losslessly compressed downloadable version of the audio version of this article.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uber" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uber</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uber</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google treats www example com and example com...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/google-treats-www-example-com-and-example-com</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/google-treats-www-example-com-and-example-com</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 22:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Google treats www.example.com and example.com as different. This can cause problems with things like the Google Webmaster Tools, and can result in the duplicate content penalty. Redirect one to the other.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/googlewebmastertools" class="p-category" rel="tag">#googlewebmastertools</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#googlewebmastertools</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Phrase &#x201C;Social Justice&#x201D;</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-phrase-social-justice</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-phrase-social-justice</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/socialjustice.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/socialjustice.jpg" alt="socialjustice" width="1000" height="800" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2439"></a>The above image is a collage of three of the top results on Flickr for a search of the phrase "Social Justice". The <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sully_aka__wstera2/4478077831/">top-left image is from user wstera2 </a>and is titled "When liberals are losing a debate". The top right image is from user Takver and is titled "C<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/takver/5415825802/">hange, Freedom, Social Justice - Egypt Uprising protest</a>". The bottom image is titled "<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rikkis_refuge/16400696138/">World Day for Social Justice</a>" and is via user Rikki's Refuge.</p>

<p>By its self, the phrase "social justice" is pretty meaningless. The phrase is effectively equivalent to the word "fairness". Try taking an article that uses the phrase and swapping out all occurrences of "social justice" for fairness. Very little meaning will be lost.    But "fairness" is an arbitrary concept. Almost every political ideology will perceive their goals as "fair".  Phrases like "social justice" are the political equivalent of "maximizing synergies" business speak. Such concepts are almost entirely dependent on ideology. What one will perceive as "fair" or "just is largely subjective in global terms. Every major political ideology has a different conception of the public good. Libertarians regard markets as properly "fair", others regard egalitarianism as "fair", and others take a roughly utilitarian perspective of the greatest good for the greatest number as "fair". However, the concept is still subjective.  In regards to talk of "fairness" in economic policy, <a href="http://blog.dilbert.com/post/102964895406/fairness-test">Scott Adams (the author of the Dilbert cartoon) made a similar point</a>. "<em>fairness is a concept invented so dumb people can participate in debates. Fairness isn't a natural law of the universe. It's a psychological problem. We sometimes get fairness confused with equality. Equality is usually good, and can often be measured with a satisfying precision. Fairness, on the other hand, is usually just a rationale for some sort of bias ….It's just a psychological phenomenon that is easily manipulated.</em>"</p>

<p>However, there is one case where the phrase "social justice" carries more meaning than the word "fairness". The only meaning that is conveyed by that term is signaling about the speaker. Only certain ideologies refer to their goals as maximizing social justice. This gets us to pejoratives like "SJW".  So when a gater rants about "SJWs" they are attacking the ideologies refer to their goals as maximizing social justice. However, SJW is a strong pejorative. Using it is like saying "M$" in a discussion about Windows 10. It removes any indication that you are processing facts in a rational way and indicates that confirmation bias is at work. It's an inherently mocking tone, one that should only be used with clearly unreasonable positions. And treating reasonable positions as unreasonable destroys one's credibility.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/business" class="p-category" rel="tag">#business</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scottadams" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scottadams</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sjw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sjw</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#business</category>
      <category>#scottadams</category>
      <category>#sjw</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I'd approve of a test liability insurance system...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/id-approve-of-a-test-liability-insurance-system</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/id-approve-of-a-test-liability-insurance-system</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 01:21:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I'd approve of a test/liability insurance system for gun regulation, but, only if it was part of a total redesign of the gun regulation system that took way all of the trash gun control laws. But that's not going to happen because a lot of gun control types are just like pro-lifers who realize that they can't outright ban abortion, so they just slam clinics with as much bullshit regulation as possible to make doctors' lives as hard as possible.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The problems with the Recently Released Study on Gun Control In Connecticut</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-problems-with-the-recently-released-study-on-gun-control</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-problems-with-the-recently-released-study-on-gun-control</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 23:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/nogun.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/nogun.jpg" alt="nogun" width="1000" height="539" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2442"></a>A study titled "Association Between Connecticut’s Permit-to-Purchase Handgun Law and Homicides" has been published in the American Journal of Public Health. Its abstract can be found here <a href="http://ajph.aphapublications.org/doi/10.2105/AJPH.2015.302703">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>ajph.aphapublications.org/<wbr></wbr>doi/<wbr></wbr>10.2105/<wbr></wbr>AJPH.2015.302703</a>    The thesis of the authors is that the handgun permit-to-purchase law passed in Connecticut in October of 1995 produced a large reduction in the rate of homicides caused by firearms.  They write "We estimated that the law was associated with a 40% reduction in Connecticut’s firearm homicide rates during the first 10 years that the law was in place. By contrast, there was no evidence for a reduction in nonfirearm homicides". The method they use produces an indeterminate result in regards to whether non-firearm homicides increased, or decreased. So, their results are entirely consistent with a situation where the law transferred the weapon used in homicides with little impact on their over all rate., even though a lot of the commentary on the paper (and even the authors themselves to some degree) portray these results as a major facet in the case for gun control</p>

<p>At first glance, there seem to be some major methodological issues with this study. There is, a zone of weaseldom in-between perfectly done and rigorous studies, and outright forgery. And due to some of the previously mentioned issues with this paper, that is what I see this one as.  The first is the paper's total reliance on arbitrary cutoffs. In particular, they (with little explanation) choose 2005 as the end of the date range that they were studying (despite that later data was available from the data set they were using).  It seems that their results are pretty much dependent on that 2005 cutoff. Expanding it to the full dataset, or reducing it to earlier dates, or even moving it forward one year to 2006 totally causes the correlation to break down. They no longer get a p-value less than 0.05.  This is a huge red flag and really reflects negatively on the quality of the whole study. This type of result dependence on a cutoff like that needs a lot of justification ,but all I see is handwaveing. Fortunately, they do adjust for the nationwide trend in reduction in violence, but the fact that there has been a nation wide reduction in gun violence of a similar magnitude brings up issues with causation. There is little direct evidence for causation, and the 30% number seems quite high (particularly when compared to the relatively weak correlation between homicide rates and gun ownership between nations).</p>

<p><strong>Image credit</strong>: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/b578sH">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>b578sH</a> Flickr user Steve Snodgrass</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I've deployed twitter blocklists like GG autoblocker and...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-deployed-twitter-blocklists-like-gg-autoblocker-and</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/ive-deployed-twitter-blocklists-like-gg-autoblocker-and</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 22:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I've deployed twitter blocklists (like GG autoblocker, and the A+ blocklist) because I've gotten a bit of trolling because of tweeting about controversial topics (like gamergate). And I'm a man with ~4000 followers. But even despite a smallish audience and my gender, the trolling was annoying enough. And the blocklists shut the trolls up. I'm not totally a fan of them -- the method of adding accounts to the lists seems more aggressive than a Klingon with an anger management problem -- but its better than nothing. Really, these twitter blocklists are like some of the first spam blocklists. Problematic in how they decided to add ip addresses to the killfile, but good enough at killing spammers to make it worth it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/twitter" class="p-category" rel="tag">#twitter</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#twitter</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merging MMT and Market Monetarism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/merging-mmt-and-market-monetarism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/merging-mmt-and-market-monetarism</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2015 22:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/fed.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/fed.jpg" alt="fed" width="1000" height="572" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2446"></a>[podcast]<a href="https://objects.dreamhost.com:443/theopodcasts/MMT%20%26%20MM_01.mp3%5B/podcast%5DThere">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>objects.dreamhost.com:443/<wbr></wbr>theopodcasts/<wbr></wbr>MMT%20%26%20MM_01.mp3[/<wbr></wbr>podcast]There</a> are two recently popularized perspectives in economic theory that have a lot of promise. The first is post-Keynesian theories like Modern Monetary Theory. These emphasize the role of fiscal policy, and argue that the monetary system is fundamentally a legal construct. For a country with its own, floating currency the only constraints on fiscal policy are inflation and unemployment. If a government keeps its levels of deficit spending too low it can risk unemployment, but if it spends too much it risks inflation. Post-Keynesians treat taxes (and levels of spending) primarily are regulators of aggregate demand and the over-all money supply. Taxes destroy money, spending creates it. There is no "crowding out" of private sector debt caused by government spending. And MMTers/post-Keynesians dispute the role of the money multiplier as commonly understood. Banks can borrow directly from the Fed, and the Fed will expand the monetary base if interest rates slip from targets, making the money multiplier a useless formality with interest rates, and fiscal policy the real drivers of the money supply. It's a continuation of older Keynesian thought, but with a more sophisticated understanding of the monetary system. I think the main limitation on this train of thought is the mechanism through they wish to stabilize the economy. They advocate for a separation between aggregate demand stabilization and employment stabilization -- full employment AND price stability. One commonly proposed mechanism for this is the "job guarantee" wherein a government agency would provide employment to all unemployed people. The macroeconomic justification for this is reasonable, the politics and microeconomics of this is not. It would be an administrative train wreck. There would difficulties with creative socially useful employment in sufficient quantities (particularly when you are running this program in a near-full employment economy). There would be issues with hiring and firing while still maintaining the universal nature of the program. It sounds good in theory but would be hard to put into practice. Also post-Keynesians tend to rely very heavily on discretionary policy by policy makers in their response to fluctuations. This is problematic. Politicians tend to handle this very poorly. They either do what the US and the EU has done with the ongoing economic depression (they are not nearly aggressive enough in their policy making), or they way overspend (like in Venezuela) and engender inflation. The stabilization of the economy should be on autopilot. The second new-ish perspective in economic policy that I have sympathy towards is Market Monetarism. This is an extension of classic monetarism -- the idea that central banks should stabilize the level of growth of the money supply This has benefits over targeting inflation and/or price stability because there are clear ways that central banks can attempt to meet such a target, and a money supply target lacks some of the more arbitrary factors involved with other potential targets. But they bring a twist to this idea. They argue that central banks should target nominal GDP growth instead of the money supply. A prediction market can be used to determine the right level of money to inject into the economy to make this target. It's nice, clean, and mechanistic. A NGDP target as other benefits. It handles supply shocks (like oil price increases) pretty will compared to other targets. Inflation/price stability targeting would advise a massive bout of austerity in response to a supply shock, causing a depression and extreme unemployment. Employment targeting would advise the exact opposite, triggering a wage-price spiral and very high inflation. NGDP targeting would advise a balanced intermediate solution. Where market monetarists fall down is on their very strong reliance on monetary policy. They effectively think the NGDP could be stabilized by mass purchases of finical assets by central banks – quantitative easing on steroids. This is problematic. Monetary policy, particularly when interest rates are very low is quite weak. And the level of purchases by central banks would 1) be very large, 2) involve politically problematic categories of asset, like foreign currency, and the debt of private companies.</p>

<p>I think it is possible to merge these two perspectives. The market monetarists are quite good at defending the NGDP target as a good target for macroeconomic stabilization, but have yet to convince me that monetary policy has what it takes. The post-Keynesians are quite good at defending the proper role of fiscal policy, but their exact policy proposals are problematic. The two ideas can be merged in my opinion. Target NGDP with fiscal policy. Enact a basic income plan, but with the exact levels of payment set based on a meeting the NGDP target. A prediction market can be useful for setting this level. You could even take this further and merge fiscal and monetary policy. Set interest rates at a constant level, and fund government deficits through creating new monetary base.</p>

<p><strong>Image Credit</strong>: <a href="https://flic.kr/p/cFbZTh">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>cFbZTh</a> Flickr user Stefan Fussan</p>

<p><em>See <a href="https://objects.dreamhost.com:443/theopodcasts/MMT%20%26%20MM_01.flac">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>objects.dreamhost.com:443/<wbr></wbr>theopodcasts/<wbr></wbr>MMT%20%26%20MM_01.flac</a> to download losslessly compressed audio for this article.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/eu" class="p-category" rel="tag">#eu</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/modernmonetarytheory" class="p-category" rel="tag">#modernmonetarytheory</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ngdp" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ngdp</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/venezuela" class="p-category" rel="tag">#venezuela</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#eu</category>
      <category>#modernmonetarytheory</category>
      <category>#ngdp</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#venezuela</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
