<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23business</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?q=%23business&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>The problem with Uber</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-problem-with-uber</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-problem-with-uber</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 05:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/uberharm.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2427" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/uberharm.jpg" alt="uberharm" width="640" height="360"></a>Uber recently lost an administrative decision in California over whether their drivers are independent contractors or employees. <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/dandiamond/2015/06/17/if-uber-drivers-are-employees-company-faces-hard-decision-on-health-care/">This could have very important implications for the company</a>. It would mean that the company is bound by a wide variety of regulations that fall on companies that hire employees. Uber would be bound to pay employees the minimum wage (regardless of the number of rides given), health benefits, it would be bound by working hours regulations, and many other regulation. Probably worst of all for the company, Uber would have to cover the business expenses of employees, or at least take them into account in tabulating wages paid. This was not a positive ruling for Uber. But to this outcome, I say it’s about time. Uber's entire business model is to ignore every regulation on their industry to keep costs down. Now, some of these regulations are useless. But Uber throws out the good with the bad. It’s nice to hear that regulators are finally "disrupting" them. Now, I will say that the conventional taxi system is pretty terrible. Where I live there aren't too many outright ripoff cab drivers, but there are ones that are 20 minutes late and which are otherwise unreliable. When you get to larger cities that are more dependent on cabs, it gets even worse some of the problems with cabs across the country is due to shitty regulations (hello, New York City medallion system). I can see why people like Uber and use their products, as they provide a very strong improvement over other taxi networks. However, as I said before they toss out the good with the bad in regards to regulations. In this post I’ll discuss some things I believe solidly that Uber should change with their business model.</p>

<p>The first big issue with Uber is their limited insurance for their drivers. There are very strong reasons why anyone driving for a business should have commercial insurance. Regular car insurance does not cover business driving. However, many of Uber’s drivers are driving illegally without the proper commercial insurance, posing strong legal risk to them, to consumers, and to other motorists. Fortunately, Uber has made some improvements on this issue recently by proving their drivers a limited secondary insurance policy for their Uber driving. But it’s not enough, and the coverage this provides is quite limited and poorly fits the legal requirements on commercial driving. This lack of insurance also serves to externalize costs on to the public. If an Uber driver gets into a car wreck while driving, both the victim of the car accident, and the driver have a huge problem. The driver has a large potential liability, while the victim of the car wreck will be left out to dry. The risk created by driving safety by Uber is unloaded onto the public.</p>

<p>The second major issue with Uber is their pricing scheme. All prices on Uber are set by the company. This is bad, because the price that optimizes Uber profits might not be the socially optimal price. In fact, if you accept Uber’s line that they are just a “platform” for independent contractors then, <a href="http://www.interfluidity.com/v2/5822.html">as the economics blogger Steve Waldman points out</a>, in effect Uber is a price-fixing cartel. A more flexible form of pricing set by the drivers is possible. Also, Uber’s pricing system is highly unstable because their surge level fluctuates a lot. I (along with most consumers I would guess) would prefer a much more predictable pricing system. But congestion pricing isn’t totally useless. It is useful to charge riders more for traveling at rush hour, in order to keep cars available for those who need to travel at that time. An intermediate solution is possible. A revision for Uber’s pricing system would involve the following, allow each driver to set his price for different categories of time (ie. Morning rush hour, evening rush hour, rest of the day, night time) but encourage drivers to refrain from changing their rates too much. This would also mean that all prices are human set, avoiding issues like what happened in Sidney, Australia where <a href="http://gawker.com/uber-turned-on-surge-pricing-for-people-fleeing-sydney-1671193132">Uber surged priced people fleeing a hostage situation</a>.</p>

<p>The third major issue with Uber is their tendency to off load a lot of their costs onto the drivers in a way that is nowhere near transparent. <a href="https://get.uber.com/cl/">Uber’s page recruiting new drivers</a> states, “<em>Got a car? Turn it into a money machine. The city is buzzing and Uber makes it easy for you to cash in on the action. Plus, you've already got everything you need to get started.</em>” An ad bought by Uber on the Bing search engine states that drivers “<em>Make Up To $17/hr In Fares</em>”. Of course, this claimed pay is highly misleading. It doesn’t take into account the cost of car maintenance (which not only increase with respect with miles driven, but also should be put to the higher standards of commercial driving). It also doesn’t take into account the cost of fuel, insurance, or other necessities of driving. Probably, the adjusted pay is more like 8-10 dollars per hour. The IRS estimates (for the purposes of tax deductions) that the <a href="http://www.irs.gov/Tax-Professionals/Standard-Mileage-Rates/">non-labor cost of business miles</a> is 57 cents per mile.</p>

<p>Image credit <a href="https://flic.kr/p/qvKug6">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>qvKug6</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/business" class="p-category" rel="tag">#business</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uber" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uber</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#business</category>
      <category>#uber</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Phrase &#x201C;Social Justice&#x201D;</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-phrase-social-justice</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-phrase-social-justice</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/socialjustice.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/socialjustice.jpg" alt="socialjustice" width="1000" height="800" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2439"></a>The above image is a collage of three of the top results on Flickr for a search of the phrase "Social Justice". The <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sully_aka__wstera2/4478077831/">top-left image is from user wstera2 </a>and is titled "When liberals are losing a debate". The top right image is from user Takver and is titled "C<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/takver/5415825802/">hange, Freedom, Social Justice - Egypt Uprising protest</a>". The bottom image is titled "<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rikkis_refuge/16400696138/">World Day for Social Justice</a>" and is via user Rikki's Refuge.</p>

<p>By its self, the phrase "social justice" is pretty meaningless. The phrase is effectively equivalent to the word "fairness". Try taking an article that uses the phrase and swapping out all occurrences of "social justice" for fairness. Very little meaning will be lost.    But "fairness" is an arbitrary concept. Almost every political ideology will perceive their goals as "fair".  Phrases like "social justice" are the political equivalent of "maximizing synergies" business speak. Such concepts are almost entirely dependent on ideology. What one will perceive as "fair" or "just is largely subjective in global terms. Every major political ideology has a different conception of the public good. Libertarians regard markets as properly "fair", others regard egalitarianism as "fair", and others take a roughly utilitarian perspective of the greatest good for the greatest number as "fair". However, the concept is still subjective.  In regards to talk of "fairness" in economic policy, <a href="http://blog.dilbert.com/post/102964895406/fairness-test">Scott Adams (the author of the Dilbert cartoon) made a similar point</a>. "<em>fairness is a concept invented so dumb people can participate in debates. Fairness isn't a natural law of the universe. It's a psychological problem. We sometimes get fairness confused with equality. Equality is usually good, and can often be measured with a satisfying precision. Fairness, on the other hand, is usually just a rationale for some sort of bias ….It's just a psychological phenomenon that is easily manipulated.</em>"</p>

<p>However, there is one case where the phrase "social justice" carries more meaning than the word "fairness". The only meaning that is conveyed by that term is signaling about the speaker. Only certain ideologies refer to their goals as maximizing social justice. This gets us to pejoratives like "SJW".  So when a gater rants about "SJWs" they are attacking the ideologies refer to their goals as maximizing social justice. However, SJW is a strong pejorative. Using it is like saying "M$" in a discussion about Windows 10. It removes any indication that you are processing facts in a rational way and indicates that confirmation bias is at work. It's an inherently mocking tone, one that should only be used with clearly unreasonable positions. And treating reasonable positions as unreasonable destroys one's credibility.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/business" class="p-category" rel="tag">#business</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scottadams" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scottadams</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sjw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sjw</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#business</category>
      <category>#scottadams</category>
      <category>#sjw</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Limitations of Worker Owned Companies</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-limitations-of-worker-owned-companies</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-limitations-of-worker-owned-companies</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 04:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The idea of companies that are ran by their employees has been getting some attention in the liberal blogosphere. Often this discussion comes with extreme hype about their promise. Take <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/EnoughLibertarianSpam/comments/37cbxv/hey_you_earnest_socialists_has_this_ancap_got_a/">a recent thread on Reddit</a> where the topic came up. There are plenty of people who think that a shift to such a form of organization over the current corporate form will result in a vast improvement in regards to all sorts of political and economic issues. The claimed benefits are wide ranging. Some on that Reddit thread say that eliminate the types of conflicts of interest between business and the public that make regulation necessary, others say there'll be vast environmental benefits, while others happen to believe that a switch to worker owned cooperatives will be the end of unfair treatment by employers and will be a general boon to workplace safety. However, despite the enthusiasm for this idea, it is way oversold. The issue with much of current business occurs when there is no external constraint on the working of business that forces the actions of businesses to follow the interests of the population as a whole. Will cooperatives change this? Probably not. The switch to cooperatives would change the beneficiaries of a company's actions, and the people get to choose the actions of the company, from the shareholders to the employees. However, nothing in economics provides any guarantee that the interests of the average employee of a company will be any more in line with the public purpose then the interests of the average shareholder. Although switch to employee cooperatives would change some issues, namely those that result from insufficient negotiating power on the side of employees, it would introduce new issues and leave many currently existing issues unresolved. The first big category of issues that worker cooperatives have little improvement on over traditional firms is externalities-a coal power plant ran as a cooperative will still have the same economic interests in polluting as a conventionally owned coal plant. The second major issue that cooperatives will be unable to resolve is a situation of economic rents-situations where due to monopoly or scarce resources a firm is able to get revenue that is far in excess of the actual cost of bringing a good into production. A worker owned firm will still want to collect the benefits of these economic rents, and disperse the profit to its members. There is also one major category where such cooperatives would be expected to perform worse than traditional firms, situations where increasing the average per employee revenue of a company is in conflict with increasing its overall productivity. A cooperative will not want to expand into potentially beneficial operations that produce less per worker the current business because there is a risk that such a thing will tend to force the share of the profits given to the incumbent members downward. A better alternative to worker owned cooperatives might be much more egalitarian ownership of conventional firms.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/business" class="p-category" rel="tag">#business</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/coops" class="p-category" rel="tag">#coops</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/externalities" class="p-category" rel="tag">#externalities</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#business</category>
      <category>#coops</category>
      <category>#externalities</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
