<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=80</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/all/?offset=80&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Should a Researcher be Removed From a Technical Conference Due to Unrelated Political Views? No.</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/should-a-researcher-be-removed-from-a-technical-conference-due</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/should-a-researcher-be-removed-from-a-technical-conference-due</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 01:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/5082518408_00ed489f1e_o.jpg"><img class="wp-image-2548 " src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/5082518408_00ed489f1e_o-1024x762.jpg" alt="Attendees at the Strange Loop Conference &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8K8eDJ</a>" width="485" height="361" /&gt;</p>
<p class="wp-caption-dd"></p>
<p>Curtis Yarvin is a software engineer who researches distributed computing methods. <a href="http://unqualified-reservations.blogspot.com/">He also authors </a><a href="http://moldbuggery.blogspot.com/">political writing under the pen name Mencius Moldbug</a>. Yarvin's political views are very problematic by any account. He describes his views as "reactionary" and believes that democracy is a mistake and that the optimal form of government is absolute monarchy. There is also a strong dose of sexism and racism in his political writings. One could get the feeling that a person with Yarvin's views would be sympathetic to the claim that Saudi Arabia is the greatest country in the world (although, to be clear here, Yarvin has never said so). In his professional career, he is currently working on <a href="http://popehat.com/2013/12/06/nock-hoon-etc-for-non-vulcans-why-urbit-matters/">Urbit</a>, a distributed computing system. Yarvin was scheduled to speak at the <a href="https://thestrangeloop.com/about.html">Strange Loop </a> information technology conference on the subject of Urbit. The talk was not political in nature. Even if Yarvin's political writing is wrongheaded, Urbit seems to be worthy scientific and technical work. However, the conference organizers withdrew his speaking spot after becoming aware of his political writings. This in my opinion is quite wrong headed. By all means, if Yarvin tried to turn the conference into a Klan rally, the organizers ought to act. But as far as I can tell that's not what was happening. The questions of whether monarchies are a good idea, or if Urbit is a reasonable approach to distributed computing are unrelated. To reject a bit of scientific work because of its author is an ad hominem attack in simple form. One can easily have <a href="http://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Nobel_disease">idiotic ideas in one field and brilliant ideas in another</a>. Society does not benefit in any meaningful way when a good idea is lost because of politics. And an even worse possibility is that this type of thing will spread to mainline political views. A world where academics are forced to refrain from political activism for the sake of career advancement would not be a good one. It would be the spread And as legal blogger <a href="http://popehat.com/2015/06/10/two-kinds-of-freedom-of-speech-or-strangeloop-vs-curtis-yarvin/#comments">Clark Bianco points out this </a>type of thing reflects a general turning away from freedom of speech in the political discourse, "<em>freedom of speech is not merely a legal issue centering on the first amendment, but also a cultural issue, centering on our willingness to tolerate the presence and the words of those we disagree with</em>".</p>

<p>Image Credit:Attendees at the Strange Loop Conference <a href="https://flic.kr/p/8K8eDJ">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8K8eDJ</a> Via Flickr user Chris Yunker CC-SA</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#comments</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The only confederate flag that mattered</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-only-confederate-flag-that-mattered</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-only-confederate-flag-that-mattered</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 21:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The only confederate flag that mattered.<br /><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/11214072_407037059503674_2531820035432787173_n.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/11214072_407037059503674_2531820035432787173_n.jpg" alt="11214072_407037059503674_2531820035432787173_n" width="360" height="470" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2540"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Recent Gay Marriage Decision</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-recent-gay-marriage-decision</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-recent-gay-marriage-decision</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 20:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>As you likely already know, the US Supreme Court struck down prohibitions on gay marriage. The opinion (and its dissents) can be found here <a href="http://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/14pdf/14-556_3204.pdf">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.supremecourt.gov/<wbr></wbr>opinions/<wbr></wbr>14pdf/<wbr></wbr>14-556_3204.pdf</a> The ruling is a very good one and it will be good to see gay marriage become law across the nation. I have previously written about why I think gay marriage should be legal here <a href="https://www.theojones.name/if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage-5/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>if-you-love-freedom-vote-to-allow-gay-marriage-5/<wbr></wbr></a> and here <a href="https://www.theojones.name/the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.theojones.name/<wbr></wbr>the-legal-basis-behind-the-gay-marriage-lawsuits/<wbr></wbr></a></p>

<p>Before I get in to the core of the opinion and the legal issues, I will give an overview of some of the reasons why I think it is good that gay marriage is now legal, as a policy issue. Anti-gay marriage advocates are often (if not usually) motivated by either severely misguided and false stereotypes and/or a desire to force everyone to conform to their conservative religious code of morality. There’s no justification for current bans on gay marriage and I can't think of a reasonable argument in their favor. The impact of this ruling on gay couples will certainly be strong.</p>

<p><a name="__DdeLink__0_472281813"></a> Marriage licenses provide many important legal benefits. A 2004 study by the United States General Accounting Office found that 1,138 federal laws use marital status as a factor in determining or receiving benefits, rights, and privileges. According to the Ontario Consultants on Religious Tolerance (OCRT), <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/aboutus.htm">a nonsectarian group that</a> "<em>that promotes the freedom of individuals to follow the religious path of their choosing, without discrimination or oppression</em>", <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/hom_marr.htm">these include benefits</a> to individuals that affect their "<em>Social Security, Medicare, medical leave, and other benefits; property inheritance; the right to visit their spouse in hospital, and make medical decisions if they are incapacitated; security of the couple and of their children</em>". This means gay couples lack the financial security of married couples and the right to have their partner involved in critical decisions if they become incapacitated.</p>

<p>Conservatives advocating bans on gay marriage cannot show they will be harmed in any way by gay marriages. Many conservatives argue that permitting gay marriage will be corrosive to families and society. However, there is a great body of evidence that contradicts this assertion. A <a href="http://www.aaanet.org/issues/policy-advocacy/Statement-on-Marriage-and-the-Family.cfm">statement issued by the American Anthropological Association</a> states that "<em>The results of more than a century of anthropological research on households, kinship relationships, and families, across cultures and through time, provide no support whatsoever for the view that either civilization or viable social orders depend upon marriage as an exclusively heterosexual institution …..a vast array of family types, including families built upon same-sex partnerships, can contribute to stable and humane societies</em>". I ask those conservatives who reject the vision of liberty for all including gay couples and those turning to religious dogma to consider is the Bible really a good guide for governance? Slavery, stoning, executing whole families for the crimes of one member, mass murder and genocide are <a href="http://www.religioustolerance.org/imm_bibl.htm">all found in the Bible</a>. Are religious ideologues asking the government to enforce a biblical version of Sharia law?</p>

<p>I am less impressed with the majority opinion (authored by Justice Kennedy) than with the ruling its self. It is strong on flowery language but quite weak on actual substance. It has the feel of being written much more towards a popular audience than the legally knowledgeable. Justice Kennedy will tell you about the "transcendent importance of marriage" but he provides little guidance towards courts in regard to future gay rights issues. He relies on arguments that are very narrowly focused on the issue of marriage -- instead of a more broad based recognition of gay rights. These might not be flaws that are that problematic (incrementalism, and comprehensibility to outsiders are not bad things) were it not for the it embraces arguments that are quite frankly weak, in order to obtain this.</p>

<p>As guidance to future courts, this opinion really falls down. It fails to set a scrutiny standard for evaluating future laws that affect gays. The courts tend to interpret the equal protection clause based on varying standards of scrutiny. The higher standards are only applied to certain protected classes. For a law that targets a group of people to pass the scrutiny of the courts, the law must meet standards that vary based on the scrutiny test applied.</p>
<ol><li>Strict Scrutiny. This standard is applied to laws that impact a fundamental right (i.e one in the Bill of Rights). More relevant to this case is the fact that this standard is used in regards to some protected classes, particularly race. To pass this standard the government must have a compelling governmental interest, the legislation must be narrowly tailored to fulfill the interest, and must be the least restrictive means of meeting the interest. This is the most stringent of the standards.</li>
    <li>Intermediate Scrutiny. This is the standard that applies on the basis of sex/gender discrimination, among other protected classes.To pass this standard a law must further an important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest</li>
    <li>The third standard is the rational basis test. It has two poorly defined sub-types. The cases where eachis used have not beenwell defined.
<ol><li>Regular rational basis -- this is the generic standard that applies to all laws. It is nearly all permissive. A law has to be rationally related to a legitimate government interest. This legitimate government interest does not need to be the actual reason for the law nor do the costs of the legislation have to be proportionate to the interest.</li>
    <li>Rational basis with teeth. This is a poorly defined heightened version of the rational basis test This adds to the regular rational basis standard by declaring that the interest must be strong enough that a reasonable and impartial legislature could come to the conclusion that the legislation is justified. The gay marriage related cases that have involved rational basis have used this standard.</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<p>Where does the court put this boundary? It didn't set it. It evaded the question. It hangs the case on the due process clause by treating marriage as a free-standing right. The first thing to note about this is that this results in a ruling that has little applicability to other areas of law. And frankly, I consider it to be a fairly weak argument in favor of gay marriage. Its clear to me that discrimination in regards to marriage licenses is a decidedly bad thing. But that is because discrimination is in regard to important areas of law is inherently bad and needs to be strongly justified (if it occurs at all), not because of an inherent value in marriage licenses. If one of the libertarian proposals to abolish marriage licenses all together were adopted would it be unconstitutional? (disregarding the degenerate case <a href="http://newsok.com/article/5400240">where in such a proposal were adopted with the direct intent to evade this ruling</a>) I would suggest not (although such a proposal would likely be wrong-headed on other grounds). If Justice Kennedy desired a narrow ruling for some reason, he would of been better to make an equal protection argument on the basis of the already established law regarding sex/gender discrimination.</p>

<p>If the majority opinion is weak, the dissenting opinions are worthless. Justice Scalia is not happy with the ruling "<em>The opinion is couched in a style that is as pretentious as its content is egotistic .... If, even as the price to be paid for a fifth vote, I ever joined an opinion for the Court that began: 'The Constitution promises liberty to all within its reach, a liberty that includes certain specific rights that allow persons, within a lawful realm, to define and express their identity,' I would hide my head in a bag. The Supreme Court of the United States has descended from the disciplined legal reasoning of John Marshall and Joseph Story to the mystical aphorisms of the fortune cookie</em> "</p>

<p>Aside from the bile, Scalia puts a huge emphasis on democracy. But this tends to be weak when laws that have a huge impact but little justification are in question. The court system in a strong way provides a roadblock to shortsightedness by the public. While the law does not prohibit a legislature from enacting a stupid law, it to some extent limits the damage. This is not to say I am prone to sloganeering about how rights shouldn't be brought to a vote. At some point such a thing is inevitable as the range of rights and their limits are in dispute. And some rights require more detailed policy making to enforce than could be provided through a court order. Democracy is the worst system of government except for all the others. But that does not mean that the only legitimate way to contest a law is through the ballot box. And that does not mean that it is consistently a bad idea to refer certain type of decision making to specialized bodies like courts. And the strong history of abuses of rights of gay people, and shortsightedness by policy makers in regards to equal protections, probably means that the courts have a role on this issue.</p>

<p>Justice Roberts is a bit more sensible. He emphasises the argument that a lot of the cases supporting a right to marriage cited by the majority come from the realm of procreation and child bearing. He does not dispute that gay marriage is good policy but he argues that it is not mandated by the constitution. At some point, this history is a good showcase of the weakness of the main argument fronted by the majority. But I do not think that such an argument is sufficient to over come all but the most weakest equal protection analysis. If discrimination against gays was subject to intermediate scrutiny, or a stronger standard, it is hard to think that such a historical analysis would further an important government interest in a way that is substantially related to that interest (and just the discrimination based on sex factor in gay marriage prohibitions suggests intermediate scrutiny).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Criticism Versus Aggression</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/criticism-versus-aggression</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/criticism-versus-aggression</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 04:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><font style="line-height:150%" size="1"><strong><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_1.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-2506" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_1.jpg" alt="7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_1" width="289" height="390"></a>!!!!!!Trigger Warning!!!!!!</strong><br />This post may contain discussion of at least one of the following<br /><br />Swearing, Rape, Abuse (physical, mental, emotional, verbal, sexual),Child abuse/pedophilia ,Self-injurious behavior (self-harm, eating disorders, etc.) ,Talk of drug use (legal, illegal or psychiatric)<br />,Suicide ,Descriptions/pictures of medical procedures (even if they don’t contain blood or gore),Descriptions/pictures of violence or warfare (including instruments of violence, such as knives or guns)<br />,Corpses, skulls or skeletons ,Needles ,Discussions of -isms, shaming, or hatred of any kind (racism, classism, hatred of cultures/ethnicities that differ from your own, sexism, hatred of sexualities or genders that differ from your own, anti-multiple, non-vanilla shaming, sex positive shaming, fat shaming/body image shaming, neuroatypical shaming) ,Any time slurs are used (this includes words like “stupid” or “dumb”, which are still widely considered to be socially acceptable) ,Trans* degendering, or anti-trans* views of bodies ,Dismissal of lived oppressions, marginalization, illness or differences ,Kidnapping (forceful deprivation of/disregard for personal autonomy) ,Discussions of sex (even consensual)<br />,Death or dying ,Spiders ,Insects ,Snakes ,Vomit ,Pregnancy/childbirth ,Blood ,Serious injury<br />,Trypophobia ,Scarification ,Nazi paraphernalia ,Slimy things ,Anything that might inspire intrusive thoughts in people with OCD<br /><br />!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!</font>The above comes from an actual list of possibly "triggering" types of material via <a href="http://privilege101.tumblr.com/triggers.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>privilege101.tumblr.com/<wbr></wbr>triggers.html</a></p>

<p>There has been a substantial tendency on the in recent political movements (particularly from the left) to redefine criticism as coercion  and coercion as criticism.</p>

<p>The redefining of criticism as coercion comes from the recent tendency to paint disagreeable speech as the direct equivalent of a personal confrontation, or a personal intrusion.  This ideological viewpoint holds that literature that takes place in a world of inequality and oppression contributes to furthering it. This is the main fuel behind the "trigger warning" movement and the "safe place" movement.</p>

<p>The concept of "trigger warnings" paints speech as a direct threat to psychological well being. Under the trigger warning point of view attempts to hide disagreeable or discomforting material found in college courses behind a warning, often with the additional demand that students be allowed to opt out of possibly "triggering" material. The related "safe place" movement attempts to treat the possibility of exposure to new ideas, or worse yet ideas that directly contradict one's preconceptions, as a direct threat to personal safety.</p>

<p>The alternative to such a threat, of course, is to create "safe places" where no one will face any challenge to their beliefs. <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/02/17/opinion/the-new-college-campus.html?_r=0">An article in the New York Times discusses the furor </a>that arose when a debate at Brown University between a feminist and a libertarian occurred. Feminist activists were horrified at such a possibility. In the words of one senior at the school "Bringing in a speaker like that could serve to invalidate people’s experiences.” Activists rushed to create a safe place where those "damaged" by the possibility of hearing viewpoints other than their own could repair. This safe place "was equipped with cookies, coloring books, bubbles, Play-Doh, calming music, pillows, blankets and a video of frolicking puppies, as well as students and staff members trained to deal with trauma."</p>

<p><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/the-trigger-happy-generation-1432245600">The range of "triggering" material includes </a>quite a few classics,<a href="http://columbiaspectator.com/opinion/2015/04/30/our-identities-matter-core-classrooms"> one editorial written by students at Colombia singled out Ovid’s epic poem “Metamorphoses</a>" as particularly harmful "like so many texts in the Western canon it contains triggering and offensive material that marginalizes student identities in the classroom."  The authors furthermore went on to note that such works contain “histories and narratives of exclusion and oppression... difficult to read and discuss as a [rape] survivor, a person of color, or a student from a low-income background” and worse of all a student faced with such triggering material "completely disengaged from the class discussion as a means of self-preservation. She did not feel safe in the class.”</p>

<p>As a university student who probably qualifies as a low-income peasant in the eyes of the typical student at Ivy League universities like Colombia , I can solidly state that avoiding Roman literature is not a matter of self-preservation. Nor is it a matter of feeling safe. In fact, this type of rhetoric is exactly the issue with the "trigger warning" movement . They have confused being comfortable with feeling safe. And at some point exposure to new concepts will make one feel uncomfortable. But its a dubious type of safety that is gained by putting your head in the sand in order to avoid new ideas. Speech is not coercion, nor is it a threat to safety.</p>

<p>(I have a feeling that for many Ivy League students, the line defining low income versus regular income looks something like this <a href="http://knowyourmeme.com/photos/455847-rich-kids-of-instagram">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>knowyourmeme.com/<wbr></wbr>photos/<wbr></wbr>455847-rich-kids-of-instagram</a>)</p>

<p>In fact, exposure to new ideas is at the core of democratic discourse. The only mode of decision making compatible with democracy on a large scale is rational deliberation. And rational deliberation takes exposure to different proposals and ideas. Some of them may be controversial. Some of them may even be "triggering". And this exposure requires a strong degree of freedom of speech and discussion over policy. The Ancient Athenians considered isogoria -- freedom of speech and the right to contribute to political discourse, to be one of two defining features of democracy (the other being political equality or isonomia)</p>

<p>When pressed, advocates will attempt to defend the world of  in terms of the well being of sufferers of  mental illnesses like PTSD. But this claim becomes absurd when you evaluate the actions of the advocates of such policies and the reality of mental health care. With a physical illness you CAN assume that fulfilling any reasonable request made by the patient would help him. You just can't assume that with a mental illness. In fact its well known in the relevant scientific literature that avoidance is commonly requested by PTSD patients, but actively HARMFUL. It makes the illness worse. Avoidance is so common in PTSD that its considered one of the classic symptoms of the illness (see for instance, <a href="http://psycnet.apa.org/journals/ccp/66/3/586/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>psycnet.apa.org/<wbr></wbr>journals/<wbr></wbr>ccp/<wbr></wbr>66/<wbr></wbr>3/<wbr></wbr>586/<wbr></wbr></a>). In fact, the opposite of avoidance is helpful. A common therapy for PTSD involves gradual intentional exposure to triggers. By facilitating avoidance behavior you are being the opposite of compassionate (remember the rule of medicine: "first do no harm"). I seriously couldn't find a single peer-reviewed paper from a relevant field (psychology,medicine, neuroscience, biology, etc) that advocated the types of trigger warnings you see on college campuses and on internet blogs. About the only papers advocating it I could find were from humanities and women's studies and such and were by authors that had no relevant expertise. Here are few other relevant papers on the topic<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0005796700000887">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>S0005796700000887</a><br />"A prospective investigation of the role of cognitive factors in persistent Posttraumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) after physical or sexual assault"<br />This paper's abstract notes "avoidance/safety seeking" as a maladaptive control strategy .<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0005796700000930">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>S0005796700000930</a><br />"Cognitive-behavior therapy vs exposure therapy in the treatment of PTSD in refugees"<br />This study finds that exposure therapy is similar in effectiveness to regular talk therapy.<br /><a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0005796796000198">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.sciencedirect.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>pii/<wbr></wbr>0005796796000198</a><br />"Early avoidance of traumatic stimuli predicts chronicity of intrusive thoughts following burn injury"<br />Pretty much what this paper says is that avoidance tendencies strongly correlate with more severe PTSD symptoms, and the impact of avoidance can last for months.</p>

<p>This brings us to the second prong of this post. Just as many on the hard left have been effective in defining speech as harmful aggression (or "micro-aggression") they have also been effective in defining actual coercion as speech. In many subsets of the feminist/social justice community doxxing and similar behaviors have become common. Attempts to get people expressing disfavored opinions fired, or removed from unrelated positions have become quite common (with the Brendan Eich incident being a prominent example of this). Activists have attempted to get platforms with strong market concentration (like Twitter and Facebook) to shut down speech they don't like.</p>

<p>Even worse, they have tried to brand harassing/ trying to shut down speech they don't like as a legitimate for of criticism. "Freedom of speech is not freedom from consequences " is a common refrain among this type. These people view the government as the only authority that can censor in any meaningful way. Freedom of speech in this point of view is merely a constraint on government power -- like separation of powers -- and not an individual right in its own end.  And its an absurd claim, one that would be rejected in almost any other area of policy by the same people. Ability to censor comes from power. And many private actors have plenty of power.  Consequences imposed can certainly affect one's freedom of speech. The worst part of this is they have been able to massively change public opinion  on the nature of freedom of speech.</p>

<p>However, the two tendencies; branding speech as coercion and coercion as speech are strongly connected. Once you view hearing speech you don't like as a form of personal assault, it follows that speech is a source of power. And like all forms of coercion it is one that can be used badly. In this point of view speech much be directed so that it serves the public interest. Its an illiberal, authoritarian, anti-democratic, and very dangerous point of view. Its ultimately a pre-modern point of view that rejects rationality, and harkens back to the ancient tendency to treat insults as threats to honor that deserve a violent response. But it has gained a lot of traction and needs to be resisted.</p>

<p>Image via: <a href="http://blog.simplejustice.us/2014/12/17/the-environmental-cleanup-of-toxic-academia/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>blog.simplejustice.us/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>17/<wbr></wbr>the-environmental-cleanup-of-toxic-academia/<wbr></wbr></a></p>

<p>Facebook thread (and attached email image) created by a student who wanted out of her finals because she was "traumatized" and triggered by the events in Ferguson. That thread explains a lot of the problem here. That student seems to live in a social media bubble of people who not only truly believe that that student's request was reasonable, but also think that the professor was unreasonable by rejecting it. And even worse, the people who should be the reasonable adults in the room are doing noting about it. The article notes cases where professors have dropped material due to this nonsense, and the "traumatized" student's mother is apparently "proud" of her.</p>

<p>More of it is as follows (click to enlarge)</p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Facebook.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-2510 alignleft" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Facebook-300x179.jpg" alt="Facebook" width="300" height="179"></a></p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p> </p>

<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_2.jpg"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-2511 alignleft" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_2-208x300.jpg" alt="7-Timeline-Photos-Della-Kurzer-Zlotnick_Page_2" width="208" height="300"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water scarcity and water shortage</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/water-scarcity-and-water-shortage</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/water-scarcity-and-water-shortage</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 22:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The ongoing drought in California has made it clear that water is now a scarce good  --- in many areas of the world there is not an effectively unlimited supply of it. Potential users of water just can't take as much of as they want without impacting other potential users negatively. However, scarcity of water does not mean shortage, scarcity is when there are practical limits to how much one can take, shortage is when even those who have a socially useful efficient use for the good cannot obtain it. What is happening in California is a shortage.  And this is unnecessary . In this post I will discuss a bit more about what I mean by this difference. In a future post, I will discuss what can be done to avoid having scarcity of water turn into shortage of water.</p>

<p>Scarcity is a fact of many economic goods. It is a simple truth that unconstrained demand will exceed possible production of goods and services. Wants and desires are effectively unlimited compared to what can actually be produced. Water will no longer be an exemption from this rule. When the system of water rights in the US was constructed, water was effectively non-scarce. Sure, there may have been a nominal amount of scarcity, but the even a fairly minimal set of limits on water draw could manage these. However, the actual sustainable output of waterways and ground water is limited. A river only has so much water flowing through it, and a ground water source only contains so much water. California is hitting up against those limit. Other states will be bound to hit extreme water scarcity in the near future.  And as the drought shows, climate change will make this worse.  Even if it were not for climate change, we would still encounter water scarcity eventually. The US (like most developed nations) uses a lot more water than the typical human. And these is simply not enough water on the planet to extend such a level of water use to the whole planet.  The system of water rights set up in the western United States was primarily designed to maximize the potential for migration to the west. Water rights in the east manage water as a commons -- a system inherited from British law. Neither setup is designed to handle true water scarcity and both systems were designed under much lower global population densities, and much lower levels of water consumption than exist today.</p>

<p>Despite this, there is no reason scarcity has to amount to shortage. Food is a scarce good, but it is rarely in shortage in western countries. One cannot take as much beef as one wants at only a minimal price because the possible desires for beef (and/or the resources required to produce it) are not available in an effectively unlimited amount.  However, there is not a shortage of it. Store shelves are not empty. This is because there is a price on beef. If beef were available at unlimited quantities at a very small price (such as is done with water) there would be a shortage of beef. Adding a price to a scarce good serves two purposes, 1) it limits how much of the good one can take, 2) it requires buyers to weigh  the relative utilities of different goods (is the benefit of consuming beef really better enough than the benefit of consuming chicken?), and 3) it discourages waste and inefficiency in the use of a good. The price charged for a good is fundamentally a reflection of its scarcity. Supply and demand are simply reflections of scarcity. Due to factor 1 a more plentiful good will be cheaper, while one with more demand will tend to be more expensive due to factor 2.</p>

<p>Now, it is worth noting that there is an intermediate case between shortage and non-shortage. Economic scarcity. particularly in developing nations with high poverty and high inequality, a price can poorly reflect the underlying utility provided by a good due to the ability to pay of most poor people. But this is fundamentally a reflection of poverty. And due to the very low costs of water infrastructure, this is a very limited problem in developed nations. The cost of water and water infrastructure is small compared to prevailing incomes in the United States.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sortition as a way to remove bias in selecting for exclusive positions</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/sortition-as-a-way-to-remove-bias-in-selecting-for</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/sortition-as-a-way-to-remove-bias-in-selecting-for</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 05:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/sorition.png"><img class="  wp-image-2494 alignright" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/sorition.png" alt="sorition" width="392" height="294"></a>Sortition -- the selection of people for positions of practical value by random lot --- can be used as a strong way to eliminate bias in the choice of people for positions of significance. In my opinion the source of a lot of implicit bias in the selection of people for employment, university admissions, and other highly selective positions comes from one clear source. The simple fact that there are almost no objective criteria to select from the very best. Subjective criteria are all there is when you get to the highest levels of candidates. And when subjective feelings are at work, a lot of times those feelings can come from ill places. Multiple studies have shown that a large part of society has a degree of implicit bias in regards to such criteria as race and gender.</p>

<p>The most selective universities in the country (for, instance, Ivy League schools) admit a very small portion of their applicants, often less than 5%. Many scarce job positions are similarly exclusive. It is extremely doubtful that the top 5% of applicants to a school are substantially different in any meaningful way than the top 10%. At that level of achievement merit is a totally subjective concept. And the current system of selecting people for such positions allow those in power to put a lot of their subjective biases into selecting people. It is doubtful that the result of applying those biases will be fair in any meaningful way.</p>

<p>That is where my preference for random choice comes in. Probability is fair, it is objective, and it perceives no bias It gives everyone an equal weight. And so, when there is no clear objective reason to differentiate between people, it is the only fair option. Chance is better than subjective views and bias. Adding an element of random selection to choosing people for exclusive positions could eliminate a lot of bias. My suggestion for doing so would change the role of human panels that handle things like college admissions and selection for employment positions, away from selecting the <strong>best</strong> applicant towards eliminating demonstrably unqualified ones. The process for eliminating unqualified applicants would rely as much as possible on objective criteria, and would definitely not be in the hands of a lone person (but would instead be referred to a committee). Once unqualified applicants are removed from the pool, a random set of them can be selected by chance.</p>

<p>Title image create with <a href="https://www.canva.com/">canva</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An article that shows why companies don't have...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-article-that-shows-why-companies-dont-have</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/an-article-that-shows-why-companies-dont-have</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 07:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>An article that shows why companies don't have to file tons of crap lawsuits to keep their trademarks.<br /><a href="http://blog.grabeh.net/The-myth-of-mandatory-trade-mark-enforcement">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>blog.grabeh.net/<wbr></wbr>The-myth-of-mandatory-trade-mark-enforcement</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Trade mark disputes pop up all the time. Often it's a David v Goliath affair with a large incumbent with an equally large legal budget seeking to squish to plucky start-up.</p>

<p>In some cases, the Goliath can attempt to use its registered trade marks to oppress an upstart providing goods or services in an area completely unrelated to it. </p>

<p>Some may see this kind of action as completely unreasonable on the basis that there couldn't conceivably be any confusion or intention to take advantage of the reputation of the incumbent.</p>

<p>Others might comment that a trade mark owner is required to enforce their trade marks otherwise risk losing the ability to enforce them in the future or as is sometimes mooted lose the trade mark altogether.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/law" class="p-category" rel="tag">#law</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#law</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As a reliable source of steady electricity nuclear...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/as-a-reliable-source-of-steady-electricity-nuclear</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/as-a-reliable-source-of-steady-electricity-nuclear</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 07:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <blockquote>
<p>As a reliable source of steady electricity, nuclear energy serves an important role in U.S. grid stability. Even as regional grids become more sophisticated in managing fluctuating input from renewable sources, there remains a base-load requirement to maintain an on-demand minimum generation level. Nuclear energy provides this grid certainty by generating its maximum amount of electricity more often than any other electricity source — on average, more than 90 percent of the time. Life extension technologies, like AREVA's new cavitation peening for reactor heads, help utilities ensure continued safe generation for another 40 years.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><cite><a href="http://thehill.com/blogs/pundits-blog/energy-environment/240605-whats-the-value-of-nuclear-energy-to-the-united-states">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>thehill.com/<wbr></wbr>blogs/<wbr></wbr>pundits-blog/<wbr></wbr>energy-environment/<wbr></wbr>240605-whats-the-value-of-nuclear-energy-to-the-united-states</a></cite></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/energy" class="p-category" rel="tag">#energy</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/nuclear" class="p-category" rel="tag">#nuclear</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/quote" class="p-category" rel="tag">#quote</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#energy</category>
      <category>#nuclear</category>
      <category>#quote</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The government can't seize hotel records without due...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-government-cant-seize-hotel-records-without-due</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-government-cant-seize-hotel-records-without-due</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 07:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The government can't seize hotel records without due process. <br /><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/jurisprudence/2015/06/city_of_los_angeles_v_patel_the_supreme_court_rules_that_police_can_t_simply.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.slate.com/<wbr></wbr>articles/<wbr></wbr>news_and_politics/<wbr></wbr>jurisprudence/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>city_of_los_angeles_v_patel_the_supreme_court_rules_that_police_can_t_simply.html</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>In a decision heralded as a big win for privacy rights, the U.S. Supreme Court decided, on 5–4 lines Monday morning, that the Fourth Amendment prevents the city of Los Angeles from enforcing a 116-year-old ordinance that compels hotel operators to turn over certain records to the police. In an opinion authored by Justice Sonia Sotomayor and joined by Justices Ruth Bader Ginsburg, Stephen Breyer, Elena Kagan and Anthony Kennedy, the majority struck down the ordinance punishing hotel operators that refuse to turn over such records “without affording them any opportunity for pre-compliance review.” Justice Antonin Scalia penned a feisty rebuttal in response, accusing the majority of making it vastly more difficult for cops to break up drug rings, human trafficking, and prostitution operations.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/law" class="p-category" rel="tag">#law</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#law</category>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The employment trilemma</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-employment-trilemma</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-employment-trilemma</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Employment-Trilemma.png"><img class="  wp-image-2484 alignright" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/Employment-Trilemma.png" alt="Employment Trilemma" width="400" height="300"></a>In this post I will contend that macroeconomic policy faces a trilemma in regards to employment and that this trilemma makes alleviating poverty through full employment highly problematic (leaving transfer payments the only viable means of alleviating poverty on a large scale).  This is a large reason why I am a supporter of a basic income as the only viable way to eliminate poverty.   Namely, I will argue that the following three goals can not be satisfied simultaneously.</p>
<ul type="disc"><li>Full employment</li>
    <li>High wages --- the wages paid are living wages.</li>
    <li>No make-work, ie. the jobs being created are economically productive in way that is commiserate with the wages they pay. There are no useless jobs being produced just for the sake of increasing employment</li>
</ul>
<p>The core of this trilemma comes from the fact that the economically efficient wage level has very little to do with the needs of the people involved. In ideal circumstances, wages, like all other prices reflect the relative scarcity of the service or good in question. It is entirely possible, if not undoubtedly true, that the market equilibrium wage level for some workers would be far below any reasonable living wage, just as for some workers it is way higher.  At this point we get to the trilemma. If the government attempts to provide for a high wage level, say through a minimum wage increase, <a href="http://www.theojones.name/why-a-higher-minimum-wage-2/">there is a risk of increased unemployment</a> when the economy is out of recession. Thus we are at a case where there are high wages, and the work is useful, but there is unnecessary unemployment.</p>

<p>Now, the government could try to offset this in one of a few ways. The most obvious is a wage subsidy, such as the earned income tax credit. The government would pay a large portion of the wages, reducing the disemployment effect involved. Another proposal in this vein would be for the government to just outright hire the unemployed segment of the population. However, it seems probable that this would violate the third criteria. There would be high paying jobs, but the jobs being created have a good chance of not winding up economically productive in way that is commiserate with the wages they pay. In the case of a subsidy, employers would no longer feel the full cost of the labor they use. Their grounds for hiring someone would be based on the subsidized price of the wages, not the actual price. There would now be a solid range of circumstances when it would be viable for an employer to hire employees even when they produce less then their post-subsidy pay. Likewise, in the job guarantee case, the government would have to come up with the jobs to hire people under. If these are for services that are not desired by the public for reasons other than their employment production, then these services are probably of limited economic value. And thus we are at a case where you can have high wages, and full employment, but some of the employment would be useless.  There should be no useless jobs being produced just for the sake of increasing employment, as if you are paying people for nothing, you might as well enact a basic income.</p>

<p><strong>Title image produced with <a href="http://www.canva.com">canva</a>.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
