<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23middleeastern</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23middleeastern&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>New Papers Show How Global Warming Harms Agriculture</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/new-papers-show-how-global-warming-harms-agriculture</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 23:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Three recent papers looked into the effect that global warming has on our agricultural system, and found many possibly harmful impacts. Food price instability can be expected to increase and households and farmers in developing nations will feel the pain of a changing climate. Hundreds of thousands will face risk of starvation. Farmers in developed nations will face reduced agricultural output and possibly increased exposure to plant diseases. The papers I will discuss provide case studies into this issue through looking at the impacts that can be expected in Yemen, Australia and the Netherlands.<br /><!--more--><br />[caption id="attachment_624" align="alignright" width="365"] Graph from Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change[/caption]</p>

<p>The paper<a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0306919213001139"> <em>Compounding food and income insecurity in Yemen: Challenges from climate change</em></a> published in the journal Food Policy discusses the effect that global warming will have on the people of the Middle Eastern nation Yemen. The paper found substantial harms. Agricultural productivity will be reduced in Yemen and the cost of imported food will increase. 32% percent of Yemen's population is unable to afford enough food to meet their calorie requirements. Unfortunately, global warming can be expected to increase this problem.  An additional 224,000 people can be expected to face hunger in Yemen in an average year between 2010 and 2050 because of climate change. Rural populations will be the most strongly affected. This study uses the climate change models by the Model for Interdisciplinary Research on Climate and the Commonwealth Scientific and Industrial Research Organisation which are based on the IPCC's A1B projection<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&rct=j&q=&esrc=s&source=web&cd=1&cad=rja&ved=0CCsQFjAA&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ipcc.ch%2Fpdf%2Fassessment-report%2Far4%2Fwg1%2Far4-wg1-spm.pdf&ei=ODY9UqWtOYSwyQHpx4GQBQ&usg=AFQjCNH3kgAs4cAqOcmHrYLSRHIUIbkouw&bvm=bv.52434380,d.aWc"> which predicts 2.8 degrees Celsius warming by the end of the century</a>.The A1B scenario assumes that substantial attempts will be made to convert from fossil fuels to clean energy but that a complete conversion will not be attempted. The harsher A1FI projection assumes that no substantial changes to energy policy will be made and predicts 4.0C warming by the turn of the century.</p>

<p>The paper <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1467-8489.12021/abstract;jsessionid=986D3D8963DAA5D9F2A14937CB6BB8BE.d02t02?systemMessage=Wiley+Online+Library+will+be+unavailable+for+approximately+4+hours+between+09%3A00+EDT+and+14%3A00+EDT+on+Saturday%2C+28+September+2013+as+we+make+upgrades+to+improve+our+services+to+you.+There+will+also+be+some+delays+to+online+publishing+between+25+to+28+September+2013.+We+apologize+for+the+inconvenience+and+appreciate+your+patience.+Thank+you+for+using+Wiley+Online+Library%21&userIsAuthenticated=false&deniedAccessCustomisedMessage="><em>Economic impacts of climate change on the Australian dairy sector</em></a> published in the Australian Journal of Agricultural and Resource Economics looks at how global warming will affect dairy production in Australia. This study finds that production of dairy products will be substantially reduced by climate change. Additionally, production will be pushed to the areas of the country that are least affected by global warming. This effect will be so strong that some of these mildly affected areas will actually increase production because they will gain a competitive advantage over the areas with the most damaged productivity.<a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0073602#s4"><em>Impact of Climate Change Effects on Contamination of Cereal Grains with Deoxynivalenol</em></a> looks at how global warming (with intensity based on the A1B) will affect the spread of fungus infestations responsible for wheat and corn deoxynivalenol contamination in the Netherlands. The paper found no nationwide change in fungus growth but some regions may experience changes and increases after 2040.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/australia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#australia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ipcc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ipcc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/middleeastern" class="p-category" rel="tag">#middleeastern</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/yemenchallenges" class="p-category" rel="tag">#yemenchallenges</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#s4</category>
      <category>#australia</category>
      <category>#ipcc</category>
      <category>#middleeastern</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#yemenchallenges</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
