<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23lewrockwell</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23lewrockwell&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>One Quote that Showcases A Core Problem with Libertarianism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/one-quote-that-showcases-a-core-problem-with-libertarianism</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/one-quote-that-showcases-a-core-problem-with-libertarianism</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2013 17:46:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>I just discovered this quote from libertarian commentator Lew Rockwell's website in an article by Walter E. Block.Keep in mind</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_708" align="alignright" width="267"] Image via Wikipedia and Dedicated to the Public Domain[/caption]</p>

<p>that Block is actually trying to argue for libertarianism but ends up presenting a reductio ad absurdum of the philosophy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“<a href="http://www.lewrockwell.com/2003/02/walter-e-block/turning-their-coats-for-the-state/">First, you are standing on the balcony of a 25th story high-rise apartment when, much to your dismay, you lose your footing and fall out. Happily, in your downward descent, you manage to grab onto a flagpole protruding from the 15th floor of the balcony of another apartment, 10 floors below. Unhappily, the owner of this apartment comes out to her balcony, states that you are [trespassing] by holding on to her flag pole, and demands that you let go (e.g., drop another 15 floors to your death)… the only proper questions which can be addressed in [the libertarian] philosophy are of the sort, if the flagpole hanger attempts to come in to the apartment, and the occupant shoots him for trespassing, Would the forces of law and order punish the home owner?… When put in this way, the answer is clear. The owner is in the right, and the trespasser in the wrong</a>.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote proves two things about libertarianism</p>
<ol><li>The ideology has very little to do with actually preserving liberty, but instead tries to redefine liberty as the right to back up business and property by force</li>
    <li>Libertarianism is more a theory of legitimizing power then a theory of freedom.</li>
</ol>
<p><!--more-->That quote and the rest of Block's writing show libertarianism is about preserving property and business at all costs rather than what any normal person would call liberty. By any reasonable definition of liberty shooting someone definitely results in a strong reduction of their liberty and such an action should only be justified under very extreme circumstances. The shooting in Block's thought experiment was certainly not proportionate. However, property takes absolute priority in libertarian ideology.As Block put it "<em>libertarianism is a theory concerned with the justified use of aggression, or violence, <strong>based on property rights</strong>, not morality</em>" (emphisis added). The corollary of this analysis is that libertarianism is about legitimizing power, not freedom. The libertarian ideology would give individuals and groups absolute power over an area, regardless of the effects on others. By my definition people are free to the extend that they have the largest possible range of capabilities that are not subject to be limited by arbitrary power by others. The libertarian ideology would concentrate power and this power would give others the ability in interfere in the lives of others without substantive check. The government is not the only powerful entity on earth and given the right circumstances private actors can wield great power. But according to a libertarian this power inequality is AOK as long as the property rights check out.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/aok" class="p-category" rel="tag">#aok</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lewrockwell" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lewrockwell</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#aok</category>
      <category>#lewrockwell</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
