<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23argentina</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23argentina&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Debt and Political Questions</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/debt-and-political-questions</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/debt-and-political-questions</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 19:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In this post I will argue that lawsuits in U.S courts by vulture funds against governmental defaults, <a href="http://en.mercopress.com/2014/08/16/global-trade-union-summit-condemns-actions-of-vulture-funds-against-argentina">like the litigation that recently forced Argentina into default</a>, should be dismissed due to separation of powers under the political question doctrine. The political question doctrine declares that some questions before the courts cannot be heard because hearing them would step on a fundamental role of the political branches. In <i>Baker v. Carr</i> the U.S supreme</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1336" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/4123495075_dd9a64af31_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1336" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/4123495075_dd9a64af31_o-300x200.jpg" alt="Image via flickr (user Orin Zebest) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7hnZqF</a>" width="300" height="200" /&gt; Image via flickr (user Orin Zebest) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/7hnZqF%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>7hnZqF[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>court found that the doctrine prevents the courts from hearing a case when any of the following conditions are met</p>
<ol><li>"Textually demonstrable constitutional commitment of the issue to a coordinate political department;"</li>
    <li>"A lack of judicially discoverable and manageable standards for resolving it;"</li>
    <li>"The impossibility of deciding without an initial policy determination of a kind clearly for nonjudicial discretion;"</li>
    <li>"The impossibility of a court's undertaking independent resolution without expressing lack of the respect due coordinate branches of government;"</li>
    <li>"An unusual need for unquestioning adherence to a political decision already made;"</li>
    <li>"The potentiality of embarrassment from multifarious pronouncements by various departments on one question."</li>
</ol>
<p>In the area of foreign policy, this doctrine has been used by the courts to dismiss legal claims that involve the legal status of Taiwan, and the legality of military actions.</p>

<p>The litigant suing Argentina is a vulture fund. Vulture funds buy distressed debt that is near or in default. They then collect on this debt at a large profit. They are debt collectors for governments. <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jun/27/us-vulture-funds-argentina-bankruptcy">All creditors other than the group of vulture funds suing Argentina</a> settled the debt at a loss .</p>

<p>In the case of lawsuit at question in the Argentina debt case, the judiciary is taking up questions of international relations and public finance that fundamentally belong in the political branches. A lawsuit that forces a country into the risk of default has clear foreign policy consequences, and is almost entirely a foreign policy question. The case requires the courts to make a determination of the relative importance of debt payment over other obligations of the government of Argentina. This is also an inherently political decision. The court's actions in this case is already causing the U.S government international embarrassment. Such a decision should of never of been made.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/argentina" class="p-category" rel="tag">#argentina</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/orinzebest" class="p-category" rel="tag">#orinzebest</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#argentina</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#orinzebest</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
