<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23costnuclear</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23costnuclear&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Top Three Reasons Why Nuclear Energy is Better than Fossil Fuels</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/top-three-reasons-why-nuclear-energy-is-better-than-fossil</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/top-three-reasons-why-nuclear-energy-is-better-than-fossil</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 18:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Nuclear energy is a fuel source that is far superior to the fossil fuels that our economy is currently based on. As I will show in this post  nuclear power produces lower greenhouse gas emissions, is safer and is cheaper than many fossil fuels.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_526" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Nuclear_Power_Plant_Cattenom_a.png"></a> Unlike fossil fuel power plants, the only substance leaving the cooling towers of nuclear power plants is water vapour and thus does not pollute the air or cause global warming. Image and caption via Wikipedia and licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license.[/caption]</p>
<ol><li><strong>Lower Greenhouse Gas Emissions:  </strong>France with 73% of its power from nuclear has per-capita CO2 emissions three times LOWER then the U.S. Power costs in France are half that of Germany.</li>
    <li><strong>Health and Safety:</strong> The pollution produced by the fossil fuel industry kills more Americans every year than nuclear energy generation has in the entire world in all of history. <!--more-->A study of more than 400 coal power plants by the American Lung Association<a href="http://www.lungusa.org/about-us/our-impact/top-stories/toxic-air-coal-fired-power-plants.html"> found that the pollution from the power plants kill approximately 13,000 people a year</a> or about 20 people a power plant. <a href="http://www.facebook.com/l.php?u=http%3A%2F%2Fatomicinsights.com%2F1996%2F04%2Fchernobyl-health-effects-best-available-data.html&h=jAQH8I97P">The Chernobyl disaster killed 42 people.</a>What the nuclear industry calls their worst disaster in history the coal industry calls "clean coal". Fukushima and Chernobyl were light water reactors from the 1970s based on designs from the 50s. 95% of the radioactive material from Fukushima was contained and there were no fatalities. The failure of the Fukushima reactor was caused by a once in a lifetime magnitude 9.0 earthquake and a 45 foot high tsunami. Three similar but more modern reactors were hit by the same tsunami and earthquake and remained intact. The latest reactor designs can produce even better safety results. Generation III reactors such as Westinghouse Electric's AP1000, which are the most modern designs currently in production have a very small risk of accident.A report by British regulators found that the AP1000 has a less than 1 in ten million chance of undergoing an accident that results in reactor core damage. The risk of a similar failure from a fourth generation reactor design such as a lead-cooled fast reactor is near-negligible. <a href="http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,2050039-1,00.html">These reactors can also breeder reactors that are much smaller and compact than light water reactors and require much less fuel. In these reactors liquid lead is used to cool the reactor and transfer heat instead of water.</a> These reactors can not produce enough heat to vaporize the lead and cause an explosion. If there is a fuel leak the escaped lead solution will quickly solidify. A lead-cooled fast reactor that can produce enough power for 17,000 households and the fuel needed to run it for over a decade can be the size of a household refrigerator (the equipment to control and monitor the reactor would be the size of a small factory) and kept underground and covered by enough steel and reinforced concrete to contain any failure.</li>
    <li><strong>Cost:</strong> Nuclear power is the cheapest clean energy source and is cost competitive with fossil fuels. <a href="http://www.energy.ca.gov/2007publications/CEC-200-2007-011/CEC-200-2007-011-SD.PDF">According to the California Energy Commission</a> without subsidies nuclear power costs 7.7 cents per kilowatt hour. Coal without subsidies costs 7.4 cents per kilowatt hour. Natural gas and oil cost more than nuclear without subsidies.</li>
</ol><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/americanlungassociation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#americanlungassociation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/costnuclear" class="p-category" rel="tag">#costnuclear</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/westinghouseelectric" class="p-category" rel="tag">#westinghouseelectric</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#americanlungassociation</category>
      <category>#costnuclear</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#westinghouseelectric</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
