<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23paulyes</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23paulyes&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Rand Paul Flip-Flops on U.S Funding Granted to The Israeli MIlitary</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/rand-paul-flip-flops-on-us-funding-granted-to-the-israeli</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/rand-paul-flip-flops-on-us-funding-granted-to-the-israeli</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 08:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>See <a href="http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2014/aug/07/rand-paul/did-rand-paul-propose-cutting-aid-israel/"></a><a href="http://www.politifact.com/truth-o-meter/statements/2014/aug/07/rand-paul/did-rand-paul-propose-cutting-aid-israel/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.politifact.com/<wbr></wbr>truth-o-meter/<wbr></wbr>statements/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>aug/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>rand-paul/<wbr></wbr>did-rand-paul-propose-cutting-aid-israel/<wbr></wbr></a></p><p>U.S Senator Rand Paul said the following on Israeli aid:</p><blockquote>
<p>I haven’t really proposed that in the past. We’ve never had a legislative proposal to do that. You can mistake my position, but then I’ll answer the question. That has not been a position — a legislative position — we have introduced to phase out or get rid of Israel’s aid. That’s the answer to that question. Israel has always been a strong ally of ours and I appreciate that. I voted just this week to give money — more money — to the Iron Dome, so don’t mischaracterize my position on Israel.</p>
</blockquote><p>However, in a 2011 budget proposal he wrote the following:</p><blockquote>
<p>"While this budget proposal does eliminate foreign aid to Israel, it is not meant to hurt, negate, or single out one of America’s most important allies. This proposal eliminates all foreign aid to all countries. Israel’s ability to conduct foreign policy, regain economic dominance, and support itself without the heavy hand of U.S. interests and policies, will only strengthen the Israeli community. The elimination of all foreign aid, including provisions to Israel, is not necessarily a new idea. In 1996, during an address before the U.S. Congress, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu declared that his nation would eventually wean itself from dependence on U.S. foreign aid. Prominent Israeli politicians and economists alike have called for the end of foreign aid. Among them is economist Amon Gafney, who served as governor of the Bank of Israel from 1970 to 1981. He pointed out that foreign aid has caused Israel to suffer from ―Dutch Disease, a situation in which a generous gift brings short-term benefits but impairs a country’s long-term competitiveness."</p>
</blockquote><p>He also quoted the following from Stanford University economist Alvin Rabushka "Free money is the scourge of Israel’s economy. It is the difference between a free, prosperous Israel and a statist, dependent Israel."</p><p>He gave the following interview on CNN</p><blockquote>
<p>Blitzer: "You want to end all foreign aid as well, is that right?"</p>

<p>Paul: "Yes, and in fact, the other day Reuters did a poll, 71 percent of American people agree with me that when we're short of money, where we can't do the things we need to do in our country, we certainly shouldn't be shipping the money overseas. …"</p>

<p>Blitzer: "What about the $2 billion or $3 billion that goes every year to Israel? Do you want to eliminate that as well?"</p>

<p>Paul: "Well, I think what you have to do is you have to look. When you send foreign aid, you actually (send) quite a bit to Israel's enemies, Islamic nations around Israel get quite a bit of foreign aid, too."</p>

<p>Blitzer: "Egypt gets almost the same amount?"</p>

<p>Paul: "Almost the same amount, so really you have to ask yourself, are we funding an arms race on both sides? I have a lot of sympathy and respect for Israel as a democratic nation, as a fountain of peace and a fountain of democracy within the Middle East. But at the same time, I don't think funding both sides of the arms race, particularly when we have to borrow the money from China to send it to someone else. We just can't do it anymore. The debt is all-consuming and it threatens our well being as a country."</p>

<p>The Jonathan Karl interview. Then, on Feb. 3, 2011, Paul sat for an interview with ABC News’ Jonathan Karl. Here’s a portion of their conversation:</p>

<p>Paul: "I’m not singling out Israel. I support Israel. I want to be known as a friend of Israel, but not with money you don’t have. We can’t just borrow from our kids’ future and give it to countries, even if they are our friends. ... I think they’re an important ally, but I also think that their per capita income is greater than probably three-fourths of the rest of the world. Should we be giving free money or welfare to a rich nation? I don’t think so."</p>

<p>Karl: "And you think they can handle their own defense?"</p>

<p>Paul: "I think they’re probably 10 years ahead of any neighboring country. I think their defense is very significant, and I think probably well in advance of any of their potential enemies."</p>

<p>Karl: "Would you leave any foreign aid intact?"</p>

<p>Paul: "No."</p>

<p>Karl: "None?"</p>

<p>Paul: "No. I just don’t think you can give people’s money away when we can’t rebuild bridges in our country."</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/blitzeregypt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#blitzeregypt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/middleeast" class="p-category" rel="tag">#middleeast</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/paulalmost" class="p-category" rel="tag">#paulalmost</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/paulyes" class="p-category" rel="tag">#paulyes</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#blitzeregypt</category>
      <category>#middleeast</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#paulalmost</category>
      <category>#paulyes</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
