<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?offset=0</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?offset=0&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Why I ad block</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-i-ad-block</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/why-i-ad-block</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 20:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>There have been a few recent <a href="http://blog.practicalethics.ox.ac.uk/2015/10/whats-the-moral-difference-between-ad-blocking-and-piracy/">controversies</a> about internet adblocking. <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/sep/18/peace-app-ad-blocker-pulled-marco-arment-iphone-ios-9">The most prominent of these</a> has been Apple's decision to allow ad-blocking software on the App Store for Ipads. I will admit to running adblocking software on my computer and on the pfsense box I use as a router. I realsize that there are some issues with this. I get that there is an impact on the revinue of the websites I visit, as many websites use cost per impression ads that pay out based on the number of visitors to the website. I know that there have been cases where ad blockers have abused their control over the blocklists inorder to make profit. Adblock Plus, for instance, will de-list the ads on a website -- for a fee. However, there are some reasons why I use adblocking software on my computer</p><ol><li>Tracking and privacy. Advertisers use their networks to monitor what websites the viewers of the ads go to, and keep a databse of this tracking. They use this information about web browsing habits to create a profile of each user, and to guess at a wide range of other personal information. This information is used to "target" the ad to the users, and is quite often sold to other companies. This is a substintial violation of privacy and one of the main reasons I ad block. </li>
<li>Computer performance issues. A lot of ads contain flash/javascript code that is quite ram and CPU hogging. </li>
<li>Secutity issues. There have been cases where ads have contained malware. Which isn't surprising, considering that the core of internet targeted advertising is to load untrusted content onto the website you are viewing. Due to the need to keep advertising "targeted" this is pretty much unavoidable under the current internet marketing model. </li>
<li>These problems are at the core of the internet advertising model. Unlike a dead-tree publication, you can't effectively target on geographic location, or the like. So, the much more intrusive methods of advertising become unavoidable. </li>
</ol></div>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systemic Causation and Anti-Science </title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/systemic-causation-and-anti-science</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 22:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>In previous posts I have mentioned George Lakoff's ideas about how misunderstanding systemic causation contributes to science denialism. He describes <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/george-lakoff/sandy-climate-change_b_2042871.html">his ideas at HuffPo</a> and academically in <a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/17524030903529749">a 2010 paper </a>(as usual, full citation at end of post). Lakoff differentiates between two types of causation; systemic and direct. Direct causation is the type of non-probablistic causation that occurs when you shove a box. The box moves, and it will move pretty much every time you shove it. Systemic causation instead involves shifting the probability distribution of events. Climate change does not make a hurricane of a given strength at a given location an unvoidable occurance, in the same way that pushing the box make its movement unavoidable. However, it does make certan types of hurricanes more likely, and therefore can be said to cause hurricanes. A lot of science involves systemic causation. And the fields of science where the causation involved is the most systemic and probabilistic tend to be the biggest denialism magnets. Think climate change or evolution. Why does the role of systemic causation tend to correlate with tendiencies to deny the science? Lakoff seems to think the cause is political ideology.  In his opinion, conservative/libertarian political beliefs tend to have more difficulties with systemic causation. </p><p>However, I doubt this ideological explanation. It is wrong (and perhaps actively dangerous)  for roughly the reasons that <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1744-540X.2007.00466.x/abstract;jsessionid=EB663E5ADD49D613AFCC5CED88563015.f02t03">Steve Pinker points out</a>. Conservatives use arguements that reily on systemic causation all the time, particulary in regards to economic policy. And it is particulary dangerous to treat ideological framing as a goal of political discourse, instead of an all to common discription of it. Such a goal involves a brain-rotting mixing of normative goals and positive description of how the world works. Read Lakoff's writings on GMOs and nuclear energy to see the mind-rot in action.  </p><p>Instead I propose two other explinations of how systemic causation relates to denialism</p><ol><li>The fact that denialism relies on the asymmetry of difficulty in creating reasonable sounding, but incorrect arguements, and refuting them. </li>
<li>The fact that complex systems create emergent properties that often go aganist the intuitions and herististuics that underlie a lot of human reasoning.</li>
</ol><p>Lets start with point one.</p><p><img src="http://www.theojones.name/file/339c444f4e618040977c19a343fd4d1c" alt="The amount of energy necessary to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude bigger than to produce it width=" height="239"></p><p><em>Image via <a href="https://jasonapril.wordpress.com/2014/06/05/the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/"></a><a href="https://jasonapril.wordpress.com/2014/06/05/the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>jasonapril.wordpress.com/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>06/<wbr></wbr>05/<wbr></wbr>the-amount-of-energy-necessary-to-refute-bullshit/<wbr></wbr></a></em></p><p> </p><p>The claims that climate change deniers and creationists and their ilk make reily on very subtle misconseptions. The misconceptions are pretty beleiveable to a non-expert, and a full explination of why the misconception is wrong can take a lot of effort. Go to SKS or a similar website that rebuts climate change deniers. Look at the section where they list their rebuttials to these arguements <a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php"></a><a href="http://www.skepticalscience.com/argument.php">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.skepticalscience.com/<wbr></wbr>argument.php</a> . Note that the rebuttal is usually at least a few times longer than the claim itself.  But it is only a certan type of science that follows the bullshit asymtery rule. Sciences that involve a lot of systemic causation. Complex systems can behave in some pretty subtle ways. Ways that are not ovious, and that take a lot of effort to understand and predict. Due to the Dunning-Kruger effect, and such, it can take quite a bit of knowledge to even be able tell good arguements from bad ones. Add bias, and the generally poor quality of human reasoning, and it becomes easy to talk from <a href="http://imgur.com/cNFqi">Mt. Stupid</a>. </p><p>But when was the last time you saw a math denialist? Not recently? The reason for that is the fact that math does not follow the bullshit asymmetry rule. Its hard to come up with a reasonable sounding, but wrong mathmatical arguement. And when you do come up with one the reason why it is wrong is usually pretty simple. It has actually  become a bit of a game in the math community to come up with invalid "proofs" that seem pleasing. Usually the "proof" is of a clearly absurd claim, like 1=2. Take the following example from Wikipedia. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero"></a><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>en.wikipedia.org/<wbr></wbr>wiki/<wbr></wbr>Mathematical_fallacy#Division_by_zero</a></p><p>Let a and b be be equal non-zero quantities.</p><p>$$a=b$$</p><p>Multiply  both sides of the above equation by a. This results in </p><p>$$a^2 = ab$$</p><p>Subtract </p><p>$$b^2$$</p><p>from both sides, resulting in </p><p>$$a^2 - b^2 = ab - b^2$$</p><p>Factor both sides</p><p>$$(a-b)(a+b) = b(a-b)$$ </p><p>Divide both sides by </p><p>$$(a-b) $$</p><p>Resulting in </p><p>$$a + b = b$$ </p><p>Because we know that a = b</p><p>$$ b + b = b $$ </p><p>$$2b = b$ </p><p>$$2 = 1$$ </p><p>The issue with this is simple, there was an implicit division by zero in the "proof" </p><p> </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/denialism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#denialism</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/science" class="p-category" rel="tag">#science</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/lakoff" class="p-category" rel="tag">#lakoff</a> </p><p>Lakoff, George. "Why it matters how we frame the environment." Environmental Communication 4.1 (2010): 70-81.</p><p>Pinker, Steven, and George Lakoff. "Does language frame politics?." Public Policy Research 14.1 (2007): 59-71.</p><p> </p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#Division</category>
      <category>#Division</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
      <category>#denialism</category>
      <category>#science</category>
      <category>#lakoff</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Climate Change and the Effectiveness of Geoengineering</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/rate-of-change-and-geoengineering</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/rate-of-change-and-geoengineering</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 23:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Geoengineering refers to proposals to ameliorate global warming by causing a man-made cooling effect. This may have the potential to blunt some of the more destructive effects of climate change. I'm not entirely opposed to the idea, as it might be good for blunting some of the worse effects of climate change. It is probably better than doing nothing, although is a worse option than keeping emissions at their current rate. It serves as a middle ground between actually dealing with the issue by reducing emissions, and doing noting about the problem. What this post is about is why it isn't a good alternative to emissions reduction.</p><p>The ultimate problem with climate change/global warming isn't that the climate is warming, or even that it is switching to a different climate pattern. The problem is the rate of change at which this is happening. Its that the new climate will have new weather patterns, and that our infrastructure, and the locations of human populations are suited for the old ones. It is even possible that the new weather patterns could be at least as "good" as the old ones. But the problem is the disparity between how our infrastructure and society is set up, and what the climate patterns look like.</p><p>Temperature is one of many variables that sets what the climate and the weather patterns of the world look like. It is the one that is currently being modified by greenhouse gas pollution. Geoengineering will have the effect of adjusting the temperature in a way that offsets the effects of greenhouse gasses on temperature. But, it will also have the effect of modifying other key aspects of the global climate. These modifications mean that we will not end up with the same climate that we had before the introduction of greenhouse gas pollution after geoengineering. The net change may be less drastic. But it will not be non zero. Geoengineering offsets the effects of human activity on one climate variable at the expense of poking at others. This means that we will still have a substantial climate change even after geoengineering.</p><p>What could some of that climate change in a post-geoengineering world look like? A 2009 paper by Robock et al looked at some of those issues (see the end of this post for a full citation). </p><p><a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1029/2009GL039209/full">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>onlinelibrary.wiley.com/<wbr></wbr>doi/<wbr></wbr>10.1029/<wbr></wbr>2009GL039209/<wbr></wbr>full</a></p><p>In particular, they looked at one commonly proposed method, stratospheric aerosol injection. They write:</p><blockquote><p>Anthropogenic stratospheric aerosol injection would cool the planet, stop the melting of sea ice and land-based glaciers, slow sea level rise, and increase the terrestrial carbon sink, but produce regional drought, ozone depletion, less sunlight for solar power, and make skies less blue.</p></blockquote><p> </p><p> </p><p><span style="color: #222222; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;">Robock, Alan, et al. "Benefits, risks, and costs of stratospheric geoengineering." </span><em style="color: #222222; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;">Geophysical Research Letters</em><span style="color: #222222; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;"> 36.19 (2009).</span></p><p> </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/geoengineering" class="p-category" rel="tag">#geoengineering</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/climatechange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#climatechange</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#222222</category>
      <category>#geoengineering</category>
      <category>#climatechange</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Francis and Kim Davis</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/pope-francis-and-kim-davis</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/pope-francis-and-kim-davis</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 17:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Pope Francis met with Kim Davis, and in the process killed some <a href="https://twitter.com/VincentHarris/status/649291050067099648">endangered social media feels</a>. I'm with Washington Post <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2015/09/30/why-no-one-should-be-surprised-that-pope-francis-met-with-kim-davis/?tid=sm_fb">editorial writer Chris Cillizza on this, why is anyone surprised</a>? </p><p>Its not like the pope kept his opinions on gay marriage a secret. And on a similar note, why do people think that Pope Francis is such a change from previous popes? Other than changing the presentation, he has made minimal changes to catholic doctrine. His opinions on economic issues are the same as most other recent popes, and skepticism about capitalism has been part of the religion for quite a while. And the catholic church is as opposed to gay marriage, and abortion as ever. It is still the same religion as before, only with different packaging. </p><p>And do Davis' opinions and those  of the Pope actually vary that radically? Other than the fact that Davis is a million times more of an asshole about them?</p><p>Consider the following:</p><ul><li>Pope Francis is the monarch of a country that is decidedly not issuing marriage licenses to gay people.</li>
<li>Until a week ago, Davis was a member of the democratic party, so we can at least assume her opinions are at least somewhat moderate on economic issues.</li>
</ul><p>A lot of the sympathy going around towards both individuals is just political signaling. Davis  sends out the conservative political signals, while Francis is associated with liberal ones. Supporters of both follow these signals.</p></div>]]></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With The Growing Toxicity Of American Politics Does Not Mean Centrism</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/dealing-with-the-growing-toxicity-of-american-politics-does-not</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/dealing-with-the-growing-toxicity-of-american-politics-does-not</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 07:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';">There are two ideas about what is wrong in American politics that, are often confused with each other</div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><strong> </strong></div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><strong>The toxicity problem</strong>— The idea that politics has become very divisive, partisan, and that this toxicity is beginning to undermine shared goals and values. This issues is roughly symmetrical on both sides of American politics. Furthermore, this is worse than in the recent past. There are a few sub-issues with in this that I identify</div><ul style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><li>Partisanship </li>
<li>Irreason (science denials, the inability for people to challenge wrong/disingenuous arguments from their own side) </li>
<li>The inability to admit uncertainty in one’s beliefs </li>
<li>The growth of political media outlets — (Fox News, social media, talk radio etc.) </li>
<li>Attacks on important shared values like civil liberties, due process, and freedom of speech.</li>
<li>The end of bipartisan cooperation to meet shared goals</li>
<li>The increasing inability to separate personal, non-political life from politics </li>
<li>Overconfidence — over estimating the probability that one’s ideas are correct</li>
</ul><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><strong>The centrism solution </strong>— The idea that the ideas promoted by both sides of American politics are extreme, and the optimal set of policies is roughly in-between the two extremes. </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"> </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';">I believe that the increasing toxicity of American politics is a major problem for the country. However, centrism is not the solution to it. The ultimate issue with the current American political situation is the <em>way</em> that political issues are being resolved. It is the political culture where the other side is viewed as the enemy. A threat to be countered before it destroys the real americans. It is the political culture that considers a “safe place” as one in which the other side is not present. It is the red tribe versus blue tribe politics. However, this is not nessarily an issue with the particular policies being promoted. It does not mean that the correct policy is halfway in-between those favored by the typical democrat and those favored by the typical republican. In many cases one side is wrong, and one side is right. Either action needs to be taken on climate change or it does not. The half-way centrist solution may very well be the worse of all options — one that neither side desires, and one that does just enough to incur a lot of costs but not enough to actually fix the climate change issue (think of the introduction of biofuels as a real world example of this). Either gay marriage should be legal or it shouldn’t, and any attempts at half way policies (such as civil unions) are unsatisfactory at best. Either the minimum wage produces dangerous disemployment effects or it doesn’t. And so on. </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"> </div><p> </p><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';">Now, the centrism-as-the-solution idea seems intuitive for a simple reason — in an highly toxic political climate , people will reject the good with the bad from the other side. The mere fact that an idea comes from the other side of the political spectrum (or even attains an association with it) becomes sufficient reason to reject it. The behavior and ideas of one side are given favoritism compared to the ideas from the other side. This may give one the idea that the middle is where the solution can be found. But even though some good conservative ideas may be rejected by liberals and some good liberal ideas may be rejected by conservatives , this does not mean that the correct choice for each issue is the middle. It means that liberals and conservatives should pay attention to each others’ ideas. </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"> </div><div style="font-family: 'Helvetica Neue';"><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/centrism" class="p-category" rel="tag">#centrism</a><strong> </strong></div></div>]]></description>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#centrism</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unusually Toxic Nature of Social Issues </title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-unusually-toxic-nature-of-social-issues</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/the-unusually-toxic-nature-of-social-issues</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 22:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Speaker of the House John Boehner resigned earlier this week, <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/dandiamond/2015/09/25/planned-parenthood-fight-costs-john-boehner-his-job/">in part due to the fight over funding for Planned Parenthood</a>.  Incidents like this show something that is fairly obvious to most people, that social issues are among the most persistently toxic issues. But why should abortion, gay marriage, and such be so at the core of U.S politics. Why should they be major litmus tests for both parties? By any reasonable measure these issues are pretty low impact for the level of attention they receive. By impact, they certanily aren’t as important as immigration, climate change, poverty, or other issues that have a very large effect on over all social well being. But there is a dearth of individuals writing flameage about urban planning on social media, nor are there government shutdowns about that topic, despite the fact that urban planning policy probably has a <a href="http://faculty.chicagobooth.edu/chang-tai.hsieh/research/growth.pdf">much larger impact on the over-all wellbeing of the typical person </a></p><p>So, why do social issues produce the toxicity that they do? I have a few ideas</p><ul><li>The zero sum nature of them. A loss for one side is a gain for the other. Allowing gay marriage is a victory for those who want gay marriage but a loss those who don’t want it. Defunding Planned Parenthood means a rather direct loss for people who want to keep abortion services available, but it is a rather direct win for those opposed to abortion (ignoring indirect effects of contraceptive avaiability on the number of abortions).</li>
<li>The incommensurability of moral systems. The ethical assumptions that underlie one side <em>make no sense</em> from the other side. From the perspective of a supporter of abortion availability, the arguments of the other side seem like at best mindless superstition, and at worst outright sexism. From the perspective on an abortion opponent the other side seems like a villan from a James Bond movie. Likewise with gay marriage, the “family values” that conservatives are interested in promoting have close to no value to liberals.  This probably by its self produces a lot of the inability for the different sides to deal with each other -- they begin to perceive each other as downright evil. </li>
<li>The role of religion. The U.S is one of the few countries where religion is important enough to have a major political role, but not so powerful to totally dominate politics. This creates the clashes over social issues, as the U.S is really in a transitional point between religion and secularism. The importance of this is obvious from the conservative side, but I think there is a more subtle role here in the politics of the left. A lot of the social justice activism that plays out on social media, and on college campuses, seems to me like a secular substitute for religion — a replacement for its role in society. This would also explain a lot of the uniquely American aspects of these issues.  </li>
<li>The clearly disengenious nature of many of the arguements fronted on these issues. </li>
</ul><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/SocialIssues" class="p-category" rel="tag">#SocialIssues</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/PlannedParenthood" class="p-category" rel="tag">#PlannedParenthood</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Abortion" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Abortion</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/GayMarrage" class="p-category" rel="tag">#GayMarrage</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/JohnBoehner" class="p-category" rel="tag">#JohnBoehner</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Politics</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#SocialIssues</category>
      <category>#PlannedParenthood</category>
      <category>#Abortion</category>
      <category>#GayMarrage</category>
      <category>#JohnBoehner</category>
      <category>#Politics</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the topic of the latest flash ownage...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-topic-of-the-latest-flash-ownage</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-topic-of-the-latest-flash-ownage</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 04:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>On the topic of the latest flash ownage ---- I don't get why people are so committed to having a browser that can run stuff that has as much application-like functionality as possible. Write once, debug anywhere. The story of web apps, Java, Flash, and all similar attempts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/status" class="p-category" rel="tag">#status</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#status</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Look at this Reddit post which seems to...</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/look-at-this-reddit-post-which-seems-to</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/look-at-this-reddit-post-which-seems-to</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 04:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Look at this Reddit post, which seems to be from former Reddit CEO Yishan Wong.I get the real feeling that Reddit is falling apart at the seams, and I'm not sure it will be able to recover.<br /><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/announcements/comments/3dautm/content_policy_update_ama_thursday_july_16th_1pm/ct3n7hc">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.reddit.com/<wbr></wbr>r/<wbr></wbr>announcements/<wbr></wbr>comments/<wbr></wbr>3dautm/<wbr></wbr>content_policy_update_ama_thursday_july_16th_1pm/<wbr></wbr>ct3n7hc</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Ellen was more or less inclined to continue upholding my free-speech policies. /r/fatpeoplehate was banned for inciting off-site harassment, not discussing fat-shaming. What all the white-power racist-sexist neckbeards don't understand is that with her at the head of the company, the company would be immune to accusations of promoting sexism and racism: she is literally Silicon Valley's #1 Feminist Hero, so any "SJWs" would have a hard time attacking the company for intentionally creating a bastion (heh) of sexist/racist content. She probably would have tolerated your existence so long as you didn't cause any problems - I know that her long-term strategies were to find ways to surface and publicize reddit's good parts - allowing the bad parts to exist but keeping them out of the spotlight. It would have been very principled - the CEO of reddit, who once sued her previous employer for sexual discrimination, upholds free speech and tolerates the ugly side of humanity because it is so important to maintaining a platform for open discourse. It would have been unassailable.<br />Well, now she's gone (you did it reddit!), and /u/spez has the moral authority as a co-founder to move ahead with the purge. We tried to let you govern yourselves and you failed, so now The Man is going to set some Rules. Admittedly, I can't say I'm terribly upset.</p>
</blockquote><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/link" class="p-category" rel="tag">#link</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#1</category>
      <category>#link</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Chipotle Price Increases</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-chipotle-price-increases</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-chipotle-price-increases</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 03:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The following article price increases in San Francisco by food chain Chipotle has gone viral, Huffington Post linked to it, and I've seen it on Facebook and quite a few other social media sources I use.<br /><a href="http://www.takepart.com/article/2015/07/12/chipotle-minimum-wage?cmpid=tp-ptnr-huffpost">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.takepart.com/<wbr></wbr>article/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>chipotle-minimum-wage?cmpid=tp-ptnr-huffpost</a><br />In this post I'll do an analysis of where this article goes wrong. Let's first jump to the fairly idiotic section towards the middle of the article.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But before conservative economists use the beloved chain—which has ditched GMOs and is working toward preservative-free tortillas—</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There are two quite stupid things with this line. The first is that the article offers seems to think that GMOs and preservatives are somehow relevant to the discussion of minimum wages. But even more seriously, is the fairly inane idea that appears all throughout this article that an increase in the minimum wage will have no effect on prices. Since labor costs are quite a substantial factor in overall business costs, increase in those costs have a fairly direct impact on prices. As far as I know, this is not reasonably disputed by any economist conservative or liberal. Pretty much the entire academic debate on minimum wage policy involves auxiliary effects of minimum wages such as effects on the overall employment level. You will see in the next quote that the article authors' understanding of what those effects on the price level might be definitely confused at best. And at the worst totally nonsensical.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So, Why Should You Care? One of the common arguments against raising the minimum wage is tied to price increases for consumers. If this cyclical effect were to take place in every industry, the result would be pure inflation. That has critics asking, what good is making a dollar more for minimum wage workers if every purchase also costs a dollar more?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This at once is  a severe understanding of what pretty much a reasonable economic model on the subject says, and probably a total misunderstanding of what the "critics" actually believe. Of course, it won't be purely inflationary. In the worst case, where there  is perfect pass through from the company to consumers. What will happen will be an up tick in prices that will mostly wind up in the income of the workers. It will not be purely inflationary in the nonsensical way described in the article because the percentage increase in the wages will exceed the increase in the price level caused by the wage increase. And even though the article author suggests otherwise, I don't see any reasonable way in which there can be no price increase.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>University Runs Anti Vax Course</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/university-runs-anti-vax-course</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/university-runs-anti-vax-course</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://arstechnica.com/science/2015/07/u-of-toronto-oks-anti-vaccine-homeopathy-course">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>science/<wbr></wbr>2015/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>u-of-toronto-oks-anti-vaccine-homeopathy-course</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The syllabus for the course has been posted online, and it reads a bit like a bad blog post. "Quantum physics is a branch of physics that understands the interrelationship between matter and energy," It states. "This science offers clear explanations as to why homeopathic remedies with seemingly no chemical trace of the original substance are able to resolve chronic diseases, why acupuncture can offer patients enough pain relief to undergo surgery without anesthesia, why meditation alone can, in some instances, reduce the size of cancerous tumors."</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is the type of crap I've seen a lot. There is Deepack Chopra and his ilk. Quantum gobbledygook is about the only justification for water memory I have heard other than total evasion of the issue. At the very least a lot of the homeopathic types also believe in quantum woo.</p>

<p>The really crappy thing with this is that is that it is under a natural sciences department. I've seen crap like this leak into social science classes. I've even had the misfortune of taking a class that somehow got into the Womens' studies department (taken for distribution requirements) with cross listing with other social science departments with a textbook that talked about how alternative medicine and homeopathy are perfectively good "ways of knowing" on par with "western medicine", and then went on to talk about the health risks of living near a power-line EMF field.</p>

<p>But this is the first I have seen from a department that should know better. At least its not from my university.</p>

<p>On a side note, I have a funny homeopathic story. I beekeep. One friend of mine heard this and insisted that a homeopathic dilution of bee alarm pheromone would work to calm bees in lue of smoke. All you have to do is spray the homeopathic remedy on the bees with a spray bottle. I am not making that up. It almost made me want to spray water on the bees to see what would happen, but I didn't do that because it is likely that the bees wouldn't be happy about it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/notweet" class="p-category" rel="tag">#notweet</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#notweet</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
