<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23imageviaflickr</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23imageviaflickr&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Client Side Data Validation; or How Security Flaws Can Get Into Software</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/client-side-data-validation-or-how-security-flaws-can-get</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/client-side-data-validation-or-how-security-flaws-can-get</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 06:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>There is a reason why attacks like the Sony breach still happen. Hacking is fundamentally about having the creativity and knowledge to put well known methods together into a well designed overall line of attack. The things that hackers exploit are mistakes that are easy to make, and the people who build a network have to get lucky all the time. But the people attacking it have to just</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1318" align="alignright" width="226"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/31436961_33399f4066_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1318" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/31436961_33399f4066_o-226x300.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user sylvar) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3M87z</a>" width="226" height="300" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user sylvar) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/3M87z%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>3M87z[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>get lucky a few times. Hacking may involve some technical skill, but the people that crack computer networks have more creativity than technical wizardy. And with the likes of Sony, you can't rule out the possibility of technical incompetence. But there is a reason why these exploits keep being present in the frequency that they do, and that reason is simple -- programmers and network designers don't know security and thereby make even very simple errors in the systems they design. One simple error is client side validation, trusting a calculation made on a remote device that could be completely under the control of an attacker. The problems with this type of design is clear, programmers are putting their security on the hacker's computer, but this error keeps on being made. Take this thread on Stack Exchange for instance <a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/76974/verify-client-side-created-data"></a><a href="http://security.stackexchange.com/questions/76974/verify-client-side-created-data">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>security.stackexchange.com/<wbr></wbr>questions/<wbr></wbr>76974/<wbr></wbr>verify-client-side-created-data</a></p>

<p>The OP in question here has a simple issue. "<em>I have a Java applet, which records the whole screen of the user and uploads the images to the server. If one would be able to (and many people could, I know) falsify the screen recording they could cheat legitimate users of the system out of their money, so there are incentives.</em>". The problem, of course, is that there is no way to make that type of design secure. Since the java applet is under the user's control, a user could make any change to the screen shot. A design that relies on the proper behavior of a remote system is inherently insecure. But such designs keep being made.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/stackexchange" class="p-category" rel="tag">#stackexchange</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#stackexchange</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Should the Energy Grid Be Ran?</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-should-the-energy-grid-be-ran</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/how-should-the-energy-grid-be-ran</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 23:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>The way in which the U.S energy grid is ran is severely flawed. Energy pricing is unrelated to consumer demand. This creates many problems. It encourages consumers (and even more importantly industry) to use energy without concern for the impacts on the grid.<br />The way in which the U.S energy grid is ran is severely flawed. Energy pricing is unrelated to consumer demand. This creates many problems. With a power grid</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1322" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1322" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o-300x178.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H</a>" width="300" height="178" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/e8B95H%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>the only thing that matters isn't raw energy production, it is the time frame during which the energy is produced, not all energy production is equally valuable. It encourages consumers (and even more importantly industry) to use energy without concern for the impacts on the grid. It encourages the formation of energy producers with a parasitic business model that is based around dumping as much energy on the grid as possible, regardless of whether this is actually useful production. By extension it wastes the money of consumers and results in higher prices for them. This setup also distorts the energy sources used by producers. The current energy system also merges two unrelated things, producing the energy and distributing it. This creates a wide range of inefficiencies. I will propose four simple changes</p>
<ol><li>Prevent energy producing companies from also owning the distribution systems for energy</li>
    <li>Set up a two stage system for energy purchase by consumers. Along with dealing with the energy distributor, consumers will also select an energy producer to buy from. (energy producers could still buy from a wholesale market). Consumers with their own energy production (such as a home solar setup) would sell this energy to a producer</li>
    <li>Allow energy producers to experiment with a wide range of energy pricing methods</li>
    <li>The energy distribution companies should charge a flat fee for the use of the grid.</li>
</ol>
<p>Why should you care about this? Simple. The structure of the energy grid has a wide range of impacts. How it conducts its pricing affects the mix of energy sources used. If this is set wrong, both consumers and the public may suffer. If energy companies use their power over distribution to affect production, consumers will lose. Inefficient management of the energy grid may slow deployment of sustainable energy, and energy storage tech. The concentration of energy production into a single hand will also remove choice from consumers, and reduce the level of competition in the energy markets.</p>

<p>Slate did an article about something called "Demand Destruction". They make it sound like something that is the result of people just switching over to home-produced electricity, thereby becoming independent of the grid and leaving the power company in the dust. In reality, truly off-grid systems are extremely rare -- and expensive at almost $3.20 a kilowatt hour (mostly batteries and energy storage, commercial energy storage is much cheaper than home energy storage, but energy storage in general is quite expensive). The source of the problem is malformed renewable energy incentive laws that force power companies to pay all energy production an equal rate -- even if the energy is produced at an off-peak time that has little use. This enables a business model that I will call "Grid Leeching". This business model takes advantage of a simple fact. Electricity companies are required to pay and receive payment based on energy produced. But consumers don't want raw energy; they want power -- a constant flow of energy. energy is much cheaper to produce than power. Individuals and businesses buy cheap solar production systems that are designed to barf large amounts of off-peak energy on to the grid. The electricity company is required to pay full price for this energy. The grid leechers then get to use the power grid for their actual power needs practically free of charge. These cheap solar systems can sell for as little as $2 a watt average production or about the equivalent to 15 cents a kilowatt hour. Around this has developed a little market of companies that specialize in attaching leeches to the grid. One of these profiled is SolarCity, which rents out these cheap solar systems. This is very destructive to the grid. The only way that a electricity company can make up for this type of thing is to run load-following power plants -- usually natural gas -- in an inefficient, and rapidily fluctuating way. This happens while the leechers are drawing power while not paying anything on the net. The leechers only give back low quality, off-peak energy.</p>

<p>What can be done about this. It is simple: fluctuate energy charges, and energy production payouts based on the current demand. When there is little energy demand, pay the producers of energy less (and charge the consumers less). When energy demand is high, pay producers more and charge consumers more. Charge a flat monthly fee for a connection to the grid (based on the maximum current the user is allowed to draw). This will put the grid leechers out of business, because their core business model of dumping energy on the grid at low-demand times will no longer work. This will encourage companies to produce constant power (or even better, demand following energy), and will encourage consumers to modulate their energy usage during peak demand times. This may reduce the incentives for renewable energy deployment. However, the current model encourages the formation of grid leechers, instead of actually productive renewable energy firms. Furthermore, it puts nuclear energy (one of the best sources of baseload power) at a disadvantage. Sustainable energy should be directly subsidized at very large levels.</p>

<p>I will contend that energy utilities really do two distinct things that can and should be separate. The first is producing energy. The second is distributing that electricity. Separating these two roles will vastly improve the competitiveness of the electricity markets and will have benefits in regard to climate change and pollution. It would improve consumer choice , and allow consumers greater choice in what energy is consumed and how it is produced. However in reality, most utilities are also the main producers of the electricity that they distribute. As I will discuss towards the end of the post, this change would be<br />Electricity production is a natural monopoly — that is the lowest cost market outcome is one electricity utility serving an entire community. This of course has problems, a monopoly can of course over charge consumers. Monopolies charge based on what the consumer is willing to pay while a firm in a competitive market charges based on the actual cost. Additionally, a monopoly can abuse their power to gain market share of other related markets. This is in effect what most utilities have done with energy production. Because they are the sole distributor of electricity it is easy for them to make themselves the main producer of it. This not only increases costs to consumers, but also reduces their choice. If a consumer wants an energy plan heavy on a given energy source, or billed in a certain way, it may be very difficult to arrange that in the current system. In a more competitive energy market, there would be many energy producers each vying for the dollars of consumers. They would not have to wait for the sluggishness of one utility company for a new method to arrive. There would be an explosion of energy plans and energy sources, and types of billing. Want a energy plan centered on nuclear power, but no fossil fuels? Tough to find under current conditions, but perhaps not so tough under a more competitive arrangement. Want a energy plan billed on a fixed monthly rate — like how internet is billed? Very few utilities offer such a thing, but it might be more easy to find that type of thing in a more competitive market. More examples of how this would work could be envisioned.<br />Such a change would also have positive implications for the environment. Remember the issue about net metering of solar production at home? There is a great public benefit to allowing consumers to sell back energy they produce. But the types of net metering that regulators commonly implement have a severe flaw. They enable people to produce energy at low-value, off peak times and use the grid as a free battery. Separating energy production from distribution would solve this dilemma. People with home solar systems would sell their energy production to a energy production company, and a reasonable agreed upon value that takes into account the level of demand for the energy. But the distribution utility would charge a fee for the connection to the grid. This would prevent people from producing low value energy in-order to use the grid as a free battery. But it would reward people who use clean energy production at home to produce valuable energy. There are other clean energy production benefits of such a change. There would be a great opportunity for energy producers to experiment with clean energy sources, and sell this production to consumers who are willing to be early adopters. This is in contrast to utilities which can take many years to adapt to a change.</p>

<p>This change would be easy to implement. Instead of dealing with one power company, consumers would pay two companies. Consumers would pay a utility to hook their house to the grid. This would likely be billed as a flat monthly fee. They would then find a energy production company that has a plan that they like. The billing for this would vary from plan to plan. Despite the increased complexity of this setup, consumers would greatly benefit.</p>

<p>In this blog post I have proposed a way to reform the energy grid. This proposal will benefit consumers. It will result in increased consumer choice. And it will result in lower prices and a more efficient market.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Demand Destruction"? More like "Grid Leeching"</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/demand-destruction-more-like-grid-leeching</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/demand-destruction-more-like-grid-leeching</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 17:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Slate did an article about <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/business/the_juice/2014/07/energy_efficiency_vs_demand_destruction_the_big_problem_facing_america_s.html">something called "Demand Destruction"</a>. They make it sound like something that is the result of people just switching over to home-produced electricity, thereby becoming independent of the grid and leaving the power company in the dust. In reality, truly off-grid systems are extremely rare -- and expensive at almost <a href="http://life.gaiam.com/article/whats-it-going-cost-me-go-solar">$3.20 a kilowatt hour</a> (mostly batteries and energy storage, commercial energy storage is much cheaper than home energy storage, but energy storage in general is quite expensive). The source of the problem is malformed renewable energy incentive laws that force power companies to pay</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_1322" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1322" src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/8618709561_53c8c8a794_o-300x178.jpg" alt="Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H</a>" width="300" height="178" /&gt; Image Via Flickr (user Angelo DeSantis) <a href="https://flic.kr/p/e8B95H%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>e8B95H[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a></p>

<p>all energy production an equal rate -- even if the energy is produced at an off-peak time that has little use. This enables a business model that I will call "Grid Leeching". This business model takes advantage of a simple fact. Electricity companies are required to pay and receive payment based on energy produced. But consumers don't want raw energy; they want power -- a constant flow of energy. energy is much cheaper to produce than power. Individuals and businesses buy cheap solar production systems that are designed to barf large amounts of off-peak energy on to the grid. The electricity company is required to pay full price for this energy. The grid leechers then get to use the power grid for their actual power needs practically free of charge. These cheap solar systems can sell for as little as $2 a watt average production or about the equivalent to 15 cents a kilowatt hour. Around this has developed a little market of companies that specialize in attaching leeches to the grid. One of these profiled is SolarCity, which rents out these cheap solar systems. This is very destructive to the grid. The only way that a electricity company can make up for this type of thing is to run load-following power plants -- usually natural gas -- in an inefficient, and rapidily fluctuating way. This happens while the leechers are drawing power while not paying anything on the net. The leechers only give back low quality, off-peak energy.</p>

<p>What can be done about this. It is simple: fluctuate energy charges, and energy production payouts based on the current demand. When there is little energy demand, pay the producers of energy less (and charge the consumers less). When energy demand is high, pay producers more and charge consumers more. Charge a flat monthly fee for a connection to the grid (based on the maximum current the user is allowed to draw). This will put the grid leechers out of business, because their core business model of dumping energy on the grid at low-demand times will no longer work. This will encourage companies to produce constant power (or even better, demand following energy), and will encourage consumers to modulate their energy usage during peak demand times. This may reduce the incentives for renewable energy deployment. However, the current model encourages the formation of grid leechers, instead of actually productive renewable energy firms. Furthermore, it puts nuclear energy (one of the best sources of baseload power) at a disadvantage. Sustainable energy should be directly subsidized at very large levels.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/imageviaflickr" class="p-category" rel="tag">#imageviaflickr</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#imageviaflickr</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
