<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23NotAShield</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23NotAShield&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Message to Any Reasonable People Attached to #GamerGate : You are Scoring an Own Goal</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/message-to-any-reasonable-people-attached-to-gamergate-you-are</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/message-to-any-reasonable-people-attached-to-gamergate-you-are</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 04:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>This post is a consequence of the fact that I've seen an recent uptick in gamergate related stuff in my twitter feed and elsewhere. It is pretty difficult to define what Gamergate is, and as far as I can tell GGers are more closely defined by what they are against than what they are for. The best reasonably neutrally stated sense of what GG is that I can make is that it a coalition of various groups in opposition to encroachment of feminist activists into the gaming community. Furthermore, the movement was formed as a byproduct of conflicts between internet trolls and internet feminist communities. Well before GG started, trolls from 4chan, 8chan and other trolling groups and communities, realized that the feminist community makes a trolling target which produces a good source of lulz. Gamergate, or at least its prelude, was the crown jewel of this trolling campaign. It is not a coincidence that Gamergate formed around many trolling communities; this includes the likes of 4chan, 8chan, Wizardchan, and[caption id="attachment_1380" align="alignright" width="300"]<a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4906597504_3fae1326d2_o.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/4906597504_3fae1326d2_o-300x210.jpg" alt="Image via Flickr user Sam Howzit &lt;a href=" https:>https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8tzAuG</a>" width="300" height="210" class="size-medium wp-image-1380" /&gt; Image via Flickr user Sam Howzit <a href="https://flic.kr/p/8tzAuG%5B/caption%5D">https:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>flic.kr/<wbr></wbr>p/<wbr></wbr>8tzAuG[/<wbr></wbr>caption]</a> <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/josephbernstein/gamergates-headquarters-has-been-destroyed-by-trolls#.ymkD0Mvg3">Niko of Death, one of the leaders of the 8chan gamergate community has recently been exposed as connected</a> to the infamous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gay_Nigger_Association_of_America">GNAA</a> trolling crew (GNAA stands for Gay Nigger Association of America). But is is not safe to say that all, or even most, GGers are trolls. Gamergate came out of the effort of trolls to focus anger at internet feminists in the most lulz producing way possible. Namely trolls at 4chan and such saw that the events which served as the prelude to GG were the perfect opportunity. They realized that there were a number of types of people in the gaming community opposed to feminists, and that good lulz was to be had by blurring the lines, and by uniting them in an incoherent and almost comical message, along with adding a good dose of harassment and threats to the mix. It is even better trolling because it has caused some in progressive/feminist circles to defend some pretty bad stuff -- the enemy of my enemy is my friend apparently.  However, critics of feminism are not a uniform group and the trolling that gave rise to GG was good trolling because of this heterogeneity. These critics and the GG community for the most part, be binned into a handful of groups 1) outright trolls 2) fanboys of certain games who respond virulently to criticism of their favorite games, 3) a number of true sexists,4)conservative activists who have little actual ties to the gaming world , and finally 5) the sub-group with reasonable points. This post is aimed at the last group, a group that I've seen enough of to think exists to an extent. This is also the subset of GG that I think is worth engaging with to some degree, a and that I think makes a number of good points (I will detail this later in the post). And to them I have one question. Why <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/GamerGate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#GamerGate</a>? By associating yourself with a community with so many toxic elements you are destroying the credibility of the reasonable points you make. GG has become so toxic and problematic that anything with even the whif of a Gamergate connection is discredited. One last note, just because I am against GG does not mean that I agree with those facing the fiercest criticism by the GGers, other than to decry the harassment they face.  On this post, I will note that I am open to comments on this article. You can comment here, or tweet at me  @Theo_Jones1  With the comments on this post, I'm going to take a pretty light hand with moderation, due to the nature of the subject.</p>
<h1>The Start of Gamergate</h1>
<p>A time line of the start of gamergate is like this <br />*    The fight between 4chan and  internet feminists serves as a substantial backdrop of the whole gamergate issue.<br />*    Quinn (who is also a critic of video games from a feminist perspective) writes her game on depression. The game gets positive press in some publications.<br />*    It comes out that Quinn cheated on her boyfriend with multiple men due to the fact that the now ex-boyfriend leaked chat logs on to 4chan. Some of the men she had relations with worked at some of the publications that reviewed the Depression Quest game, but none of those people were responsible for any of the reviews.There are allegations that the positive reviews of the game came because of Quinn's sexual activity. This echoed to some extent in the community because in many gaming publications there are concerns about issues like payola and other forms of bias. There is no indication that the people who actually wrote the reviews had any .. um .. personal encounters ... with Quinn, and as far as I can tell there seems to be little basis to these allegations. The whole Quinn thing strikes me as just gossip stuff that has little relation to anything important (other than the trouble created by 4chan). I don't care about the personal life of the people who write the software that I use. I just care if the game is any good.<br />*      4chan and others in the internet trolling community, such as GNAA, think that this would be a good chance to stir up come trouble, considering that Quinn is also a vocal feminist.  The assumption seems to be that a war between elements of the gamer community and femminists over gossip BS would be good lulz. The 4chaners cycle through a few hashtags that have a short life span, such as, <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fiveguys" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fiveguys</a>. Readers of internet forums can now enjoy the flame wars on the subject. <br />*      The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> hashtag is created by Adam Baldwin (who seems to be mainly interested in this because of his conservative politics rather than a interest in gaming). The trolls then move to this and 4chaners move to seed and promote the <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> hashtag. The <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotYourShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotYourShield</a> tag is later created by a mix of 4chaners and 8chaners. <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotYourShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotYourShield</a> is supposed to be for women/minority GGers. The footprint of trolling can be seen in the selection of these tags, which can easily be interpreted as double entandres. One could say that its <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotYourShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotYourShield</a> instead of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/NotAShield" class="p-category" rel="tag">#NotAShield</a> for a reason. And <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/Gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#Gamergate</a> itself implys a scandal in gaming, but doesn't say what caused the scandal.<br />*      The dispute extends to other feminists who write about gaming. Anita Sarkeesian , who creates a video series criticizing the portrayal of women in games, gets the brunt of this. Sarkeesian faces death threats and intense harassment. If you are interested, this Wa Po article <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/08/29/gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/"></a><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/08/29/gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.washingtonpost.com/<wbr></wbr>news/<wbr></wbr>morning-mix/<wbr></wbr>wp/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>08/<wbr></wbr>29/<wbr></wbr>gaming-vlogger-anita-sarkeesian-is-forced-from-home-after-receiving-harrowing-death-threats/<wbr></wbr></a> has one of her videos. I think there is a lot to criticize about her work (there is strong sexism in gaming, and a lack of serious female characters in games but she overplays here and on this to an extent), but nothing excuses the level of harassment she has received.<br />*     The movement grows to become a general reaction to feminists and other forms of what the GGers affectionately call "social justice warriors". <br />*      None of the above should be interpreted as an endorsement of either Sarkeesian or Quinn. On this issue it is dangerous to assume that the enemy of your enemy is your friend. Quinn seems to be an asshole with some fringe political views. Sarkeesian has made a number of claims and arguments in her videos that are problematic, or just outright wrong, and has been caught plagiarizing footage and screenshots from reviews of the games she criticizes. Both are active in the quite toxic internet feminist community that regularly uses many of the tactics rightfully criticized when used by GGers.</p>
<h1>The Toxic Elements of GG</h1><h2>The Trolls</h2>
<p>I think these guys have been discussed quite a bit already. These are the 4chaners, the 8chaners, the wizardchaners, the GNAAers.</p>
<h2>The Ideologues</h2>
<p>Gamergate quickly attracted a lot of ideological conservatives that have little interest in gaming or any of the controversy surrounding it. There is a reason why conservative rags like Brebiart, and Daily Caller have been the only mainstream publications to take a pro-GG side. This people dislike progressives and feminists and are willing to take the side of anyone who also does.</p>
<h2>The Fanboys</h2>
<p>A large number of GGers seem to be there because their favorite games were insulted. This seems to be the reasoning behind such things as the outrage over the Polygon Review of Tropico. Sure it was a stupid review, but there isn't much more you can reasonably say.</p>
<h2>The Sexists</h2>
<p>Within the GG community there seems to be a heavy presence of MRAs and other forms of sexists. This is hugely problematic.</p>
<h1>Who Are the Reasonable GGers and What Do They Say</h1>
<p>Are you one of the people that I mean when I talk of reasonable GGers? Here are some questions that will help you decide<br />*  Do you oppose the harassment and toxic behavior of some elements in your community?<br />*  Do you oppose the use of boycotts as a tool of censorship even when your side is doing it (the attempts to get advertisers to pull the plug on anti-GG publications)?<br />*  Do you accept that there are some issues with sexism in the gaming community?<br />*  When you speak of "gaming journalism bias", do you have something in mind more than some idiot writing a dumb review of a game you like?<br />*  What is your reason for being a GGer?<br />*  When you speak of opposing censorship, does that include ideas you don't like?</p>

<p>The subset of reasonable people in GG are the ones that I think make some good points. For these people the problem seems to be some of the authoritarian tendencies of the feminist/identity politics left.  Rather than mangle their words, I will quote one of the better things I've seen written by GGers. Note that there is not total agreement here, but these are the points of view worth dealing with to some extent.  This article <a href="http://www.gamepolitics.com/2014/12/30/gamergate-political-attitudes-part-two-old-liberals-vs-new-progressives#.VKSSBM3OphE"></a><a href="http://www.gamepolitics.com/2014/12/30/gamergate-political-attitudes-part-two-old-liberals-vs-new-progressives#.VKSSBM3OphE">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>www.gamepolitics.com/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>12/<wbr></wbr>30/<wbr></wbr>gamergate-political-attitudes-part-two-old-liberals-vs-new-progressives#.VKSSBM3OphE</a>   attempts to summarize the politics of gamergate. It goes a bit far in trying to find reasonableness where there is none (i.e with MRAs and such in the GG world). However, the end of that article is worth a read.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Political historians have often remarked that the right won the big economic arguments of the 20th century, while the left won the social and cultural ones. Neo-liberalism rolled back economic socialism in the 1980s, and the cultural left beat the moral majority in the 1990s.<br />...<br />Where once social and cultural issues were a source of unity for the left, they now appear to divide it. While many left-leaning GamerGate supporters continue to show strong support for core “cultural left” positions such as abortion and gay marriage, the results also show that they are completely turned off by any of the more recent additions to the progressive agenda – positive discrimination, “call-out culture,” trigger warnings, safe spaces, etc. And, as we saw in my last piece, their level of trust in the left has been severely shaken. </p>

<p>It would be foolish to assume that debates on these issues are limited to gaming. In the past two years, there have been growing signs of quite serious division on the cultural left. It wasn’t just conservatives who were up in arms about Brendan Eich’s firing – liberal publications like The Atlantic and Slate sounded the alarm as well. Alan Dershowitz is no right-winger, nor is columnist Emily Yoffe, yet the former is leading a campaign of Harvard lawyers against the university’s interpretation of Title IX laws, and the latter’s 9-page critique of the same policies went viral. Guardian columnist Nick Cohen is a leading liberal in the UK, and yet an increasing number of his columns are devoted to critiquing what he sees as a growing culture of censorship and “call-outs” [1, 2, 3].</p>

<p>Battle lines are being quietly, warily drawn in the culture wars – not between conservatives and liberals (although conservatives are certainly aware of what’s going on [1, 2, 3, 4] ) – but between liberals and progressives. These two groups, who once appeared indistinguishable, are becoming more so. Liberals are increasingly concerned by what they see as progressives’ embrace of vigilantism. Progressives, by contrast, seem increasingly concerned with the need to change culture by any means possible.</p>
</blockquote><h1>Why The Reasonables Should Disavow GG</h1>
<p>I would agree with a large portion of the previously quote. But people of that nature really should stay clear of <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a>. Gamergate has a clear density of outright sexists, trolls, and other types that are bad news. You do not want to give those toxic types a platform. You do not want your reasonable ideas associated with that harassers, and sexists. You want to make it clear that you do not like sexism, while still disputing censorship and authoritarianism. Being part of GG will not help you at all in this. In fact, it will discredit any good idea you have. By promoting a community like gamergate you will score a huge own goal, and will be the biggest help that your opposition could wish for.</p>

<p>Edit to this post: spelling and grammar.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/adambaldwin" class="p-category" rel="tag">#adambaldwin</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/computersecurityandtrolling" class="p-category" rel="tag">#computersecurityandtrolling</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gamergate" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gamergate</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gaming" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gaming</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/gnaa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#gnaa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/samhowzit" class="p-category" rel="tag">#samhowzit</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#GamerGate</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#fiveguys</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#NotYourShield</category>
      <category>#NotYourShield</category>
      <category>#NotYourShield</category>
      <category>#NotAShield</category>
      <category>#Gamergate</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#42</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#adambaldwin</category>
      <category>#computersecurityandtrolling</category>
      <category>#gamergate</category>
      <category>#gaming</category>
      <category>#gnaa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#samhowzit</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
