<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23worldbank</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23worldbank&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-funding Energy Consumption: A Proposal to Encourage Energy Efficiency of Consumer Products</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/pre-funding-energy-consumption-a-proposal-to-encourage-energy-efficiency-of</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/pre-funding-energy-consumption-a-proposal-to-encourage-energy-efficiency-of</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 21:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>It is clear that there is much that we can do to improve the energy efficiency of our economy. However, the main reason why these options are not deployed is consumers are unable to price and evaluate the future energy consumption of the products that they buy. Here I will propose a method of pre-funding energy consumption of consumer products. Under my proposal manufacturers of consumer, business and industrial electronics and appliances would be required to make an energy deposit based on the future energy consumption of their products. This deposit will be equal to the cost of the energy that the typical user of the product would pay over a typical product lifetime. The consumer could then redeem this energy deposit when they buy electricity or fuel.This proposal would provide consumers a clear signal of the value of the future energy consumption of their purchases. This is because the energy consumption would be part of the cost of purchase. The effect of this proposal on the pocketbooks of consumers would be minimal because the cost of the energy deposit would be rebated dollar for dollar to the consumer's future energy consumption.If consumers buy more efficient products as a result of this program then they will on the whole save money.Unlike alternatives, my proposal is a market-based way of encouraging energy efficiency. It works by making markets more efficient instead of telling consumers what they can buy. As far as I can tell no one has proposed this idea before. This blog post gives an overview of the justifications for this program. In later posts I will go deeper into these issues and provide more details on how pre-funding energy consumption would work.</p>
<!--more-->
<p>The potential scale of energy efficiency improvements that can be made in the United States is vast. The United States is much less efficient in its energy usage than other industrialized nations. <a href="http://data.worldbank.org/indicator/EG.USE.PCAP.KG.OE">According to the World Bank,</a> the average American uses about 300.91 GJ (83586 KWH) of energy per year. For comparison, the average resident of France uses a little over half that or 169.28 GJ per year.The following map depicts the differences of energy consumption between different countries.</p>

<p>[caption id="attachment_490" align="alignnone" width="530"]<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Energy-consumption-per-capita-2003.png"></a> Map Via Wikipedia and licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported license.[/caption]</p>

<p>It is possible that America could attain this type of energy efficiency in two decades.</p>

<p>Why haven't we achieved a more efficient economy already? One important reason is that consumers have imperfect information about energy usage.When buying a product consumers often have little knowledge about which is more energy efficient. Even when the energy usage of a product is labeled, it is difficult for a typical person to quantify this into a long term cost of ownership. How many consumers check how much money a 60 watt light-bulb will cost to run? How many even know how to conduct these calculations? Most likely very few. To run efficiently markets require consumers to have good information on what they are purchasing and how the product compares to alternatives. My proposal will solve this issue. The future cost of energy will be made immediately known to the consumer because it will show up on the price tag.The guesswork that consumers have to do to compare energy efficiency will be eliminated. A strong source of bias and inefficiency in the marketplace will be fixed.</p>

<p>My proposal is different than others which have been previously made as it relies on giving consumers and businesses a market signal without supporting particular options on the market. Consumers are allowed to apply other information they have and their knowledge of their exact circumstances to their product decisions. While the government should certainly use multiple methods to encourage energy efficiency my proposal may be best suited to form the core of an energy efficiency policy because of its market-based nature. Regulations that ban certain products act by taking choose away from consumers. When the government subsides a type of product it may be picking favorites, even when an even more cost effective energy efficiency option may be available.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/france" class="p-category" rel="tag">#france</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/kwh" class="p-category" rel="tag">#kwh</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/mapviawikipedia" class="p-category" rel="tag">#mapviawikipedia</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/worldbank" class="p-category" rel="tag">#worldbank</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#france</category>
      <category>#kwh</category>
      <category>#mapviawikipedia</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#worldbank</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
