<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23employmentdivision</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23employmentdivision&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Indiana RFRA (part 2: why I disagree with the law)</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/thoughts-on-the-indiana-rfra-part-2-why-i-disagree</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/thoughts-on-the-indiana-rfra-part-2-why-i-disagree</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 05:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>In my previous posts on the Indiana RFRA, I focused on some of the misconceptions going around about what the law actually is about. Now, with that issue cleared up, I will discuss why I think that the RFRA legislation is a bad idea. Now, there are some reasons why exempting people who disagree with a law from it whenever reasonably practical might seem attractive. However, I contend that the practical issues with such a rule end up making it fundamentally unworkable. Furthermore I have some more general conceptual issues the idea behind the law. My first objection to it, is about how the law favors religious objections to legislation over secular ones this is fundamentally unfair the nonreligious individuals who might have an objection to a law that does not involve religious belief. The second objection is to the legal standard the RFRA uses to evaluate potential requests for exemptions-taken at its face it's much too strong and lets in too many objections that interfere with the public purpose. The third objection is fundamentally the bureaucratic hassle involved in evaluating such requests even a more lax standard for evaluating objections to laws will require creating many special situations for people. This will bring the associated paperwork bureaucratic tangle that one would expect from such a situation. Finally, proposed ways to patch the law, such as ruling out the ability for corporate entities to claim exemptions (even when owned by individuals of uniform belief), will fundamentally not work to resolve the issues involved will bring their own issues. Now, I will say, this issue brings up complicated trade-offs inverse rest of this post I will try to give the opposing side its due, and I will look at some of their arguments. I hope you will find his explanation my opinion to be reasonably balanced and take opposing arguments is having some degree of credibility-even if I express fundamental disagreement.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>An editorial by Daniel O. Conkle published March 26 <a href="http://www.indystar.com/story/opinion/readers/2015/03/07/indiana-needs-religious-freedom-legislation/24477303/">defends the Indiana law on the grounds that it allows the protection</a> of "religious believers of all faiths by granting them precisely the same consideration [as the federal RFRA provides]. He notes that the level of scrutiny provided for in the law has served to provide some potentially useful protections of the rights of religious groups.</p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>Applying this test, a unanimous U.S. Supreme Court recently ruled that a Muslim prisoner was free to practice his faith by wearing a half-inch beard that posed no risk to prison security. Likewise, in a 2012 decision, a court ruled that the Pennsylvania RFRA protected the outreach ministry of a group of Philadelphia churches, ruling that the city could not bar them from feeding homeless individuals in the city parks.
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>…..
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>In any event, most religious freedom claims have nothing to do with same-sex marriage or discrimination. The proposed Indiana RFRA would provide valuable guidance to Indiana courts, directing them to balance religious freedom against competing interests under the same legal standard that applies throughout most of the land.
</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailykos.com/story/2015/03/29/1374196/-The-Strange-Career-of-RFRA">A writer on the liberal website Daily Kos likewise says that</a> the history of the law comes from a strong intent to protect the rights of religious miniorities, and to defend separation of church and state. Treating the right to free exercise of religion as strongly as other rights furthers this goal in the author's opinion.</p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>As long as laws were facially neutral, i.e., were not targeting or singling out particular religious groups for discrimination, then a law which indirectly restricted or burdened a religious practice was/is constitutional. Scalia replaced the Sherbet test of "compelling interest and strict scrutiny" with a "no coercion" test. If your religious practice is accidentally harmed by a facially neutral law that is not intended to coerce or punish your religious group, tough shit.</em>
<em>People were outraged and the outrage spanned the political spectrum of the early 1990s. Strict separation groups like the ACLU, Americans United, the BJCPA, and the People for the American Way made common cause with the Catholic Bishops, the American Jewish Congress, the Christian Legal Society (a very conservative group) and many others to craft the Religious Freedom Restoration Act which was designed to restore the strict scrutiny and compelling interest tests at the federal level
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>….
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>Without Sherbet [v. Verner – a case setting a similar standard to the one found in RFRAs], one gets a form of secular society more like France's (e.g. where one can ban wearing of religious symbols) than the "benevolent neutrality" that has always been the American tradition.
</em></p>
<p><a href="http://wthitv.com/2015/03/27/one-indiana-state-representative-sits-down-with-news-10-to-explain-his-vote-for-rfra/">A member of the Indiana legislature had the following to say in favor of the law</a>:</p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>First and foremost, what does RFRA do? It establishes a judicial standard of review that will provide the courts with clear guidance on how to resolve any matters that come forth surrounding religious freedom. RFRA protects the rights of everyone, regardless of their religious affiliation or lack thereof. This bill is about prohibiting a governmental entity from substantially burdening a person's exercise of religion. It only applies to government action, not citizen to citizen.
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>A quick example, in 2012 a court determined that RFRA protected the outreach ministry of a group of Philadelphia churches, ruling that the city could not bar them from feeding homeless individuals. Along with practical examples, it is equally important to look at the history behind RFRA.
</em></p>
<p>However with the clear good at such laws have provided on some points there is substantial possibility for negative outcomes. And on its surface test the RFRA demands is exceedingly harsh. Probably legitimate claims such laws been known to bring in frivolous or at least highly dubious ones. The only reason we haven't seen the worst of what that standard truly means that courts have implicitly watered it down to a much more reasonable one. Doing so, courts have probably saved the legislature from itself. But, one should take a moment to think what the standard entailed by the plain language of RFRAs would entail if taken seriously. In <em>Employment Division v. Smith</em> (the case which RFRAs are primarily meant to reverse) the Court said the following:</p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>The "compelling government interest" requirement seems benign, because it is familiar from other fields. But using it as the standard that must be met before the government may accord different treatment on the basis of race, see, e.g., Palmore v. Sidoti, or before the government may regulate the content of speech, see, e.g., Sable Communications of California v. FCC, is not remotely comparable to using it for the purpose asserted here. What it produces in those other fields -- equality of treatment, and an unrestricted flow of contending speech -- are constitutional norms; what it would produce here -- a private right to ignore generally applicable laws -- is a constitutional anomaly.
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>… The rule respondents favor would open the prospect of constitutionally required religious exemptions from civic obligations of almost every conceivable kind -- ranging from compulsory military service to the payment of taxes to health and safety regulation such as manslaughter and child neglect laws, compulsory vaccination laws, drug laws, and traffic laws; to social welfare legislation such as minimum wage laws, child labor laws, animal cruelty laws, environmental protection laws, and laws providing for equality of opportunity for the races.
</em></p>
<p>The only reason that the disaster posed in that opinion did not occur that the courts corrected for the flaw by, at least de facto, substituting the standard stated in the federal RFRA a much more lenient and reasonable one. As the RFRA has been applied, the strict scrutiny stated in the law, has been converted into something that looks a lot more like weaker standards like intermediate scrutiny. However, this workaround is not neutralized the threat that putting such a harsh standard the law poses. Strict scrutiny the legal standard used in a lot of areas; such as free speech law and privacy law. When courts out of necessity say something is the least restrictive means to meeting a compelling need in order to accommodate a malformed law passed by Congress, the application of that standard is undermined in all areas of law.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">In my opinion, another critical flaw of RFRAs is that they favor religion over non-religion by allowing for exemptions based on religious grounds but not allowing for exemptions based on secular beliefs. I haven't been able to find the proponent of the law attempts to seriously justify this element of the law. It makes little sense to give a religious exemption, but not an exemption to someone who has a secular objection. In fact, I would argue that, if anything, it should be the secular exemptions to get degree of priority-as these tend to be the ones that have the highest chance based on some grounds that are widely justifiable and contestable based on shared values. Belief that comes from musings about what a sky fairy wants, have a much lower chance of being based on publicly contestable and justifiable values.</p>
<p>A common suggestion to fix some of the deficiencies of the law is to remove reginition of corporations as eligible for protection under RFRAs – with the argument that the problems come from applying it to businesses. The above mentioned Daily Kos article elaborates on this position</p>
<p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>In all this legal history, there is no mention of allowing businesses to discriminate on which customers to serve. There is no targeting of LGBTQ persons or Muslims or women trying to fill birth control prescriptions, etc. RFRA and its state counterparts were designed to stop a majoritarian minded SCOTUS and overreaching government from restricting religious practices--usually practices by minority groups overlooked by majorities. RFRA and its state clones were supposed to be protections for relatively powerless groups, not weapons by powerful groups against vulnerable individuals. So, what happened?
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>…..
</em></p><p style="margin-left: 36pt;"><em>The other start to this strange twist was Citizens United because, even though the case was about campaign finance regulations, the SCOTUS ruled that corporations are persons and entitled to free speech protection. Then the Hobby Lobby case extended this "logic" further, allowing a business to have a religious liberty claim--when never before in this country had "religious liberty" meant an employer's liberty to impose his/her religious convictions on employees (If my employer is a Jehovah's Witness, can s/he now deny blood transfusions in my health coverage because of his/her religious belief?) or customers.
</em></p>
<p>This point of view is pretty counterfactual as to the actual role of corporate personhood in the law. It is not something that originated with the citizens untied case, and goes as far back as the 1800s. Furthermore, not all of the issues with RFRAs, or even the most severe issues with the concept behind them come from its applications to businesses. As I explained to some degree in the last post on the RFRA, courts are pretty unlikely to apply it in a way that allows for discrimination. And even the Hobby Lobby case was not as huge a problem as it would seem at first glance. And the HL case isn't an example of it being a huge problem there was an easy workaround to that ruling. Funny accounting. And that is what the HHS eventually did to deal with the issue. But the HL case does illustrate the real issue with RFRAs -- that it will mandate special work abounds that consume a lot of administrative effort. HL got an arrangement where the insurance company uses non-HL money to pay for the birth control and uses HL money to pay for non-birth control treatment for other people than HL employees. Waste of time bullshit. And RFRAs are good at generating circumstances that require that type of pointless work around. But there isn't going to be any disastrous outcomes, just a large number of minor annoyances. The hugely problematic issues come from lone individuals. One of the precursors of the Indiana RFRA was a law providing for religious exemptions to vaccinations. Also inherent in this type of argument seems to be the thought that it is impossible for anyone with a problematic religious view to use a wide grant of exemption in an adverse way.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/employmentdivision" class="p-category" rel="tag">#employmentdivision</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hl" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hl</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hobbylobby" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hobbylobby</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/politics" class="p-category" rel="tag">#politics</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rfra" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rfra</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#employmentdivision</category>
      <category>#hl</category>
      <category>#hobbylobby</category>
      <category>#politics</category>
      <category>#rfra</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the Hobby Lobby Case</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-hobby-lobby-case</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/thoughts-on-the-hobby-lobby-case</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 18:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>Yesterday the U.S Supreme Court announced its decision in <em>Burwell v. Hobby Lobby</em>. The Court ruled that the Religious Freedom Restoration Act (RFRA) mandates that Hobby Lobby and other companies with owners that have religious objections to the federal contraceptive mandate be given an exemption to the mandate. The RFRA is a statute passed in 1993 that requires religious exemptions to a wide range of laws and was passed due to Congressional frustration at the courts' unwillingness to mandate exemptions to neutral laws under the First Amendment. The range of the protections for religious objection provided by RFRA are much broader than what the Constitution requires. The RFRA can be repealed or amended like any other law, and due to the Court's ruling in <em>City of Boerne v. Flores</em> (1997) it only applies to federal regulations, not state laws. A Democratic controlled Congress, and Bill Clinton passed the RFRA despite court rulings that stated that applying such a standard would open a floodgate of litigation and requests for exemptions. In <em>Employment Division v. Smith</em> (1990) the Court rejected the standard eventually imposed by the RFRA saying it would effect laws that include "payment of taxes to health and safety regulation such as manslaughter and child neglect laws, compulsory vaccination laws, drug laws, and traffic laws; to social welfare legislation such as minimum wage laws, child labor laws, animal cruelty laws, environmental protection laws, and laws providing for equality of opportunity for the races" . For reasons I will discuss later I think that the majority opinion is the correct interpretation of the RFRA and of current law. The problems with this ruling are mostly the fault of Congress.  However, I also think that the RFRA should be repealed and I am largely opposed to grants of religious exemptions to neutral laws. I will discuss that problem in a future blog post.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Historically, the Supreme Court has long ruled that while religious exemptions can be added to laws, there is no obligation under the First Amendment to grant such exemptions. The First Amendment requires that members of different religions be allowed to communicate their beliefs, requires that the government refrains from favoring certain religious beliefs, and protects the freedom of believers to associate with others who share their beliefs. However, the religious still have to abide by the same laws as everyone else. The first case where the court found this is in <em>Reynolds v. United States</em> (1878) which upheld a law banning polygamy against a religious freedom based challenge.  It is worth noting that <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/12/15/us/a-utah-law-prohibiting-polygamy-is-weakened.html">a 2013 case before the United States District Court in Utah struck down</a> the same polygamy ban statute on privacy grounds. <em>Reynolds</em> created a solid boundary between belief and action. While it is acceptable for one to have and express a religion, it is not as acceptable to put this belief into action, when that action conflicts with the law. That principle was the law until the Supreme Court broadened its interpretation of the Free Exercise clause to allow for more religious exemption to laws. In <em>Sherbert v. Verner</em> (1963) the court found that it violated the First Amendment when the plaintiff in the case was deprived of unemployment benefits as a result of refusing to accept a job that required work on the Sabbath. In <em>Wisconsin v. Yoder</em> (1972) the Court ruled that Amish parents and children must be exempted from truancy laws when those laws mandate attendance to a school that conflicts with Amish belief. In these cases the court ruled that when someone has <span style="color: #252525;">a sincere religious belief that conflicts with a law and when complying with the law would put a substantial burden on the objector's ability to act on that belief, the government has a strong obligation to grant exemptions to the law. The only times when a exemption does not have to be granted occur when the government has a compelling interest that cannot be fulfilled by lesser means. </span> These rulings soon provoked further litigation that eventually drove the Supreme Court to reconsider its stance on this subject matter. In Employment Division v. Smith (1990) the court finally reversed itself and returned to the policy that religious exemptions are not required. In the majority opinion justice Scalia wrote</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The "compelling government interest" requirement seems benign, because it is familiar from other fields. But using it as the standard that must be met before the government may accord different treatment on the basis of race, see, e.g., Palmore v. Sidoti, or before the government may regulate the content of speech, see, e.g., Sable Communications of California v. FCC, is not remotely comparable to using it for the purpose asserted here. What it produces in those other fields -- equality of treatment, and an unrestricted flow of contending speech -- are constitutional norms; what it would produce here -- a private right to ignore generally applicable laws -- is a constitutional anomaly.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Later in the opinion he said</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The rule respondents favor would open the prospect of constitutionally required religious exemptions from civic obligations of almost every conceivable kind -- ranging from compulsory military service to the payment of taxes to health and safety regulation such as manslaughter and child neglect laws, compulsory vaccination laws, drug laws, and traffic laws; to social welfare legislation such as minimum wage laws, child labor laws, animal cruelty laws, environmental protection laws, and laws providing for equality of opportunity for the races</p>
</blockquote>
<p>However, Congress didn't see the problem and passed the RFRA three years later, finding that "<span style="color: #000000;">laws 'neutral' toward religion may burden religious exercise as surely as laws intended to interfere with religious exercise"</span>. The full text of the RFRA can be found at <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130611205052/&lt;a%20href=" http:>http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>religiousfreedom.lib.virginia.edu/<wbr></wbr>sacred/<wbr></wbr>RFRA1993.html</a>"&gt;<a href="http://religiousfreedom.lib.virginia.edu/sacred/RFRA1993.html">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>religiousfreedom.lib.virginia.edu/<wbr></wbr>sacred/<wbr></wbr>RFRA1993.html</a> The core of the law states that</p>
<blockquote>
<p>(a) In General: Government shall not substantially burden a person's exercise of religion even if the burden results from a rule of general applicability, except as provided in subsection (b). (b) Exception: Government may substantially burden a person's exercise of religion only if it demonstrates that application of the burden to the person-- (1) is in furtherance of a compelling governmental interest; and (2) is the least restrictive means of furthering that compelling governmental interest..</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Even the application of the word "person" to a corporation such as Hobby Lobby isn't something the Court just came up with. If you object to that <span style="color: #262626;">blame Congress for it.  Even the application of it to corporations is due to the wonderful work of Congress. The Dictionary Act statute at 1 U.S. Code § 1 defines what "person" refers to in legislation in the absence of clarification otherwise, and  the RFRA just said "person" without any clarification otherwise. </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p>the words “person” and “whoever” include corporations, companies, associations, firms, partnerships, societies, and joint stock companies, as well as individuals;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Furthermore, it is worth noting that ultimately the application of religious freedom legislation to a company protects the owners of it. The rights of a company come out of their rights. And the Hobby Lobby company is owned by just a few individuals, all of whom are of uniform opinion on this matter..<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2014/06/30/hobby-lobby-and-the-legal-rights-of-people-organized-as-corporations/"> An editorial in the Washington Post discusses this, and quotes the following passage</a> from Justice Alito's opinion in the Hobby Lobby case.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Congress provided protection for people like the [owners of Hobby Lobby and Conestoga Wood] by employing a familiar legal fiction: It included corporations within RFRA’s definition of “persons.” But it is important to keep in mind that the purpose of this fiction is to provide protection for human beings. A corporation is simply a form of organization used by human beings to achieve desired ends. An established body of law specifies the rights and obligations of the people(including shareholders, officers, and employees) who are associated with a corporation in one way or another. When rights, whether constitutional or statutory, are extended to corporations, the purpose is to protect the rights of these people. For example, extending Fourth Amendment protection to corporations protects the privacy interests of employees and others associated with the company. Protecting corporations from government seizure of their property without just compensation protects all those who have a stake in the corporations’ financial well-being. And protecting the free-exercise rights of corporations like Hobby Lobby, Conestoga, and Mardel protects the religious liberty of the humans who own and control those companies….</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Now that it has been established that a firm like Hobby Lobby can claim religious freedom rights under the RFRA, now lets see why the RFRA mandates religious exemptions to the mandate. To win the case Hobby Lobby at the least has to prove two things.</p>
<ol><li>That its owners have a sincere religious belief that conflicts with the mandate. A<span style="color: #262626;">ll that has to be proven is that Hobby Lobby's owners' belief is sincerely held. They don't have to prove that their belief is actually correct.</span></li>
    <li>They have to prove that their ability to exercise  their beliefs are substantially burdened by their beliefs</li>
</ol>
<p>In regards to the first question, the owners of Hobby Lobby claim to believe that using certain forms of contraceptives, or even being complicit in their distribution is immoral. The trial court found no reason to doubt their sincerity in this belief. Much press coverage has though it is absurd that such a indirect connection to the allegedly immoral activity as buying an insurance plan that could be used to acquire contraception, can be the foundation of a RFRA claim. <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/volokh-conspiracy/wp/2014/06/30/the-religious-freedom-restoration-act-and-complicity-in-sin/">However, the RFRA clearly allows such a claim.</a> As per the terms of that legislation, all that matters is that the owners of Hobby Lobby believe that the law compels them to do an immoral action. If they believe that contributing to someone else's activity is itself immoral, than that is still sufficient.  The conditions for a substantial burden to occur and similarly broad. All that needs to be met is that the owners of the company think that the law compels them to do something that is intolerably sinful.</p>

<p>At this point the government could still salvage its case if it could prove the following two things</p>
<ol><li>There is a compelling government interest involved</li>
    <li>The regulation is the least intrusive legislation possible to meet the interest.</li>
</ol>
<p>The court found that there is a compelling government interest involved. However, there are regulations possible that put less of a burden on the beliefs of the Hobby Lobby owners. The government could for example pay for the contraceptives out of pocket.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/employmentdivision" class="p-category" rel="tag">#employmentdivision</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/hobbylobby" class="p-category" rel="tag">#hobbylobby</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/rfra" class="p-category" rel="tag">#rfra</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/supremecourt" class="p-category" rel="tag">#supremecourt</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#252525</category>
      <category>#000000</category>
      <category>#262626</category>
      <category>#262626</category>
      <category>#employmentdivision</category>
      <category>#hobbylobby</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#rfra</category>
      <category>#supremecourt</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
