<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23scottadams</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23scottadams&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>On the Phrase &#x201C;Social Justice&#x201D;</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-phrase-social-justice</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2015/on-the-phrase-social-justice</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 21:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/socialjustice.jpg"><img src="http://www.theojones.name/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/socialjustice.jpg" alt="socialjustice" width="1000" height="800" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2439"></a>The above image is a collage of three of the top results on Flickr for a search of the phrase "Social Justice". The <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/sully_aka__wstera2/4478077831/">top-left image is from user wstera2 </a>and is titled "When liberals are losing a debate". The top right image is from user Takver and is titled "C<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/takver/5415825802/">hange, Freedom, Social Justice - Egypt Uprising protest</a>". The bottom image is titled "<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/rikkis_refuge/16400696138/">World Day for Social Justice</a>" and is via user Rikki's Refuge.</p>

<p>By its self, the phrase "social justice" is pretty meaningless. The phrase is effectively equivalent to the word "fairness". Try taking an article that uses the phrase and swapping out all occurrences of "social justice" for fairness. Very little meaning will be lost.    But "fairness" is an arbitrary concept. Almost every political ideology will perceive their goals as "fair".  Phrases like "social justice" are the political equivalent of "maximizing synergies" business speak. Such concepts are almost entirely dependent on ideology. What one will perceive as "fair" or "just is largely subjective in global terms. Every major political ideology has a different conception of the public good. Libertarians regard markets as properly "fair", others regard egalitarianism as "fair", and others take a roughly utilitarian perspective of the greatest good for the greatest number as "fair". However, the concept is still subjective.  In regards to talk of "fairness" in economic policy, <a href="http://blog.dilbert.com/post/102964895406/fairness-test">Scott Adams (the author of the Dilbert cartoon) made a similar point</a>. "<em>fairness is a concept invented so dumb people can participate in debates. Fairness isn't a natural law of the universe. It's a psychological problem. We sometimes get fairness confused with equality. Equality is usually good, and can often be measured with a satisfying precision. Fairness, on the other hand, is usually just a rationale for some sort of bias ….It's just a psychological phenomenon that is easily manipulated.</em>"</p>

<p>However, there is one case where the phrase "social justice" carries more meaning than the word "fairness". The only meaning that is conveyed by that term is signaling about the speaker. Only certain ideologies refer to their goals as maximizing social justice. This gets us to pejoratives like "SJW".  So when a gater rants about "SJWs" they are attacking the ideologies refer to their goals as maximizing social justice. However, SJW is a strong pejorative. Using it is like saying "M$" in a discussion about Windows 10. It removes any indication that you are processing facts in a rational way and indicates that confirmation bias is at work. It's an inherently mocking tone, one that should only be used with clearly unreasonable positions. And treating reasonable positions as unreasonable destroys one's credibility.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/business" class="p-category" rel="tag">#business</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/scottadams" class="p-category" rel="tag">#scottadams</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/sjw" class="p-category" rel="tag">#sjw</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#business</category>
      <category>#scottadams</category>
      <category>#sjw</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
