<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23electronicfrontierfoundation</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23electronicfrontierfoundation&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Secret Law, Secret Courts and The Worst Element of the NSA Surveillance Program</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/secret-law-secret-courts-and-the-worst-element-of-the</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/secret-law-secret-courts-and-the-worst-element-of-the</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 17:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        
<p>While there are many things we should be concerned about with the NSA's vast data collection programs, in my opinion the worst is the fact that politicians are making many critical decisions about our privacy rights in secret without public debate. This secrecy is an assault on the basic principles of the rule of law and democracy.</p>

<p>As the<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/07/us/in-secret-court-vastly-broadens-powers-of-nsa.html?pagewanted=all&_r=1&"> New York Times reports t</a>he court has "created a secret body of law" and has assumed a role that is greatly beyond its initial purpose of "approving case-by-case wiretapping orders". In secret, and without making public any justifications for its decisions, the court has approved vast data collection programs. <a href="http://wonkette.com/521997/fisa-court-busy-making-awesome-secret-law-awesomely-in-secret">Additionally</a> the court , has reinterpreted the definition of “foreign intelligence” to include not just communications involving a foreign national, but also many communications between Americans. The FISA court <a href="http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2013/08/new-leak-nsa-can-search-us-e-mail-data-but-theoretically-isnt-allowed-to/">has declared</a> that the NSA can collect all American email data and create a system that allows this data to be searched -- even when the emails are between Americans using an American service provider. It is likely that the NSA has used this power to search American emails.Why won't the FISA court release summaries of its rulings? As the top judge on the court explains, the public <a href="http://www.fas.org/irp/agency/doj/fisa/fisc-032713.pdf">cannot be trusted to "understand"</a> the decisions -- especially after important details are edited out of released opinions. Furthermore, actually giving the public even a summary of what the government is doing on its behalf would overwork the judges so much that the expanded workload  "would have a detrimental impact on the FISC's ability to address matters currently before the court" because "small number of judges, attorneys, and staff that comprise the FISC are fully occupied by its current caseload".</p>

<p>Why do I call this great secrecy the worst element of the NSA program? In a free society it is necessary that policy makers are held to governing in the public's interest, not their own. The only way to make sure that the government is held accountable is to create a political and legal system where voters and the public have the ability to effectively contest government policy. The public must know what the government is doing on its behalf in-order to evaluate the actions of the state. A secret court is unable to fully hear and take into account opposing arguments. Furthermore, even if the NSA program turns out to be legal, secret decisions cannot be contested on election day and the politicians who allowed the spying program will not face any consequences if they have made a bad call. It is ultimately the task of voters' to decide if the NSA programs have employed the proper level of protections for privacy but if the executive branch orders and court decisions allowing these programs are not known to the public, voters will not be able to make this evaluation.</p>

<p><em> </em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/electronicfrontierfoundation" class="p-category" rel="tag">#electronicfrontierfoundation</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fisa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fisa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/fisc" class="p-category" rel="tag">#fisc</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/nsa" class="p-category" rel="tag">#nsa</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#electronicfrontierfoundation</category>
      <category>#fisa</category>
      <category>#fisc</category>
      <category>#nsa</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
