<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23firefoxphone</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23firefoxphone&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Appoints New CEO</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mozilla-appoints-new-ceo</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2014/mozilla-appoints-new-ceo</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 13:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>This happened: <br /><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2014/07/mozilla-confirms-interim-ceo-as-new-top-hire/"></a><a href="http://arstechnica.com/business/2014/07/mozilla-confirms-interim-ceo-as-new-top-hire/">http:/<wbr></wbr>/<wbr></wbr>arstechnica.com/<wbr></wbr>business/<wbr></wbr>2014/<wbr></wbr>07/<wbr></wbr>mozilla-confirms-interim-ceo-as-new-top-hire/<wbr></wbr></a> <br /></p><blockquote>
<p>On Monday, the Mozilla Corporation announced that its last-minute April hire for interim CEO, Chris Beard, has been permanently appointed to the position. Mozilla Executive Chairwoman Mitchell Baker confirmed the news in a blog post, stating that "the board has reviewed many internal and external candidates—and no one we met was a better fit."</p>

<p>Beard's Mozilla tenure began in 2004 and saw him eventually rise to chief innovation and chief marketing officer. He left the company in 2013 to become an "executive in residence" at Greylock Partners, an investment firm with a heavy focus on tech companies. His return to Mozilla in April came on the heels of Brendan Eich's controversial hire to the CEO position, which ended with Eich's resignation that month.</p>
</blockquote><p>Its idiotic to make decisions about the management of a company based on the basis of political stuff that has little to do with the running of the company. Based pretty much on the opinion of people writing flamage on Tumblr, Mozilla replaced one of the founders of the company, a person with wide experience in the firm's core competency -- creating web browsers -- with a marketing type based solely on a donation to a political campaign in 2008. This is utter insanity. I believe that this decision will be a future business school case  study on why it is a good idea to keep personal politics out of the running of a company. The new CEO's current tenure has already shown that he is an inferior candidate. As interim CEO Beard has doubled down on multiple bad decisions by expanding the company's phone project and attempting to enter the computer market by creating a laptop. Beard is attempting to run the company like a regular software company. But the world of open source is different. The open source world already suffers from a high degree of market fragmentation and the actions of the new management of Mozilla will only make matters worse. Beard's decision to add Digital Rights Management systems to the Firefox browser has widely alienated the Linux community. The decision to manafucture a phone puts them in open warfare with many companies with deeper pockets -- particularly Microsoft and Google. It also takes Mozilla far from areas where it has a history of product development. Considering the fact that the Firefox Phone has no user or developer base it has no chance on the market. It is in the same price range as Microsoft's low end phones, and it is also in direct competition with the various Chinese landfill Androids that are on the market. They have simply no serious hope of winning this battle. Their decision to make a Chromebook competitor is similarly boneheaded.  They will be competing with dozens of established computer manufacturers when they have no experience in this area. </p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/brendaneich" class="p-category" rel="tag">#brendaneich</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ceo" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ceo</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/digitalrightsmanagement" class="p-category" rel="tag">#digitalrightsmanagement</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/firefoxphone" class="p-category" rel="tag">#firefoxphone</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#brendaneich</category>
      <category>#ceo</category>
      <category>#digitalrightsmanagement</category>
      <category>#firefoxphone</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
