<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:g="http://base.google.com/ns/1.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title>Theo Jones</title>
    <description><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></description>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[Thoughts and Ideas]]></itunes:summary>
    <link>http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23industrialage</link>
    <atom:link href="http://withknown.superfeedr.com/" rel="hub"/>
    <atom:link href="http://www.theojones.name/content/posts/?q=%23industrialage&amp;_t=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <generator>Known https://withknown.com</generator>
    <item>
      <title>Libertarian Holiday Cheer</title>
      <link>http://www.theojones.name/2013/libertarian-holiday-cheer</link>
      <guid>http://www.theojones.name/2013/libertarian-holiday-cheer</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 15:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Theo Jones</author>
      <description><![CDATA[<div>
        <p>Think that Ebenezer Scrooge is a paragon of greed? Well there are many libertarians that would tell you that Scrooge represents the real spirit of the holiday season. Let's start with the Von Mises Instute's <a href="http://archive.mises.org/4460/scrooge-defended/">often reposted</a> classic "<a href="http://mises.org/daily/110">Scrooge Defended</a>". Apparently "his business benefits his employees, society, and himself" -- well at least himself. But that's all that matters to a libertarian businessman.  </p><blockquote>
<p>The fact is, if Cratchit's skills were worth more to anyone than the fifteen shillings Scrooge pays him weekly, there would be someone glad to offer it to him. Since no one has, and since Cratchit's profit-maximizing boss is hardly a man to pay for nothing, Cratchit must be worth exactly his present wages.</p>
</blockquote><p>In glorious Libertopia employees are able to know of all possible job openings and are able to effortlessly switch from job to job at no cost. Employers know about the abilities of every possible employee in existence. Also, Libertopia has no unemployment and everyone has capital available in unlimited quanties, so they can start their own businesses. However, the real world does not work that way.  </p><blockquote>
<p>No doubt Cratchit needs—i.e., wants—more, to support his family and care for Tiny Tim.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Food is just a "want" in Libertopia.  <br /><!--more--></p>
<blockquote>
<p>As for that one lump of coal Scrooge allows him, it bears emphasis that Cratchit has not been chained to his chilly desk. If he stays there, he shows by his behavior that he prefers his present wages-plus-comfort package to any other he has found, or supposes himself likely to find.</p>
</blockquote><p>Its ok to be an asshole to others if they have no other options.  </p><blockquote>
<p>More notorious even than his miserly ways are Scrooge's cynical words. "Are there no prisons," he jibes when solicited for charity, "and the Union workhouses?"Terrible, right? Lacking in compassion? Not necessarily. As Scrooge observes, he supports those institutions with his taxes. Already forced to help those who can't or won't help themselves, it is not unreasonable for him to balk at volunteering additional funds for their extra comfort.</p>
</blockquote><p>Nothing says "extra comfort" like a prison or a workhouse.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Dickens doesn't mention Scrooge's satisfied customers, but there must have been plenty of them for Scrooge to have gotten so rich.</p>
</blockquote><p>We all know that the only way that bankers can get rich is by having lots of satisfied customers.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Scrooge is said to hound debtors so relentlessly that—as the Ghost of Christmas Yet To Be is able to show him—an indebted couple rejoices at his demise.</p>
</blockquote><p>Sounds like we have ourselves a banker.  </p><blockquote>
<p>This canard is triply absurd. First, a businessman as keen as Scrooge would prefer to delay payment to protect his investment rather than take possession of possibly useless collateral.</p>
</blockquote><p>Looks like this libertarian has not done very much business with banks lately.</p><p>Next lets look at the Forbes article "<a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/fredsmith/2013/07/17/charles-dickens-ebenezer-scrooge-was-the-ultimate-job-creator/">Charles Dickens' Ebenezer Scrooge Was The Ultimate Job Creator</a>".  </p><blockquote>
<p>The Scrooges of the world were the stewards of the scarce capital—the seed corn prosperity—of that earlier Industrial Age. Ensuring that it was used wisely and honestly was critical to the wealthier England in which Dickens lived.</p>
</blockquote><p>I don't recall reading about how Scrooge invested his wealth on useful investments. I do remember reading about some one who hoarded wealth and gold. Remember that ones spending is someone else's income. Money saved is not money earned.  </p><blockquote>
<p>Every so often, a talented and enterprising individual would launch a new business.....But in this closely knit community, success placed cultural demands on the entrepreneur. He would be expected to make place in his business for an out-of-luck Uncle Bill or Aunt Sally.</p>

<p>Often, that entrepreneur would give into such cultural pressures and add these individuals to his payroll and the operation’s efficiency would decline, often leading to its collapse.</p>
</blockquote><p>Hear that? If a business does not treat its employees and customers like dirt it will shut down. Not being an asshole is like graft.</p><p><a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/ebenezerscrooge" class="p-category" rel="tag">#ebenezerscrooge</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/industrialage" class="p-category" rel="tag">#industrialage</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/old" class="p-category" rel="tag">#old</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/tinytim" class="p-category" rel="tag">#tinytim</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/uncategorized" class="p-category" rel="tag">#uncategorized</a> <a href="http://www.theojones.name/tag/vonmisesinstute" class="p-category" rel="tag">#vonmisesinstute</a></p></div>]]></description>
      <category>#ebenezerscrooge</category>
      <category>#industrialage</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#old</category>
      <category>#tinytim</category>
      <category>#uncategorized</category>
      <category>#vonmisesinstute</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
